<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Impact of Utility Balance and Endogeneity in Conjoint Analysis</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2003-08-26">August 26, 2003</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
							<email>jhauser@mit.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Toubia</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">MIT Sloan School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>38 Memorial Drive</addrLine>
									<postCode>E56-314, 02142</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>Massachusetts</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Columbia Business School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>522 Uris Hall</addrLine>
									<postCode>3022, 10027</postCode>
									<settlement>Broadway, New York</settlement>
									<region>New York</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Impact of Utility Balance and Endogeneity in Conjoint Analysis</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 05 2403 0498</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2003-08-26">August 26, 2003</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1040.0108</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-13T12:15+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>conjoint analysis</term>
					<term>efficient question design</term>
					<term>adaptive question design</term>
					<term>Internet market research</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Motivation</head><p>Adaptive conjoint analysis (ACA) has been used widely, both academically and commercially, for more than 25 years. Many authors have studied and improved both the theory and practice of ACA and many firms have relied on ACA for both product development and advertising decisions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Allenby and Arora 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">, Carroll and Green 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">, Choi and DeSarbo 1994</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">, Green and Krieger 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">, Green et al. 1991</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">, Huber et al. 1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">, Toubia et al. 2003</ref>. Sawtooth Software claims that ACA is one of the most popular forms of conjoint analysis in the world, likely has the largest installed base, and, in 2001, accounted for 37% of their sales <ref type="bibr">(private communications and Marketing News April 1, 2002, p. 20)</ref>. To its credit, Sawtooth Software has responded to academic critique with improvements through five generations. For example, hierarchical Bayes (HB) estimation is now available and ACA v.5 addresses the scaling issues highlighted by <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Green et al. (1991)</ref>. However, while both scaling and estimation have improved steadily, question selection in ACA has not changed since "they were originally programmed for the Apple II computer in the late 70s <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Orme and King 2002)</ref>."</p><p>Adaptive metric utility balance has always been at the heart of ACA question selection. That is, (1) the preference scale is metric (interval, not ordinal), (2) paired-comparison questions are chosen adaptively based on prior responses by individual respondents, and (3) the key criterion is utility balance (subject to other balance constraints). By utility balance, we mean that "ACA presents to the respondent pairs of concepts that are as nearly equal as possible in estimated utility" <ref type="bibr">(Sawtooth Software 2002, p. 11)</ref>.</p><p>In recent years, in an attempt to improve on the philosophy of ACA, researchers have begun to experiment with different forms of question adaptation. One set of researchers has explored "aggregate customization" for choice-based questions <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Arora and Huber 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Huber and Zwerina 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Johnson et al. 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Kanninen 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Orme and Huber 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Sandor and Wedel 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">, 2002</ref>. These researchers retain the utility-balanced criterion as one criterion in their algorithms, but focus on choice questions (one profile  is chosen from a set) rather than metric questions. They adapt questions between respondents (pretest, then full-scale study) rather than within respondents. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Another set of researchers drop the utility-balanced criterion, but use metric questions that are adapted within respondents <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Toubia et al. 2003)</ref>. This paper focuses on the impact of adaptive metric utility balance. We show that this criterion often leads to biases, inefficiencies, and, potentially, higher response errors. We provide examples where these biases and inefficiencies can adversely affect managerial decisions, but, fortunately, in most cases, the magnitude of the effects is modest. Nonetheless, the phenomena are real and can be easily avoided. In particular, the biases and inefficiencies can be mitigated with the use of choice questions and/or polyhedral methods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">An Illustrative Example</head><p>We draw on an application in which ACA was used as an aid to the design of a laptop computer bag with nine binary features plus price, specified at two levels-$100 and $70 <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Toubia et al. 2003)</ref>. We examine that data below, but first consider a hypothetical example in which all respondents are homogeneous and the true partworth differences are 10 20 30 100 as shown in the second column of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. For example, the partworth of "no handle" is −5 and the partworth of having a handle on the bag is +5. We simulate 1,000 respondents as follows:</p><p>• The a priori self-explicated questions (SEs) are chosen to be unbiased with normally distributed noise (ACA needs the SEs to select questions).</p><p>• Twenty metric paired-comparison questions are chosen by the utility-balance criterion using ACA's question-selection algorithm.</p><p>1 For example, the title of the <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Huber and Zwerina (1996)</ref> paper is "The Importance of Utility Balance in Efficient Choice Designs." Many of the other papers build on that paper. The <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Johnson et al. (2003)</ref> paper adapts choice questions for each respondent based on prior self-explicated (SE) questions, utility balance, and efficiency.</p><p>• Respondent answers are unbiased with normally distributed noise.</p><p>• Estimation uses standard ordinary least squares (OLS) estimation (later in this paper, we examine the impact of hierarchical Bayes estimation).</p><p>The results, shown in the third column of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, suggest that the estimates based on ACA questions are upwardly biased and that the bias increases with the magnitude of the true partworth differences. The fourth column suggests that the bias increases less than proportionally-there is relative bias. Features with low partworths are biased proportionally more than features with high partworths. This relative bias survives normalization (column 5 of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>). Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> is illustrative-we can make the bias larger (or smaller) with other examples. The exact parameters for this simulation, and all simulations in this paper are available in an online appendix.</p><p>The data of <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Green et al. (1991)</ref> anticipate the upward bias in partworths, but not the relative bias. They hypothesize that the bias "results as subjects attempt to utilize the full range of the (metric) scale" <ref type="bibr">(Green et al.,</ref><ref type="bibr">p. 219)</ref>. Such "stretching" bias is not in our simulations, thus the bias in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> must be because of another effect. However, the Green-Krieger-Agarwal (GKA) effect would reinforce the bias identified in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. We return to the GKA effect later in this paper.</p><p>The relative bias is modest, but it can affect managerial decisions. We compute "true" and estimated willingness to pay (WTP) in the last two columns of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. For features with small partworths, the differences are barely noticeable, but for the partworths of important and costly features, the differences are larger. If the "boot" cost $145 to manufacture, the true partworths would imply it should be included, but the estimated partworths would not. Aggregated over the nine hypothetical features the estimated partworths underpredict WTP by approximately 5.6%. In some product categories, this could be a managerially significant percentage. For example, Colgate introduced body washes with a unique no-leak "Zeller Marketing Science 24(3), pp. <ref type="bibr">498-507, © 2005 INFORMS</ref> valve" cap that enabled bottles to be stored cap-side down. The increase in cost was only a few percentage points. However, subsequent market research suggested that consumers' WTP for body washes did not justify this improvement (private communication). Had adaptive metric utility balance been used, even a small bias in estimated WTP would have caused Colgate to miss the substantial savings from dropping the Zeller valve.</p><p>Empirical data differ from the illustrative example in many ways. The SEs may not be unbiased, there may be heterogeneity in respondents' partworths, and the errors, both in the SEs and in the metric pairedcomparison questions may be larger or smaller than in our simulation. Furthermore, most comparative empirical experiments are between groups of respondents rather than within respondents.</p><p>As an example, consider the empirical data from <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Toubia et al. (2003)</ref> in which 88 randomly assigned respondents answered fixed orthogonal questions and 80 randomly assigned respondents answered ACAgenerated questions. The average OLS partworth estimates based on 16 questions are shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. The estimated mean partworths in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> are dramatically different. As in our illustrative example, the ACA estimates suggest different managerial decisions. The ACA estimates suggest that, on average, a handle will be bought at $20, but the orthogonal questions suggest otherwise.</p><p>Notice that the percent differences in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> are much larger than those in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. On average, partworths are 42% larger when ACA questions are used than when orthogonal questions are used. In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, the percent difference is negatively correlated with the true partworths (r = −0 78, t = −3 5). In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref>, the correlation with the orthogonal partworths is negative, but not significant (r = −0 23, t = −0 66) and slightly smaller for WTP (r = −0 14, t = −0 39). (The correlations do not change if we use normalized partworths.) Not obtaining significance is not surprising because empirical data are less precise than "known"  <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">22 2  2 5 6  1 5  −18  12 33  12 87</ref> homogeneous partworths. In addition, the Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> comparison is between groups of respondents who might vary slightly in their true partworths because of finite sampling, there is heterogeneity within groups, and, even if the orthogonal question estimates are unbiased, they are subject to response errors. Furthermore, as discussed later, there might be other sources of empirical noise and/or bias in metric utility-balanced adaptive questions than the systematic bias highlighted in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> is illustrative and Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> is only suggestive, but they anticipate our theoretical findings. Adaptive metric utility questions are relatively biased because of endogeneity. We also demonstrate that such questions are inefficient and may induce more response error. Although the effects are modest, they can affect managerial decisions. We also demonstrate that these biases and inefficiencies (and perhaps greater response error) can be avoided with other questionselection methods that are now available. Finally, we demonstrate why "shrinkage" estimates do not overcome these biases and may, themselves, introduce new biases when coupled with adaptive metric utility-balanced questions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Endogeneity and Adaptive Metric Utility Balance</head><p>When questions are selected adaptively based on previous answers by a respondent, there is the potential for endogeneity bias because new questions might depend upon the errors made by respondents in their previous answers <ref type="bibr">(Judge et al. 1985, p. 571</ref>).</p><p>If such endogeneity bias is to produce the results in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, it must be systematic (all partworths are biased upward) and relative (smaller partworths are biased relatively more than larger partworths). In this section, we explore whether adaptive utility-balanced metric questions cause systematic and relative endogeneity bias. We use a stylized model to understand and illustrate the cause of the biases, then provide a more general explanation based on the winner's curse. Finally, we provide simulations that isolate the bias as systematic winner's curse endogeneity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Formal Analysis of a Simple Problem</head><p>Consider products with two binary features (with levels denoted by 0 and 1) and assume no interactions among the features. Scale the low level of each feature to zero and let w i be the partworth of the high level of feature i. Denote the utility of a product with feature 1 and feature 2 by u(feature 1, feature 2). There are four possible profiles with true utilities given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">u 0 0 = 0 u 1 0 = w 1 u 0 1 = w 2 and u 1 1 = w 1 + w 2</formula><p>Assume response error is an additive, zero-mean random variable, , with probability distribution f . For example, if the respondent is asked to compare 1 0 to 0 1 , the answer is given by w 1 − w 2 + . If he or she is asked to compare 1 1 to 0 1 , the answer is given by w 1 + . Denote the estimates of the partworths with w 1 and w 2 .</p><p>Without loss of generality, assume the off-diagonal question, which compares 0 1 to 1 0 , is the most utility-balanced first question and that w 1 &gt; w 2 . Label the error associated with the first question as ub and label errors associated with subsequent questions as either 1 or 2 . In this simple problem, adaptive metric utility balance implies the following sequence:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">First question: w 1 − w 2 = w 1 − w 2 + ub Second question: w 1 = w 1 + 1 if ub &lt; w 2 − w 1 (Case 1) w 2 = w 2 + 2 if ub ≥ w 2 − w 1 (Case 2)</formula><p>Because the second question depends upon the error in the first question, there is endogeneity. We demonstrate in an appendix (available from the authors) that Case 1 leads to upward bias in w 2 and Case 2 leads to upward bias in w 1 . The intuitive idea is that the second question depends on the error in the respondent's answer to the first question. Overall bias depends upon the probabilities that each case is chosen, times the conditional expectations of the estimates for each case. The online appendix shows that biases are always positive and relative. (We show E w 2 − w 2 /w 2 − E w 1 − w 1 /w 1 &gt; 0.) This mathematical result applies formally to the 2 × 2 stylized model, but we feel it illustrates the basic phenomenon that applies more generally.</p><p>Proposition 1. For a simple problem involving two binary features, adaptation based on metric utility balance (1) biases partworth estimates upward and (2) biases smaller partworths proportionally more than larger partworths.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>More General Analysis-The Winner's Curse</head><p>In the stylized model, the second conjoint question focuses on the partworth, which is believed to be smaller based on the answer to the first question. However, this belief is influenced by noise and may be inaccurate. This is the basic, generalizable source of the bias: when we select the question we predict to be most utility balanced, we overestimate (in expectation) its level of utility balance. More formally, we choose the next question from a pool of questions q i i∈I and, based on the previous answers, we estimate the absolute value of the answer, w i . However, if the estimate is a random variable with mean w i , the very act of choosing the question q i * with the smallest w i implies that E w i * &lt; w i * . Indeed, the expectation of a random variable conditional on it being the smallest from a set of random variables is lower than its unconditional expectation. This is the same probabilistic phenomenon as the winner's curse, a well-known result in auction theory: the winner of a first-price auction for a common value good is "cursed" by the act of winning and pays too high a price <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Capen et al. 1971</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, Kagel and Levin 1986</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">, Thaler 1992</ref>.</p><p>The winner's curse is consistent with GKA's observation that respondents' answers use a larger range of the response scale (than predicted); however, the underlying mechanism is different. The winner's curse is because of endogenous question selection rather than a change in the respondents' reactions to the questions.</p><p>To see this formally, let w q be the estimated vector of binary partworths, estimated after the qth pairedcomparison question. We use binary features to simplify exposition, and without loss of generality, scale the low level of each feature to zero. The same arguments apply, but with more cumbersome notation, to multilevel features and to standard ACA scaling. Let x q be the row vector corresponding to the qth question, and let X q be the matrix of the first q questions obtained by stacking the q row vectors. If a q+1 is the answer to the q + 1 st question, then the predicted answer is a q+1 = x q+1 w q and the q + 1 st estimate can be obtained from the qth estimate by the following equation (Sawtooth Software 2002, p. 19, Equation <ref type="formula">5</ref>). 2</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">w q+1 − w q = I + X q X q −1 x q+1 • a q+1 − a q+1 1 + x q+1 I + X q X q −1 x q+1 (1)</formula><p>Marketing Science 24(3), pp. 498-507, © 2005 INFORMS Because I + X q X q is positive definite, the denominator is positive. After balancing utility, ACA randomly selects one of the profiles as the right side of the comparison. Thus, in Equation ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>), without loss of generality, we can orient questions mathematically such that the predicted answer a q+1 is nonnegative. (Actual empirical questions are randomly oriented.)</p><p>The winner's curse causes a q+1 to be larger than a q+1 in expectation. Let e be a row vector of 1's; then e w q+1 − w q is the change in the sum of the estimates from question q to q+1. The remainder of the argument, given in the online appendix, demonstrates that the winner's curse implies that e w q+1 − w q is more likely to be positive if e x q+1 &gt; 0, negative if e x q &lt; 0, and small in absolute value if e x q+1 = 0. Let us then define "up" questions as those questions in which there are more features on the side of the question predicted to be positive ( e x q+1 &gt; 0 , 3 "down" questions as those questions in which there are more features on the predicted negative side ( e x q &lt; 0 , and "same" questions as those questions in which there are equal numbers of features on both sides ( e x q+1 = 0 .</p><p>The winner's curse predicts more "cursed" questions for adaptive utility balance than for an algorithm in which utility balance is not a criterion. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> This will lead to an increase in the average estimated partworths for "up" questions, a decrease for "down" questions, and no change for "same" questions. Because utility balance makes a q+1 as small as possible, we also expect more "same" questions and more "down" questions. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Smaller partworths are more likely than larger partworths to be updated in the same direction as the sum of the partworths. For example, consider a situation in which exactly three binary partworths vary in a question. With utility balance, x q+1 will contain either (1) two +1's and one −1 or (2) two −1's and one +1. Because the utility-balance goal is to make x q+1 w q as small as possible, the smaller partworths are more likely than larger partworths to be in the same direction as e x q+1 . That is, the smaller partworths are more likely to be on the same side as either the two +1's or the two −1's.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Simulation Evidence for the Winner's Curse</head><p>We completed the following four simulation experiments to isolate the winner's curse explanation:</p><p>(1) Comparing ACA question selection to a modified version of ACA that does not involve utility balance confirms that the evolution of estimates (q to q + 1) has a positive trend for ACA but not for nonutility-balanced ACA. Detailed predictions (described above) are also confirmed.</p><p>(2) Restricting ACA question selection to remove the winner's curse ("same" questions) removes the bias.</p><p>(3) The overall bias increases as more questions are asked.</p><p>(4) Redrawing noise to retain utility balance but remove endogeneity removes the bias.</p><p>Test 1. The predictions are tested in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref> where four features are allowed to vary in each question.</p><p>(We obtain similar results when we allow two, three, five, six, or seven features to vary. Details are in the online appendix.) As predicted, adaptive utility balance leads to more "same" questions and more "down" questions. For each category ("up," "down," or "same"), more questions are "cursed" when we use adaptive utility balance. "Up" evolution leads to an upward bias (on average partworth estimates increase by 1.25 when utility balance is used but decrease by 0.10 when it is not) and "down" mitigates the upward bias (increase of 1.06 versus increase of 1.25), but the effects do not cancel out. The net effect, for both "up" and "down" questions, is systematically toward Percent of "up" questions 61% 49% that are "cursed" Percent of "down" questions 17% 14% that are "cursed" Percent of "same" questions 35% 34% 35% that are "cursed" Evolution for "up" questions 1 25 −0 10 -Evolution for "down" questions 1 06 1 25 -Evolution for "same" questions 0 06 −0 01 0 00</p><p>Evolution for "up" 0 22 −0 06 questions x percent "up" Evolution for "down" 0 14 0 05 questions x percent "down" Evolution for "same" 0 04 −0 01 0 00 questions x percent "same" Overall bias 4 21 * 0 11 −0 25 * Significant at 0.01 level. Test 2. If the winner's curse is the correct explanation, we can eliminate bias if we restrict ourselves to "same" questions such that e x q+1 = 0. This algorithm eliminates bias (last column of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref>). This algorithm is of theoretical interest only; it is not designed to be practical. We examine feasible alternatives later in this paper.</p><p>Test 3. For the simulations in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref>, <ref type="bibr">Sawtooth (2002, p. 11)</ref> recommends that approximately 20 paired-comparison questions be chosen adaptively from a set of 1,470 possible questions. If all 1,470 questions were asked, we expect the bias to disappear. However, the winner's curse and Equation 1 predict that bias should increase with the number of questions, at least in the beginning. Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> examines this prediction. Consistent with the winner's curse, biases appear to increase for the first 20 or so questions and stabilize with a slight decrease until at least the fortieth question. Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> also cautions that adaptive metric utility balance could give a false impression that true partworths change as more questions are asked. We recommend instead the procedure developed by <ref type="bibr">Liechty et al. (2004)</ref> to examine dynamic changes in true partworths.</p><p>Test 4. The winner's curse requires both endogeneity (adaptation) and utility balance. Removing endogeneity by redrawing response errors for ACA questions should remove the winner's curse. When we redraw noise for the simulations in Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1 and 3</ref>, the bias becomes insignificant (−0 48 for the Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> questions and 0.20 for the Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>questions).</head><p>In summary, all four tests are consistent with the winner's curse explanation. Finally, we note that published evidence suggests a statistically significant 6.6% bias for ACA when averaged across domains that include both high and low response error and high and low heterogeneity <ref type="bibr">(Toubia et al. 2003, p. 285</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Metric Utility Balance and the Reduction in Efficiency</head><p>Perhaps we should accept a modest amount of bias if there are reciprocal benefits. For example, hierarchical Bayesian methods shrink individual estimates toward the population mean to enhance accuracy. In another example, <ref type="bibr">Huber and Zwerina (1996, p. 309, 312)</ref> attempt to "improve efficiencies of (choice) designs by balancing the utilities of the alternatives in each choice set," and demonstrate that swapping and relabeling to increase utility balance improves efficiency (defined below) by 33%. Their improved design is significantly more utility balanced than an orthogonal design-11 of the 15 pairs are balanced (versus 0 of the 15 in the orthogonal design). (Their design is, appropriately, not perfectly balanced-an issue we address below.) Thus, if greater utility balance in choice designs increases efficiency, we should explore whether greater utility balance for metric paired-comparison questions increases efficiency. Perhaps increased efficiency could justify the modest bias introduced by the winner's curse. Efficiency focuses on the standard errors of the estimates. When the estimates, w, of the partworth vectors, w, are (approximately) normally distributed with variance , the confidence region for the estimates is an ellipsoid defined by w − w −1 w − w <ref type="bibr">(Greene 1993, p. 190)</ref>. For most estimation methods, (or its estimate) depends upon the questions that the respondent is asked, and hence, an efficient set of questions minimizes the confidence ellipsoid. This is implemented as minimizing a norm of the matrix, . A-errors are based on the trace of ; D-errors are based on the determinant of <ref type="bibr">(Kuhfeld et al. 1994, p. 547)</ref>.</p><p>For metric data, −1 = X X (for an appropriately coded X). Perfect metric utility balance imposes a linear constraint on the columns of X because X w = 0. This constraint induces X X to be singular. When X X is singular, the determinant will be zero and D-errors increase without bound. Imperfect metric utility balance leads to smaller det X X and larger D-errors. A-errors behave similarly. Thus, utility balance is likely to make metric questions inefficient. As an illustration, we computed the average efficiency loss with ACA relative to a fixed orthogonal design for simulations replicating Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. The net loss in efficiency was 26.5%.</p><p>Unlike choice-based utility balance, greater metric utility balance does not seem to lead to increased efficiency.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Empirical Issues with Metric</head><p>Utility-Balanced Questions <ref type="bibr">Orme (1999, p.</ref> 2) hypothesizes that "a difficult choice provides better information for further refining utility estimates." <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Huber and Hansen (1986)</ref> ascribe "greater respondent interest in these difficult-to-judge pairs." For choice data, <ref type="bibr">Haaijer et al. (2000, p. 380</ref>) suggest that respondents take more time on choice sets that are balanced in utility, and therefore make less errorprone choices. These hypotheses are consistent with <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Shugan's (1980)</ref> theory that the cost of thinking is inversely proportional to the square of the utility difference. On the other hand, as noted previously, <ref type="bibr">Green et al. (1991, p. 221)</ref> hypothesize that respondents tend to use more of the response scale than would be predicted by utility balance.</p><p>To investigate whether metric utility balance leads to lower response errors, which might compensate for endogeneity bias and inefficiency, we used HB methods to estimate partworths based on only the paired-comparison questions in the laptop computer bag data (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref>). HB estimation provides an estimate of the response error in these questions-it was 16% larger for ACA-chosen questions than for fixed, orthogonal paired-comparison questions (significant at the 0.01 level). Thus, in this empirical example, we could find no evidence that metric utility balance led to lower response error than orthogonal questions. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> The empirical estimate of response error also gives us the ability to examine the magnitude of endogeneity bias. Simulations suggest that endogeneity bias is approximately 12%-18% and that efficiency losses are approximately 26.5%. As a comparison, empirical data suggest that response error is approximately 21% of total utility. Thus, systematic endogeneity bias and efficiency loss are of the order of magnitude of response error. This is good news. The practical impact of adaptive metric utility balance will only affect those managerial decisions that are highly sensitive to partworth estimates. However, as we argue below, there are good alternatives to metric utility balance. Researchers can obtain the benefits of adaptation and challenging questions without the problems introduced by adaptive metric utility balance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Heterogeneity and Selection Bias in</head><p>Metric Utility-Balanced Questions</p><p>Another hypothesis might be that we can mitigate endogeneity bias with procedures that "borrow information from other respondents" by shrinking individual respondent estimates toward the population mean (Sawtooth Software 2001, p. 1). 7 HB estimation provides a viable alternative that has proven effective in metric conjoint analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Lenk et al. 1996)</ref>. It is easy to verify with a simulation problem similar to that in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> that HB estimates with orthogonal questions produce average partworth estimates that are unbiased. However, were we to attempt a "shrinkage" estimation for utility-balanced questions, our estimate of the population means would suffer from another form of endogeneity bias in question selection (selection bias among respondents). In particular, when questions are adapted to each respondent, the questions are based on the respondent's true partworths as well as the noise in the respondent's answers. As an illustration, reconsider the stylized 2 × 2 model and suppose that the two partworths are distributed across respondents with probability density function, f w 1 w 2 . For simplicity, suppose there is no measurement noise. We still ask the first utility-balanced question and it is unbiased. In the second question, we encounter Case 1 and observe w 1 = w 1 only for those respondents for which w 1 &lt; w 2 . We encounter Case 2 and observe w 2 = w 2 only for those respondents for which w 2 &lt; w 1 . Thus, the observations on partworths will be biased toward those respondents with lower partworths.</p><p>The selection bias occurs because E w 1 w 1 ≤ w 2 ≤ E w 1 and E w 2 w 2 ≤ w 1 ≤ E w 2 . Furthermore, because selection bias depends on the lower tails of the density function, the bias will be greater for higher levels of heterogeneity. We demonstrate this formally in the online appendix for the stylized model-the average observation for the second question is w − /3, where is an index of heterogeneity.</p><p>To illustrate the phenomenon with a realistic problem, we repeated the simulations in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, but chose true partworths from a normal distribution and used OLS to obtain aggregate partworths (one regression using data from all respondents). In this case, the aggregate partworths were downwardly biased by 41% relative to orthogonal questions. Relative selection bias was also significant (r = 0 93, t = 7 3) and led to smaller normalized mean partworths being biased downward by 30%-50% and larger normalized mean partworths being biased upward by 6%-7% (see the online appendix). Because HB shrinks partworth estimates toward the population mean, it too will be affected by the selection biases in the data. For example, the estimates of the population means, produced by applying HB with ACA questions in a simulation problem similar to that in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, were significantly biased downwards. (Please note that this is a data problem because of adaptive metric utilitybalanced question selection, not a problem with HB estimation.)</p><p>To illustrate the differential impacts of endogeneity and selection biases, we use four interrelated simulations (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">4</ref>). We keep ACA questions constant It is fortuitous that endogeneity bias raises partworth estimates and selection bias lowers partworth estimates and both act disproportionally on small partworths. However, it is dangerous to assume that the relative biases will cancel. More importantly, if partworths are differentially heterogeneous (e.g., respondents vary in their preferences for color but not for handles), then aggregate ACA estimates will be biased in unpredictable ways. For example, the average individual respondent-based orthogonal question and ACA question respondent partworths in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> are significantly correlated (r = 0 75, t = 3 2), but the aggregate estimates are not significantly correlated (r = 0 39, t = 1 2) (details in the online appendix). Indeed, the aggregate ACA estimates are 53% lower than the orthogonal question-based estimates. Thus, alas, shrinkage estimates do not overcome the biases in question selection introduced by adaptive metric utility balance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">Alternatives to Utility Balance for Adapting Metric Questions</head><p>If a researcher wishes to retain metric questions, then an alternative criterion exists to metric utility balance. Polyhedral methods select questions to reduce the feasible set of partworths rapidly by focusing questions relative to the "axis" about which there is the most uncertainty. This criterion does not appear to be subject to a winner's curse. Furthermore, this criterion imposes a constraint that the rows of X be orthogonal <ref type="bibr">(Toubia et al. 2003, Equation A9)</ref>. After p questions, X will be square, nonsingular, and orthogonal (XX ∝ I implies X X ∝ I . 8 Subject to scaling, this orthogonality relationship minimizes D-error (and A-error). Thus, while the adaptation inherent in metric polyhedral methods leads to endogenous question design, the lack of an explicit winner's curse and the orthogonality constraint appear to avoid the biases in Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1-3</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Toubia et al. (2003)</ref> report at most a 1% bias for metric polyhedral question selection, significantly less than observed for ACA question selection. Polyhedral question selection performs better than ACA in simulation (mean absolute error of true versus predicted partworths) and as well or better than ACA in the two empirical tests to date. <ref type="bibr">Toubia et al. (2003, Table 7</ref>) report significantly better performance when almost all questions were chosen by polyhedral methods. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Orme and King (2002)</ref> compare ACA to a hybrid in which one-third of the questions are polyhedral and two-thirds of the questions are ACA. They report no significant differences. Thus, polyhedral methods do at least as well as ACA question selection and represent a viable alternative to metric utility balance. Other researchers are working on another alternative question-selection algorithm that is based on support vector machines <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Evgeniou et al. 2004</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.">Alternatives to Metric</head><p>Questions-Utility Balance for Choice-Based Questions <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Arora and Huber (2001)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Huber and Zwerina (1996)</ref>, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Kanninen (2002)</ref> use utility balance as one criterion for choice-based questions. They improve D p -efficiency relative to orthogonal designs by using designs that are significantly more utility balancede.g., 73% utility balanced for customized versus 0% utility balanced for orthogonal in <ref type="bibr">Huber and Zwerina (1996, Table 3</ref>). <ref type="bibr">9</ref> Choice-based utility balance can improve efficiency because the covariance matrix of the choice-based estimates is a function of the choice probabilities. Thus, if providing challenging questions to respondents is our goal, we can use choice questions rather than metric questions. In the online appendix, we show formally that, as response errors decrease, optimal questions become more utility balanced. Proposition 2 is consistent with prior simulations. For example, in Huber and Zwerina (1996, Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref>), more swaps are accepted (greater utility balance) when response accuracy increases. <ref type="bibr">Arora and Huber (2001, Table 2</ref>) also report greater efficiency gains for more accurate partworths.</p><p>Proposition 2. When optimizing A-efficiency for binary choice, greater response accuracy implies greater utility balance.</p><p>Utility balance could also be helpful when designing questionnaires to elicit respondents' reservation prices for product bundles (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Jedidi et al. 2003</ref>) and when designing choice experiments to augment panel data (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Swait and Andrews 2003)</ref>. Finally, we examine whether we introduce bias by using utility balance to adapt choice-based questions based on individual respondent data. We examined relative bias and efficiency for one such algorithm based on polyhedral methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Toubia et al. 2004)</ref>. (Published simulations have already shown that, in most domains, adaptive polyhedral choicebased questions lead to more accurate partworths than either orthogonal or aggregately customized questions.) To test relative bias, we sort the true partworths, divide them into M ordered subsets, and compute the average error (predicted minus true) within each subset. This allows examining bias as a function of the relative size of the partworths. We did this for (1) adaptive polyhedral questions and</p><p>(2) orthogonal questions. If there were relative bias, then (1) would be significantly different from (2). They were not significantly different. (Graphs are provided in the online appendix to this paper.) We also computed the average efficiency for (1) and (2). The D p -efficiency for polyhedral choice questions was 3% higher than for fixed questions, reflecting the fact that efficiency is a function of the true parameters and suggesting that adaptive polyhedral questions do not lead to any loss in efficiency relative to orthogonal questions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="10.">Summary</head><p>We examine the endogeneity bias, lowered efficiency, response errors, and selection biases that result from adaptive metric utility balance-the question selection algorithm at the heart of ACA. We have shown that the biases and inefficiencies are real and in the direction predicted. We provide stylized models and more general explanations with which to understand and isolate the cause of these phenomena. Furthermore, empirically, we find no evidence that metric utilitybalanced questions reduce response error. Contrary to common wisdom, orthogonality (efficiency) in metric questions appears to be a more important goal than utility balance. 10 Fortunately, the adverse effects of adaptive metric utility balance can be avoided easily. For those researchers seeking to retain metric questions, polyhedral methods provide an alternative that avoids both endogeneity bias and lowered efficiency. For those researchers seeking to ask difficult, challenging questions to encourage respondents to think harder, utility balance appears to help choice-based questions. Finally, adaptive utility-balanced choice questions do not appear to be biased.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Bias as a Function of the Number of Adaptive Utility-Balanced Questions</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Hauser and Toubia: The Impact of Utility Balance and Endogeneity in Conjoint Analysis Marketing Science 24(3), pp. 498-507, © 2005 INFORMS 499 Illustrative Example of Relative Bias Because of Adaptive Metric Utility Balance</figDesc><table><row><cell>Hypothetical</cell><cell>"True"</cell><cell>ACA</cell><cell>Percent</cell><cell cols="2">Percent difference, "True" willingness Estimated willingness</cell></row><row><cell>features</cell><cell cols="3">partworths questions difference (%)</cell><cell>normalized (%)</cell><cell>to pay ($)</cell><cell>to pay ($)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Differences in Average Utility Weights Between ACA and Orthogonal Questions</figDesc><table><row><cell>Actual</cell><cell>Orthogonal</cell><cell>ACA</cell><cell>Percent</cell><cell>Percent difference,</cell><cell>Orthogonal</cell><cell>ACA</cell></row><row><cell>features</cell><cell>questions</cell><cell>questions</cell><cell>difference (%)</cell><cell>normalized (%)</cell><cell>WTP ($)</cell><cell>WTP ($)</cell></row><row><cell>Handle</cell><cell>28 0</cell><cell>5 5 5</cell><cell>9 8</cell><cell>4 2</cell><cell>1 5 54</cell><cell>27 91</cell></row><row><cell>Price</cell><cell>54 0</cell><cell>5 9 6</cell><cell>1 0</cell><cell>−21</cell><cell>30 00</cell><cell>30 00</cell></row><row><cell>Logo</cell><cell>24 3</cell><cell>1 8 4</cell><cell>−24</cell><cell>−46</cell><cell>13 49</cell><cell>9 26</cell></row><row><cell>Closure</cell><cell>13 3</cell><cell>2 2 8</cell><cell>7 2</cell><cell>2 3</cell><cell>7 33</cell><cell>11 48</cell></row><row><cell>Mesh pocket</cell><cell>7 3</cell><cell>1 0 4</cell><cell>4 2</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>4 07</cell><cell>5 22</cell></row><row><cell>PDA holder</cell><cell>9 4</cell><cell>−2 6</cell><cell>−127</cell><cell>−119</cell><cell>5 21</cell><cell>−1 29</cell></row><row><cell>Cell phone</cell><cell>11 2</cell><cell>8 6</cell><cell>−23</cell><cell>−45</cell><cell>6 23</cell><cell>4 34</cell></row><row><cell>Color</cell><cell>27 7</cell><cell>4 9 8</cell><cell>8 0</cell><cell>2 8</cell><cell>1 5 39</cell><cell>25 03</cell></row><row><cell>Size</cell><cell>7 3</cell><cell>3 8 2</cell><cell>425</cell><cell>275</cell><cell>4 04</cell><cell>19 20</cell></row><row><cell>Boot</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Simulations to Demonstrate the Winner's Curse</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Adaptive</cell><cell cols="2">Questions not Restrict to</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>utility-balanced</cell><cell>utility</cell><cell>"same"</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>questions</cell><cell>balanced</cell><cell>questions</cell></row><row><cell>Percent of "up" questions</cell><cell>17%</cell><cell>59%</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>Percent of "down" questions</cell><cell>14%</cell><cell>4%</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>Percent of "same" questions</cell><cell>69%</cell><cell>37%</cell><cell>100%</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Examining the Causes of Endogeneity and Selection Biases</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Endogeneity bias</cell><cell>Selection bias</cell></row><row><cell>Adaptive utility-balanced</cell><cell>Significant</cell><cell>Significant</cell></row><row><cell>questions</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Same response errors,</cell><cell>Significant</cell><cell>Not significant</cell></row><row><cell>heterogeneity redrawn</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Response errors redrawn,</cell><cell>Not significant</cell><cell>Significant</cell></row><row><cell>same heterogeneity</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Response error and</cell><cell>Not significant</cell><cell>Not significant</cell></row><row><cell>heterogeneity redrawn</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">and redraw either heterogeneity and/or response</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">error. All simulations use OLS to estimate the popu-</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">lation means as well as the individual utilities.</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">ACA includes the SE questions when selecting the next question. For p parameters, this prefaces a p-dimensional identity matrix, I, to the top of X q .</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Recall that the jth coefficient of x q+1 is coded 0, +1, or −1 if the feature is not involved, is present in the right profile only, or is present in the left profile only, respectively.4  ACA uses utility balance to select from a set of equally balanced and orthogonal questions. We remove utility balance by selecting randomly from this set.5 "Same" questions naturally tend to be more balanced. "Down" questions have more −1's than +1's and have predicted positive answers. Such predicted answers are likely to be small in absolute values.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">Aggregate estimates themselves might be subject to selection biases as discussed later in this paper. That phenomenon might cause us to underestimate response errors in ACA. However, at minimum, we can state that there is no evidence in these data to suggest that ACA leads to lower response errors.7  Approximately 25% of ACA applications use HB estimation (Sawtooth 2004).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8">Orthogonal rows assume that XX = I, where is a proportionality constant. Because X is nonsingular, X and X are invertible, thus X XX X −1 = X X −1 ⇒ X X = I.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">Endogeneity bias is not a problem in these algorithms; they do not adapt questions for individual respondents.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="10">In a related paper (available from the authors), we examine another form of efficiency designed to enhance managerial decisions by focusing on managerially relevant combinations of partworths, M w. We examine the properties of M-efficiency, which minimizes a norm of M X X −1 M .</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This research was supported by the MIT Sloan School of Management and MIT's Center for Innovation in Product Development. An appendix to this paper contains additional analyses, tables, figures, and proofs to the propositions and may be downloaded from http://mktsci. pubs.informs.org. Demonstrations of many of the preference measurement questions discussed in this paper can be viewed at http://mitsloan.mit.edu/vc. Special thanks to Eric Bradlow, Ely Dahan, Theodoros Evgeniou, Jim Figura, Sangman Han, Oded Koenigsberg, Oded Netzer, Duncan Simester, and the Marketing Science reviewers, area editor, and editor-in-chief for insightful comments and examples. The authors are listed in alphabetical order; contributions were equal and synergistic.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporating prior knowledge into the analysis of conjoint studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Greg</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Neeraj</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="152" to="163" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving parameter estimates and model prediction by aggregate customization in choice experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Neeraj</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="283" />
			<date type="published" when="2001-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competitive bidding in high-risk situations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Capen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Clapp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Campbell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Petroleum Tech</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="641" to="653" />
			<date type="published" when="1971-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychometric methods in marketing research: Part I, Conjoint analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Carroll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Douglas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="385" to="391" />
			<date type="published" when="1995-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A conjoint-based product designing procedure incorporating price competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wayne</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Chan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Desarbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Product Innovation Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="459" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized robust conjoint estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Theodoros</forename><surname>Evgeniou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Constantinos</forename><surname>Boussios</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Giorgos</forename><surname>Zacharia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="415" to="429" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attribute importance weights modification in assessing a brand&apos;s competitive potential</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abba</forename><surname>Krieger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="270" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Part</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adaptive conjoint analysis: Some caveats and suggestions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abba</forename><surname>Krieger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Manoj</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="222" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Econometric Analysis</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Englewood Cliffs, NJ</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Prentice-Hall, Inc</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response latencies in the analysis of conjoint choice experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rinus</forename><surname>Haaijer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wagner</forename><surname>Kamakura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Wedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="376" to="382" />
			<date type="published" when="2000-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intensity measures of consumer preference</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Oper. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1980-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing the impact of dimensional complexity and affective differences of paired concepts in adaptive conjoint analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Hansen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Consumer Research</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Melanie</forename><surname>Wallendorf</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Provo, UT</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="163" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The importance of utility balance in efficient choice designs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Klaus</forename><surname>Zwerina</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="307" to="317" />
			<date type="published" when="1996-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Impact of Utility Balance and Endogeneity in Conjoint</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Toubia</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>INFORMS 507</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Analysis Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="498" to="507" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effectiveness of alternative preference elicitation procedures in predicting choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dick</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wittink</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fiedler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="114" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring heterogeneous reservation prices for product bundles</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Jedidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sharan</forename><surname>Kamel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Puneet</forename><surname>Jagpal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Manchanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="130" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comment on adaptive conjoint analysis: Some caveats and suggestions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="225" />
			<date type="published" when="1991-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adaptive choicebased conjoint</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lynd</forename><surname>Bacon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Sawtooth Software</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Sequim, WA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Theory and Practice of Econometrics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Judge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lutkepohl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
			<publisher>John Wiley and Sons</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The winner&apos;s curse and public information in common value auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kagel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="894" to="920" />
			<date type="published" when="1986-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal design for multinomial choice experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kanninen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="214" to="227" />
			<date type="published" when="2002-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient experimental design with marketing research applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Warren</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Kuhfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Randall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Tobias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Garratt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="545" to="557" />
			<date type="published" when="1994-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hierarchical Bayes conjoint analysis: Recovery of partworth heterogeneity from reduced experimental designs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lenk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wayne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Desarbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="173" to="191" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The evolution of consumer utility functions in conjoint analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Liechty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Duncan</forename><surname>Fong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wayne</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Desarbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="293" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A unified approach to conjoint analysis models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pablo</forename><surname>Marshall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eric</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Bradlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">97</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="674" to="682" />
			<date type="published" when="2002-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ACA, CBC, or both: Effective strategies for conjoint research. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><surname>Orme</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Sawtooth Software</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Sequim, WA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving the value of conjoint simulations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><surname>Orme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving ACA algorithms: Challenging a twenty-year-old approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><surname>Orme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">Christopher</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advance Res. Tech. Conf</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<publisher>American Marketing Association</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing conjoint choice experiments using managers&apos; prior beliefs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zsolt</forename><surname>Sandor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Wedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="430" to="444" />
			<date type="published" when="2001-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Profile construction in experimental choice designs for mixed logit models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zsolt</forename><surname>Sandor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Wedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="455" to="475" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Differentiated Bayesian conjoint choice designs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zsolt</forename><surname>Sándor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Wedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.sawtoothsoft-ware.com/productforms/ssolutions/ss20.shtml#ss20usage" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="s">ERIM Report Series Reference No. ERS-2003-016-MKT</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<publisher>Sawtooth Solutions</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Update on relative conjoint analysis usage</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The cost of thinking</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="111" />
			<date type="published" when="1980-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enriching scanner panel models with choice experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Swait</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rick</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Joffre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Andrews</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="442" to="460" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Polyhedral methods for adaptive choice-based conjoint analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">H ;</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Toubia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Olivier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Duncan</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Simester</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="131" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The Winner&apos;s Curse: Paradoxes and Anomalies of Economic Life</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fast polyhedral adaptive conjoint estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Toubia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Duncan</forename><surname>Simester</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ely</forename><surname>Dahan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="303" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
