<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian Estimation of Bid Sequences in Internet Auctions Using a Generalized Record-Breaking Model</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2005-07-18">July 18, 2005</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Eric</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Bradlow</surname></persName>
							<email>ebradlow@wharton.upenn.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">The Wharton School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>3730 Walnut Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>761 JMHH, 19104-6371</postCode>
									<settlement>Philadelphia</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Young-Hoon</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Johnson Graduate School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Cornell University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>330 Sage Hall</addrLine>
									<postCode>14853-6201</postCode>
									<settlement>Ithaca</settlement>
									<region>New York</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian Estimation of Bid Sequences in Internet Auctions Using a Generalized Record-Breaking Model</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 07 2602 0218</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2005-07-18">July 18, 2005</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1060.0225</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-13T12:15+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>latent bidders</term>
					<term>bidding dynamics</term>
					<term>record-breaking events</term>
					<term>Bayesian inference</term>
					<term>data augmentation History:</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>A sequence of bids in Internet auctions can be viewed as record-breaking events in which only those data points that break the current record are observed. We investigate stochastic versions of the classical recordbreaking problem for which we apply Bayesian estimation to predict observed bids and bid times in Internet auctions. Our approach to addressing this type of data is through data augmentation in which we assume that participants (bidders) have dynamically changing valuations for the auctioned item, but the latent number of bidders "competing" in those events is unseen.</p><p>We use data from notebook auctions provided by one of the largest Internet auction sites in Korea. We find significant variation in the number of latent bidders across auctions. Our other primary findings are as follows:</p><p>(1) the latent bidders are significant in number relative to observed bidders, (2) the latent number of remaining bidders is considerably smaller than that of new entrants to the auction after a given bid, and (3) larger bid and time increments significantly influence the bidding participation behavior of the remaining bidders. As part of our substantive contribution, we highlight the model's ability to understand brand equity in an Internet auction context through a brand's ability to simultaneously bring in bidders, higher bid amounts, and faster bidding.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>The growing importance of online auctions as exchange mechanisms is evident in the emerging auction literature from economists (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bajari and</ref><ref type="bibr">Hortaçsu 2003, Roth and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Ockenfels 2002)</ref> to behavioral researchers (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Ariely and</ref><ref type="bibr">Simonson 2003, Greenleaf 2004</ref>). We present here a new approach to modeling auction data (the entire sequence of bids and bid times) that relies on merging (yet also modifying) an existing record-breaking literature in statistics (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Carlin and Gelfand 1993)</ref> with Bayesian data augmentation methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Albert and</ref><ref type="bibr">Chib 1993, Tanner and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Wong 1987)</ref>.</p><p>Record-breaking data, in which only those data points that break the current record are observed (among those accumulated sequentially over time), have been well-studied in a variety of practical situations such as World and Olympic sporting records (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Gelfand 1993, Robinson and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Tawn 1995)</ref> and meteorological data (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Brown and</ref><ref type="bibr">Katz 1995, Coles and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Tawn 1996)</ref>. Our link to this literature is to note that the arrival of a new bid for an auction item can be considered a "record-breaking event," that is, the current bid has broken the record of the last bid. We note that the record-breaking mechanisms are somewhat different in these two areas, that is, a sequence of bids in auctions are placed by thinking individual bidders, while record-breaking data in the previous literature are realized through stochastic independent events. We thus seek to present a modeling framework that makes these two data structures inherently identical.</p><p>While this link is tight, the existing record-breaking literature is deficient to examine auction data in a number of important ways. The literature has been concerned with independent events and a constant (stationary) mean (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Tryfos and Blackmore 1985)</ref>. In our application area, assuming stable bidder valuations, while commonly assumed in rational economic models (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Guerre et al. 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">, Hendricks et al. 2003</ref>, has been questioned in a variety of empirical settings (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Ariely and</ref><ref type="bibr">Simonson 2003, Park and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Bradlow 2005)</ref>. Furthermore, the literature has directly incorporated record-breaking opportunities wherein occurrence times of all failed record-breaking attempts are known (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Carlin and Gelfand 1993)</ref>. In auctions, however, the assumption of perfect knowledge about the "failures" (unobserved bidders) could be very restrictive, which represents the unique merging of the record-breaking and the data augmentation literature developed here.</p><p>We apply the proposed modeling framework of records with unseen intermittent events to auction data in which bid amounts and bid times are analogous to record-breaking events and the event times. Bid amounts (and bid times) are accumulated sequentially and are recorded as long as a bid amount exceeds the outstanding bid. That is, (observed) bid increments have to be greater than zero. Moreover, the number of latent competing bidders, i.e., recordbreaking attempts, is not observed (or there exists an unseen competition set as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bradlow and Fader 2001)</ref>. Instead, we only observe the largest of the potential bids but not those by the latent bidders. We therefore investigate stochastic versions of the classical record-breaking problem for which we apply Bayesian estimation to predict observed bids and bid times. In this respect, our research appears to be a clear generalization of the research on recordbreaking events. To the best of our knowledge, it is the first time the record-breaking paradigm has been applied to auction data.</p><p>We note that our stochastic modeling approach differs considerably from the empirical auction literature in economics. Specifically, our research is an attempt to add to the growing body of literature by providing a descriptive and exploratory look at auction data utilizing a flexible and parsimonious stochastic model. We note that our model does not rely on theoretical assumptions of utility maximization or strategic behaviors that have provided a significant path forward in this research area (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Jofre-Bonet and</ref><ref type="bibr">Pesendorfer 2003, Pakes et al. 2005)</ref>. Instead, our work is meant to extend empirical understanding of bidding behavior and provide a platform by which structural aspects can be incorporated into a stochastic approach. In this vein, the closest paper to ours is <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Park and Bradlow (2005)</ref>; however, their work assumes that the competing set of bidders is known based upon similar auctions that are on sale concurrently. In contrast, we stochastically impute the latent competition set, decompose those bidders into new entrants at a given bid and remaining bidders from the previous bid, and derive the distribution of the largest-order statistic <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Johnson et al. 1994</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Johnson et al. , 1995</ref> conditionally on having imputed the unseen attempts.</p><p>The remainder of the paper is organized as follows. Section 2 gives an overview of the data and describes exploratory analyses. In §3, we provide a detailed specification of our Bayesian model. Section 4 has model results and inferences. Section 5 concludes and suggests future research directions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Data Description</head><p>We obtained a database of notebook computer auctions from one of the largest Internet auction sites in Korea. The auction mechanism on this site uses an ascending first-price or English auction in which the highest bidder wins and pays the amount he bids and is essentially identical to the format used by Yahoo!Auctions. The database contains information regarding the complete history of bids, auction design features set by the seller, seller characteristics, and product specifications. The total number of notebook auctions considered here is 218 with 3,124 bids. Thus, on average, there are about 14.33 bids (standard deviation = 11 22), i.e., record-breaking events, per auction. The data set used in this research are a subset of the data used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Park and Bradlow (2005)</ref>.</p><p>There are three auction design variables under the sellers' control: placement (yes or no) of product images on the listing page, minimum bid ("public" reserve price), and auction duration. These variables are used as descriptors and are treated as exogenous. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> In addition, we utilize seller reputation ratings given by past successful bidders. The rating is in the form of a positive, negative, or neutral response after each transaction, which we operationalize by using log(positive ratings + 1) and log(negative and neutral ratings + 1).</p><p>The product specifications contain the following variables: (1) CPU type (Pentium or Celeron), (2) CPU speed, (3) memory, (4) hard disk, (5) screen size, (6) the number of months that the auction item has been used, and (7) brand name. There are two American (Compaq and IBM), two Japanese (Fujitsu and Sony), and two Korean brands (Sambo and Samsung) which account for about 31%, 11%, and 52% of the 218 items, respectively. All the rest of the brands were aggregated and grouped into a category "others." Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref> reports detailed descriptions of auction design, seller reputation ratings, and product specifications. These variables, along with bid-specific (time-varying) variables to be described, will serve as covariates towards explaining the latent number of competing bidders, the magnitude of new recordbreaking events (bid amounts), the bid times, and the variance (dispersion) of the underlying dynamic bidder valuations.</p><p>1 Current research in both economics and marketing has focused on the so-called endogeneity problem, both from an instrumental variables perspective (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Vilcassim et al. 1999, Villas-Boas and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Winer 1999)</ref> and from a modeling perspective (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Manchanda et al. 2004</ref>) which suggests an area in which to extend our modeling framework.  In Internet auctions, incremental bid amounts are of great importance since the key decision by potential bidders centers on how much more to bid. Thus, our primary dependent variable is the bid increment, and specifically, log(bid increment). Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> shows a histogram of log(bid increment), measured in Korean currency (won), where a fairly regular pattern of bid amounts is observed. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Besides the amount of bids, bid submission times (or bid time increments) are of major interest both for sellers and potential bidders. Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> shows that bidding activity is highly time concentrated primarily near the end of each auction: About 40% (50%) of bids are submitted within a one-(two-) hour window. This practice of a last-minute bidding phenomenon has attracted a good deal of attention among academic researchers (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bajari and</ref><ref type="bibr">Hortaçsu 2003, Roth and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Ockenfels 2002)</ref>. Thus, we also model the bid time, hence, a joint model of the amount and timing of new record-breaking events.</p><p>Next, we build an explicit parametric and descriptive model of bid amount and time increments by inferring the number of latent potential bidders between subsequent "records." Along this line, we investigate the determinants of increments in bid amounts and bid times through various auction-specific and bid-specific covariates. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">A Bayesian Record-Breaking Model</head><p>We first present a descriptive interpretation of our model and its assumptions. In §3.2, we describe the heart of our Bayesian model, a time-varying latent process. A description of the likelihood and priors and computational details are provided in § §3.3 and 3.4, respectively. A simulation study to demonstrate the efficacy of our approach is given in §3.5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Model Description</head><p>At the heart of our model is a latent record-breaking process where we observe only the maximum amount and its bid time. We assume that there are a maximum of N i latent bids (or bidders) for auction i. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> For auction i and bid k, two types of latent bidders exist: a mixture of n i k new entrants, and n * i k remaining bidders who carry over from prior to bid k (the process is described below). Letn i k = n i k + n * i k denote the total number of latent bidders. Thus, our model considers bidding participation behavior wherein latent bidders come in (n i k of them), stay (n * i k ), or go out of the bidding process. In particular, our stochastic auction model proceeds as follows:</p><p>1. Imagine that the (k − 1)st bid for auction i has just arrived at time t i k−1 and that there is (T i − t i k−1 ) time left in the auction where T i is the known and set (by the seller) auction duration.</p><p>2. A latent competition set (maximum size N i , as above) of asymmetric bidders, (a mixture of new entrants and remaining bidders, as above) determine (in isolation) their expected valuations for auction i starting at time (t i k−1 + ) until the next bid (if it does) arrives. We denote the observed bidder as the (n i k + 1)st one. 3. Each of the n i k new latent bidders have bidding intensities given by i k for log-transformed bid increments through a truncated normal distribution, and by i k for bid time increments through the truncated exponential distribution. For the n * i k remaining bidders, their bidding intensities are given by * i k j for log-transformed bid increments through a truncated normal distribution and i k for bid time increments.</p><p>4. Let t i k ∈ t i k−1 T i ] denote the arrival time of bid k and b i k n i k +1 the amount of that bid.</p><p>That is, our model proposes (as given in §3.2) that the observed bid time increment is the one among the latent bidders with the smallest "arrival" time, which is determined by the minimum of (n i k + 1) exponential bidders, and the value of that bid increment is determined by i k and * i k j . We next provide a formal layout of the model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Model Development</head><p>More formally, we model the number of new latent entrant bidders n i k , who enter auction i = 1 2 I after bid (k − 1), k = 1 2 K i , by a truncated Poisson distribution with mean i k :</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">f n i k i k = n i k i k exp − i k n i k ! n i k ∈ 0 N i −n * i k (1)</formula><p>The n i k in our model is in accordance with <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Shugan (2005)</ref> in which he calls for future research on auctions where the arrival of bidders is endogenous depending on the auction rules. To model the time-varying mean (within auction and across bids) i k , we choose an identical regression specification (same predictors yet varying coefficients) for all four core "kernels" of our model (described below): the distribution for the number of latent bidders, the distribution of bidder valuations for bid increments and their variance, and the distribution for bid time increments. This unified approach allows us to assess the impact of variables on all key aspects simultaneously. More specifically, we model</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">log i k = X i k • + i k = 0 + 1 AD i + 2 SR i + 3 PS i + 4 MC i + 5 BC i k + i k (2)</formula><p>where AD i is a vector of design variables, i.e., placement of product images, log(minimum bid), and auction duration; SR i is a vector of variables for seller reputation, i.e., log(positive ratings + 1) and log(negative and neutral ratings + 1); PS i is a vector of variables for product specifications, i.e., CPU type, CPU speed, memory, hard disk, screen size, the number of months for use, and brand names as in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref>; MC i is a vector indicating the degree of marketing competition, i.e., breadth (how many items similar to the focal item are on sale concurrently) and depth (how many of those similar items also of the same brand as the focal item are on sale concurrently); 4 BC i k is a vector of time-varying variables, i.e., number of bids before the kth bid (i.e., k − 1), the previous incremental bid amount and bid time, and the amount of remaining time (T i − t i k−1 ) in the auction; and i k ∼ N 0 2 . <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Given n i k latent entrant bidders as in Equations ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>) and (2) and n * i k latent bidders who remain from the (k − 1)st bid, in the participation process at bid k for auction i, this implies that there aren i k unseen bids which we denote b i k j , j = 1 n i k . Define b i k j as the jth corresponding bid order statistic at bid k for auction i. Therefore, b i k n i k +1 is the kth observed bid and b i 0 n i 0 +1 is the minimum opening bid in auction i. We define random variables</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">y i k j = b i k j − b i k−1 n i k−1 +1</formula><p>as the latent bid increments, and y i k n i k +1 the observed bid increment at bid k for auction i.</p><p>To complete the model description, we need to describe the process by which latent bidders are assumed (if at all) to "carry over" and remain after a bid occurs. While there were numerous ways to do this, we believe our choice is both plausible and, at the same time, an area for future research. In particular, we use a latent threshold model for continued Marketing Science 26(2), pp. 218-229, © 2007 INFORMS participation. That is, let z i k j be one if the jth latent bidder from the (k − 1)st bid remains in bid k for auction i, and zero otherwise. We operationalize z i k j to be one if</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">y i k j ≥ • y i k n i k +1 , 0 ≤ ≤ 1. That is, n * i k = n i k−1</formula><p>j=1 z i k j a sum of latent bidders who are " -close" competitors of the observed bidder. As a result of this component, the latent bidders after each bid are no longer symmetric, nor are they all assumed to be new. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> We describe below how these bidder types are modeled with different parameters.</p><p>The proposed model assumes that the log-transformed bid increments have a normal distribution truncated below by zero (bids are ascending) with density functions, for j = 1</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">n i k + 1, f y i k j i k 2 i k = 1 2 2 i k 1/2 exp − 1 2 2 i k y i k j − i k 2 • 1− i k i k −1 (3)</formula><p>The ability of our model to describe and predict the bid increments (record-breaking events) is thus due to our ability to flexibly specify a model for i k , the mean of the bid increments at time (t i k−1 + ). Specifically, we model the time-varying (bid k) mean vector for the n i k latent entran and one observed bidder as</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">i k = X i k • + i k i k ∼ N 0 2 (4)</formula><p>where = 0 1 5 , an identical regression specification as in Equation (2). For the n * i k carry-over latent bidders, we modify the mean valuation vector in Equation ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>) to account for the fact that the mean bid increment for remaining bidders may be affected by their previous "latent" bid increments. We thus build in an AR(1) process where we allow for the possibility that previous latent bidders "anchor" in some way on their previous valuations:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">7 * i k j = X i k • + 6 • y i k−1 j • z i k j + i k i k ∼ N 0 2 (5)</formula><p>Note that once augmented with latent bid increments y i k 1 y i k n i k , the conditional distribution of the largest bid increment, i.e., the observed bid <ref type="bibr">6</ref> The way in which we have implemented an AR process in our model is but one way and can be related to the auction literature on private versus common value auctions. In particular, our AR process states that person j's mean valuation changes as a function of her bid history (private value) as opposed to that from the population of bidders. One could certainly extend our model to incorporate differing degrees of information on a given bidder's time-varying valuation. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> We assume the same error distribution for i k and * i k j for model parsimony.</p><p>y i k n i k +1 , given the unseen bid increments, is given by a normal distribution truncated below at the largest of the unseen bid increments. Furthermore, the conditional distribution of the unseen bid increments, conditional on the observed bid increment, is also truncated normal, now truncated below by zero and above by the observed bid increment, hence the computational simplicity of our augmented data model.</p><p>We also posit an identical regression specification for the auction by bid-specific variances 2 i k from Equation (3), given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">log 2 i k ∼ N X i k • 2 (6)</formula><p>a log-normal regression. Again, such a specification allows us to flexibly model the uncertainty in bid increments using the same set of covariates.</p><p>Finally, we now uncondition on the arrival time of the kth bid, t i k , by building a predictive model for its arrival (if it occurs). As described in §3.1, if we have (n i k + 1) potential bidders, each with truncated exponential arrival "speeds," the observed bid time is the value of the minimum order statistic, "the fastest participant." 8 That is, the smallest of the t i k , the observed bid time after the (k −1)st bid for auction i, is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">Pr min t i k j − t i k−1 = t i k = n i k +1 • i k ×exp − n i k +1 • i k • t i k 1−exp − n i k +1 • i k • T i −t i k−1 (7)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">log i k = X i k • + i k i k ∼ N 0 2 (8)</formula><p>As shown in Equation ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>), the probability of when bid k occurs is also truncated exponential with rate equal to the sum of i k across all the latent and observed bidders. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> This result, that the minimum of a set of exponentials is exponentially distributed with rate equal to the sum of the rates, is a nice property of the exponential distribution. It is important to note that our choice of the exponential distribution comes with a balance of positive and negative aspects. In particular, the positive aspects are that it leads to closed-form solutions to the model, a feat that should not be minimized. On the other hand, a more general <ref type="bibr">8</ref> Our model can be thought of as a continuous time model where bids arrive according to a continuous exponential process with discrete "restarts" at the observed bids. It is assumed that each bidder instantaneously decides (renews) her rate right after the (k −1)st bid is realized and that the rate remains constant until the kth bid happens. We approximate that the sum of the rates for each time period starts after the previous bid, i.e., bidders immediately update. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> We only included a parameter corresponding to the magnitude shift of the AR(1) process for bid increments. We note that the AR(1) process could also be included for bid time and variance in future research.</p><p>timing model, like the Weibull model, would be more flexible, albeit at the cost of closed-form tractability. However, the error term in Equation ( <ref type="formula">8</ref>) affords us a great degree of flexibility.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Likelihood and Prior Specification</head><p>To obtain the likelihood function of bid amounts, we multiply Equation (3) across the I auctions and K i bids while integrating across then i k latent bidders and their mean valuation parameters i k and * i k j :</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">I i=1 K i k=1 f y i k n i k +1 i k 2 i k dF n i k dF i k dF * i k j</formula><p>(9) To obtain the likelihood function of bid times, we multiply Equation ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>) across the I auctions and K i bids while integrating over the number of latent bidders n i k and their rates i k :</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">I i=1 K i k=1 Pr min t i k j −t i k−1 = t i k dF n i k dF i k (10)</formula><p>Taken together, the joint likelihood function of the proposed model is L = Equation 9 × Equation <ref type="formula">10</ref>(11)</p><p>and emphasizes the joint identification ofn i k , the total number of latent bidders from both the bid amounts in Equation ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) and bid times in Equation (10).</p><p>The main advantages of the Bayesian paradigm, utilized here, are to allow for sharing of information across auctions for which there is sparse information and to provide small sample exact p-values not based on asymptotic approximations. Information sharing represents a significant issue for many of the observed auctions due to the large fraction of auctions with few bids. Recent research, albeit in the context of conjoint analysis (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Liechty et al. 2005)</ref>, has also applied Bayesian methods to models where there is a time-varying trend (i.e., valuation in our context) with much success.</p><p>There were a number of possible ways in which we could incorporate shrinkage. All slope parameters which govern the time-varying number of latent bidders , mean log(bid increment) , bid increment variances , and mean log(rate of bid speed) are given slightly informative but vague priors N 0 precision = 0 00001 to ensure proper posteriors but also to allow the data to primarily govern the inferences. Sensitivity analyses by varying these precisions indicated no impact due to the large sample sizes that are being used here. All variance components 2 , 2 , and 2 are given slightly informative inverse-gamma priors <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Gelman et al. 1995)</ref>, with shape and scale set at 0.01.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.">Computational Approach</head><p>Inferences were obtained using a data augmentation MCMC sampler, implemented in the freely available software Bayesian Inference Using Gibbs Sampling, WinBUGS. Results reported are from the output of 3 independent chains run for 10,000 iterations, each started from hyperdispersed starting values with a burn-in period of 7,500 iterations and utilizing the 7,500 draws (2,500 per chain) thereafter. Convergence was diagnosed both graphically and using the F -statistic diagnostic of <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Gelman and Rubin (1992)</ref>. We believe it is of importance to note how the model can be fit in WinBUGS (with ease) once the data augmentation scheme was utilized.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5.">Simulation Experiment</head><p>Due to the complex nature of the model and the latent processes that are specified within, we conducted a small scale MCMC simulation experiment to understand the identifiability of our proposed model. To accomplish this, we simulated ten (replicate) data sets using a reduced set of covariates (described below) but a fully parameterized and structured version of our model. The values for the simulation parameters (intercepts and slopes) were chosen to mimic the values found in our real data. Other simulation values were chosen to mimic our data set in size and nature. Further simulations not reported suggest that parameter recoverability is robust, at least for the other limited conditions that we tested.</p><p>In particular, the ten simulated data sets were generated as follows. Each consisted of data for 200 auctions and 15 bids per auction. For each of the four model components, we utilized an intercept, one static (auction-specific) covariate, and one timevarying (bid-specific) covariate. This structure was chosen as it represents the basic structure of each aspect of our latent linear regressions: an intercept, static covariates, and time-varying covariates. In addition, for the latent bid increments we also included another parameter corresponding to the magnitude shift of the AR(1) process to determine those bidders who remain from the previous bid and a corresponding threshold parameter ( ). Thus, this simulation structure is fully general.</p><p>The results reported in   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Model Results</head><p>Before presenting detailed results for our fully general model, we demonstrate its superiority in comparison to a number of interesting nested models, as well as a simple benchmark model. In particular, our model in §3 considers bidding participation wherein latent bidders come in, stay, or go out of the bidding process. This model, however, nests a model where all bidders, once they arrive, stay throughout for subsequent periods as operationalized here ( = 0), as well as a model where latent bidders are independent across bids, i.e., a new set of latent bidders arrives at each bid ( = 1). We also performed a series of OLS regression analyses of bid and time increments as a function of the same covariates. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref> reports that our general model performs best based on the overall mean absolute prediction error (MAPE) in bid increments as well as time increments. Furthermore, in parentheses we also report on the MAPE in bid and time increments for the final bid, statistics of high importance. Again, as with the overall fit measure, we see the superiority of Model 3. Given the theoretical completeness as well as its model fit, we focus on results of our general model (Model 3 in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref>) hereafter.</p><p>There are four major areas that we report upon in summarizing our results. First, we describe inferences for the latent number of competing bidders (both new and remaining), as inferred by the posterior distribution of the n i k and n * i k . These are particularly informative as they represent a unique contribution of our model formulation. Second, we describe inferences relating n i k to the covariates X i k , i.e., as empirical data set, the panel structure of the database over a heterogeneous set of bidders is likely to ensure enough bid and time variation. A bivariate plot of bid versus time increments can inform in this regard. The correlation between these two variables is a mere −0 0607. Thus, longer time increments do not have larger or smaller bid increments, which helps identify the proposed model. in Equation ( <ref type="formula">2</ref>). Third, we describe inferences that can be obtained by looking at summaries (posterior means) of the posterior distribution for and , the parameters governing the distribution for bid and time increments, respectively, and for , the parameters governing the distribution of bidder valuation variances. Finally, we report findings on assessing the fit of the model by looking at the posterior predictive distribution <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Gelman et al. 1996)</ref> for a variety of different quantiles along the observed empirical distribution of bid and time increments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Latent Bidders</head><p>Besides computational convenience due to closedform conditional distributions, understanding the latent bid and time increments provides a unique look into the underlying latent bidder process and hence the auction as a whole. To summarize the inferences for the number of latent bidders (both new and remaining), we describe summaries of the posterior distributions of the n i k and n * i k themselves, in particular their posterior means denoted n i k andñ * i k , and posterior means of the total number of latent biddersn i k as a fraction of total bids max ñ i k ∀ k / max ñ i k ∀ k + K i , where K i is the number of observed bids in auction i. This auctionlevel statistic provides an "impact" measure on the role (fraction) of total latent to observed bidders (bids) in the auction process across auctions. <ref type="bibr">12</ref> An interesting and unique aspect of findings surrounds the distribution of theñ i k andñ * i k , the posterior means of the number of latent bidders (new and remaining) across the 3,124 bids in 218 auctions. In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">4</ref>, we present a summary of the posterior means and 95% posterior intervals for n i k and n * i k corresponding to the minimum, 2.5 percentile, 25 percentile, median, 75 percentile, 97.5 percentile, and maximum values ofñ i k andñ * i k . We see that the posterior mean of the latent number of new (remaining) biddersñ i k (ñ * i k ) ranges from 0.38 (0.15) to 33.17 (53.93), indicating significant variation in those values.</p><p>An analysis of the latent bidders, by looking at the posterior means of the ratio of the total number of latent bidders to the total number of bids (seen = K i and unseen =n i k ), max</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">ñ i k ∀ k / max ñ i k ∀ k + K i</formula><p>, is presented in Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref>. It shows that the latent number of bidders play a significant role, i.e., the latent bidders are significant in number relative to the observed bidders. Also, we note that the correlation between the predicted number of latent bidders and number of actual bidders across auctions is 0.563, a finding suggesting that, while auctions with larger observed bidders tend to have more latent bidders, there is still significant variation. Furthermore, we provide in Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref> the posterior means of the ratio of the latent number of remaining bidders to the number of total latent bidders (both new and remaining). As shown in Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref>, the latent number of remaining bidders is considerably smaller than the latent number of new entrants (on average) but is still an important consideration.</p><p>Figures <ref type="figure">5 and 6</ref> show a more detailed analysis of the bivariate relationships between the latent number of remaining bidders and observed log(bid increment) and time increment, respectively. In each figure, we break the observed x-axis measure (log/bid increment or bid time increment) into deciles and then do a boxplot of the posterior means of the latent number of   Remaining latent bidders as a fraction of total latent bidders Frequency remaining bidders for each decile. Both figures show a clear downward pattern inñ * i k over deciles, which implies that larger bid and time increments significantly influence the bidding participation behavior of the remaining bidders. This is corroborated by a very high threshold estimate (posterior mean of = 0 959) in our results.</p><p>Another set of inferences related to the latent number of bidders, in this case new entrant bidders n i k , of particular interest is how the number of latent entrant bidders varies with the covariates as given in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref> and Equation (4). The results are presented in the first column in Table <ref type="table">5</ref> and are derived from the posterior means which describe log i k . First, the auction design variables AD i are important descriptors in explaining the number of latent entrant bidders n i k . They have significant impact, positive for image and negative for minimum bid amount and auction duration. That is, auction items with product images attract more latent bidders, and those that have a high "buy-in" (minimum bid) or a long wait to determine a winner (long auction duration) have lower values. Second, seller reputation ratings SR i are significant predictors for bidder entry behavior. Specifically, the extent (number) of positive ratings is more important than that of negative ratings, and in the expected direction. Third, most variables related to the product specifications PS i are important predictors of entry, n i k in a positive manner, except for usage which is negative. This is somewhat confirmatory, as one might expect that higher levels  </p><formula xml:id="formula_13">MC i Breadth −0 060 −0 025 * −0 165 * −0 005 Depth −0 009 −0 032 * −0 068 * −0 051 * BC i k k − 1 0 026 * 0 018 * −0 021 * 0 728 * y i k−1 n i k−1 +1 −0 025 * −0 112 * 0 035 * 0 024 * t i k−1 −0 209 * 0 027 * −0 088 * −0 071 * T i − t i k−1 −0 559 * −0 225 * 0 592 * −0 405 * AR(1) i k j y i k−1 j 0 013 * Notes.</formula><p>Parameter estimates for brand names are not included. * indicates that zero lies outside of the 95% posterior interval.</p><p>of product specification would lead to greater attraction, albeit depending on price, and that an older item (higher usage) would attract less. Finally, one important set of inferences centers on the bid-specific variables BC i k , i.e., the dynamics as the auction progresses: As the number of observed bids (i.e., k − 1) increases, there tends to be a greater number of latent entrant bidders. We also observe negative effects of the bid and time increments in the previous round and the remaining time in the auction duration. This suggests that when bid activity is clustered either in terms of bid amount or bid time, the number of latent bidders increases. In sum, all time-varying variables are important predictors of the number of latent bidders and demonstrates the importance of the time-varying nature in our stochastic model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Parameter Inferences</head><p>In addition to understanding the latent bidding process, one major goal is to understand the drivers of the observed bid increments, the source of variations in bidder valuations, and bid time increments. Such inferences are available by looking at summaries of elements of the posterior distribution of , , and , respectively, as shown in Table <ref type="table">5</ref>.</p><p>The major findings suggested are as follows. Considering the three auction design variables AD i , we note a significant positive effect for having a product image on the listing page, indicating that our observed bid increments increase when potential bidders see the product they are going to bid on. This suggests that adding a product image may indeed raise confidence and perceptions of products and, as further corroboration, we also found lower bid increment variances ( for presence of image). However, it did not affect the speed (bid time increments) at which bids arrive. Second, minimum bid is not a significant predictor for i k or log 2 i k , indicating a lack of effect on bid increments. However, it is negatively related to bid time increments, hence a larger minimum bid leads to smaller time increments and thus a greater concentration of bids. Third, auctions of shorter duration have larger bid increments and marginally larger variations. We note that without explicitly modeling the equilibrium-generating process on the part of bidders, one should be cautious about interpreting these findings for "optimal" auction design. As stated earlier, we consider these useful for further theoretical and/or empirical study.</p><p>Among variables of seller reputation SR i , we find that the amount of negative plus neutral ratings received from past bidders has a very significant negative effect on the bid increment, and that positive seller reputation has a very significant positive effect on bidding behavior yet no impact on the speed of the bid increments. The magnitude of positive reputation is much larger than that of the negative reputation. Furthermore, both positive and negative seller reputation ratings reduce variance in bidding behavior, suggesting that they are considered as viable sources of information (variance reduction) by the bidders. We note that ours is the first research to simultaneously look at the impact of reputation on attracting bidders ( ), bid increments (˜ ), bidder uncertainty (˜ ), and bid time increments ( ).</p><p>Third, we note very significant positive effects for CPU type (Pentium having larger bid increments than Celeron) and CPU speed in megahertz on bid increments and bid time increments, which, given their importance in defining notebook computers, is expected. That is, more valuable items tend to have larger bid increments and larger gaps between those bids. We note that this story is played out through all of our parameter estimates as is negative,˜ is negative,˜ is positive, and is positive for y i k−1 n i k−1 +1 . We also observe a significant positive effect on bid increments for the size of the hard disk (in gigabytes), an expected effect of exp 0 024 = 1 020 for every one gigabyte increase in hard disk space, and similarly an increase in the bid time increments. We also observe a significant positive effect for screen size both for bid increments and variances, which is somewhat intuitive given the sizes considered here. One other note is that these findings, in conjunction with those for the number of latent bidders, suggest more (less) attractive auction items attract more (less) bidders who might bid more (less). Certainly this set of patterns is apparent in this data; an area for future research would be to confirm this empirically in a broader setting.</p><p>Fourth, we observe significant negative effects for bid increments and variances in both market competition measures (MC i ). This informs that both measures (breadth and depth) help bidders better determine bid amounts which in turn reduces the uncertainty in bid increments. This explanation is consistent with literature in psychology and marketing in terms of consumer consideration and choice set formation and decision making. That is, the two market competition measures examine overall competition and substitution effects which are likely to exist in the auction market. A more detailed look at this issue, e.g., explicit prices of those auction items, can be addressed in future research and is more fully described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Chan et al. (2006)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Dholakia and Simonson (2005)</ref>. Fifth, we observe a positive effect on the size of bid increments for the (number of bids − 1), i.e., effectively bid k, and a negative effect on bid increments for remaining time; these are an identical pattern to what we found for latent bidders as well. We also find a significant positive effect for the AR(1) process which indicates that bid increments tend to be higher for continued participants, possibly due to their having not been the "record breaker" at the previous round.</p><p>Another set of findings of particular interest is to understand brand equity (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Elrod and Keane 1995)</ref>. In our context, we do this in Figure <ref type="figure">7</ref> by looking at a brand map constructed using the brand intercept's posterior means for the number of latent bidders and the size of bid and time increments for the corresponding brands. From this, we see that Samsung, for example, increases both the latent number of bidders and the size of the bid increments, suggesting "high" brand equity in online auctions. In fact, all the named brands as compared to the baseline "others" have higher bid increments, yet Samsung is the only one with increased latent bidders. We believe that this is the first time that brand maps have been applied in the Internet auction context and represents another contribution of our research. 13</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Model Fit</head><p>To assess our degree of confidence about the inferences derived under our model, we assess its fit using a variety of more detailed measures than MAPE given in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref>.</p><p>As shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">6</ref>, the model's ability to recover observed log(bid increment) values at differing points along the distribution of observed log(bid increment) is excellent. The table is generated by comparing the observed log(bid increment) at the minimum, maximum, and five common percentiles to posterior means from their respective posterior predictive <ref type="bibr">13</ref> As shown in Figure <ref type="figure">7</ref>, the brand intercepts for the number of latent bidders (ranging from −1 5 to 0.5) and bid increments (ranging from −1 0 to 3.0) are relatively larger than the brand intercepts for bid time increment (ranging from −1 0 to 0.5). This could be true because the bid timing is less of an issue in Internet auctions because bidders will be better off by bidding at the last minute of the auction duration.  distributions. This is crucial to assessing the quality of the model, as we are interested in providing a model that would allow for adequate predictions along the entire spectrum of bids.</p><p>As shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">6</ref>, in all cases from the minimum to the maximum value of observed log(bid increment) the model fits quite well, as the observed increment falls well within the posterior predictive interval. For the maximum bid increment, the model slightly underpredicts (i.e., the posterior mean is too low) the observed value. This suggests potentially an area for future model improvement in which we consider utilization of a longer-tailed distribution as compared to log-normal for the bid increments, or potentially including a more extensive set of descriptors for the bid increments.</p><p>With regard to bid time increments, we produce the corresponding table <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">(Table 7</ref>), demonstrating the model's ability to predict the bid times along its entire distribution. Again, the results in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">7</ref> suggest that all observed bid time increments are well within their posterior predictive 95% intervals, though for longer bid time increments there is some underestimation. The underestimation of the bid time increments at the maximum value is significant and suggests that further improvements to the model might be warranted. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusion</head><p>In this research, we have generalized the classic record-breaking problem in which records in a sequence can contain an underlying trend, yet the number of latent participants (in our jargon, bidders) and their arrival times are unobserved. The way in which we have done this, via data augmentation of the number of and the valuation of their bids as well as arrival times, has led to closed-form conditional distributions for the observed and latent bidder valuations. One obvious benefit of this approach is computational simplicity, in this case the ability to run the model in the freely available software WinBUGS and to avoid the common difficulty in dealing with the marginal distribution of the largest-order statistic.</p><p>We note a number of caveats and limitations to our research. First, the data collected here are from ascending first-price auctions. This choice by the site in which the winner pays the price that he or she bids, in contrast to second-price auctions in which the winner pays the second highest bidder's offer, has been under much discussion in the auction literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Lucking-Reiley 1999)</ref>. With that in mind, the empirical regularities found here are considered more suggestive than in any way definitive. Yet, we hope our model provides a framework for further empirical exploration. Second, the model developed here is descriptive and exploratory in nature and is not based on theoretical assumptions of auction behavior and equilibria in the extant economic auction literature. In particular, extant research suggests that bidders may act strategically, not choosing to reveal their true valuations when facing competition. The n i k and n * i k latent bidders can be considered hypothetical competitors in the mind of a bidder to which he or she does not strategically respond. However, our work provides a platform by which structural aspects can be incorporated into a stochastic approach. For instance, our threshold model provides one way to think about ongoing and future bidder behavior but, in addition, models which incorporate forward-looking behavior could also be incorporated.</p><p>Third, our model only records information from the last bid for remaining latent bidders through the AR(1) process and assumes all others start anew. It would be desirable to track the entire bidding history of remaining latent bidders, though this would add complexity for uncertain gains. Fourth, we consider the standard auction formats here which represent the general structure of record-breaking events and do not address the buy-it-now feature of online auctions. While this would be very tangential to the main thrust of this paper, it could be an interesting future research area due to the growing importance of this auction mechanism. Last, the lack of explicit modeling of variables under the control of the seller as endogenous to his knowledge is an area for interesting extension 229 in this research domain and could be incorporated through instrumental variables, possibly latent <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Ebbes et al. 2005)</ref> or through an extended likelihood <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Manchanda et al. 2004</ref>).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Bradlow and Park: Bayesian Estimation of Bid Sequences in Internet Auctions Marketing Science 26(2), pp. 218-229, © 2007 INFORMS 219</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Histogram of log (Bid Increment)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2Histogram of Bid Time Increment</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3Histogram of Maximum Latent Bidders as a Fraction of Total Bids</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Frequency</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 4Histogram ofñ * i k / ñ i k +ñ * i k</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 5Posterior Means of n * i k Based on Decile of log (Bid Increment)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 7Brand Equity on Latent Bidders and Bidding Behavior</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Data Description</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Variable</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>Std. dev.</cell></row><row><cell>Auction design</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Image (Yes = 1, No = 0)</cell><cell>0 64</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>log(minimum bid)</cell><cell>10 48</cell><cell>3 42</cell></row><row><cell>Duration (days)</cell><cell>5 8 3</cell><cell>3 02</cell></row><row><cell>Seller reputation</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>log(positive ratings + 1)</cell><cell>0 46</cell><cell>0 81</cell></row><row><cell>log(negative and neutral ratings + 1)</cell><cell>0 41</cell><cell>0 76</cell></row><row><cell>Product specification</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>CPU (Pentium = 1, Celeron = 0)</cell><cell>0 81</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>CPU speed (MHz)</cell><cell>525 74</cell><cell>211 04</cell></row><row><cell>Memory (megabytes)</cell><cell>111 09</cell><cell>57 62</cell></row><row><cell>Hard disk (gigabytes)</cell><cell>11 59</cell><cell>6 77</cell></row><row><cell>Screen size (inches)</cell><cell>12 93</cell><cell>1 32</cell></row><row><cell>Usage (months)</cell><cell>9 37</cell><cell>9 81</cell></row><row><cell>Brand name</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Compaq</cell><cell>0 16</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>IBM</cell><cell>0 15</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Fujitsu</cell><cell>0 03</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Sony</cell><cell>0 08</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Sambo</cell><cell>0 11</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Samsung</cell><cell>0 41</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Others</cell><cell>0 06</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Note. Brand names are not included.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>are the average over</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Simulation Results</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Estimated value</cell></row><row><cell>Variable</cell><cell>True value Posterior mean 95% posterior interval</cell></row><row><cell>in log i k</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Model Fit: Mean Absolute Prediction Error-All Bids (Last Bid)</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Regression Model 1: = 0 Model 2: = 1 Model 3: 0 ≤ ≤ 1</cell></row><row><cell>log(bid increment) 1.362 (1.034) 1.188 (1.100) 0.725 (0.490)</cell><cell>0.637 (0.384)</cell></row><row><cell>Bid time increment 0.399 (0.562) 0.347 (0.068) 0.345 (0.060)</cell><cell>0.299 (0.058)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Posterior Means and 95% Probability Intervals for Particular n i k and n *</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>i k</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>n i k</cell><cell></cell><cell>n  *  i k</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Posterior</cell><cell>95% posterior</cell><cell>Posterior</cell><cell>95% posterior</cell></row><row><cell>Quartile</cell><cell>mean</cell><cell>interval</cell><cell>mean</cell><cell>interval</cell></row><row><cell>Minimum</cell><cell>0 38</cell><cell>0 1</cell><cell>0 15</cell><cell>0 1</cell></row><row><cell>2.5%</cell><cell>0 68</cell><cell>0 2</cell><cell>0 45</cell><cell>0 2</cell></row><row><cell>25.0%</cell><cell>4 72</cell><cell>1 12</cell><cell>1 24</cell><cell>0 4</cell></row><row><cell>50.0%</cell><cell>9 48</cell><cell>2 24</cell><cell>3 01</cell><cell>0 8</cell></row><row><cell>75.0%</cell><cell>15 79</cell><cell>3 41</cell><cell>7 50</cell><cell>2 14</cell></row><row><cell>97.5%</cell><cell>25 60</cell><cell>5 56</cell><cell>48 27</cell><cell>37 56</cell></row><row><cell>Maximum</cell><cell>33 17</cell><cell>6 59</cell><cell>53 93</cell><cell>48 59</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Observed log (Bid Increment) vs. Predicted log (Bid Increment)</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Predicted log(bid increment)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Observed</cell><cell>Posterior</cell><cell>95% posterior</cell></row><row><cell>Quartile</cell><cell>log(bid increment)</cell><cell>mean</cell><cell>interval</cell></row><row><cell>Minimum</cell><cell>5 704</cell><cell>5 700</cell><cell>5 684 5 713</cell></row><row><cell>2.5%</cell><cell>6 908</cell><cell>6 905</cell><cell>6 820 6 952</cell></row><row><cell>25.0%</cell><cell>8 517</cell><cell>8 521</cell><cell>8 304 8 638</cell></row><row><cell>50.0%</cell><cell>8 556</cell><cell>8 648</cell><cell>8 395 8 971</cell></row><row><cell>75.0%</cell><cell>10 309</cell><cell>10 250</cell><cell>9 234 11 400</cell></row><row><cell>97.5%</cell><cell>12 897</cell><cell>12 560</cell><cell>9 716 15 480</cell></row><row><cell>Maximum</cell><cell>14 604</cell><cell>13 560</cell><cell>9 982 17 310</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table 7</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Observed Time Increment vs. Predicted Time Increment</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Predicted time increment</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Observed time</cell><cell>Posterior</cell><cell>95% posterior</cell></row><row><cell>Quartile</cell><cell>increment</cell><cell>mean</cell><cell>interval</cell></row><row><cell>Minimum</cell><cell>2 3E − 05</cell><cell>0 0052</cell><cell>0 0001 0 0191</cell></row><row><cell>2.5%</cell><cell>0.0003</cell><cell>0 0065</cell><cell>0 0002 0 0229</cell></row><row><cell>25.0%</cell><cell>0.0107</cell><cell>0 0130</cell><cell>0 0003 0 0498</cell></row><row><cell>50.0%</cell><cell>0.0787</cell><cell>0 0798</cell><cell>0 0024 0 2836</cell></row><row><cell>75.0%</cell><cell>0.3405</cell><cell>0 3404</cell><cell>0 0108 1 0889</cell></row><row><cell>97.5%</cell><cell>2.7150</cell><cell>1 7939</cell><cell>0 0410 4 8058</cell></row><row><cell>Maximum</cell><cell>6.0978</cell><cell>3 7484</cell><cell>0 1635 8 7359</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">$1 corresponded approximately to 1,200 won at the time these data were collected.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">We examined that our model is not particularly sensitive to the choice of maximal N i used for computation. Furthermore, it can be made arbitrarily large. N i is included to allow for the possibility of a known competition set. We thank an anonymous reviewer for a comment that led to this choice.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">We followed<ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Chan et al. (2006)</ref> who operationalized these measures via auction-specific variables. First, we pooled all items being auctioned during the time interval that the focal item is being auctioned. We calculate the mean CPU speed, memory, hard drive, and screen size of these items. We next select items that are within one standard deviation of the focal item's speed, memory, hard drive, and screen size. We then match the items on the discrete attributes. We define these items as comprising the "similar item superset."5 One could extend the covariate set to incorporate various aspects of bidding behavior such as the day of the week or time of day which can impact when people are online and hence available to bid on auctions.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="10">Standard errors for each result are available from the authors upon request.11  One point to note is the separable identification of the size of bid and time increments. While this is not guaranteed for any</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="12">Note that in our model we do not differentiate between bids and bidders as our interest is in the bid increments. If one is interested in the bidders and their increments, one might look at max ñ i k ∀ k / max ñ i k ∀ k + U i instead, where U i is the number of unique bidders.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank seminar participants at Columbia University, 2004 Joint Statistical Meetings, 2004 Marketing Science Conference, New York University, Stanford University, Washington University in St. Louis, and University of Michigan for their comments.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian analysis of binary and polychotomous response data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Albert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chib</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">422</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="669" to="679" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Buying, bidding, playing or competing? Value assessment and decision dynamics in online auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ariely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Simonson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Psych</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The winner&apos;s curse, reserve prices, and endogenous entry: Empirical insights from eBay auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bajari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hortaçsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="329" to="355" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Bayesian lifetime model for the &quot;Hot 100&quot; billboard songs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Bradlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">96</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">454</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="368" to="381" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Regional analysis of temperature extremes: Spatial analog for climate change?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Climate</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="108" to="119" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parametric likelihood inference for record breaking problems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Carlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Gelfand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biometrika</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="507" to="515" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Willingness to pay and competition in online auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Chan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kadiyali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y.-H</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res. Forthcoming</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Bayesian analysis of extreme rainfall data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Coles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Tawn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="463" to="478" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of explicit reference points on consumer choice and online bidding behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dholakia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Simonson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="206" to="217" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New evidence for the effect of education on income: Solving endogeneity with latent instrumental variables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ebbes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Steerneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Böckenholt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="365" to="392" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A factor-analytic probit model for representing the market structure in panel data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Elrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inference from iterative simulation using multiple sequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statist. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="457" to="472" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Posterior predictive assessment of model fitness via realized discrepancies (with discussion)</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X.-L</forename><surname>Meng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statistica Sinica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="733" to="807" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bayesian Data Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Carlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<pubPlace>London, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reserves, regret, and rejoicing in open English auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Greenleaf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="264" to="273" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal nonparametric estimation of first-price auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Guerre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Perrigne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Vuong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="525" to="574" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empirical implications of equilibrium bidding in first-price symmetric, common value auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hendricks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pinkse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Porter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="115" to="145" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimation of a dynamic auction game</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jofre-Bonet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Pesendorfer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1443" to="1489" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kotz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Balakrishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Continuous Univariate Distributions</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kotz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Balakrishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Continuous Univariate Distributions</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic models incorporating individual heterogeneity: Utility evolution in conjoint analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Liechty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K H</forename><surname>Fong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Desarbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="293" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using field experiments to test equivalence between auction formats: Magic on the Internet</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lucking-Reiley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1063" to="1080" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response modeling with non-random marketing mix variables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Manchanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rossi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="467" to="478" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simple estimators for the parameters of discrete dynamic games with entry/exit examples</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pakes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ostrovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Berry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Forthcoming</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An integrated model for bidding behavior in Internet auctions: Whether, who, when, and how much</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y.-H</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Bradlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="470" to="482" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistics for exceptional athletics records</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Tawn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="499" to="511" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Last-minute bidding and the rules for ending second-price auctions: Evidence from eBay and Amazon auctions on the Internet</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ockenfels</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1093" to="1103" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Editorial: Marketing and designing transaction games</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="525" to="530" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The calculation of posterior distributions by data augmentation (with discussion)</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Tanner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">398</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="528" to="550" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Forecasting records</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Tryfos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Blackmore</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">389</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="46" to="50" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating dynamic multifirm market interactions in price and advertising</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Vilcassim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kadiyali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="499" to="518" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Endogeneity in brand choice models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Villas-Boas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Winer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1324" to="1338" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
