<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Strategic Manufacturer Response to a Dominant Retailer</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Tansev</forename><surname>Geylani</surname></persName>
							<email>tgeylani@katz.pitt.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Katz Graduate School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>320 Mervis Hall</addrLine>
									<postCode>15260</postCode>
									<settlement>Pittsburgh</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dukes</surname></persName>
							<email>adukes@econ.adu.dk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Economics and Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Aarhus</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Building 1322</addrLine>
									<postCode>8000</postCode>
									<settlement>Aarhus C</settlement>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kannan</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
							<email>kannans@andrew.cmu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Tepper School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>5000 Forbes Avenue</addrLine>
									<postCode>15213</postCode>
									<settlement>Pittsburgh</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Strategic Manufacturer Response to a Dominant Retailer</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 07 2602 0164</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1060.0239</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-13T12:15+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>T he growing dominance of large retailers has altered traditional channel incentives for manufacturers. In this paper, we present a theoretical model to illustrate a strategic manufacturer response to a dominant retailer. In our model, a dominant and a weak retailer compete for the sale of a single product supplied by a single manufacturer. The dominant retailer has the power to dictate the wholesale price, but the manufacturer sets the wholesale price for the weak retailer. The manufacturer also has partial ability to transfer demand between retailers. In the strategic manufacturer response, the manufacturer begins by raising the wholesale price for the weak retailer over that for the dominant retailer. This makes the weak retailer the high-margin channel. The manufacturer then transfers demand to the weak retailer by engaging in joint promotions and advertising. We then use this strategic response model to derive a testable hypothesis that may guide future research in determining the source of dominant retailers' low prices.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>In a growing number of industries, a few retailers, such as Wal-Mart, Tesco, and Home Depot, are determining how consumer products are made and sold in the United States and Europe. These dominant retailers, also known as "category killers" or "power retailers," have been enormously successful. For example, Wal-Mart, with its $285 billion sales, is one of the largest companies in the world <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Maier 2005)</ref>. Tesco is the number one grocer in the United Kingdom, accounting for almost 30% of the supermarket sales and, by some accounts, taking in $1 out of every $11 spent on retail <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Carney 2004</ref>). In the home improvement market, the total market share of Home Depot and Lowe's is more than 50% <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Knight 2003)</ref>.</p><p>Emergence of the dominant retailers is a result of the shift of channel power from manufacturers to retailers. This trend has been attributed to increased use of information technology by retailers, insufficient shelf space due to a large number of new product introductions, increased concentration of the retailing industry, and introduction of successful privatelabel brands <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Kadiyali et al. 2000)</ref>. Other commonly cited causes include a decline in advertising and improved quality of retail management <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Messinger and Narasimhan 1995)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Butaney and Wortzel (1988)</ref> show that distributors have more power when industry competition is strong and industry sales are equally distributed among industry manufacturers. Dominant retailers use finely tuned product line selections and, most importantly, competitive pricing to attack weaker channel players and attract more customers. For example, Business Week reports that on a comparable basket of grocery items, Wal-Mart's prices were, on the average, 20% lower than those of other stores <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Koretz 2002)</ref>.</p><p>To keep prices low, these retailers enjoy advantages that traditional retailers do not. For example, Home Depot's state-of-the-art inventory system makes it very difficult for regional firms to be competitive with Home Depot <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Dunne and Kahn 1997)</ref>. It has been argued that Wal-Mart's superior operating margins leave plenty of room for Wal-Mart to offer lower prices <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Neff 2003)</ref>. Logistical efficiencies have been attributed to Wal-Mart's cost advantage <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Facenda 2004</ref>).</p><p>However, it has also been argued that the retail giant systematically uses its channel power with the manufacturers to buy products at the lowest cost possible and pass the gains on to the consumer through extremely low prices <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Useem 2003)</ref>. Many argue that Wal-Mart has a reputation for getting favorable wholesale terms via aggressive negotiating tactics with their suppliers <ref type="bibr">(Facenda 2004, Munson and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Rosenblatt 1999)</ref>. For example, Business Week reported that "One multinational supplier says Wal-Mart buyers in Mexico were aggressive and abusive pulling his product off shelves for several months when he objected to a deep price cut that would have wiped out his profits" <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Smith 2002</ref>). Fortune's report was similar: "[Wal-Mart's] suppliers are expected to give their best price period. It is not even negotiated anymore says of a consulting company that helps manufacturers sell to big retailers" <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Useem 2003)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> As in the case of Wal-Mart, Tesco's remarkably low grocery prices have also been attributed to its ability to squeeze supplier margins <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Carney 2004)</ref>. This squeeze has been so severe, in fact, as to cause street protests against Tesco in sympathy with milk suppliers. According to a group of independent music retailers, Best Buy uses its clout to extract price concessions from major record companies, which enables it to sell new albums at lower prices <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Christman 2003)</ref>.</p><p>Why do these retailers have such power over the manufacturers? Potential benefits may arise for manufacturers when they work with dominant retailers. First, dominant retailers' sheer size and the velocity at which they sell their inventory allow them to sell large volumes. This helps their suppliers to benefit from scale economies in transaction costs. For example, the marginal cost of transacting with the retailer may be smaller the bigger the shipped lot. This could take the form of transportation costs or billing costs. In the home-repair category, for instance, Home Depot has won the favor of suppliers by consolidating regional buying offices into a single entity, which streamlines purchasing and helps Home Depot to pay its vendors faster <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Foust 2004)</ref>. Another source of suppliers' distribution efficiency is made possible by the dominant retailers' sophisticated information technologies. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> For example, Wal-Mart in the early 90s <ref type="bibr">1</ref> An issue is whether or not such lower prices to one retailer results in violation of the Robinsom-Patman Act. Business Week reports, "Wal-Mart appears to be in no imminent danger of running afoul of federal antitrust statutes. The Robinson-Patman Act of 1936 was passed in large part to protect mom-and-pop grocers from the Great Atlantic &amp; Pacific Tea Co., the Wal-Mart of its day. But contemporary antitrust interpretations eschew such David-and-Goliath populism. Giants like Wal-Mart have wide latitude to do as they wish to rivals and suppliers so long as they deliver lower prices to consumers. 'When Wal-Mart comes in and people desert downtown because they like the selection and the low prices, it's hard for people in the antitrust community to say we should not let them do that,' says New York University law professor Harry First." <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bianco et al. 2003)</ref>. This is a complex legal issue that is beyond the scope of the paper and the capabilities of the authors. was known to develop its "retail link," which gave many of its suppliers access to inventory positions of their products at its retail locations <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bradley and Ghemawat 2002)</ref>. Wal-Mart is well known for its technological innovations. In the 1990s, Wal-Mart was a leader in applying electronic data interchange (EDI), which allows retailers and suppliers to readily exchange data. Now it is leading the industry in applying RFID, Internet-based, and scan basedtrading technologies, which will bring further efficiencies not only to Wal-Mart but also to its suppliers. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> Competing retailers of the dominant players do not enjoy the same kind of leverage with their suppliers, and therefore are at a competitive disadvantage. For example, a group of more than 100 auto parts retailers claimed that category killers, including Wal-Mart and Pep Boys, induced price discrimination and purchased auto parts from the suppliers at prices 40% less than the other retailers <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Balto 2002)</ref>.</p><p>How manufacturers might manage such asymmetric channel relationships is the main focus of this research. Our results indicate that when faced with a dominant retailer who dictates wholesale terms, hard-pressed manufacturers and nondominant retailers have an incentive to mitigate the power of the dominant retailer. Our analysis suggests that joint marketing initiatives with selected channel members can be used as a way to deal with the threat imposed by a power retailer in a particular industry or product category. We refer to this type of general marketing activity as a strategic manufacturer response to a dominant retailer. We make a distinction between a dominant and a weak retailer and examine the dominant retailer/manufacturer/weak retailer channel structure, in which the dominant retailer dictates the wholesale price to the manufacturer. The manufacturer then sets the wholesale price for the weak retailer in combination with joint advertising or promotion.</p><p>Our study, however, does not foreclose the notion that the dominant retailer's low prices come from its operational efficiencies. Rather, we isolate from the cost efficiency explanation the dominant retailer's ability to obtain favorable supply terms via its tough negotiating leverage. By doing so, we are able to separate the consequence of its raw ability to dictate channel terms from that arising from an efficiency advantage.</p><p>Marketing Science 26(2), pp. <ref type="bibr">164-178, © 2007 INFORMS</ref> In our theoretical analysis, the weak retailer and the dominant retailer compete for the sale of a single product supplied by a manufacturer. The dominant retailer dictates the wholesale price to the manufacturer, who then sets the wholesale price for the weak retailer. The manufacturer has the ability to transfer demand from one retailer to another. The analysis reveals insights for a strategic manufacturer response to the dominant retailer pricing pressures. Specifically, by raising the wholesale price for the weak retailer over that for the dominant retailer and transferring demand from the low-margin (dominant) channel to the high-margin (weak) channel, the manufacturer can shift the distribution of channel profits away from the dominant retailer. By raising the weak retailer's wholesale price (which raises the weak retailer's consumer prices), the manufacturer induces higher prices by both retailers due to strategic complementarity, which results in higher consumer prices. Thus, the retailers are able to extract more surplus from the consumers. The manufacturer gets some part of this increased surplus through its higher wholesale price in the weak retail channel. Given this higher wholesale price for the weak retailer, the manufacturer is able to make more profits by transferring demand to this high-margin (weak retailer) channel.</p><p>The manufacturer can transfer demand from the dominant retailer to the weak retailer using different tools. For example, it can give the weak retailer cooperative advertising allowances that induce the weak retailer to promote its product. Alternatively, the manufacturer can shift some demand from the dominant retailer to the weak retailer by collaborative advertising and promotions. <ref type="bibr">4 5 4</ref> There are different ways a manufacturer can help a retailer through such collaboration. For example, Kellogg's developed TV commercials that had the company in tandem with a local retailer, talking about support for certain community programs <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Fusaro 2000)</ref>. Here is the message in another collaborative ad: "The laundry is almost done when the young woman moans that crayons in the dryer melted over her expensive jeans. To the rescue: Tide and Vons Club" (The Plain Dealer 1995). In the summer of 1995, Keebler ran local advertising spots in addition to its national advertising for its Salty Snacks brands to promote both the brands and local grocery stores in more than 50 major markets <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Marx 1995a)</ref>. Retailers could also tie in with Keebler's national promotions with vacation and entertainment partners by awarding free prizes from Keebler's marketing partners to local shoppers <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Marx 1995b)</ref>. Billboard reported that EMI launched its channel concept in 1996 to help small stores compete with major chains. Under the EMI channel initiative, the retailers had access to listening posts, an in-store marketing unit, and special promotions <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Ferguson 1996)</ref>. According to Advertising Age, to help small retailers, Kodak is reported to issue a handbook containing marketing insights and to give direct-mail materials and provide co-op ad dollars <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Wilke 1997)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> There are indications in the marketplace suggesting that this might be the case. For example, according to an article in Billboard, alarmed by the increased dominance of large retailers (e.g.,</p><p>The incentive to transfer demand to a weak retail channel has implications for detecting the source of the power retailers' low prices. A purely efficiency view would suggest that retailing efficiencies singularly enable these retailers to keep costs low. Alternatively, a channel power view would imply that the dominant retailers' ability to dictate channel terms provides an explanation to these low prices. In §4, we derive a testable hypothesis that suggests the following. If it is empirically observed that manufacturers provide exclusive support for weak retailers, then dominant retailers' power in bargaining with suppliers is a contributing factor to their low prices. Otherwise, if manufacturers do not offer exclusive assistance to weak retailers, then dominant retailers' low prices are likely not a consequence of their ability to induce favorable wholesale prices from their suppliers.</p><p>There has been a sustained interest in game-theoretic modeling of marketing channels (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Choi 1991</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">, Chu and Desai 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">, Coughlan 1985</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">, Jeuland and Shugan 1983</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">, Kim and Staelin 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">, Lal and Narasimhan 1996</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">, Lee and Staelin 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">, McGuire and Staelin 1983</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">, Moorthy 1988</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">, Purohit 1997</ref>, and different channel structures have been introduced. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">McGuire and Staelin (1983)</ref> characterized the manufacturer Stackelberg model, in which the manufacturer sets the wholesale price for the retailer. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Jeuland and Shugan (1983)</ref> described the vertical Nash model, where there is a balance between the manufacturer and the retailer in the sense that they set their prices simultaneously. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Choi (1991)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Lee and Staelin (1997)</ref> used the retailer Stackelberg model, in which the retailer dictates its margin to the manufacturer. In our model, we incorporate power asymmetry between retailers. In the channel structure analyzed here, the dominant retailer has the power to dictate the wholesale price to the manufacturer, but the weak retailer does not have such power.</p><p>There is also literature in marketing on power within the channel. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Butaney and Wortzel (1988)</ref> demonstrate that customer market power as Wal-Mart, Target, and Best Buy), the major record labels in the music industry are now supporting independents (weaker retailers) with a greater flow of cooperative advertising dollars <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Christman 2002)</ref>. Moreover, according to an ex-brand manager of Heinz via informal discussion, to balance the power of dominant retailers such as Wal-Mart, manufacturers help weaker retailers such as Kroger and Safeway via promotions and collaborative advertising. The reader, however, should not interpret these examples as suggesting that manufacturers assist weaker retailers only. Although here we only mention those examples suggesting exclusive advertising support, manufacturers also provide advertising support to the dominant retailers. What is relevant is that our objective in this paper is to explain why exclusive advertising support to weak retailers might occur in some, but not all, instances. (Please see §4 for complete details.) well as manufacturer market power play a role in determining distributor power in industrial goods markets. <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Messinger and Narasimhan (1995)</ref> investigate whether there has been a power shift in the supply channel by investigating the change in profitability of manufacturers and retailers. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Banks et al. (2002)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Iyer and Villas-Boas (2003)</ref> more recently examine the consequence of reputation and bargaining power, respectively, in one-on-one channel relationships. Our research, alternatively, considers how the power in one channel affects the manufacturer's behavior in other channels.</p><p>A recent study that recognizes the relevance of asymmetric channel relationships in retail competition is <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Dukes et al. (2006)</ref>. This research focuses on characterizing the impact of asymmetric retailing costs on wholesale bargaining and on the distribution of profits. Alternatively, in this paper, we consider a dominant retailer whose ability to dictate channel terms may or may not derive from a cost advantage. In addition, unlike <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Dukes et al. (2006)</ref>, we examine a manufacturer's marketing strategy beyond that of just pricing. Another study that examines asymmetric channels is that of <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Raju and Zhang (2005)</ref>. They investigate how a manufacturer can best coordinate a channel in the presence of a dominant retailer. In their paper, the asymmetry is in price leadership (i.e., the dominant retailer sets its price and the other retailers take this price as the market price), while in ours asymmetry arises from one retailer's ability to dictate the wholesale price to the manufacturer.</p><p>Subsequent sections are organized as follows. Section 2 provides the basic modeling framework and characterizes the equilibrium that defines the strategic manufacturer response. In §3, we examine several properties of the strategic manufacturer response. Section 4 derives a test for detecting the source of the power retailers' competitive advantage. Section 5 evaluates the robustness of the manufacturer's strategic response when we relax two modeling assumptions. In concluding, §6 summarizes the results, outlines the limitations of the study, and proposes directions for future research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Strategic Manufacturer Response</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Manufacturer's Pricing Response</head><p>In this section, we develop a two-stage equilibrium model to illustrate the basic incentives behind strategic manufacturer response. Consider an industry with two differentiated retailers who compete for the sale of a single product supplied by a common manufacturer. Initially, the manufacturer and the two retailers play a two-stage pricing game in which the manufacturer moves in Stage 1 and the two retailers compete in retail prices in Stage 2. The two retailers differ with respect to the manufacturer's control over wholesale prices. The manufacturer is unable to directly influence the wholesale price for one of the retailers, which we refer to as the dominant retailer D . Denote by w D ≥ 0 the unit price paid to the manufacturer for each unit sold to the dominant retailer. This price is assumed to be exogenous. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> For the other retailer, the weak retailer W , the manufacturer is endowed with the ability to dictate the channel terms by offering a take-it-or-leave-it wholesale price w W . This occurs in Stage 1.</p><p>Note that our notion of channel dominance is defined as the ability of one retailer to dictate its wholesaling costs upstream to its supplier. The quotes given in the introduction illustrate this notion of dominance. We take channel dominance by a retailer as an assumption. In our model, we do not aim to explain where this dominance comes from. This is a substantive and interesting issue, but beyond our research scope. We are interested in how the manufacturer responds given this dominance. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> After observing the manufacturer's choice of w W in Stage 1, retailers simultaneously chose retail prices p D and p W in Stage 2. Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> illustrates model's timing and the arrangement of the agents. The retailers' marginal costs of retailing are c W and c D , respectively. In order to isolate the intuition for the manufacturer's strategic response, we initially set c W = c D = 0. Later, in §3.2, however, we relax this assumption in order to investigate the impact of retailer cost asymmetry c W &gt; c D ≥ 0 on the manufacturer's ability to Marketing Science 26(2), pp. 164-178, © 2007 INFORMS implement its strategic response. The manufacturer's marginal cost of production is normalized to zero. Fixed costs for all firms are also set to zero, without loss of generality.</p><p>Consumers have different preferences over the two retailers. We model this differentiation as consumers being uniformly distributed along a straight line of unit length with retailers located at both ends. Each consumer visits exactly one retailer and buys one unit of the product. When visiting a retailer, a consumer incurs a "transportation" cost of t &gt; 0 times the length traveled. This transportation cost parameter captures the extent of differentiation between the two retailers. A useful interpretation is that retailers are differentiated by the various attributes of the store. For example, stores might differ with respect to location, store layout, or product assortment. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> Formally, let x ∈ 0 1 represent the location of a consumer by denoting her distance to retailer D. Given retail prices p D and p W , this consumer's utility from each retailer as a function of location x is</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">U i x =    v − tx − p D i= D v − t 1 − x − p W i = W (1)</formula><p>where v &gt; 0 is the gross benefit from consuming the manufacturer's product. It is assumed that v is sufficiently large so that U i x &gt; 0 for all possible p D , p W , and x. Specifically, this assumption takes the following form:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Assumption 1. v &gt; 11t/2 + 2c W + c D /3 + w D .</formula><p>The consumer located at x chooses retailer i to maximize (1). Consequently, retailer i's demand can be expressed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">q i = 1 2 + p j − p i 2t i = D W j = i (2)</formula><p>and Stage 2 profits as</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">i = p i − w i 1 2 + p j − p i 2t i = D W j = i (3)</formula><p>Retailer i's optimal pricing in Stage 2, as a function of wholesale prices w D and w W , is then given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">p i w W w D = t + 2w i 3 + w j 3 i = D W j = i (4)</formula><p>which are determined by maximizing (3) with respect to p i for i = D W . Stage 2 pricing functions, given by ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>), suggest that an increase in the weak retailer's wholesale price leads to higher prices by both retailers. Because wholesale price w W is retailer W 's marginal cost, an increase causes the weak retailer to increase p W . In addition, because retailer D observes changes in wholesale price w W , retailer D strategically anticipates an increase in p W and raises p D accordingly. This effect endows the manufacturer with the ability to coordinate retail prices even though he has control in only one channel. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> The manufacturer exploits this effect to her benefit when choosing the wholesale price w W in order to maximize profit, which is expressed by</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">m w W w D = i=D W w i q i (<label>5</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_6">)</formula><p>and incorporates Stage 2 responses in retail prices.</p><p>The solution to manufacturer's Stage 1 optimization yields the wholesale price in equilibrium presented in the following proposition. Equilibrium variables in the pricing response model are denoted with the notation ∼.</p><p>Proposition 1. Given w D ≥ 0 and Assumption 1, the equilibrium is characterized as follows.</p><p>1. The manufacturer charges the weak retailer a wholesale price w W = 3t/2 + w D .</p><p>2. Retailers set retail prices</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">p W = 2t + w D andp D = 3t/2 + w D</formula><p>3. Retailer and manufacturer profits are:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">W = t 8 D = 9t 8 and m = 3t 8 + w D</formula><p>What is important to note from this proposition is that, in equilibrium, the manufacturer sets its wholesale price w W &gt; w D . If the manufacturer were to set w W less than the exogenously set w D , the strategic effect discussed above would lead to less retail price coordination. This could only be beneficial to the manufacturer if it resulted in more overall sales for the manufacturer. However, because we consider a fixed set of consumers, the manufacturer does not gain anything by keeping retail prices low.</p><p>Also, it follows from the fact w W &gt; w D that the dominant retailer sets the price lower than the weak retailer:p W &gt;p D . As a result, a greater volume of the manufacturer's sales occurs through the dominant retail channel. Hence, the dominant retailer has a larger market share than the weak retailer solely as a result of its channel position vis-à-vis the manufacturer. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> The manufacturer would prefer the distribution of market share to be opposite. In particular, because it earns higher margins through the weak retailer, she would like to shift consumers away from the dominant to the weak retailer. This is precisely the motive of the manufacturer to engage in some sort of marketing activity, which encourages consumers to choose the weak retailer over the dominant one. We expand on this point in the following section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Strategic Manufacturer Response</head><p>In the previous section, it was argued that the manufacturer, when facing a dominant retailer, obtains a higher margin from the weak retailer. Consequently, if the manufacturer had the ability to influence consumers' retailer choice, then she would encourage them to choose the weak retailer. In this section, we formalize this reasoning by extending the model to allow the manufacturer to engage in marketing activities, such as collaborative advertising with the retailer, which can influence consumers' retailer choices. Extending the model in this way permits us to investigate the extent to which the manufacturer should invest in such an activity. In addition, we can use the model to predict how industry parameters, such as retailer differentiation, affect the incentive to induce consumers to switch retailers.</p><p>Suppose that in Stage 1 the manufacturer can invest in some marketing activity that encourages consumers to shop at a particular retailer. For example, the manufacturer can develop commercials that encourage shoppers to visit the retailer. (Please also see Footnote 4.) Let k ∈ − + denote the manufacturer's investment choice. (For simplicity of exposition, from now on we will refer to this as the manufacturer's advertising investment.) If k &gt; 0, the manufacturer invests k to encourage shoppers to choose the weak retailer. If k &lt; 0, the manufacturer spends −k to encourage shoppers to choose the dominant retailer. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> Let A k be a component of the consumer's utility, which measures the degree to which consumers are predisposed toward a particular retailer. For example, if A k &gt; 0, then consumers gain an additional benefit when shopping at the weak retailer. To incorporate this additional factor into the model, we extend the utility specification in (1) as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">U i x =    v −A k I k&lt;0 −tx −p D i= D v +A k I k≥0 −t 1−x −p W i= W (6)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">A k =    √ k k &gt; 0 − √ −k k &lt; 0</formula><p>&gt; 0 and I • is an indicator function, which takes on the value of one when the bracketed condition holds, and takes on zero otherwise. The parameter denotes the sensitivity consumers have toward the advertising. We further assumed that is not too large, so that the manufacturer cannot advertise so high as to direct all consumers to one retailer. Formally, we make the following assumption.</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">Assumption 2. 18t &gt; 2 .</formula><p>This assumption ensures that the manufacturer's profit maximization problem has an interior solution. Note, in addition, that our specification of A • is chosen to exhibit decreasing returns, which is in line with standard notions of advertising <ref type="bibr">(Agrawal 1996, Kim and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Staelin 1999)</ref>.</p><p>With the ability to affect some of the consumers' retailer choices, we must reexamine the manufacturer's pricing decision. Relative to the model described in the previous section, for a given amount of advertising k = 0, some consumers are induced to switch retailers and this alters retailers' pricing strategies. For example, if k &gt; 0, the dominant retailer concedes market share to the weak one. To retain consumers, the dominant retailer must compete more aggressively with price while the weak retailer can afford to raise its price. Optimal retail prices, given k and w W , lead to the following distribution of market shares</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">q D = 1 2 + w W − w D 6t − A k 6t and q W = 1 2 + w D − w W 6t + A k 6t (7)</formula><p>Note that in the above formulation, three possibilities are allowed. If we find in equilibrium that k &lt; 0, then demand is transferred to the dominant retailer (via manufacturer's advertising). If we find k &gt; 0, then demand is transferred to the weak retailer (via manufacturer's advertising). If we find k = 0, then there is no transfer of demand between the retailers. The quantities given by ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>) fully describe the demand facing the manufacturer in each channel. The manufacturer's Stage 1 problem in the strategic response model can thus be described as follows. Given w D , the manufacturer chooses k and w W to maximize</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">m = i=D W w i q i − k (<label>8</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_14">)</formula><p>Marketing Science 26(2), pp. 164-178, © 2007 INFORMS subject to <ref type="bibr">(7)</ref>. The maximizers of (8) constitute the unique equilibrium strategy of the manufacturer in the strategic response model. As seen in §2.1, the manufacturer responds by raising the weak retailer's wholesale price w W over w D in order to help coordinate retail prices. The same effect applies here, but with its advertising support, the manufacturer can transfer demand to the weaker channel, which is the high-margin channel. Equilibrium variables in the strategic response model are denoted with * and expressed in Proposition 2.</p><p>Proposition 2. Under Assumptions 1 and 2, the strategic response in equilibrium is characterized as follows.</p><p>1. The manufacturer chooses k * &gt; 0 in support of the weak retailer:</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">k * = w * W − w D 12t 2 = 3 t 24t − 2 2</formula><p>2. The manufacturer charges the weak retailer a wholesale price, which is higher than in the pricing response model:</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">w * W = 3t 2 + √ k * 2 + w D = 36t 2 24t − 2 + w D &gt; w W 3. Retail prices are: p * W = 48t 24t − 2 t + w D &gt;p W and p * D = 36t − 2 2 24t − 2 t + w D &lt;p D</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Retailer and manufacturer profits are:</head><formula xml:id="formula_17">* W = 2t 6t 24t − 2 2 * D = 2t 18t − 2 24t − 2 2 and * m =</formula><p>9t 2 24t − 2 + w D Part 1 of Proposition 2 states that, in equilibrium, the manufacturer will aid the weak retailer by shifting demand in its favor (k * &gt; 0 , as just discussed. The second part of the proposition says that the manufacturer will claim the additional channel profits brought forth by her investment in k through an increase in wholesale price w W . Finally, part 3 of Proposition 2 shows that the consequent shift in market share from the dominant retailer to the weak one results in an increase in p W and a decrease in p D . 12 Hence, the price <ref type="bibr">12</ref> Note that, in equilibrium, the weak retailer's market share is greater than that of the dominant retailer for high values of the advertising sensitivity parameter. However, in most of the allowable parameter space (as restricted by Assumption 2), this does not occur. Specifically, the dominant retailer has more demand (for 12t &gt; 2 in this range. Note also that given our notion of dominance (see §2.1), the dominant retailer is dominant not because of the resultant market share. Rather, we assume the dominant retailer has ex ante channel power-it has this power before the product is actually sold. differential between retailers increases as a result of manufacturer advertising.</p><p>It can be directly verified that * m &gt; m . Thus, profits of the manufacturer are higher in the strategic response model because the manufacturer has more strategic degrees of freedom. The implication is that manufacturers with the ability to influence consumer retailer choice have an opportunity to respond to a dominant retailer. And, in order to capitalize on this effect, the manufacturer must raise its wholesale price to the weak retailer. It can also be further verified that * W &gt; W and * D &lt; D . The manufacturer, by aiding the weak retailer through advertising, shifts profits from the dominant to the weak retail channel. These additional channel profits are then shared between the weak retailer and manufacturer. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> From Proposition 2, we observe that the dominant retailer's price is lower compared to that of the weak retailer. 14 This characteristic closely depicts dominant retailers like Wal-Mart, which are famous for their low prices and high profits. <ref type="bibr">15</ref> We emphasize here that the observed lower prices of dominant retailers are not necessarily due to their operational efficiencies (we assume marginal retailing costs of the retailers are equal to each other so far); as we show in both the pricing response and strategic response models, these retailers' low prices may emerge solely as a result of their power in marketing channels.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Properties of Strategic Manufacturer Response</head><p>The analytical model presented in the previous section illustrates the basic principle behind the strategic manufacturer response: When faced with a dominant retailer who dictates wholesale terms, a manufacturer can strategically react by raising margins in competing channels and transferring demand from the dominant to the weaker channels. In this section, we explore some of the properties of the model to <ref type="bibr">13</ref> Note that our strategic manufacturer response is similar in spirit to <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Liu and Zhang's (2006)</ref> direct selling and personalized pricing. They show that direct selling and personalized pricing favor manufacturers at the expense of retailers, and thus can help manufacturers to regain leverage lost to retailers. While <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Liu and Zhang's (2006)</ref> study focuses on a dyadic channel with one manufacturer and one retailer, our research examines an asymmetric channel in which one retailer has the power to dictate the wholesale price to the manufacturer, but the other retailer does not have such power.</p><p>see how the manufacturer's incentives change with respect to changes in the industrial environment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Retailer Loyalty and Advertising Sensitivity</head><p>In this section, we investigate the impact of retail loyalty and advertising sensitivity parameters on strategic manufacturer response, as defined in the previous section. We ask, for example, if strategic manufacturer response would be more effective if consumers are more loyal to one retailer, and how this might relate to the sensitivity of manufacturer advertising.</p><p>To investigate the this issue, we appeal to Proposition 2 and examine the comparative statics of the equilibrium outcome with respect to the parameters t and . A large value of t can be interpreted as a case in which consumers are relatively loyal to a particular retailer. This might be due to location, customer service, or some idiosyncratic characteristics of the retail stores. It can be shown that advertising spending increases with a decrease in the loyalty parameter t. When the consumers are less loyal to the retailers, because advertising is more effective in transferring demand, the manufacturer has more incentive to spend on advertising. Thus, when loyalty to the retailers is low, the manufacturer spends more on advertising and transfers more demand to the high-margin (weak retailer) channel.</p><p>The loyalty parameter has two opposing effects on wholesale price w W . First, as consumers become more loyal to the retailers, the weak retailer's demand loss-due to a higher price-decreases. Hence, the manufacturer is able to increase w W without significant loss of the weak retailer's market share. Second, as consumers' loyalty to the retailers increases, manufacturer advertising becomes relatively less effective in transferring demand to the weak retailer. Thus, the manufacturer is not able to compensate for lost demand due to the higher weak retailer wholesale price-via advertising-when loyalty to the retailers is high. The high degree of loyalty to the retailers causes the manufacturer to lose its flexibility to raise w W without hurting the weak retailer demand. When 12t &gt; 2 , the first mentioned loyalty effect dominates, and w W is increasing in t. Otherwise, when 18t &gt; 2 &gt; 12t, w W is decreasing in t.</p><p>A similar intuition applies to the sensitivity parameter . A low value of corresponds, for instance, to a setting where consumers are not responsive to the manufacturer's advertising and joint promotions. The strategic manufacturer response suffers as a result. The following corollary summarizes these results.</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">Corollary 1. If 18t &gt; 2 &gt; 12t, then k * t w * W t &lt; 0 &lt; k * w * W and if 12t &gt; 2 , then k * t &lt; 0 &lt; k * w * W t w * W</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Differences in Retail Costs</head><p>The second property we investigate concerns asymmetric cost differences between the two retailers.</p><p>A manufacturer might recognize that the dominant retailer not only has the advantage in setting channel terms, but also has significant cost advantages over the weak retailer. In this case, a manufacturer might ask: How does this cost advantage affect the efficacy of the strategic response derived above? Indeed, some dominant retailers are famous for their operating efficiencies. For example, according to Business Week, Wal-Mart holds its operating and selling expenses to 15% of sales, versus 28% for Sears, Roebuck &amp; Co <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Schiller et al. 1992</ref>).</p><p>To examine how strategic manufacturer response is affected by the presence of a cost advantage in favor of the dominant retailer, we specify nonzero retailing costs c W , c D . Furthermore, we allow for the possibility that the dominant retailer might enjoy an advantage. Specifically, we assume c W &gt; c D ≥ 0. The retailers' pricing decision is then to maximize</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">i = p i − w i − c i q i p W p D k i = D W</formula><p>We further assume that the cost difference c W − c D is not very large, because a large cost difference may result in consumer prices that encourage all the consumers to buy from the dominant retailer. Formally, this assumption takes the following form:</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">Assumption 3. 3t &gt; c W − c D .</formula><p>This assumption guarantees nondegenerate demands (0 &lt; q W &lt; 1 and 0 &lt; q D &lt; 1 , and the profit maximization problem has an interior solution.</p><p>Recall that the dominant retailer's ability to dictate price w D endows it with a lower wholesale price than that of its rival. The dominant retailer was then able to set the price more competitively, p D &lt; p W , which resulted in a larger market share. With an additional cost advantage, this market share is even more lopsided in favor of the dominant retailer:</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">q D − q W = 1 3t w W − w D + c W − c D − A k</formula><p>(See the appendix for more details.) The manufacturer is less inclined to invest in the strategic response now that the weak retailer is less competitive, and therefore it is more difficult to get consumers to switch to the higher-priced retailer.</p><p>Proposition 3. Under Assumptions 1-3, when retailers face marginal costs c W &gt; c D ≥ 0, the strategic manufacturer response is less effective. That is, the equilibrium </p><formula xml:id="formula_22">response k * = w * W − w D 12t 2 = 3 t − c W − c D 24t − 2 2 w * W = 12t 3t − c W − c D 24t − 2 + w D is decreasing in c W − c D .</formula><p>There are two important implications of this proposition. The first is that some degree of strategic response remains profitable for the manufacturer despite the cost asymmetry. However, the manufacturer's return is diminished when a cost advantage exists.</p><p>Second, note that it is the cost difference only, rather than the presence of positive marginal costs, that drives this detrimental result. Therefore, industrywide cost factors will not alter the incentives for strategic manufacturer response. For example, if trucking cost increases, thereby affecting all retailers equally, then the strategic manufacturer response remains as effective as before the cost increase.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Incorporating Benefits to the Manufacturer</head><p>When Working with the Dominant Retailer As mentioned in the introduction, potential benefits for manufacturers may arise when dealing with dominants retailers if there are scale economies in transaction costs. Also, the dominant retailers' information systems, such as Wal-Mart's Retail Link, can make manufacturers more efficient. These cost savings may offset the benefits of the strategic manufacturer response of §2.2, if sufficiently large. In this section, we briefly evaluate the impact of these cost savings on the incentive for strategic manufacturer response.</p><p>Suppose that when dealing with the dominant retailer D, the manufacturer obtains a cost savings of s per unit sold. It is not necessary to assume that there are no cost savings when dealing with the weak retailer W . Rather, s &gt; 0 represents a net savings across the two retailers. If s is sufficiently large, then the manufacturer would prefer to deal exclusively with the dominant retailer. Hence, we shall place bounds on the transaction cost savings: 3t &gt; s &gt; 0. Represented this way, s is saved for each unit sold to D, so that the manufacturer's profits can be written as</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">m = w D + s q D + w W q W − k</formula><p>where q D and q W are given in (7). This modification to the model does not alter the retailers' price reactions as functions of wholesale price w W and advertising support k relative to the case in §2.2. Using these reaction functions, the equilibrium can be derived directly by maximizing m above with respect to w W and k. This leads to the outcome in the following proposition.</p><p>Proposition 4. Suppose the manufacturer accrues a net marginal benefit s &gt; 0 from transacting with the dominant retailer. Under Assumptions 1 and 2, if 3t &gt; s, then the manufacturer's optimal strategic response is characterized as follows.</p><p>(i) Advertising support</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">k * = 3 t − s 24t − 2 2 &gt; 0 is decreasing in s.</formula><p>(ii) Wholesale price</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">w * W = 36t 2 + 12t − 2 s 24t − 2 + w D is increasing in s.</formula><p>It is worthwhile to point out that if s ↓ 0 we get the basic result in Proposition 2. To see the intuition for Proposition 4, recall that in the original model, with s = 0, the manufacturer wants to shift demand to the weak channel where the margin is large. However, with s &gt; 0, there is an opportunity cost of shifting demand away from the dominant retailer. The manufacturer thus balances this trade-off by reducing k (the amount it spends to provide support to the weak retailer). In addition, the manufacturer raises wholesale price w * W when transaction cost savings are present. This forces the weak retailer to react with a higher retailer price, thereby pushing more units through the dominant retailer, which generates the transaction cost savings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Detecting the Source of Competitive Advantage</head><p>It is debatable whether dominant retailers' low consumer prices are attributable to their ability to dictate wholesale prices to the manufacturers. In simplistic terms, for example, a purely efficiency view would suggest that retailing efficiencies singularly enable these retailers to keep costs low. Alternatively, a channel power view admits that costs may also be held in check by hard-nosed bargaining with manufacturers. By marginally modifying the notion of dominance in the previous models, we can derive a testable hypothesis to determine whether a tough stance with suppliers contributes to dominant retailers' competitive advantage. Specifically, we contrast equilibrium outcomes in two related models, one with a dominant retailer who can dictate favorable wholesale terms and one without. We will see that simply by modifying only this assumption, the models lead to distinct differences in the form of the strategic manufacturer response.</p><p>To derive this test, we require two related models with the following properties. Both models should yield equilibrium outcomes, with the dominant retailer pricing more competitively then the weak retailer. However, the models should differ with respect to the source of the dominant retailer's ability to keep its costs low. In the model representing the channel power view, the dominant retailer has the ability to dictate favorable wholesale terms with the manufacturer (i.e., low wholesale price w D ). The retailers may otherwise have identical retailing costs (i.e., c W = c D ), or the dominant retailer may have a cost advantage (c D &lt; c W ).</p><p>The efficiency view, alternatively, is represented by a model in which the dominant retailer has a certain cost advantage (i.e., c D &lt; c W ), but is otherwise unable to control wholesale terms. In this case, the manufacturer freely chooses a wholesale price. As we show below, the two models yield different outcomes with respect to advertising support for the weak retailer. By making empirical observations regarding advertising support to the weak retailer, one can deduce which modeling assumption generates the observed outcome.</p><p>The channel power (CP) view corresponds to the models discussed in §2.2 (when c W = c D ) and in §3.2 (when c W &gt; c D ). In these models, we assume that the dominant retailer dictates wholesale price w D . The consequence of this assumption is that the manufacturer aids the weak retailer through its advertising support (i.e., k CP &gt; 0) and charges the weak retailer a higher wholesale price (i.e., w CP W − w D &gt; 0). To accommodate the model for the efficiency E view, we suppose that the dominant retailer has lower costs, as in §3.2, but can no longer dictate wholesale terms. That is, suppose that c W − c D &gt; 0 and that the wholesale price w is chosen optimally by the manufacturer. <ref type="bibr">16</ref> Otherwise, all agents and their decisions are as in the model of §2.2. The corresponding objective for the manufacturer is max</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">w k w q D + q W − k subject to q D = 1 2 − A k 6t + c W − c D 6t and q W = 1 2 + A k 6t − c W − c D 6t</formula><p>Recall from the analysis in §2.2 that the manufacturer's incentive to use cooperative advertising allowances is strictly to shift demand toward its preferred channel. However, when the manufacturer <ref type="bibr">16</ref> It might be suggested to allow the manufacturer to price discriminate between the two retailers in the efficiency view. Recall, however, that our intention in this setting is to remove the ability of a retailer to elicit favorable wholesale terms from the manufacturer. In fact, in a scenario with different retail costs, it is the inefficient retailer who obtains a lower wholesale cost than the dominant one. Moreover, the efficient retailer would set higher retail prices (for all 2 &gt; 18t/7 , which violates a condition for our test, namely p D &lt; p W . sets a uniform wholesale price, it is indifferent between the channels and therefore optimally avoids exclusive ad support to either retailer: k E = 0. <ref type="bibr">17</ref> In addition, it can be readily confirmed that in this efficiency view setting, the dominant retailer sets its price lower than that of the weak retailer:</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">p E W − p E D = 1</formula><p>9 c W − c D &gt; 0 Thus, the equilibrium ordering of retail prices for the efficiency view is consistent with that of the channel power view. A comparison of these two models is given in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref>.</p><p>To summarize, the efficiency view interpretation of the model implies that the manufacturer provides no advertising support for the weak retailer. In contrast, the channel power interpretation of the model ( §2.2) suggests advertising support for the weak retailer while favoring the dominant retailer in wholesale price. Thus, if it is empirically observed that manufacturers provide exclusive support for weak retailers, then our results imply that the dominant retailers' power in bargaining with suppliers is a contributing factor to their low prices. Otherwise, if manufacturers do not offer exclusive assistance to weak retailers, then the dominant retailers' low prices are likely not a consequence of their ability to induce favorable wholesale prices from their suppliers. It is important to note that we do not claim that this testable hypothesis can be used to detect the sole factor in explaining dominant retailers' low prices. More succinctly, rather, our test can be used to determine whether the ability to induce wholesale price discrimination is a part of the explanation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Extensions and Robustness</head><p>The results of the previous sections rely on the following two modeling assumptions.</p><p>1. Wholesale price w D is not strategically chosen.</p><p>2. Total demand is fixed (e.g., q D + q W = 1 .</p><p>These were invoked in order to convey the main aspects of the strategic manufacturer response. To get a sense of the general conditions under which our results hold, we consider in this section the implications when relaxing them. We illustrate, in particular, that our results are qualitatively robust to the relaxation of these assumptions. To do so, we consider a model in which total demand is not fixed and the dominant retailer chooses the wholesale price w D strategically.</p><p>It is instructive to note that under the original consumer choice model any wholesale price w D is optimal for the dominant retailer. The reason can be seen by examining the profit expressions for the dominant retailer, given in Propositions 1 and 2. None of the objectives are functions of the dominant retailer wholesale price w D . This is an artifact of the demand functions implied by our consumer choice specification. For the derived demand functions of §2, a unit increase in the dominant retailer wholesale price w D results in an equal unit increase in both the dominant retailer consumer price p D and the weak retailer's price p W . Consequently, the dominant retailer is indifferent to changes in the wholesale price because neither its margin nor its demand depends on w D . Obviously, such a consequence is unlikely to hold for specifications in which total demand is not fixed. Therefore, in this section we consider nonfixed demand when determining the dominant retailer's strategic choice of w D .</p><p>By a nonfixed demand specification, we simply mean that consumers have an outside alternative to the two retailers. Therefore, consumers may enter or leave the market for the manufacturer's product depending on retail prices. We implement this consumer model in reduced form using the following linear demand functions</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">q W = − p W + p D + A k (9) q D = − p D + p W − A k (10)</formula><p>where A k is the advertising component defined as in §2.2 and &gt; 0, 0 &lt; &lt; 1.</p><p>As before, the manufacturer can help either retailer via advertising. Again, k ∈ − + denotes the manufacturer's investment choice with k &gt; 0 encouraging shoppers to choose the weak retailer, and k &lt; 0 encouraging shoppers to choose the dominant retailer. We assume that the advertising parameter entering in A is not so large that the manufacturer does not wish to advertise so much as to send all consumers to one of the retailers.</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">Assumption 4. 2 2 + / 2 − &gt; 2 .</formula><p>We also assume that the retailers' marginal costs of retailing and the manufacturer's marginal cost of production is zero. Fixed costs for all firms are again set to zero, without loss of generality. The game is played in three stages. First, the dominant retailer selects the wholesale price. Then the manufacturer chooses the wholesale price for the weak retailer and its advertising (which retailer to help and how much), given the dominant retailer's wholesale price. Finally, given wholesale prices w D and w W , each retailer simultaneously chooses its price:</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">p * i w D w W = arg max p p i − w i q i i = D W</formula><p>where q i are given in ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula">10</ref>).</p><p>In Stage 2, the manufacturer chooses the wholesale price w W and its advertising k in order to maximize profit, which is expressed by ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_13">8</ref>) and incorporates Stage 3 responses in retail prices. The solution to the manufacturer's Stage 2 optimization yields the wholesale price and advertising spending as functions of w D (details are provided in the appendix):</p><formula xml:id="formula_31">w W w D = 2 + + 2 w D + 2 − √ k 2 2 − 2 = 2 2+ 2 + 4 2+ − 2 2− w D 4 2+ 2− 2 − 2 2− (11) k w D = 2 w W − w D 2 4 2 + 2 = 2 2 + 2 − 2 1 − w D 2 4 2 + 2 − 2 − 2 2 − 2 (12)</formula><p>From ( <ref type="formula">11</ref>) we observe that regardless of the dominant retailer's choice of w D , the optimal response of the manufacturer yields that w W w D &gt; w D for w D ≥ 0. Thus, as in the case with Hotelling demand functions, the manufacturer claims the additional channel profits brought forth by her investment in k &gt; 0 through an increase wholesale price w W . This is consistent with the results in Propositions 1 and 2 in that the manufacturer charges a higher wholesale price for the weak retailer than for the dominant one. This result holds, in particular, for the dominant retailer's optimal choice w * D . Proposition 5. Consider a modified extension of the game from §2 in which (i) the dominant retailer chooses an observable wholesale price w D before the manufacturer moves; and</p><p>(ii) consumer demand at each retailer is given by ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) and (10). Then, under Assumption 4, the unique equilibrium outcome has k * &gt; 0 and w * W &gt; w * D = 0 In Stage 1, the dominant retailer incorporates the third-stage pricing rules as well as the secondstage manufacturer's responses ( <ref type="formula">11</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula">12</ref>) in its wholesale price decision. It can be seen that the dominant retailer's profit is a decreasing function of the wholesale price it dictates to the manufacturer ( D / w D &lt; 0). Thus, in equilibrium the dominant retailer chooses a wholesale price that is equal to zero (the marginal cost of the manufacturer). Obviously, an incentive to lower wholesale price for the dominant retailer is to reduce its costs. Recall also the incentive to keep wholesale price high to facilitate price coordination at the retail level. However, because demand is not fixed, lowering w D creates the additional benefit of increasing total demand. <ref type="bibr">18</ref> From this result, we conclude that when endogenizing the dominant retailer's wholesale price and incorporating nonfixed demand, the strategic manufacturer response remains characterized by advertising that aids the weak retailer (k * &gt; 0 and a higher wholesale price for the weak retailer (w * W &gt; w * D ). 19 20</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusion</head><p>The issue of channel conflict and the question of power within the channel are not new. The growth of the grocer the Atlantic &amp; Pacific Tea Company (A&amp;P) in the early 20th century, for example, caused concern among competitors (as well as antitrust authorities) because of its unprecedented dominance and growth in the grocery industry. Later, in the 60s, the growth of the department store format, and recently the power-retailer phenomenon, has further provoked this question. We have proposed a modeling framework that provides insights about channel relations in an asymmetric retail setting. In our model, the dominant retailer has power over the manufacturer, while the weak retailer does not. The analysis suggests that the manufacturer can respond strategically to the dominant retailer's pricing pressures by raising the wholesale price for the weak retailer over that for the dominant retailer, while simultaneously transferring demand to the high-margin (weak retailer) channel via advertising. We find that the benefit to the manufacturer from this strategic response increases from either an increase in customers' sensitivity to advertising or from <ref type="bibr">18</ref> Anecdotes from the trade press are consistent with our result of such low wholesale prices dictated by the dominant retailer. For example, as mentioned before, 100 auto parts retailers claimed that category killers including Wal-Mart and Pep Boys purchase auto parts from suppliers at prices 40% less than those of other retailers <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Balto 2002)</ref>. "They take your guts out to get the best price says a small toymaker of Wal-Mart" <ref type="bibr">(Schiller et al. 1992, p. 2)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">19</ref> We also conducted the same analysis for the manufacturer's pricing response and differential costs of the retailers. Our analysis showed that the manufacturer's strategic response when the retailers have asymmetric costs is robust to the exogenous dominant retailer wholesale price and fixed total demand assumptions. Please contact the authors for details. <ref type="bibr">20</ref> The results of §4 are also robust to this modeling extension. a decrease in the differentiation between the retailers. Both have the effect of making the strategic manufacturer response marginally more effective with respect to the manufacturer's investment in joint advertising. <ref type="bibr">21</ref> The analysis also shows that an increase in the cost asymmetry between the retailers reduces the effectiveness of the strategic manufacturer response. Higher retailing costs for the weak retailer prevent it from pricing competitively against the dominant one. The lower market share that results erodes the incentive for investment in strategic manufacturer response.</p><p>Our analysis also suggests that a contributing factor to a dominant retailer's cost advantage might be its ability to induce favorable wholesale terms from their suppliers. Even if retailers such as Wal-Mart benefit from operational efficiencies, their raw ability to dictate supply prices can be an additional factor in achieving low costs. We compared two models that differ only with respect to whether the dominant retailer has this ability. These two models led to different equilibrium predictions regarding the strategic manufacturer response. Thus, our analysis offers a testable hypothesis that can be used to determine whether dominant retailers' hard-nosed tactics vis-à-vis their suppliers play a role in explaining their competitive prices.</p><p>It is important to point out that the manufacturer's strategic response involves setting different prices to retailers, which may raise legal concerns. <ref type="bibr">22</ref> Specifically, there is a potential violation of the law when a supplier price discriminates to competing retailers. We stress, therefore, that the intent of our research is to understand the incentives behind marketing phenomena and derive a testable hypothesis regarding the source of dominant retailers' competitive advantage in the market place rather than to advocate legally questionable behavior.</p><p>Our analysis points to new questions about channel strategy in the presence of a dominant retailer. Of particular interest is how channel members handle private information, such as demand conditions, cost parameters, or promotional activities. The channel management literature examined various incentives for sharing and withholding information within and across the channel <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Chu and Messinger 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, Gu and Chen 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">, Li 2002</ref>. Still unexplored, however, is how these incentives change when one retailer carries significantly more channel power than other channel members. In an earlier version of this paper, we examined the implication when the dominant retailer has Marketing Science 26(2), pp. 164-178, © 2007 INFORMS sole possession of information regarding the advertising sensitivities of their customers (parameter in our model). By not obtaining this information, the manufacturer faces uncertain demand and is unable to as effectively implement its strategic response.</p><p>Other important questions remain, however. For example, suppose that the manufacturer, through its market research, has knowledge of consumer preferences for its product. The manufacturer might ask whether this information should be shared and, if so, with whom. In the presence of a dominant retailer, the manufacturer may have incentives to share this information only with select channel members. We hope to address these issues in future research efforts.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Arrangement of Agents</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Test to Detect Source of Dominant Retailers' Ability to Set Low Prices</figDesc><table><row><cell>View</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Channel power</cell><cell>Efficiency</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">We thank an anonymous reviewer for suggesting to us these benefits that dominant retailers provide to their suppliers.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Wal-Mart is leading the charge to eventually eradicate EDI in favor of an Internet-based XML product. While EDI demands that each retailer/supplier relationship utilize individualized technology products, Internet-based XML is faster, easier, and can be used with multiple trading partners. Wal-Mart is also experimenting with scan-based trading. This technology makes it possible for inventory to remain the property of Wal-Mart's vendors until the product is actually sold<ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Stankevich 2003)</ref>.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">Because our focus concerns manufacturer behavior, we do not model the determination of w D in the model discussed here. Our results are general in that they hold for all values w D ≥ 0. However, as we illustrate in §5, incorporating the full control of wholesale price to the retailer does not qualitatively alter our results.7  The reader should not interpret our model as a one-for-one match with the Wal-Mart case. We do not intend to model any specific dominant retailer, but rather we aim to derive a testable hypothesis that will suggest which modeling assumption (channel power versus cost efficiency) generates the observed outcome (dominant retailers' low retail prices).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8">The demand specification in our model assumes a fixed set of consumers. As we show in §5, this is not necessary for our results.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">Note that such coordination of retail prices by a manufacturer through take-it-or-leave-it pricing is previously well established in the marketing literature<ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(McGuire and Staelin 1983</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">, Coughlan 1985</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">, Moorthy 1988</ref>).10  If the dominant retailer possessed some additional retailing cost efficiencies relative to its rival retailer, then the dominant retailer's market share would be even greater. For expositional clarity, we have equated retailers' marginal costs. In §3.2, we discuss the implication of asymmetric costs.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="11">In reality, of course, manufacturers may aid both retailers to some degree. However, because our focus is on joint marketing activities that are preferential, we model k as the amount devoted to exclusive aid to one of the two retailers. In fact, in this fixed total demand model, the manufacturer would not have any incentive to engage in positive marketing activities for both retailers simultaneously, because total quantity is fixed and any increase in willingness to pay v is competed away in a Hotelling model, i.e., retail prices do not depend upon v.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="14">This result is similar to that of<ref type="bibr" target="#b20">He and Chen (2006)</ref>. They find that in an e-marketplace with symmetric online stores offering competing products, the featured store on average has a higher price. In our study, however, we dismiss symmetry of retailers in order to understand the impact of asymmetric retail dominance.15  According to a price survey of 215 items in 2002, prices at other retailers were, on the average, 35%-38% higher than those at Wal-Mart in the Dallas market<ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Taylor 2003)</ref>.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="17">Although not used in the subsequent discussion, the corresponding optimal uniform wholesale price is w E = v − 3t/2 + c W − 3c D /6.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="21">An exception is the effect of differentiation when 12t &gt; 2 ; please refer to §3.1.22  The relevant laws are the Robinson-Patman Act in the United States and the Treaty of Rome, Article 82(c), in the European Union.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors acknowledge the valuable comments of the editor, the area editor, anonymous reviewers, and Esther Gal-Or.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix</head><p>Proof of Proposition 1. The result follows by maximizing the profit expression (5), using Stage 1 pricing functions (4). The second-order condition for the maximization is satisfied at w W because</p><p>Proof of Proposition 2. To derive the equilibrium outcome, we start with the consumer's decision given retail prices p W , p D , then determine the retailers' optimal prices, and finally derive the manufacturer's Stage 1 choices of w W and k. The indifferent consumer is located atx such that</p><p>Then q D =x and q W = 1 −x. Retailer i sets retail price p i = arg max p pq i , which leads to</p><p>The subsequent channel quantities are given by ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>). The manufacturer's optimal choice, w * W k * , maximizes (8), and must satisfy</p><p>which follow from the first-order conditions for maximization. First assume k &gt; 0. Using A k = /2 k −1/2 , one obtains the expressions for w * W and k * given in the proposition. This is the maximization if the leading principle minors of</p><p>* alternate in sign, starting with negative. The first leading principle minor is readily verified as negative at w * W k * . The second leading principle minor, expressed as</p><p>is positive at w * W k * if and only if 2 &lt; 24t, which holds under the condition of Assumption 2. The above analysis assumed that k &gt; 0. If k &lt; 0, the same analysis leads to a positive sign for 2 m . Hence, we conclude the stated maximizer w * W k * constitutes the unique equilibrium choice of the manufacturer. Substitution of the expressions for w * W and k * into (A1) gives the expressions for equilibrium retail prices as stated in the proposition. The equilibrium profits of the manufacturer are derived using ( <ref type="formula">8</ref>), and of the retailers using</p><p>Proof of Corollary 1. Differentiating the expressions for w * W and k * as given in Proposition 2 with respect to t and gives the stated result.</p><p>Proof of Proposition 3. The previous analysis of the retailers' choice of price that can be applied here using the retailers total marginal cost is w i + c i , instead of w i . This leads to channel quantities expressed by</p><p>The manufacturer's problem is to maximize (8) subject to (A2). Assuming k &gt; 0, k * and w * W , as defined in the proposition, solve the following first-order conditions,</p><p>Because it follows from an argument analogous to that in the proof of Proposition 2, we omit the details that show that w * W k * is the unique maximum. Q.E.D. Proof of Proposition 4. Use the previous analysis of the retailers' choice of price as given in (A1). Then, solve the manufacturer's problem of choosing w W and k using w D + s instead of w D in the manufacturer's objective function. Deriving the stated results is analogous to the derivation used in Proposition 2, and is thus omitted. Q.E.D.</p><p>Proof of Proposition 5. Retailers' optimal pricing in Stage 3, as a function of wholesale prices w D and w W , is then given by</p><p>where i = D W and i = −i. Substituting these best response functions into Equations ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) and (10), we can express the manufacturer's objective m w W k w D and derive the following first-order conditions with respect to its choice of w W and k: </p><p>The first leading principle minor is readily verified as negative. The second leading principle minor, expressed as</p><p>which is positive at the solution of the first-order conditions given by ( <ref type="formula">11</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula">12</ref>) provided the following two conditions hold:</p><p>The concavity condition (A7) is implied by Assumption 4, and it will be shown that (A6) holds in equilibrium. The above analysis assumed that k &gt; 0. If k ≤ 0, the same analysis leads to a negative sign for 2 m . Hence, the expressions in ( <ref type="formula">11</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula">12</ref>) are unique maximizers of the manufacturer's problem under the conditions (A6) and (A7).</p><p>Note that</p><p>The denominator is positive by (A7) and the numerator is positive under (A6). Hence, (A7) and (A6) are sufficient for w W &gt; w D . The remainder of the proof is establishes that the optimal wholesale price chosen in the first stage by the dominant retailer is w * D = 0. The dominant retailer chooses its retail price w D ≥ 0 to maximize its profits:</p><p>subject to (A3), (11), and (12). The first-order derivative, after substitution, is expressed as</p><p>where</p><p>In order to establish that w * D = 0, we show that the derivative in (A8) is negative for w D ≥ 0. From the above expression, we have that p D − w D &gt; 0 and q D &gt; 0 under the conditions &gt; w D and 2 &lt; 2 2 + / 2 − , which are implied by (A6) and Assumption 4, respectively. The denominator in (A8) is positive under (A.11), which, recall, is implied by Assumption 4. The numerator of the fractional expression of (A8) is less than zero if and only if</p><p>However, (A9) holds under Assumption 4, which can be seen as follows. The difference</p><p>can be rewritten as</p><p>which is readily observed as being greater than zero given &gt; 0. Therefore, Assumption 4 is stricter than (A9). Hence, we conclude that d D /dw D &lt; 0. Therefore, w * D = 0 is the equilibrium as long as the concavity condition (A6) holds, but this last condition is automatically satisfied because &gt; 2w * D = 0. Q.E.D.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effect of brand loyalty on advertising and trade promotions: A game theoretic analysis with empirical evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="86" to="108" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recent legal and regulatory developments in slotting allowances and category management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Balto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Public Policy Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="289" to="294" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reputation in marketing channels. Repeated-transactions bargaining with two sided uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Banks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Hutchinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="272" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is Wal-Mart too powerful?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bianco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Zellner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Diane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>France</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lowry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Byrnes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Zegel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Arndt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Berner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Therese</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bus. Week</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="100" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="2003-10-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributor power versus manufacturer power: The customer role</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Bradley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ghemawat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">;</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Butaney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Wortzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="52" to="63" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<publisher>HBS Publishing</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Wal-Mart Stores, Inc. Harvard Business School Case 9-794-024</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Not everyone buys Tesco&apos;s strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Carney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bus. Week Online</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004-12-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Price competition in a channel structure with a common retailer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="110" to="129" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">One-stop status</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ed</forename><surname>Christman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Billboard</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="86" to="89" />
			<date type="published" when="2002-03-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Indie retailers sue Best Buy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ed</forename><surname>Christman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Billboard</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2003-08-23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Channel coordination mechanisms for customer satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Desai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="343" to="359" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information and channel profits</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Messinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Retailing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="487" to="499" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competition and cooperation in marketing channel choice: Theory and application</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Coughlan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="110" to="129" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Channel bargaining with retailer asymmetry</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dukes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gal-Or</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="84" to="97" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Retailing in the USA: An interpretation of current trends</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dunne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Retail Distribution Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8/9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="164" to="178" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Caught in the squeeze</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Facenda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Retail Merchandiser</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-channel aid for indies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Billboard</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">36</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996-12-14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Home Depot&apos;s remodeling project</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Foust</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bus. Week Online</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collaborative marketing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Fusaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Dairy Foods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">101</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bargaining and information sharing in distribution channels. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Gu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<pubPlace>Stern School, New York University; New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing e-marketplace: A strategic analysis of nonprice advertising</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="187" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A bargaining theory of distribution channels</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Iyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="100" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Villas-Boas</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing channel profits</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Jeuland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="272" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manufacturerretailer channel interactions and implications for channel power</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kadiyali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Vilcassim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="148" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manufacturer allowances and retailer pass-through rates in a competitive environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Staelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="76" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surplus of home improvement stores make Indianapolis handyman heaven</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="s">Knight Ridder Tribune Bus. News</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003-06-23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wal-Mart vs. inflation: The discounter forces prices down</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Koretz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bus. Week</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">32</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002-05-13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The inverse relationship between manufacturer and retailer margins: A theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Lal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Narasimhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="132" to="151" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vertical strategic interaction: Implications for channel pricing strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Staelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="185" to="207" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information sharing in a supply chain with horizontal competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1196" to="1212" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The benefits of personalized pricing in a channel</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How to beat Wal-Mart</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="108" to="114" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The co-marketing revolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Marx</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Industry Week (October</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="80" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The power of two</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Marx</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="36" to="39" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An industry equilibrium analysis of downstream vertical integration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Mcguire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Staelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="191" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Has power shifted in the grocery channel</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Messinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Narasimhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="189" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategic decentralization channels</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Moorthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="335" to="355" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The use and abuse of power in supply chains</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Munson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Rosenblatt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bus. Horizons</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wal-Marketing: How to benefit in Bentonville</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Neff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advertising Age</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-10-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dual distribution channels. The competition between rental agencies and dealers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Purohit</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="228" to="245" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Channel coordination in the presence of a dominant retailer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Raju</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="254" to="262" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Schiller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Zellner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Stoghill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Maremont</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Clout. Bus. Week Online</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992-12-21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">War of the superstores: Wal-Mart is trouncing the locals, but they&apos;re not giving up</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bus. Week</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">60</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002-09-23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wal-Mart chips away at new systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Stankevich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Retail Merchandiser</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="37" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Top of mind; saving America&apos;s grocers. Brandweek</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Plain Dealer. 1995. Co-marketing doubles impact of commercials</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">2C</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">One nation under Wal-Mart</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Useem</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Fortune</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="2003-03-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Kodak crafts logo for chain of stores</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wilke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advertising Age</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997-08-25" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
