<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Editorial-Introduction to the Special Classics Issue</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
							<email>steven.shugan@cba.ufl.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Warrington College of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Florida</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>32611</postCode>
									<settlement>Gainesville</settlement>
									<region>Florida</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Warrington College of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Florida</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>32611</postCode>
									<settlement>Gainesville</settlement>
									<region>Florida</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Editorial-Introduction to the Special Classics Issue</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 08 2701 0009</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1070.0343</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-13T12:15+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>classic articles</term>
					<term>greatest hits</term>
					<term>most-cited articles</term>
					<term>highest impact</term>
					<term>mental accounting</term>
					<term>scanner data</term>
					<term>channel strategy</term>
					<term>defensive strategy</term>
					<term>transaction cost analysis</term>
					<term>competitive channel strategy</term>
					<term>return policies</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction for This Special Issue</head><p>The Special Classics Issue of Marketing Science represents another milestone. Marketing Science has experienced incredible growth and development in the last 26 years since John D.C. Little and Frank M. Bass founded Marketing Science. Under Donald G. Morrison's leadership as the first editor, the journal attracted many path-breaking articles. That continued through the subsequent editorships of Subrata K. Sen, John R. Hauser, Richard Staelin, and Brian T. Ratchford. With this issue, my term as editor ends and Eric T. Bradlow becomes the new editor of Marketing Science. I am pleased to have such an impressive successor.</p><p>As my term ends, the Special Classics Issue accomplishes a final task. We had many high-impact articles appearing in Marketing Science's early years, before formal inclusion in the Social Science Citation Index (SSCI) and before many libraries began subscribing to Marketing Science. Despite their impact, our early articles often suffered the fate of many articles in nascent journals-the articles suffer limited availability and less than systematic treatment by SSCI. This special issue partially resolves that problem by reprinting some of our most impactful early articles. Of course, it is only possible to reprint a few.</p><p>This issue includes classic pre-1987 articles (in 1987 Marketing Science was formally included in SSCI).</p><p>These articles are currently the most heavily cited pre-1987 articles in SSCI, with some consideration of citations by Google Scholar. SSCI data are slightly more reliable because SSCI only includes scholarly SSCIapproved journals. Google Scholar includes more sources than SSCI, including citations by working papers, but only includes more recent citations. The final seven articles were: <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Thaler (1985)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Guadagni and Little (1983)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Jeuland and Shugan (1983)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Anderson (1985)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hauser and Shugan (1983)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">McGuire and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Staelin (1983), and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Pasternack (1985)</ref>.</p><p>Beyond increasing library accessibility, this issue also provides our classic articles in electronic format so that these classic articles will be formally included in many searchable electronic databases. Moreover, the electronic format will allow content searches. To provide value beyond accessibility, some authors of these classic articles have written updates for the last 22 years.</p><p>Finally, not to ignore other articles, a 2007 Google Scholar search indicates that the following articles (in order) are currently the all-time, most-cited articles in Marketing Science. Asterisks denote the articles in this issue. The following list of articles also includes a selected finding that I view as particularly insightful. Please see <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Shugan (2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Shugan ( , 2007</ref> for the most-cited articles in recent years, according to SSCI.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>10</head><p>Marketing Science 27(1), pp. 9-11, © 2008 INFORMS 1. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Thaler (1985)</ref> is a revolutionary article integrating transaction utility, reference points, and consumer's classifying information into separate accounts. The article shows that consumers behave as if their money were not perfectly fungible and consumers alter their consumption to mentally recover acquisition costs, so that assets accounted for in different currencies have their own mental accounts. * 2. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Anderson and Sullivan (1993)</ref> study the antecedents and consequences of customer satisfaction for firms. This article finds that disappointing quality (i.e., quality below expectations) has a greater impact on satisfaction and repurchase intentions than surprisingly high quality (i.e., quality above expectations). Moreover, these effects are exaggerated when quality is easier to evaluate.</p><p>3. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Anderson and Weitz (1989)</ref> integrated the concepts of satisfaction, trust, and relationships in a channel of distribution context. The article demonstrates that building a long-term relationship in a channel requires a marketing intermediary who expects the relationship to last. The article also demonstrates the importance of communication in establishing partnership, trust, and long-term relationships.</p><p>4. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Guadagni and Little (1983)</ref>. This pioneering article integrated scanner panel data, conditional multinomial logit analysis, buyer loyalty, household brand choice, and marketing control variables. The article develops a highly accurate predictive and parsimonious model of future consumer choice behavior from the variables: brand loyalty, size loyalty, presence/absence of store promotion, regular shelf price, and promotional price cuts. It also demonstrates the importance of detailed and complete household panel data for making predictions. * 5. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Griffin and Hauser (1993)</ref> analyze and evaluate the houses (i.e., mappings) of quality function deployment methods. The article finds, for example, that product concepts derived from direct consumer statements (e.g., stated importance) are better than those derived from estimated or inferred preferences. Moreover, company-collected satisfaction data suffer from self-selection bias.</p><p>6. <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Jeuland and Shugan (1983)</ref> show that channel demand depends on the decisions of all channel members, and without coordination, prices will be higher than optimal, quality will be less than optimal, and service support will be less than optimal. The article discusses many methods for solving the coordination problem, including how a quantity-discount schedule mitigates the problem. * 7. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Novak et al. (2000)</ref> identify factors that make using the Web a compelling experience. The article finds, for example, that the degree to which the online experience is compelling can be defined, measured, and related well to particular marketing variables.</p><p>The article provides a model that conceptualizes flow on the Web as a cognitive state experienced during navigation.</p><p>8. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bolton (1998)</ref> develops a dynamic model of the duration of the customer's relationship with a continuous service provider. The article finds a strong relationship between customer satisfaction and retention. The article finds that the past duration of a relationship and cumulative past satisfaction are critical variables for predicting future duration. Moreover, certain service encounters are more critical than others, and the loss function is asymmetric (poor service hurts more than great service helps).</p><p>9. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Anderson (1985)</ref> finds, using a transaction cost analysis, that employing salespeople (in contrast to using independent agents) is better when the difficulty of evaluating performance increases (e.g., more complex and hard-to-learn product lines, greater demand for nonselling activities). Empirical evidence supports the predictions of transaction cost theory.</p><p>10. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Pasternack (1985)</ref> develops pricing strategies for products with a limited shelf-life and shows that policies such as full credit for unsold goods or no credit for unsold goods are suboptimal while partial credit achieves channel coordination. * Finally, in terms of all-time citations per year, the top five articles are (in order):</p><p>• <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Novak et al. (2000)</ref> is previously listed.</p><p>• <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Anderson and Sullivan (1993)</ref> is previously listed.</p><p>• <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Thaler (1985)</ref> is previously listed.</p><p>• <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Acquisti and Varian (2005)</ref> found that rapid advances in information technology allow sellers to condition price offers on consumers' prior purchase behavior. The article shows that although feasible, it is never optimal for the seller to distinguish between high-value and low-value consumers.</p><p>• <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Lynch and Ariely (2000)</ref> refute the notion that retailers should necessarily fear the lowering of consumer search costs made possible by the Web. Prevailing wisdom was that lower search costs intensify price competition and lower margins. However, electronic shopping also lowers the cost of acquiring nonprice information and can encourage quality search, which decreases price sensitivity. Empirical evidence supports this latter view.</p><p>I am proud to have personally invited <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Acquisti and Varian (2005)</ref> to publish in the journal.</p><p>We expect that the best is yet to come.</p></div>			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">* Denotes the all-time, most-cited articles in Marketing Science, according to a recent 2007 Google Scholar search.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditioning prices on purchase history</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Acquisti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Varian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="367" to="381" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determinants of continuity in conventional industrial channel dyads</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Weitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="310" to="323" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Shugan: Editorial: Introduction to the Special Classics Issue Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The salesperson as outside agent or employee: A transaction cost analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="234" to="254" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The antecedents and consequences of customer satisfaction for firms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Sullivan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="143" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dynamic model of the duration of the customer&apos;s relationship with a continuous service provider: The role of satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Bolton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="65" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The voice of the customer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Griffin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A logit model of brand choice calibrated on scanner data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Guadagni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D C</forename><surname>Little</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="238" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Defensive marketing strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="360" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing channel profits</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Jeuland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="272" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wine online: Search costs affect competition on price, quality, and distribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jr</forename><surname>Lynch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ariely</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="103" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An industry equilibrium analysis of downstream vertical integration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mcguire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Staelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="191" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring the flow construct in online environments: A structural modeling approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Novak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Hoffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y.-F</forename><surname>Yung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="42" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal pricing and return policies for perishable commodities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pasternack</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="166" to="176" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fifty years of Marketing Science</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="551" to="555" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thanks to the many individuals who make publication of Marketing Science possible</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="292" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mental accounting and consumer choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="214" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
