<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Commentary-Discussion of the Article &quot;Website Morphing&quot;</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2009-02-24">February 24, 2009.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
							<email>gelman@stat.columbia.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Departments of Statistics and Political Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>10027</postCode>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>New York</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Departments of Statistics and Political Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>10027</postCode>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>New York</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Commentary-Discussion of the Article &quot;Website Morphing&quot;</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 09 2802 0226</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2009-02-24">February 24, 2009.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1080.0476</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: November 17, 2008; accepted: November 17, 2008.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-13T12:15+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>"Website Morphing" <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Hauser et al. 2009</ref>) is a fun paper to discuss. In particular I like the summary of technical challenges at the beginning: The website must (1) morph based on relatively few clicks, (2) learn which characteristics are best for which customers, (3) use prior information, and (4) be implemented in real time. So often in applied statistics we find ourselves analyzing a data set in isolation or attacking a large problem with limited data; it is refreshing to see such clear goals, and I think I will try to be focused in this way in my future research projects.</p><p>At a more technical level, the trade-off between exploitation and exploration is a standard issue in statistical design of experiments: for exploitation (which we call optimization) we want the best solution based on our current state of knowledge; for exploration (in statistical terms, inference) we want the "leverage" that comes from using design points that can be far from practical. The particular tools developed in this article should be useful for other problems such as computerized adaptive testing in educational applications.</p><p>My main suggestion for improving this work is to make it more open-ended by incorporating simulation-based model checking, also called posterior predictive checks (as described, for example, in Chapter 6 of our Bayesian statistics text, <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Gelman et al. 2003</ref>). The idea is to use the fitted model to simulate several replicated data sets and then to compare these to the actual data. The comparisons can be graphical (for example, using scatterplots or time-series plots of individual users' patterns of clicks) and numerical (for example, mean squared errors or log likelihoods of observed responses given predicted probabilities from the model). This open-ended exploration gives a framework for the continuous improvement of details of the proposed method as it is being used while keeping the existing inference and optimization structure.</p><p>One advantage of a fully Bayesian model (in computer science terminology, a generative model) is that it can be used immediately to simulate replicated data. I recommend that the authors of this articleand the many readers of this journal who will surely want to apply the methods described to their own problems-take advantage of the generative property to explore the ways in which their model fits, and does not fit, reality. Such graphical and numerical diagnostics could be performed using the data gathered from the application of the fitting and optimization procedure to real users.</p></div>		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The author thanks the Columbia University Applied Statistics Center, the National Science Foundation, the National Institutes of Health, and Yahoo! Research for partial support of this work.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Carlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Bayesian Data Analysis</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>London</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Chapman and Hall</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Website morphing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Urban</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Liberali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="202" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
