<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Congratulations to Richard Thaler for Winning the Nobel Prize in Economics</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sudhir</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Congratulations to Richard Thaler for Winning the Nobel Prize in Economics</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.2017.1073</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-13T12:15+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>See press releases from the Nobel Committee 1 and INFORMS 2 related to Thaler's Nobel win. A more detailed description of the contributions of Thaler as judged by the Nobel committee can be found here. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> By Thaler's definition, mental accounting is "the set of cognitive operations used by individuals and households to organize, evaluate, and keep track of financial activities." The 1985 paper is the second highest cited paper in Marketing Science to-date, and has spawned important follow up work both at Marketing Science (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Prelec and</ref><ref type="bibr">Loewenstein 1998, Soman and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Cheema 2002)</ref> and in various other marketing, finance, and economics journals. For an overview of how mental accounting affects choice in a variety of settings including consumption, savings, individual budgeting, self-control, and giving, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Thaler (1999)</ref>. In an invited Marketing Science commentary, <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Thaler (2008)</ref> provides a retrospective evaluation of the impact of the 1985 paper in the fields of marketing, finance, and economics.</p><p>The ideas in mental accounting have had a significant impact on public policy in the appropriate design of "nudges" that improve decisions about health, wealth, and happiness. These ideas are well described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Sunstein and Thaler's (2008)</ref> popular book Nudge.</p><p>Please see below a brief reminiscence from Subrata Sen about the review process for the mental accounting paper. Also read Thaler's more colorful description of the review process as well as the impact of the idea on different fields in <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Thaler (2008)</ref>. The award of a Nobel prize for work published in Marketing Science is an occasion for celebration for the journal and the field. But Subrata's story is also a cautionary tale for all of us that traditional standards of evaluation in the review process may lead us to reject potentially pathbreaking work.</p><p>When I took over as EIC, I wrote an editorial about the importance of balancing the exploration-exploitation tradeoff in knowledge production, how reviewers and editors should consider this tradeoff when evaluating papers <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Sudhir 2016)</ref>. The story of the review process for a Nobel enabling paper at Marketing Science reminds us again of the need to keep that balance in mind when evaluating papers, for contribution and potential impact, especially as it relates to new area and novel paradigms. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Endnotes1</head><label></label><figDesc>https://www.nobelprize.org/nobel_prizes/economic-sciences/ laureates/2017/press.html. 2 https://www.informs.org/About-INFORMS/News-Room/Press-Releases/INFORMS-congratulates-Nobel-Prize-winner-Richard -Thaler. 3 https://www.nobelprize.org/nobel_prizes/economic-sciences/ laureates/2017/advanced-economicsciences2017.pdf..</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Vol. 36, No. 6, November-December 2017, pp. 813-814 http://pubsonline.informs.org/journal/mksc/ ISSN 0732-2399 (print), ISSN 1526-548X (online) Congratulations to Richard Thaler for Winning the Nobel Prize in Economics</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>K. Sudhir a</cell></row><row><cell>a Yale School of Management, New Haven, Connecticut 06520-8200</cell></row><row><cell>Contact: k.sudhir@yale.edu (KS)</cell></row><row><cell>https://doi.org/10.1287/mksc.2017.1073</cell></row><row><cell>Copyright: © 2017 INFORMS</cell></row><row><cell>Marketing Science congratulates Professor Richard</cell></row><row><cell>Thaler of the University of Chicago's Booth School</cell></row><row><cell>of Business on winning the 2017 Nobel Prize in Eco-</cell></row><row><cell>nomics for his contributions to the field of behavioral</cell></row><row><cell>economics. The Nobel citation prominently features</cell></row><row><cell>Professor Thaler's (1985) paper on mental accounting,</cell></row><row><cell>published in Marketing Science.</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Congratulations to Richard Thaler for Winning the Nobel Prize in Economics 814</head><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2017</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 36, no. 6, pp. 813-814, © 2017</ref> The "Story" Behind the Publication of Mental Accounting at Marketing Science Subrata Sen a a Yale School of Management, New Haven, Connecticut 06520-8200 Contact: subrata.sen@yale.edu (SS) I was delighted to learn that Dick Thaler had been awarded the 2017 Nobel Prize in Economics. It is a well-deserved honor.</p><p>His win reminded me of when he submitted the paper ("Mental Accounting and Consumer Choice") to Marketing Science when I was the Editor-in-Chief. It was full of great ideas but contained no math. As a result, the referees rejected it, saying that it was not appropriate for a quantitative journal like Marketing Science. However, as I thought about it, I became increasingly convinced that the paper would have great impact and would encourage a host of researchers to continue this stream of work. Hence, I called Abel Jeuland (the area editor for the paper) to discuss what we should do. After a short conversation we agreed to ignore the referees' comments and publish the paper. It was the best decision that I made as editor of Marketing Science.</p><p>I was correct in predicting that the paper would have great impact (for a long time it was the most-cited paper in Marketing Science) but must admit that I did not think that it would help win the Nobel Prize. I am so glad that I was wrong!</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The red and the black: Mental accounting of savings and debt</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Prelec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of credit on spending decisions: The role of the credit limit and credibility</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Soman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cheema</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="32" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The exploration-exploitation tradeoff and efficiency in knowledge production</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sudhir</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Nudge. The Politics of Libertarian Paternalism</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sunstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>Yale University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New Haven, CT</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mental accounting and consumer choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="214" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mental accounting matters</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Behav. Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="183" to="206" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Commentary-Mental accounting and consumer choice: Anatomy of a failure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12" to="14" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
