<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org A Theoretical Analysis of the Lean Start-up Method</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2021-03-09">March 9, 2021</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Onesun</surname></persName>
							<email>onesun.yoo@ucl.ac.uk</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Tingliang</forename><surname>Yoo</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kenan</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><surname>Arifoğlu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><roleName>Kenan</roleName><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><surname>Yoo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">UCL School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>E14 5AB</postCode>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Tingliang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<email>tingliang.huang@bc.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Business Analytics Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Carroll School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Boston College</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Chestnut Hill</addrLine>
									<postCode>02467</postCode>
									<region>Massachusetts</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kenan</forename><surname>Arifoglu</surname></persName>
							<email>k.arifoglu@ucl.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">UCL School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>E14 5AB</postCode>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org A Theoretical Analysis of the Lean Start-up Method</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 (print)</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2021-03-09">March 9, 2021</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.2020.1269</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: February 22, 2018 Revised: May 29, 2019; April 30, 2020; August 16, 2020; August 27, 2020 Accepted: September 1, 2020</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-13T12:14+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>lean start-up method</term>
					<term>entrepreneurship</term>
					<term>customer discovery</term>
					<term>new product development</term>
					<term>Bayesian learning</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Recent decades witnessed many remarkably successful start-ups disrupting old industries or creating new ones (e.g., Google, Facebook, Airbnb, Uber). These start-ups take advantage of modern technology shocks (e.g., open-source software, cloud-based computing, mobile platforms), which enable the creation of new business models and give birth to a wide category of novel products and services that are conceptually new to consumers <ref type="bibr">(Economist 2019a, b)</ref>. When developing such disruptive innovations, it is often challenging for firms to learn about consumers' preferences prior to product launch because consumers would seldom know what they want <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Hoeffler 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">, Nijssen 2017</ref>). Moreover, with the accompanying decrease in the cost of development, testing, and distribution of the innovative product <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Kerr et al. 2014, Nanda and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Rhodes-Kropf 2016)</ref>, the key challenge to creating a successful consumer-oriented innovation has shifted from tackling development challenges to tackling market uncertainty and identifying what appeals to its users <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">(von Hippel 2005)</ref>. Coupled with a significant increase in the access to financing (e.g., in the form of venture capital, angel investors, and crowdsourcing) <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Hellmann and</ref><ref type="bibr">Thiele 2015, Ewens et al. 2018)</ref>, talented entrepreneurs and their startup firms are playing an increasingly prominent role in the innovation economy <ref type="bibr">Lerner 2001, 2006)</ref>.</p><p>This emerging community of innovative start-ups had found that much of traditional guidance on innovation (originally intended for large firm research and development (R&amp;D) or market research for incremental innovation) does not apply well to their contexts in practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Blank 2005)</ref>. The lean start-up method (LSM) was introduced to fill this gap <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Ries 2011</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">, Blank 2013</ref>. Originating from the software start-up community, it promotes an experimentationbased approach to customer discovery and product development. Its build-test-learn loop takes advantage of the prevalent start-up features (e.g., low cost of development and adjustment, agile organizational structure, easy access to customers) to test hypotheses about consumers who are difficult to investigate using traditional market research methods and to adjust the product development goals accordingly after receiving consumer feedback.</p><p>A single iteration of LSM starts when the entrepreneur launches a test product, which is a version of the product that communicates the unique selling point of the product but without all the "bells and whistles" (e.g., a consumer website that has 10% of functionality that founders ultimately envision). <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Next, by observing consumers' actual purchase behavior or willingness to cross the "penny gap," 2 the entrepreneur obtains feedback about consumer preferences. Finally, after assessing the feedback, the entrepreneur modifies the development goals or pivots to better meet consumer needs <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Blank 2013)</ref>. This iterative experimentation approach allows entrepreneurs to test unproven hypotheses about consumers who are otherwise difficult to test (e.g., surveys or market research), and as a result, it has gained significant acceptance among a broad range of entrepreneurs. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> For example, in its early days, Brian Chesky and Joe Gebbia, the founders of Airbnb, believed that people would rent out their rooms to strangers and people would pay to sleep in strangers' rooms. Potential investors and customers they sought after initially all rejected the concept as unrealistic for mainstream market <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Hoffman and Yeh 2018)</ref>. To test their hypothesis, they posted pictures of their lofts on a WordPress blog as a test product; they soon discovered that large segments of population would pay to stay in their rooms, and so, they launched a web page, which evolved to become Airbnb <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Aberant 2018</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">, Gracia 2019</ref>). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Despite its wide adoption, there is limited theoretical understanding about how LSM works. The consumer responses to a test product serve as an imperfect signal about the product-market fit. As in all experiments, because of the random selection of customers, a positive outcome (e.g., sales) does not necessarily indicate that the test product has the right features (i.e., false positive), whereas a negative outcome (e.g., failure to sell) does not necessarily indicate that the test product has the wrong features (i.e., false negative). The quality, price, and design of the test product affect the consumer feedback and influence both the learning from the test product and the likelihood of attaining false positive and false negative results. In other words, the learning is endogenous to the features of the test product. Understanding how accurately an entrepreneur can learn from a test product and benefit from adopting LSM is complex and merits a formal enquiry.</p><p>In this paper, we develop a stylized analytical model of LSM to better understand its microfoundation. Using the model, we aim to explore how entrepreneurs who seek to adopt LSM should implement it in practice. Specifically, we address the following research questions. (i) How does a test product's design, quality, and price influence the entrepreneur's learning? (ii) Which attribute should the entrepreneur seek to choose or to avoid in a test product? How should the entrepreneur pivot? (iii) In which product-market environments is LSM more effective and why?</p><p>To study these questions, we consider a profitmaximizing entrepreneur who aims to develop and launch a new product under high market uncertainty. Customers are homogeneous in their valuations for product quality, but they are heterogeneous in their valuation for product design (i.e., the location in the attribute space). The consumers' tastes are clustered around an unknown location in the attribute space. The entrepreneur identifies two candidate locations as the epicenter of consumer tastes and seeks to learn and develop the product design that will sell to most customers (i.e., "ideal product"). Because of significant market uncertainty, market research helps the entrepreneur form an initial belief about the ideal product location but does not completely reveal it. To learn, he experiments with the consumers by using a test product.</p><p>We model a single iteration of the LSM as a twostage decision process as follows. In the first stage, based on his initial belief, the entrepreneur decides what test product to develop (i.e., its quality, price, and design location) and presents it to a single customer randomly selected from the population. The consumer decides to purchase the test product if its quality and price and the fit with his or her idiosyncratic taste provide positive utility. Based on the realized sales outcome, the entrepreneur updates his belief about the ideal product location in a Bayesian manner. In the second stage, using his updated belief, the entrepreneur "pivots" to a new design location, enhances the product's quality, launches it to the entire market, and obtains profit.</p><p>Our analysis reveals that the optimal test product maximizes learning and minimizes the probability of developing the wrong product, in line with the experts' suggestions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Ries 2011)</ref>. Also, it strikes the balance between minimizing false positives and false negatives. We present the following nuanced insights on the optimal implementation of LSM.</p><p>First, in terms of the vertical quality and price, the test product should have an intermediate level of quality. If the test product's quality is too high (too low), everybody (nobody) is expected to purchase the test product, and observing the obvious sale (no sale), outcome provides little information about consumer tastes. Second, in terms of design location, the test product should be located on the exterior of the two candidate locations (e.g., contains attributes unique to one candidate ideal product) aimed to either confirm a more likely design or rule out a less likely design as ideal. A design location that is between the two candidates (e.g., contains attributes from both candidate designs) achieves little learning and should be avoided. The vertical quality and design location of the test product interact: if the entrepreneur seeks to confirm a design as ideal, he should launch it at a higher vertical quality than when he seeks to rule out a less likely design. Both test products lead to an Yoo, Huang, and Arifoglu: A Theoretical Analysis of the Lean <ref type="bibr">Start-up Method Marketing Science, 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 40, no. 3, pp. 395-412, © 2021</ref> equal amount of learning, indicating that there are multiple optimal test products and in particular, that failure to sell a test product can be equally informative as success in selling it.</p><p>The outcome of learning influences the pivoting decision. To maximize expected profit, the entrepreneur should pivot to a product design represented by location interior to the two candidate locations. This is in contrast to optimal design of the test product. Yet, the pivoting location gets closer to one of two product designs as the entrepreneur learns more from the test product. The accurate learning reduces the need to hedge against the risk of developing the wrong product and allows the entrepreneur to develop products that are more appealing to customer tastes.</p><p>Finally, our parsimonious model provides insights into how product-market environments influence the effectiveness of the LSM. We find that the LSM is more effective in situations with greater market uncertainty and lower heterogeneity in consumer tastes. This is because in these situations, the risk of developing the wrong product is higher and the optimal test product is more informative about the location of the ideal product. The LSM's effectiveness is, however, more sensitive to the design of the test product in situations where consumer tastes are less heterogeneous, and they rely more on quality for their purchase. In other words, from a practical implementation perspective, the LSM's effectiveness can be highly variable. Thus, our results offer two explanations to the variability of the LSM's effectiveness observed in practice.</p><p>We examine several extensions to enrich the key insights. First, we consider the presence of pivoting friction. Because the entrepreneur must divert resources away from development to implement a pivot, pivoting reduces the final product's quality. We find that if the friction is small, the set of optimal test products reduces to a unique test product aimed to confirm the likelier design; if the friction is large, it is optimal not to pivot at all. Second, we assume that the entrepreneur can change the final product's price before launch to further improve profit. We find that the additional profit created by flexible pricing further increases with improved learning, suggesting that pricing and learning are complements. Third, we extend the model to allow for multiple iterations of the build-test-learn loop. The optimal test product allows for successive increase in the quality and price of the test product after each iteration. We also find that a single iteration can be optimal when it leads to sufficient learning. Finally, we examine a setting with three candidate locations for the ideal design and report consistent insights for the optimal test product and pivot decisions.</p><p>The rest of this paper is organized as follows. After reviewing the related literature in Section 2, we present our model in Section 3, provide our analysis in Section 4, and examine the extensions in Section 5. We conclude in Section 6. Robustness checks are provided in Online Appendix A, and proofs are in Online Appendices B and C.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Literature Review</head><p>The LSM shares many features studied in prior academic literature on new product development and market research. Its uniqueness stems from how those features are combined to address challenges in a different innovation context. We compare the LSM with related literature and highlight our paper's contributions.</p><p>Early literature on new product development focuses on the stage-gate method where a project must pass through a series of stages marked by gatekeepers to be launched as a new product. At each stage, a project is reviewed by an internal gatekeeper that collects information to gauge its potential for successful product launch and determines whether to continue to the next stage or stop it <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Cooper 1990</ref>). The gatekeeper's decision represents an investment under uncertainty and is formally studied using a real option framework (e.g., see <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Kwon and Lippman 2011)</ref>. This innovation process is necessary if each stage entails large costs and lead times (for example, in the case for the developing physical products (see review by <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Krishnan and Ulrich 2001)</ref>) and is suitable if the key uncertainty of the project in each stage can be tackled in a self-contained manner without feedback from downstream stages. It is employed in settings with high technical uncertainty through phases (e.g., in the case of drug development) or in settings where commercial risk can be reduced through market research (e.g., for incremental innovation). Because it enables firms to run multiple projects in parallel (starting with a large set of ideas and allocating resources to a small set of promising projects), the stagegate approach is employed fruitfully in large firms' R&amp;D processes to take advantage of economies of scale and reduce the cycle time of successful innovations (e.g., see <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Girotra et al. 2007</ref>). The LSM, however, originates from software start-up community and takes advantages of smaller lead time and costs in each stage. It runs through all stages quickly and relies on learning from feedback in downstream stages.</p><p>The innovation process that learns through experimentation has also been extensively studied as an alternative to the stage-gate approach. First, the stage-gate approach was found to be less effective for innovations that were considered more discontinuous (i.e., neither a product nor consumers exist). <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Yoo, Huang, and Arifoglu: A Theoretical Analysis of the Lean <ref type="bibr">Start-up Method Marketing Science, 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 40, no. 3, pp. 395-412, © 2021</ref> For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Lynn et al. (1996)</ref> examine case studies of successful disruptive innovations in large firms (e.g., GE and Motorola) and promote the "probe and learn" innovation approach. Namely, firms should iteratively test the market during product development and alter the product goals, similar to LSM. Second, the advent of technology that enabled rapid prototyping (e.g., computer-aided design technology) and testing (e.g., computer simulation) made experimentation feasible. <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Thomke (1998)</ref> studies how the innovation process can adopt these modes of experimentation, taking into consideration the tradeoff between cost and accuracy. This emergence of trial and error learning prompted <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Loch et al. (2001)</ref> to formally investigate the efficacy between the experimentation approach and stage-gate parallel learning; <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Sommer and Loch (2004)</ref> examine how the level of complexity and uncertainty influences the choice between iteration or stage-gate innovation, whereas <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Erat and Kavadias (2008)</ref> examine how design complexity influences the number of experimentations as a way of solving technical uncertainty. The key aim of the learning through trial and error discussed in the literature is tackling technological development uncertainty aimed at successfully engineering a functioning product. In contrast, the LSM employs iteration to tackle the market uncertainty to learn about what consumers want. By studying LSM, we contribute to the literature on experiment-based innovation by formalizing the process.</p><p>Mirroring the comparison between stage-gate development and experimentation, a debate had existed regarding the value of business planning in the entrepreneurship literature. Proponents of business plans argued that they allow more effective use of resources and increase decision speed <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Delmar and Shane 2003)</ref>. Those who oppose business plans argue that they divert critical resources away from business operation and prevent entrepreneurs from learning on the job <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Bhide 2000)</ref>. In a qualitative study, <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Sarasvathy (2001)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Read et al. (2011)</ref> find that successful entrepreneurs follow a process of iteratively acquiring resources through learning and shifting goals, similar in spirit to LSM. Through their metastudy, <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Brinckmann et al. (2010)</ref> find that business plans are valuable, but their value declines when the start-ups face higher uncertainty. LSM argues against relying on business plans for start-ups altogether. Our formal analysis of LSM contributes to the discussion by showing that LSM is more effective in settings where market uncertainty is greater.</p><p>Market research plays an important part in determining an innovation's success, and various techniques have been developed to fruitfully elicit consumer preferences. One of the predominant market research techniques is conjoint analysis that asks potential customers to evaluate a set of alternatives in various incrementally innovative domains, such as consumer packaged goods, consumer electronics, or new drinks flavors <ref type="bibr">Srinivasan 1978, 1990;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Mahajan and Wind 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Sandor and Wedel 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Yu et al. 2011)</ref>. Other approaches such as virtual concept testing <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Dahan and Srinivasan 2000)</ref> or crowdsourcing <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bayus 2013</ref>) similarly take advantage of existing customers. These techniques leverage the well-established customer base to learn how different attributes (e.g., resolution versus lens quality) should be included in a new product (e.g., camera). Such incremental innovations have only one chance to succeed because customers have many alternatives to choose from and are often employed in an early phase of a stage-gate process (often independently from product development decisions). In contrast, for discontinuous innovations (no preexisting products or consumers), consumers cannot conceptualize how they would use a new product <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Cooper et al. 2002)</ref>, and market research becomes unreliable <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Hoeffler 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">, Nijssen 2017</ref>. The LSM can be viewed as a different type of market research suitable for tackling the uncertainty associated with discontinuous innovations.</p><p>Building on this literature, there are streams of papers that model market research and examine how it interacts with innovation (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Ofek and Turut 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">, Lauga and Ofek 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">, Katona 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">, Kwark et al. 2018</ref>). These models assume a stage-gate innovation process with market research preceding product development. By investing in market research, firms can reduce or eliminate uncertainty about consumer preferences, which in turn, influences their strategy concerning investment in product development. These papers examine how the competitive structure of the industry influences the firms' decision to invest in market research and R&amp;D and ultimately, the innovation output. Our study also examines the interaction between learning and product development. However, our focus is on understanding the nuances of how learning via test product takes place and how LSM can be fruitfully employed to develop an innovation that maximizes the fit with consumer tastes in a noncompetitive setting.</p><p>Iteratively launching a test product is related to launching multiple versions of a product. Thus, LSM is related to the literature on strategic versioning of innovations. The aim of versioning is to launch incremental innovations to maximize earnings or profits. <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Norton and Bass (1987)</ref> study the substitution effect of having multiple product generations in the market simultaneously, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Wilson and Norton (1989)</ref> show that product line extensions should be either introduced early in a product's life cycle or not introduced at all, depending on the degree of substitutability Yoo, Huang, and Arifoglu: A Theoretical Analysis of the Lean <ref type="bibr">Start-up Method Marketing Science, 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 40, no. 3, pp. 395-412, © 2021</ref> between the original product and its extension. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bayus (1992)</ref> analyzes the prices for the two generations that maximize the discounted profit after the second product is launched. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Bhaskaran et al. (2020)</ref> study how start-ups should sequentially launch products to generate revenue to balance innovation and survival; <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Lobel et al. (2016)</ref> study how firms should behave strategically and launch new versions of existing products when consumers expect them to, whereas <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Allon et al. (2020)</ref> empirically examine mobile app developers' versioning behavior in response to customer feedback. The aim of a test product in the context of LSM is fundamentally different in that each launch aims to maximize learning about unknown consumer tastes.</p><p>Finally, in our learning model, the entrepreneur receives censored information from the launch of a test product that he uses to update his prior belief in a Bayesian fashion. Common iterative learning models in new product development and marketing employ search (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Weitzman 1979)</ref> or the multiarmed bandit models (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Hauser et al. 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">, Lin et al. 2015</ref> or Bayesian optimization (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Letham et al. 2017)</ref>. In all these models, the samples used in learning are selected from exogenously given probability distributions. In contrast, in our model the probability distribution is endogenous to the design of test product. Moreover, we examine how the entrepreneur can learn about consumer tastes by launching test products with different qualities and designs. We are the first to analytically formalize how the interplay between quality and design of test products influences the learning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Model</head><p>In this section, we present our model of LSM. We begin with the demand model with unknown consumer tastes (Section 3.1), then characterize the LSM and its process of learning based on the test product (Section 3.2), and finally, introduce the entrepreneur's problem (Section 3.3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Consumers</head><p>We consider a market where consumers are heterogeneous in their tastes of design (i.e., horizontal preferences) and homogeneous in their valuation for product quality. 6 A consumer's taste is represented by her position on the real line x ∈ R, which represents a collection of attributes, similar to spatial differentiation models (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Hotelling 1929)</ref>. The target population is distributed according to a probability density h(x|W), where the value W represents the unknown epicenter of consumer tastes. For ease of analysis and illustration, we consider finite support [W − , W + ], where the parameter represents the level of heterogeneity in consumer tastes. We normalize the population size to one and all costs to zero.</p><p>Suppose that a product with design (i.e., collection of attributes) Λ ∈ R is launched. Then, the disutility experienced by a consumer with taste x because of lack of fit is given by t • |Λ − x|. The parameter t denotes the strength of a preference for horizontal fit. A high (low) value of t implies that consumers will purchase the product primarily based on horizontal fit (vertical quality) of the product. 7 If V and p denote the vertical quality and the price of the product, respectively, a consumer located at position x experiences the net surplus:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">s x ( ) V − p − t|Λ − x|.</formula><p>The consumer purchases the product if the surplus is positive (i.e., s(x) &gt; 0). The demand for the product (Λ, V, p) then corresponds to the fraction of consumers who would experience positive surplus, which is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">D Λ, V, p ( ) ≡ ∫ V−p t + Λ − V−p t + Λ h x|W ( )dx.<label>(1)</label></formula><p>The demand depends critically on the design location of the product Λ as illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>. The left panel represents the case where Λ W so that most of the consumers around Λ have a positive Yoo, Huang, and Arifoglu: A Theoretical Analysis of the Lean <ref type="bibr">Start-up Method Marketing Science, 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 40, no. 3, pp. 395-412, © 2021</ref> surplus and purchase the product. The right panel represents the case where Λ &lt; W, in which case the entrepreneur captures only a fraction of potential consumers. Thus, a product Λ W can be thought of as the "ideal product," as it would maximize the demand for the product.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">LSM</head><p>We consider a monopolist entrepreneur who aims to introduce a new product to this consumer market. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> Based on the initial market research, the entrepreneur has narrowed down the possible ideal product to one of two possible product designs W ∈ {0, C}, where &lt; C &lt; 2 , and forms an initial belief P(W 0) r about which of these is the ideal product. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> The difference between the two product designs, C, represents the degree of market uncertainty (i.e., the higher the value of C, the greater downside risk of developing the wrong product). The entrepreneur seeks to implement the LSM to learn more.</p><p>We assume that the final product's quality V and price p are exogenously given but that the value of V − p is bounded above so that the final product results in a high demand only if the design location is close to the ideal product.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">Assumption 1. V − p ≤ t.</formula><p>We formalize a single build-test-learn iteration of the LSM, as illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>. In the first stage, the entrepreneur decides on the test product. To be precise, we model a test product defined by its design location (λ ∈ R) and its quality (v) and price (ρ) that is sold to the targeted consumers.</p><p>Next, as an abstraction of sampling, 10 we assume that the test product is launched and presented to a single consumer i with location x i who is randomly picked from the consumer distribution h(x|W). The consumer purchases the test product if her surplus is positive: that is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">s i ≡ s(x i ) v − ρ − t|λ − x i | &gt; 0.</formula><p>Based on this feedback (sale or no sale of test product), the entrepreneur updates his belief about the ideal product's location.</p><p>In the second stage, based on his updated beliefs, the entrepreneur pivots the product design from λ to Λ, adds the "bells and whistles" to develop vertical quality (V) and price (p), and launches the product. The profit is realized based on demand Equation (1).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1.">Learning with a Test Product.</head><p>A key feature of our learning model is that the entrepreneur learns through censored feedback from the test productthat is, he observes the sales outcome from a purchase but not the consumer's taste x. 11 Moreover, the test product's quality, price, and design influence the consumer's probability of purchase and the entrepreneur's updated belief.</p><p>We let g(s i |(λ, v, ρ), W) denote the probability density function of the surplus s i of a randomly chosen consumer i. We derive g(s i |(λ, v, ρ), W) by using the consumer's taste distribution h(x|W) as Lemma 1 shows.</p><p>Lemma 1 (Surplus Density Function). The probability density function of surplus s i , which depends on the test product (λ, v, ρ) and h(x|W), is</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">g s i | λ, v, ρ ( ) , W ( ) 1 t h − v − ρ ( ) + s i t + λ ( ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ W ) [ + h v − ρ − s i t + λ ( ⃒ ⃒ ⃒W ) ]</formula><p>.</p><p>Based on the density g(s i |(λ, v, ρ), W), the probabilities that the test product is sold or not sold can be represented by</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">∫ ∞ 0 g(s i |(λ,v,ρ),W) ds and ∫ 0 −∞ g(s i |(λ,v,ρ),W</formula><p>) ds, respectively, which depend on the entrepreneur's choice of test product.</p><p>Depending on the outcome of the test product's launch, the entrepreneur updates his belief from r P(W 0) to the posterior beliefr according to Bayes' rule. Intuitively, if the test product located near λ 0 is launched and results in a sale, then the entrepreneur's belief that W 0 will increase: that is,r &gt; r; if it results in no sale, then his belief that W 0 will decrease: that is,r &lt; r. The following lemma formalizes this intuition.</p><p>Lemma 2 (Posterior Belief). After launching the test product (λ, v, ρ), the prior belief r is updated to the posterior beliefr as follows.</p><p>i.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">If sale is observed (s i &gt; 0), theñ r r λ, v, ρ|r ( ) r ∫ ∞ 0 g s i | λ, v, ρ ( ) , W 0 ( ) ds r ∫ ∞ 0 g s i | λ, v, ρ ( ) , W 0 ( ) ds + 1 − r ( ) × ∫ ∞ 0 g s i | λ, v, ρ ( ) , W C ( ) ds . ii. If no sale is observed (s i ≤ 0), theñ r r λ, v, ρ|r ( ) r ∫ 0 −∞ g s i | λ, v, ρ ( ) , W 0 ( ) ds r ∫ 0 −∞ g s i | λ, v, ρ ( ) , W 0 ( ) ds + 1 − r ( ) × ∫ 0 −∞ g s i | λ, v, ρ ( ) , W C ( )<label>ds</label></formula><p>.</p><p>The outcome of the test product yields imperfect information because of the inherent randomness in the selection of a consumer. Launching an ideal test Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 40, no. 3, pp. 395-412, © 2021</ref> product (λ W) can lead to no sale (false negative) because the selected consumer's taste can be located far away from W. Similarly, launching a test product far away from the ideal product can lead to a sale (false positive) if the selected consumer's taste is located close to λ. Because each g(s i |(λ, v, ρ), W) is dependent on the attributes of the test product (λ, v, ρ), the extent of learning (whether posteriorr is close to zero or one) depends on the choice of test product.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">The Entrepreneur's Problem</head><p>We now formalize the entrepreneur's decision problem, which consists of deciding on the test product in the first stage and pivoting in the second stage.</p><p>In the second stage, given the updated beliefr, the entrepreneur aims to maximize his expected profit from product launch by determining the final pivot location Λ. Thus, the entrepreneur's problem in the second stage is as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">max Λ πr ( ) ≡ p ∫ Λ− V−p ( ) t Λ+ V−p tr • h x|W 0 ( ) [ + 1 −r ( )• h x|W C ( ) ] dx.<label>(2)</label></formula><p>We shall denote the maximum profit obtained after optimal pivot as π * (r).</p><p>In the first stage, using his initial belief r, the entrepreneur must decide which test product (λ, v, ρ) to launch so as to profitably influence the distribution of the posteriorr and maximize the expected profit from the final product launch. (We do not account for the profit from the test product in the first stage because it is from a single customer and is negligible.) The entrepreneur's problem in the first stage is as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">max λ,v,ρ ( ) E s i λ,v,ρ ( ) π * r λ, v, ρ|r ( ) ( ) ∫ ∞ 0 π * r λ, v, ρ|r ( ) ( ) r • g s i ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ λ, v, ρ ( ) , W 0 ( ) [ + 1 − r ( )• g s i ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ λ, v, ρ ( ) , W C ( ) ] ds i + ∫ 0 −∞ π * r λ, v, ρ|r ( ) ( ) r • g s i ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ λ, v, ρ ( ) , W 0 ( ) [ + 1 − r ( )• g s i ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ λ, v, ρ ( ) , W C ( ) ] ds i . (<label>3</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_9">)</formula><p>The first (second) line represents the expected profit in the event of sales (no sales). Depending on the sales outcome, the entrepreneur updates posterior tor or r as defined in Lemma 2, (i) and (ii), respectively. We next characterize the optimal decisions for the entrepreneur implementing the LSM.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Analysis</head><p>Using backward induction, in Section 4.1 we first examine the optimal pivoting location Λ * and the expression for the optimal second-stage profit given beliefr (i.e., π * (r). Then, in Section 4.2, we examine the optimal test product decision (λ * , v * , ρ * ) in the first stage that maximizes the expected second-stage profit E s i (λ,v,ρ) π * (r(λ, v, ρ)). Finally, in Section 4.3, we examine the optimal E s i (λ * ,v * ,ρ * ) π * (r(λ * , v * , ρ * )) to gain insights into how the product-market features (C, , and t) influence the effectiveness of the LSM.</p><p>To give clear insights, we assume that h</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">(x|W) is uniformly distributed in [W − , W + ]. 12 4.1. Second Stage: Optimal Pivot If h(x|W) is uniformly distributed within the range [W − , W + ], the entrepreneur's second-stage prob- lem (2) reduces to max Λ pr 2 min , Λ + V − p t ( ) − max [ { − , Λ − V − p ( ) t ( ) ] + 1 −r ( ) 2 min C + , Λ + V − p t ( ) [ − max C − , Λ − V − p ( ) t ( ) ]} .<label>(4)</label></formula><p>Solving the problem in (4), we characterize the optimal pivot location given the updated beliefr in Proposition 1.</p><p>Proposition 1 (Optimal Pivot). For any updated beliefr, the optimal pivot location is</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">Λ * − V−p t ,r ≥ 1 2 , C − + V−p t ,r &lt; 1 2 .</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>{</head><p>The proposition reveals that it is always optimal to pivot to one of two design locations depending on the updated beliefr. On the one hand, ifr &gt; 0.5, the ideal product W is more likely to be located at 0 and it is optimal to pivot to a design location that is closer to 0, Λ * − V−p t ≥ 0. On the other hand, ifr &lt; 0.5, the ideal product W is more likely to be located at C, and it is optimal to pivot to a design location closer to C, Λ *</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">C − + V−p t &lt; C.</formula><p>We observe that, because V − p ≤ t (by Assumption 1), the optimal pivot location always lies interior to the two candidate ideal products (i.e., Λ * ∈ [0, C]). This indicates that the entrepreneur should include features of both potential ideal designs in the final product to hedge against the downside of developing the wrong product. As the quality of the final product increases (V − p → t), Λ * converges toward zero or C, indicating the reduced need to hedge.</p><p>Substituting the optimal pivot Λ * in (4), we obtain the optimal expected profit as</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">π * r ( ) p V − p t − V − p t − 1 − C 2 ( ) ( ) [ minr, 1 −r { } ] .</formula><p>(5) The term min{r, 1 −r} represents the entrepreneur's probability of pivoting toward the wrong design. If the updated beliefr is equal to 0 or 1 (high level of learning from the test product), then min{r, 1 −r} 0, and the entrepreneur can pivot to the ideal product location to maximize his profit (p V−p t ). On the other hand, ifr is 0.5 (no learning from the test product), then min{r, 1 −r} 0.5, indicating that there is 0.5 probability that the entrepreneur pivots to the wrong product, which reduces his expected profit.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">First Stage: Design of the Test Product</head><p>In this section, we examine the optimal design of the test product (λ, v, ρ) in the first stage that maximizes the entrepreneur's expected profit E s i (λ,v,ρ) π * (r(λ, v, ρ)) in (3). Because expression ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>) is linear in min{r, 1 −r}, we simplify it as follows.</p><p>Lemma 3 (Equivalence of First-Stage Decision). The firststage test product design</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">max λ,v,ρ<label>(</label></formula><p>)</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">E s i λ,v,ρ ( ) π * r λ, v, ρ|r ( ) ( ) min λ,v,ρ ( ) E s i λ,v,ρ ( ) minr λ, v, ρ|r ( ) , 1 −r λ, v, ρ|r ( ) { } .</formula><p>The test product (λ, v, ρ) that maximizes the expected profit of the entrepreneur from launching the final product is equivalent to the test product that maximizes the expected learning, which is consistent with the expert opinion that test product aims to maximize learning (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Ries 2011)</ref>. We next present the closed form expressions for the optimal design of the test product by solving (3).</p><p>Proposition 2 (Optimal Test Product).</p><p>i. If r &gt; 0.5, then any (λ, v, ρ) ∈ S (i) is optimal, where</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">S i ( ) ≜ λ, v, ρ ( ) : v − ρ − λ ( )t, ∀λ ≤ 0 { } ∪ λ, v, ρ ( ) : v − ρ − + λ ( )t, ∀λ ≥ C/2 + { } ;</formula><p>ii. if r &lt; 0.5, then any (λ, v, ρ) ∈ S (ii) is optimal, where</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">S ii ( ) ≜ (λ, v, ρ) : v − ρ (C − − λ)t, ∀λ ≤ C/2 − { } ∪ λ, v, ρ ( ) : v − ρ − C − + λ ( ) t, ∀λ ≥ C { } ;</formula><p>iii. if r 0.5, then any (λ, v, ρ) in the following convex hull is optimal:</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">a. λ,v, ρ ( ) : v − ρ − λ ( )t, ∀λ ≤ 0 { } and λ, v, ρ ( ) : v − ρ C − − λ ( ) t, { ∀λ ≤ C/2 − }; or b. (λ, v, ρ) : v − ρ (− + λ)t, ∀λ ≥ C/2 + { } and λ, v, ρ ( ) : v − ρ − C − + λ ( ) t, ∀λ ≥ C { } .</formula><p>Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3</ref> illustrates the optimal test product stated in Proposition 3 in the (λ, v − ρ) plane. First, we observe that there are infinitely many optimal test products.</p><p>Also, the maximum learning occurs when the location of test product λ is on the exterior of the interval (0, C) in contrast to the pivoting decision. Moreover, the farther away it is, the higher the vertical quality v − ρ required to elicit the same level of information (this is to compensate for the greater disutility because of lack of fit). In particular, if the prior r &gt; 0.5, there are two sets of optimal test products (λ, v, ρ) indicated by the two solid (blue) lines; if the prior r &lt; 0.5, there are two sets of optimal test products (λ, v, ρ) indicated by the two dashed (red) lines. If the prior r 0.5, the optimal test product corresponds to the two sets of test products indicated by the shaded area.</p><p>Suppose that r &gt; 0.5 so that the entrepreneur initially believes that the ideal product W is more likely to be located at zero. The set of optimal test products depicted by the left line (λ, v, ρ) ∈ {(λ, v, ρ) : v − ρ (−λ + )t, ∀λ ≤ 0} represents test product designs whose position λ is closer to zero, more likely to be the ideal design. The quality v − ρ is set so that the test product will always sell if W 0 (eliminate false negative). Therefore, if the test product results in a sale (more likely event), the belief that W 0 is further strengthened (i.e.,r &gt; r &gt; 0.5); if the test product does not sell (less likely event), this reveals that the ideal product is W C (i.e.,r 0). The set of optimal test products depicted on the right line (λ, v, ρ) ∈ {(λ, v, ρ) : v − ρ (λ − )t, ∀λ ≥ C/2 + } represents test product designs for which the design position is closer to C, the design less likely to be ideal. The quality v − ρ is set such that the test product will never sell if W 0 (eliminate false positive). Therefore, if it leads to no sales (more likely event), the belief that W C will be weakened, and equivalently, the belief that W 0 will be strengthened (i.e.,r &gt; r &gt; 0.5); if the test product results in a sale (less likely event), it reveals that the ideal product is W C (i.e.,r 0). That is, the former Notes. The two solid lines (two dotted lines or two shaded areas, respectively) represent the set of optimal test products for r &gt; 0.5 (r &lt; 0.5 or r 0.5, respectively). The star (r ≥ 0.5) and the cross (r ≤ 0.5) represent the optimal test product with small pivoting friction (Section 5.1). set of test products aims to observe sales of a likely design to confirm it as ideal, whereas the latter aims to observe no sales of an unlikely design to rule it out as ideal.</p><p>The vertical and horizontal attributes of the optimal test product interact. Namely, it is optimal to either launch a test product more likely to be the ideal product with a higher quality (make sale of test product more likely) or launch a test product less likely to be ideal with a lower quality (make no sale of test product more likely). Both strategies lead to equivalent learning for the entrepreneur, suggesting that failure to sell a test product can be just as informative as success in selling it.</p><p>Corollary 1 presents further insights into the optimal test product by examining the cross-sections of E s i (λ,v,ρ) π * (r(λ, v, ρ)) with respect to the quality (v − ρ) and the design (λ) of the test product.</p><p>Corollary 1 (Properties of the Optimal Test Product). The entrepreneur's expected profit</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">E s i (λ,v,ρ) π * (r(λ, v, ρ)) is (a) increasing-decreasing in quality v − ρ of the test product and (b) minimized at λ C/2.</formula><p>The left panel of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4</ref> illustrates</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">E s i (λ,v,ρ) π * (r(λ, v, ρ)) evaluated at λ * 0 as a function of v − ρ.</formula><p>We observe that the entrepreneur should launch a test product with a quality (v − ρ) that is neither too high nor too low. As v − ρ increases, the probability of sale increases, reducing the false negative (no sale outcome becomes more informative) but increasing the false positive (sale outcome becomes less informative). If v − ρ is high so that the test product always results in a sale (for both W 0 and W C), receiving the sales outcome would result in no information about the consumer tastes. Similarly, as v − ρ decreases, the probability of sale decreases, increasing the false negative (no sale outcome becomes less informative) but reducing the false positives (sale outcome becomes more informative). If v − ρ is low so that test product never sells (for both W 0 and W C), receiving the "no sales" outcome does not give information about consumer tastes. The optimal value (v * − ρ * ) is an intermediate value that balances these two opposing effects. The right panel of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4</ref> illustrates E s i (λ,v,ρ) π * (r(λ, v, ρ)) evaluated at v * t as a function of λ. We observe that learning deteriorates as λ approaches C/2. If λ C/2 is chosen, no learning occurs regardless of the value v − ρ because sales are equally likely for both W 0 and W C.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Effectiveness of the LSM</head><p>So far, we have identified the optimal design of the test product (λ * , v * , ρ * ) and optimal pivoting decision Λ * . We now investigate the effectiveness of the LSM (peak benefit and sensitivity to implementation) and how it is influenced by the product-market environments.</p><p>As the benchmark, we assume that, without LSM, the entrepreneur will develop a product based on his prior belief r. This results in the profit:</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">π * 0 r ( ) p V − p t − V − p t − 1 − C 2 ( ) ( ) [ min r, 1 − r { } ] .</formula><p>The difference between the expression for E s i π * (r(λ, v, ρ|r). and π * 0 (r) boils down to the term β λ, v, ρ|r</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">( ) ≜ min r, 1 − r { } − E s i λ,v,ρ ( ) minr λ, v, ρ|r ( ) , 1 −r λ, v, ρ|r ( ) { } .</formula><p>This term β(λ, v, ρ|r) represents the reduction in probability of developing the wrong product (value of imperfect information) after implementing the LSM. We will refer to this term as benefit of the LSM and employ it to gauge the effectiveness of the LSM. Because the  LSM is used in settings with high market uncertainty, <ref type="bibr">13</ref> we focus on its effect when r 0.5, the entrepreneur's prior belief that represents the greatest uncertainty. Correspondingly, we focus on the optimal values (λ * , v * − ρ * ) (0, t). The following expressions reveal how the contextual parameters (C, , t) influence the effectiveness of the LSM.</p><p>Corollary 2 (Effectiveness of the LSM). The effectiveness of the LSM is characterized by its (i) peak benefit and (ii) sensitivity to implementation, which are given, respectively, as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">i. β λ * , v * , ρ * |0.5 ( ) C 4 , ii. ∂β λ, v, ρ|0.5 ( ) ∂ v − ρ ( ) ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ λ,v−ρ ( ) 0, t ( ) 1 4 t , if v − ρ &lt; t, − 1 4 t , if v − ρ &gt; t, { ∂β λ, v, ρ|0.5 ( ) ∂λ ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ λ,v−ρ ( ) 0, t ( ) 0, if λ &lt; 0, 1 , if λ &gt; 0. { Part (i)</formula><p>shows how the effectiveness of the LSM is influenced by the product-market environments. We observe that the peak benefit of the LSM increases in C and decreases in . Recall that the parameter C denotes the degree of market uncertainty. A higher C indicates less overlap between the two distributions and therefore, larger risk of developing the wrong product. The LSM shows greater peak effectiveness when there is a higher C because it reduces the probability of making the wrong choice. The parameter denotes the extent of consumer heterogeneity. When is larger, consumers are more spread out so that the risk of developing the wrong product will decrease. Because the benchmark is greater, the additional improvement by the LSM is reduced.</p><p>Part (ii) shows how the effectiveness of the LSM is influenced by the design of test product. We observe that the benefit of the LSM is more sensitive to the test product's quality (v − ρ) when the quantity • t is low and to horizontal design λ when is low. A lower t implies that consumers will purchase primarily based on the vertical quality of a product. In such a case, a small deviation from the optimal quality v * − ρ * of the test product could lead to a large fluctuation in the probability of test product's sale. Similarly, a lower indicates that more consumer tastes are concentrated around a product design. Thus, a small deviation in v − ρ or λ leads to a large deviation in the probability of test product's sale. In other words, when either or t is low, deviation from the optimal vertical value v * − ρ * or design λ * can quickly increase the false negatives or false positives and reduce the informativeness of the test product. So, the effectiveness of the LSM is sensitive to test product design. The dependence of effectiveness of the lean approach is summarized in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">1</ref>.</p><p>Practitioners often find a high variance in the reported effectiveness of the LSM (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Bosch et al. 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Dennehy et al. 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Hokkanen et al. 2016a, b)</ref>. Our model helps explain that this heterogeneity may be driven by differences in situations (e.g., one situation has higher C or lower than another) or because of implementation difficulties (i.e., entrepreneurs operate in the same product-market environment but with low or t).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Extensions</head><p>In this section, we examine four essential extensions of the model: (i) pivoting friction, (ii) endogenous pricing of the final product, (iii) multiple iterations, and (iv) more than two potential ideal products.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Impact of Pivoting Friction</head><p>Thus far, we have considered settings (e.g., software) where the pivoting friction is low (i.e., the cost of both pivoting and development are similarly low, hence normalized to zero). In many cases, however, pivoting friction is not negligible, and to overcome and implement the pivot, the firm would need to divert significant resources (e.g., time, money, people) away from development, impacting the final product quality V <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">(Teece et al. 2016</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">, Edison et al. 2017</ref>.</p><p>We assume that the resource diverted away for pivoting is proportional to the extent of the pivot, |Λ * − λ|. Then, the quality of the final product is represented by</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">V * V − f |Λ * − λ|,<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where f &gt; 0 indicates the magnitude of the friction.</p><p>(Observe that f 0 eliminates such a trade-off and reduces to the earlier analysis.)</p><p>The expression (6) characterizes the trade-off between the final product's quality (V * ) and fit (Λ * ) in the presence of pivoting friction. It endogenizes the final product quality V in the entrepreneur's secondstage problem (2) and replaces the V with V * (in the  <ref type="bibr">, , vol. 40, no. 3, pp. 395-412, © 2021</ref> interval defining the integral), complicating the pivoting decision Λ * in the second stage. Moreover, because the extent of the pivot depends on where you pivot from, the optimal second-stage profit depends on λ, so that π * (r) becomes π * (r, λ). This also influences the entrepreneur's design of the test product in the first stage, given by (3). We first examine the optimal pivoting decision Λ * , which depends on the location of the test product λ, the updated beliefr, and the magnitude of pivot friction f as illustrated next.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Proposition 3 (Optimal Pivoting Given Test Product).</head><p>Given posterior beliefr and λ, Λ * is as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">i. If f &lt; t, we have V * V − f |Λ * − λ|, where a. if λ ∈ (C − − V−p t , − V−p t ), then Λ * 1 1+f /t ( ) V−p t − + λ f t ( ) ,r &gt; 1−f /t 1+f /t , λ − V−p t &lt; − , λ,r &gt; 1−f /t 1+f /t , λ − V−p t &gt; − , 1 1−f /t ( ) − V−p t + λ f t ( ) ,r ∈ 1 2 1 − f t ( ) , 1−f /t 1+f /t ( ) , 1 1+f /t ( ) C − + V−p t + λ f t ( ) ,r &lt; 1 2 1 − f t ( ) ; ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ b. if λ ∈ ( − V−p t , C − + V−p t ), then Λ * 1 1+f /t ( ) C − + V−p t + λ f t ( ) ,r &lt; 1 2 1 − f t ( ) , λ, 1 2 1 − f t ( ) &lt;r &lt; 1 2 1 + f t ( ) , 1 1+f /t ( ) − V−p t − λf /t ( ) ,r &gt; 1 2 1 + f t ( ) ; ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ c. if λ ∈ (C − + V−p t , + V−p t ), then Λ * 1 1+f /t ( ) C + − V−p t − λ f t ( ) ,r &lt; 2f /t 1+f /t , λ+ V−p t &gt; C + , λ,r &lt; 2f /t 1+f /t , λ+ V−p t &lt; C + , 1 1−f /t ( ) C − + V−p t − λ f t ( ) ,r ∈ 2f /t 1+f /t , 1 2 1 + f t ( ) ( ) , 1 1+f /t ( ) − V−p t − λ f t ( ) ,r &gt; 1 2 1 + f t ( ) ; ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩</formula><p>ii. if f &gt; t, it is optimal to not pivot, and we have V * V and Λ * λ.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">5</ref> illustrates Proposition 3. Parts (ia) and (ib) are illustrated in the left and right panels, respectively (part (ic) is a mirror image of part (ia)). We first examine the two extreme cases of pivoting cost in both panels. First, if pivoting is frictionless ( f 0), then it is optimal to pivot to Λ * in the interior of (0, C) regardless of the starting location λ as defined in Proposition 1. The entrepreneur will then develop the product Λ * to quality V * V. If the pivoting friction is large ( f &gt; t), any gain from improved fit cannot offset the reduction in quality. Thus, it is optimal not to pivot at all and instead, develop the existing product with the highest possible quality, V. This is indicated by the blue (dashed) path in both panels.</p><p>When the pivoting friction is moderate ( f ∈ (0, t)), the optimal pivoting path is a compromise between the two extreme cases and is influenced by the location of λ, as indicated by the red (dotted) paths in both panels. The left panel represents the case with λ &lt; 0 (Proposition 3(ia)). In this case, ifr is sufficiently high (likely that W 0) and the pivoting cost is high, it is optimal to not pivot at all and instead, develop the highest-quality product V at the current location λ. Otherwise, it is optimal to pivot to Λ * , which lies in the interior of (0, C). Ifr &gt; 0.5, then Λ * is closer to zero, and ifr &lt; 0.5, it is closer to C. Observe that the quality V * is reduced according to the extent of pivot |Λ − λ|. The right panel represents the hybrid test product, λ ∈ (0, C) (Proposition 3(ib)). In this case, it is optimal to pivot toward zero or C only if the beliefr is sufficiently strong: that is, less than 0.5(1 − f /t) or greater than 0.5(1 + f /t), respectively. Otherwise, it is optimal to not pivot at all and to develop the highest quality at Λ * λ. Observe that, in both panels, the optimal pivoting location Λ * is interior to those with zero pivoting cost (green solid path) because of the increased need to hedge to account for the reduced value offering V * − p to customers.</p><p>We next examine the impact of pivoting cost on the optimal test product.</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">Proposition 4 (Optimal Test Product). i. Suppose f → 0. Then, λ * , v * − ρ * ( ) 0, t ( ), if r ≥ 0.5, C, t ( ), if r ≤ 0.5. { Furthermore, if ∂f ∂v &gt; 0, then ρ * 0 and v * t. ii. Suppose f &gt; t. Then, λ * , v * , ρ * ( ) − V−p t , V, p ( ) , if r ≥ 0.5, C − + V−p t , V, p ( ) , if r ≤ 0.5. ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩</formula><p>First, we observe that, compared with Proposition 3, the presence of small pivoting friction reduces the Note. In both panels, the solid (green) path indicates pivoting when f 0 (i.e., no pivoting friction), the red (dotted) path indicates optimal pivoting when f &lt; t (i.e., small pivoting friction), and the blue (dashed) path indicates optimal pivoting when f &gt; t (i.e., large pivoting friction).</p><p>Yoo, Huang, and Arifoglu: A Theoretical Analysis of the Lean <ref type="bibr">Start-up Method Marketing Science, 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 40, no. 3, pp. 395-412, © 2021</ref> optimal set of test products to one of two points (star and cross) in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3</ref>. These two points minimize the pivot distance compared with other test products that achieve the same learning. Moreover, if the pivoting friction increases in the quality of the test product, then it is optimal to reduce its price ρ → 0 so as to minimize v (while maintaining the same v − ρ) to save resources diverted away to pivoting. Next, if the pivoting friction is high ( f &gt; t), there is no pivoting in the second stage, and the optimal test product choice is identical to the second-stage final product launch decision.</p><p>Because of the complexity, we numerically examine the optimal test product for the intermediate range of pivoting costs, f ∈ (0, t). Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">6</ref> illustrates the contour plots for E s i π * (r, λ, v) and the optimal test product (represented by the stars) when r 0.5 as a function of the test product (λ, v, ρ) for f 0.01 (upper left panel), f 0.99 (upper right panel), f 0.3 (lower left panel), and f 0.7 (lower right panel). First, we observe that the numerical results confirm our analytical findings in the extreme cases of f . Namely, when f → 0, the optimal position of the test product λ is either zero or C (Proposition 4(i)), and the optimal quality is v * t; when f &gt; t, the contour plots are vertical lines, and the optimal position of test product is either −</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">V−p t ∈ (0, C) or C − + V−p t ∈ (0, C) (Proposition 4(ii)).</formula><p>Next, we observe that, as the pivoting cost increases from f 0.01 (upper left panel) to f 0.3 (lower left panel) to f 0.7 (lower right panel) to f 0.99 (upper right panel), the shape of the contour plots undergoes a continuous transformation. The optimal test product location, however, does not change continuously. Instead, based on our numerical analysis, there appears to be a threshold value for the pivoting cost f below which the optimal test product corresponds to the case for f 0 (i.e., λ * ∈ {0, C}) and above which it corresponds to the location for f &gt; t (i.e., (λ * ∈ { −</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">V−p t , C − + V−p t }).</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Endogenous Pricing</head><p>We next examine the case where the final product's price p is endogenously determined by the entrepreneur. Specifically, in the second stage after updating his belief tor, the entrepreneur determines the price and pivot location Λ simultaneously. We examine how this additional degree of freedom in the second stage impacts the design of test product in the first stage. Mirroring Assumption 1, we consider the setting where V ≤ Ct to ensure that V − p * &lt; t so that finding the product-market fit remains key to generating demand.</p><p>The second-stage problem (2) becomes</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">π * r ( ) ≡ max Λ,p p ∫ Λ− V−p ( ) t Λ+ V−p tr • h x|W 0 ( ) [ + 1 −r ( )• h x|W C ( ) ] dx max p max Λ p ∫ Λ− V−p ( ) t Λ+ V−p tr • h x|W 0 ( ) [ [ + 1 −r ( )• h x|W C ( ) ] dx ] max p p V − p t − V − p t − 1 − C 2 ( ) ( ) [ minr, 1 −r { } ] ,</formula><p>where the first equality is because of joint concavity of the profit function and the second equality follows from Proposition 2. The optimal price p * of the final product is characterized in Lemma 4.</p><p>Lemma 4 (Optimal Price).</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">p * V 2 + minr, 1 −r { } maxr, 1 −r { } t 2 1 − C 2 ( ) .</formula><p>Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">7</ref> (left panel) illustrates Lemma 4 and shows that it depends on the amount of learning. In particular, the entrepreneur reduces the price of the final product if the learning from the test product improves (i.e.,r → 0 orr → 1). The intuition is as follows. Suppose that the entrepreneur completely learned the ideal product design so that he pivots to develop it. Then, demand will reduce more if he increases the price. In contrast, if the entrepreneur learned nothing, then he can expect his pricing to influence only a small fraction of the consumer population. As such, the demand curve becomes steeper with increased learning. Yoo, Huang, and Arifoglu: A Theoretical Analysis of the Lean <ref type="bibr">Start-up Method Marketing Science, 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 40, no. 3, pp. 395-412, © 2021</ref> Hence, the entrepreneur would reduce the price to capture higher profits as he learns more.</p><p>The objective in the first period is to find the optimal test product that would maximize the optimal expected second-stage profit. The expression for the objective is presented next.</p><p>Lemma 5 (Expected Profit). Let s i ≡ s i (λ, v, ρ) andr ≡ r(λ, v, ρ|r):</p><formula xml:id="formula_31">E s i π * r ( ) E s i t 4 V t + minr, 1 −r { } maxr, 1 −r { } 1 − C 2 ( ) [ ] × V t − V t − 1 − C 2 ( ) [ ] minr, 1 −r { } [ ] .<label>(7)</label></formula><p>Unlike the expression in Proposition 2, the expression for expected profit is no longer a linear function of E s i min{r, 1 −r}. Thus, examining the optimal test product (λ, v, ρ) that maximizes ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_31">7</ref>) is analytically difficult, and we resort to numerical examples. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">7</ref> (right panel) illustrates the profit for the case where the prior r 0.5 so that the location of test product is symmetric, and we can focus on test product's quality as the measure for learning. The right panel of the figure plots the profit without pricing (solid curve) and with pricing (dashed curve) with respect to test product's quality v.</p><p>First, we find that the optimal test product does not change as a result of endogenizing pricing; in other words, v * 6 for both endogenous and exogenous price. Moreover, comparing the dashed curve (endogenous price) with the solid curve (exogenous price), we find that the difference between the two curves also increases as test product's quality v approaches to the optimal quality v * 6 (i.e., as learning from the test product increases). This indicates that learning by the test product accentuates the impact of flexible pricing, suggesting a complementary relationship between flexible pricing and learning via the test product.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.">Multiple Iterations of the Test Product Launch</head><p>Thus far, we assumed a single iteration of the buildtest-learn loop. In practice, the entrepreneur has the option of launching the test product and updating his belief multiple times. In such a setting, what should the optimal test product be? To gain insight into the impact of multiple iterations, we assume that the test product can be launched n times. For tractability, however, we restrict the entrepreneur's choice of test product and final product location and assume that λ, Λ ∈ {0, C}.</p><p>The optimal design and quality of the test product with n periods to go are presented next.</p><p>Proposition 5 (Optimal Policy for n Iterations). Let λ n ∈ {0, C}, v n , and ρ n denote the optimal design location for the test product and its quality and price with n periods to go, respectively. If h(x|W) is uniformly distributed in [W − , W + ], &gt; C/2, then the optimal test product is as follows for all n,</p><formula xml:id="formula_32">λ * n , v * n − ρ * n ( ) 0, t ( ), r ≥ 0.5, C, t (</formula><p>), r &lt; 0.5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>{</head><p>Proposition 5 reveals that, even with multiple additional iterations, it is optimal to first launch the test product with the design that the entrepreneur believes to be ideal and with value v n − ρ n t. Yet, this also implies that it is optimal to launch a test product that increases quality v n and price ρ n after each successive iteration, provided that the v n − ρ n remains the same.</p><p>Furthermore, to understand how the policy is implemented dynamically, we examine the optimal policy for launching the test product over two periods, as illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">8</ref>. Suppose that r &gt; 0.5. In period 1, the entrepreneur launches the test product (λ, v) (0, t). If the test product is not sold (less likely outcome), it is revealed that the ideal product W C (r 0), pivots and launches the final product Notes. We assume ρ 0 for simplicity. Parameters: V 10, p 7 (right panel), r 0.5, (C, , t) (5, 3, 2).</p><p>Yoo, Huang, and Arifoglu: A Theoretical Analysis of the Lean <ref type="bibr">Start-up Method Marketing Science, 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 40, no. 3, pp. 395-412, © 2021</ref> with design Λ C without the need to launch an additional test product. If the test product results in a sale (more likely outcome), then the entrepreneur strengthens his belief that W 0 so thatr &gt; r. In the second build-test-learn iteration, the entrepreneur launches the test product with the same position λ 0 but has flexibility in v and ρ. If a sale does not occur (less likely outcome), it is revealed that the ideal product is W C (r 0), and so, the entrepreneur pivots and launches it; if a sale occurs (more likely outcome), he strengthens his belief that W 0 is the ideal product even further, stays the course, and launches Λ * 0. The dynamic illustration shows that, if the test product is optimally selected, a single iteration could be optimal if the test product results in no sale, suggesting that a single iteration may be sufficient if the entrepreneur learns sufficiently well.</p><p>We next return to the benefit function β(λ, v, ρ|0.5) to examine the effectiveness of the LSM that allows for multiple iterations. The following corollary reveals the peak benefit of the LSM involving multiple iterations to go when the entrepreneur has a prior belief r.</p><p>Corollary 3 (Effectiveness of the LSM with n Iterations to Go). The peak benefit of the LSM with n iterations to go is</p><formula xml:id="formula_33">β n λ * , v * , ρ * |0.5 ( ) 1 2 1 − 1 − C 2 ( ) n+1 ( ) .</formula><p>Recall that, in the single iteration setting, the benefit of the LSM β(0.5) is C 4 . Thus, the additional iteration of a test product launch increases the benefit of the LSM, but it does so in a marginally decreasing manner.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4.">More than Two Candidate Ideal Products</head><p>Thus far, we have assumed that the ideal product was one of two locations W ∈ {0, C}. We now extend it to more than two and consider W ∈ {−C, 0, C}. As before, we consider h(x|W) to be uniformly distributed between [W − , W + ], ∈ [C/2, C], as illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure">9</ref>.</p><p>Observe that zero is symmetrically positioned between −C and C. To gain analytical insights, again, we assume a discrete set of design locations λ, Λ ∈ {−C, 0, C}.</p><p>Let us denote the prior probabilities with r 0 P(W 0) and r C P(W C), so that 1 − r 0 − r C P(W −C). To simplify notations, let</p><formula xml:id="formula_34">D 1 ≜ ∫ V−p t +Λ − V−p t +Λ h x|W Λ ( ) dx, D 2 ≜ ∫ V−p t +Λ − V−p t +Λ h x| |W − Λ| C ( ) dx,</formula><p>so that D 1 and D 2 are demand from launching the ideal product and adjacent-to-ideal product, respectively. (If Λ C and W −C, then the demand is zero.) The entrepreneur's second-stage problem in (2) becomes</p><formula xml:id="formula_35">π * r 0 ,r C ( ) maxr 0 D 1 + 1 −r 0 ( )D 2 ,r C D 1 +r 0 D 2 , { 1 −r 0 −r C ( ) D 1 +r 0 D 2 }.</formula><p>The following lemma characterizes the entrepreneur's optimal pivoting decision.</p><p>Proposition 6 (Optimal Pivoting). Suppose that after pivoting, we haver 0 andr C . Then,</p><formula xml:id="formula_36">Λ * r 0 ,r C ( ) C, r C &gt; D 2 D 1 + 1 − 2 D 2 D 1 ( ) r 0 , r C &gt; 1 2 − 1 2 r 0 0, r C ≤ D 2 D 1 + 1 − 2 D 2 D 1 ( ) r 0 , r C ≥ 1 − D 2 D 1 ( ) − 2 1 − D 2 D 1 ( ) r 0 . −C, r C &lt; 1 − D 2 D 1 ( ) − 2 1 − D 2 D 1 ( ) r 0 , r C &lt; 1 2 − 1 2 r 0 ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩</formula><p>The left panel of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">10</ref> illustrates the optimal pivot location as a function of posterior r 0 and r C . We observe that when the posterior is such that r 0 r C 1/3 (highest uncertainty), the optimal pivoting location is Λ * 0 as a way to hedge and take advantage of the fact that 0 overlaps with both C and −C. This is consistent with our finding in the base model.</p><p>We next examine the first-stage optimal design of the test product to maximize the expected profit in the final period launch E s i π * (r 0 ,r C ). Suppose that the prior belief is (r 0 , r C ) and the entrepreneur launches the test product (λ, v). Letr 0 andr C (r 0 and r C , respectively) denote the Bayesian posterior beliefs after observing  </p><formula xml:id="formula_37">λ∈ −C,0,C { } ,v P Sale of λ, v ( ) ( ) π * r 0 ,r C ( ) + 1 − P Sale of λ, v ( ) ( ) ( ) π * r 0 , r C ( ).</formula><p>The following characterizes the optimal test product for key settings. (The remaining settings are complemented numerically.)</p><formula xml:id="formula_38">Proposition 7 (Optimal Test Product). Suppose h(x|W) is uniformly distributed between [W − , W + ] where W ∈ {−C, 0, C}, ∈ [C/2, C]. i. If r 0 0, then λ * , v * ( ) ±C, t ( ).</formula><p>ii.</p><formula xml:id="formula_39">If r C 0 or 1 − r 0 − r C 0, then, respectively, λ * , v * ( ) 0, t ( ) r 0 ≥ 0.5 −C, t ( )r 0 ≤ 0.5 { or λ * , v * ( ) 0, t ( ) r 0 ≥ 0.5, C, t ( ) r 0 ≤ 0.5. { iii. If r 0 1/3, then λ * , v * ( ) C, t ( ) r C ≥ 1/3 −C, t ( ) r C ≤ 1/3. {</formula><p>The right panel of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">10</ref> illustrates the optimal location of the test product. Proposition 7(i) shows the case when r 0 0 (vertical solid line) where the ideal product W ∈ {−C, C}. In this case, because there is no overlap between h(x|W C) and h(x|W −C), launching a test product with quality v t at either location will reveal the ideal product location. If the entrepreneur launches a test product in C (or −C) and it sells, he confirms that C (or −C) is ideal; if it does not sell, he confirms that instead −C (or C) is ideal. The entrepreneur can then pivot appropriately to launch the ideal product. Proposition 7(ii) shows the case when r C 0 or r 0 + r C 1 (two dashed lines on the edges of the triangle) where there is zero probability that C or −C is the ideal product. In this case, the setting reduces to the original setting with two potential ideal products, and it is optimal to launch a test product that is more likely to be the ideal product. For example, if r 0 ≥ 0.5, then it is optimal to launch λ 0. If a sale occurs, it is optimal to stay the course and launch Λ 0; if a sale does not occur, it is optimal to pivot and launch C (or −C).</p><p>Finally, Proposition 7(iii) shows the case when r 0 1/3 (circle in the middle of the triangle). If r C &gt; 1/3, then C is more likely than −C to be the ideal product. In this case, it is optimal to launch a test product at location λ C. If it results in sales, it is optimal to stay the course and launch the final product at Λ C; if the test product does not result in sales, it is optimal to pivot to −C to launch the final product in Λ −C. The reason the pivot does not happen to zero is that, if sales do not occur, it becomes more likely that it is because the ideal product is in −C rather than zero. Interestingly, we observe that, when (r 0 , r C ) (1/3, 1/3) (which is the point with the highest uncertainty), the optimal location of the test product λ 0. This is consistent with our earlier analysis in Section 4 that the test product should be in the exterior (C or −C) to maximize learning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusion</head><p>The LSM is widely followed by entrepreneurs for their early product development. Its key paradigm is Yoo, Huang, and Arifoglu: A Theoretical Analysis of the Lean <ref type="bibr">Start-up Method Marketing Science, 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 40, no. 3, pp. 395-412, © 2021</ref> experimentation using build-test-learn cycles, which involves engaging early with customers to learn what they want from using test products and then pivoting product development objectives according to its feedback. Despite the influence of this approach, to date there has been no formal characterization of how learning occurs and why LSM is effective. To the best of our knowledge, our paper is the first to critically examine the build-test-learn cycle of the LSM using an analytical model. By developing a formal model to study the LSM, we investigate how the features of the test product (e.g., design, quality, and price) influence the entrepreneur's learning and pivoting decision. We have also been able to investigate how the productmarket conditions influence LSM's effectiveness.</p><p>Our paper can inform practice and future research relating to LSM. Practitioners often find it challenging to gather useful feedback through early versions of a product <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Hokkanen et al. 2016a, b)</ref> or have difficulty progressing the test product toward the final product that consumers seek <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Bosch et al. 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">, Dennehy et al. 2016</ref>. Our insights can help entrepreneurs better implement LSM and to set expectations about its effectiveness when they deploy them. On the theoretical front, Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">1</ref> presents an empirically testable hypothesis about how the product-market environment (i.e., market uncertainty, consumer heterogeneity, and strength of horizontal preference) influences the observed variance in the effectiveness of the LSM. Empirically confirming or disproving such a relationship would be a fruitful direction for further research to enhance our understanding about the LSM.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Endnotes</head><p>1 Throughout this paper, a "test product" refers to the product that is used to learn quickly and cost effectively about consumer preferences, which might be interpreted as the "minimum viable product (MVP)" in practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Merryweather 2020)</ref>. The LSM literature vaguely uses MVP and does not specify what "minimum" or "viable" means (e.g., see Ambler 2017). Because of this vagueness, the term MVP represents a broad notion ranging from a rather prototype-like product to a full-fledged and marketable product <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Ambler 2017</ref>). We use "test product" instead of "MVP" to avoid confusion. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> The concept of penny gap refers to the huge difference in customer behaviors between taking a product that is free and buying a product that costs a penny. Crossing the penny gap indicates the consumer's willingness to engage in an exchange, which need not be monetary, such as time, effort, or providing information <ref type="bibr">(Patel 2011). 3</ref> The essence of LSM has been applied in several large firms (e.g., General Electric) in their new product development processes. However, the implementation is more about fostering collaboration between sales and engineering teams, rather than iteration of the build-test-learn loop <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">(Power 2014</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">, Harris 2017</ref>). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Many other similar examples abound, including those of Dropbox, Groupon, Zappos <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Aberant 2018)</ref>, CarsDirect <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Allen 2015)</ref>, PayPal, and LinkedIn <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Hoffman and Yeh 2018)</ref> just to name a few. Similar iterative learning can be found in the nuclear energy sector, where start-ups such as TerraPower take advantage of advances in supercomputing to learn about the viability of potential nuclear technology <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Nanda and Rhodes-Kropf 2016)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> For a more detailed look at terminologies, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Garcia and Calantone (2002)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> The distinction is similar to innovation in form (design) and function <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Chan et al. 2018</ref>). 7 Note that t is not inherently connected to our model or the test product; instead, it is common across all products and can be estimated through market research (e.g., efficacy of drugs implies low t, whereas taste in flavor or color may have high t). Consistent with the literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Netessine and</ref><ref type="bibr">Taylor 2007, Huang et al. 2018)</ref>, we focus on the uncertainty in the design of the test product and assume that the parameter t is known and exogenously given. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> Because of the novelty of the product, there is higher uncertainty compared with incrementally innovative products. This results in less competition, consistent with the assumption of the LSM <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Blank 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">, Allen 2015</ref>). 9 This range of C ensures overlap between h(x|W 0) and h(x|W C) to make learning relevant. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> We consider sampling multiple customers in the launch of a single test product in Online Appendix A. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> We have also considered the case when the selected consumer reveals her surplus s i with probability ξ &lt; 1. The key insights do not change, however. Please see Online Appendix A. <ref type="bibr">12</ref> We show robustness of the results to this assumption numerically by considering different distributions for h(x|W) in Online Appendix A. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> One can show that β(λ, v, ρ|r) is unimodal in r and maximized at r 0.5 for any λ, v, and ρ. This is intuitive because r 0.5 represents the prior belief where the entrepreneur has the most uncertainty about the location of the ideal product W, and the benefit of the LSM increases with the entrepreneur's level of uncertainty.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. (Color online) Impact of Design Location (Λ) on Demand</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. Sequence of Events</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3. (Color online) Optimal Set of Test Products Illustrated in the (λ, v − ρ) Plane</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4. (Color online) Sensitivity of E si(λ,v,ρ) π * (r(λ, v, ρ)) with Respect to Quality v − ρ Evaluated at λ 0 (Left Panel) and with Respect to λ Evaluated at v − ρ t (Right Panel)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5. (Color online) Illustration of Optimal Pivoting from a Given Test Product (λ, v) to (Λ * , V * )</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6. (Color online) Contour Plots for Expected Revenue E si(λ,v,ρ) π * (r (λ, v, ρ), λ) Based on Test Product's Attribute (λ, v) for f 0.01 (Upper Left Panel), f 0.99 (Upper Right Panel), f 0.3 (Lower Left Panel), and f 0.7 (Lower Right Panel)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7. (Color online) Optimal Price as a Function of Learning (Left Panel) and Profit Comparison of E si π * (r, λ, v) With and Without Pricing (Right Panel)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Figure 8. (Color online) Test Product Is Launched over Two Stages</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 10 .</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Figure 10. (Color online) Optimal Pivot Location (Left Panel) and Test Product Location (Right Panel) in (r 0 , r C ) Space</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Yoo, Huang, and Arifoglu: A Theoretical Analysis of the LeanStart-up Method   Marketing Science, 2021, vol. 40, no. 3, pp. 395-412, © 2021 </figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Yoo, Huang, and Arifoglu: A Theoretical Analysis of the LeanStart-up Method   Marketing Science, 2021, vol. 40, no. 3, pp. 395-412, © 2021 </figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Yoo, Huang, and Arifoglu: A Theoretical Analysis of the Lean Start-up Method</figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science, 2021, vol. 40, no. 3, pp. 395-412, © 2021 INFORMS</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Benefit and Sensitivity of the LSM, Depending on C, , and t Yoo, Huang, and Arifoglu: A Theoretical Analysis of the Lean Start-up Method</figDesc><table><row><cell>ΔPeak benefit</cell><cell>ΔSensitivity to implementation</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Yoo, Huang, and  Arifoglu: A Theoretical Analysis of the Lean Start-up Method Marketing Science, 2021, vol. 40, no. 3, pp. 395-412, © 2021 INFORMS sale (no sale, respectively) of test product. The firststage problem of the entrepreneur (3) becomes max</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Vol. 40, No. 3, May-June 2021, pp. 395-412</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The power of minimum viable products (and the key to their success)</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Aberant</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">CMS Wire</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.cmswire.com/digital-experience/the-power-of-minimum-viable-products-and-the-key-to-their-success" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-01-23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Launching New Ventures: An Entrepreneurial Approach</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cengage Learning</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>7th ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">When to be agile: Ratings and version updates in mobile apps</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Allon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Askalidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Berry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Immorlica</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Moon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.3476286</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.3476286" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Disciplined Agile (DA) Framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ambler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mvp</forename><surname>Defining</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mmp</forename><surname>Mmf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mmr</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.projectmanagement.com/blog-post/61937/Defining-MVP-MMF-MMP-and-MMR" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-08-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The dynamic pricing of next generation consumer durables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bayus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="265" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crowdsourcing new product ideas over time: An analysis of the Dell IdeaStorm community</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bayus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="226" to="244" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sequential product development and introduction by cash-constrained start-ups. Manufacturing Service Oper. Management, ePub ahead of print</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhaskaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Erzurumlu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ramachandran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1287/msom.2020.0895</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1287/msom.2020.0895" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-10-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Bhide</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The Origin and Evolution of New Businesses</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Four Steps to Epiphany</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Blank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<publisher>K&amp;S Ranch Consulting Inc</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Thermal, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>3rd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why the lean start-up changes everything</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Blank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Harvard Bus. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2013</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
			<date type="published" when="2013-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The early stage software startup development model: A framework for operationalizing lean principles in software startups</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bosch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Holmstrom Olsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bjork</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J ;</forename><surname>Ljungblad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Fitzgerald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Huang</forename><surname>Yoo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arifoglu</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Theoretical Analysis of the Lean Start-up Method Marketing Science</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="395" to="412" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>© 2021 INFORMS</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Conby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Power</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Valerdi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Stol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Lean Enterprice Software and Systems, LESS 2013. Lecture Notes in Business Information Processing</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">167</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Should entrepreneurs plan or just storm the castle? A meta-analysis on contextual factors impacting the business planning-performance relationship in small firms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Brinckmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Grichnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kapsa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Venturing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On styles in product design: An analysis of US design patents</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Chan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mihm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sosa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1230" to="1249" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stage-gate systems: A new tool for managing new products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bus. Horizons</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="54" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimizing the stagegate process: What best-practice companies do</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Edgett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kleinschmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Res. Tech. Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The predictive power of Internet-based product concept testing using visual depiction and animation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Dahan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Product Innovation Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="109" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does business planning facilitate the development of new ventures?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Delmar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Strategic Management J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1165" to="1185" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Product market fit frameworks for lean product development</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dennehy</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">R&amp;D Management Conference</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kasraian</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">R&amp;D Management Conference</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>O'raghallaigh</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">R&amp;D Management Conference</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Conboy</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">R&amp;D Management Conference</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">From Science to Society: Innovation and Value Creation</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, United Kingdom</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The wave of unicorn IPOs reveals Silicon Valley&apos;s groupthink: There is more to life than blitzscaling</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.economist.com/briefing/2019/04/17/the-wave-of-unicorn-ipos-reveals-silicon-valleys-groupthink" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economist</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-04-17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">WeWork shows why some venture capitalists are in a world of make-believe: The entrepreneur&apos;s new clothes</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.economist.com/business/2019/09/28/wework-shows-why-some-venture-capitalists-are-in-a-world-of-make-believe" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economist</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-09-28" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lean internal startups for software product innovation in large companies: Enablers and inhibitors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Edison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smorsgard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Abrahamsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Systems Software</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1452" to="1466" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sequential testing of product designs: Implications for learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Erat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kavadias</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="956" to="968" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cost of experimentation and the evolution of venture capital</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ewens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Nanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rhodes-Kropf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Financial Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">128</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="422" to="442" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A critical look at technological innovation typology and innovativeness terminology: A literature review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Garcia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Calantone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Product Innovation Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="110" to="132" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Valuing R&amp;D projects in a portfolio: Evidence from the pharmaceutical industry</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Girotra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Terwiesch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ulrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1452" to="1466" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The venture capital revolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gompers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lerner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Perspect</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="168" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Venture Capital Cycle</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gompers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lerner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to build a minimum viable platform</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gracia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.sharetribe.com/academy/how-to-build-a-minimum-viable-platform/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sharetribe</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-07-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conjoint analysis in consumer research: Issues and outlook</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conjoint analysis in marketing: New developments with implications for research and practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="19" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://medium.com/startup-foundation-stories/ge-the-startup-f3317a3fdfee" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-02-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">GE the startup. Medium.com</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Website morphing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Urban</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Liberali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="202" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Friends or foes? The interrelationship between angel and venture capital markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hellmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Thiele</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Financial Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="639" to="653" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring preferences for really new products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hoeffler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="406" to="420" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Blitzscaling: The Lightning-Fast Path to Building Massively Valuable Companies (Penguin Random House</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hoffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Yeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Early product design in startups: Toward a UX strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hokkanen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kuusinen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Väänänen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>; Abbrahamsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Corral</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Olivo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Russo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="s">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9459</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="224" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Product-Focused Software Process Improvement. PROFES</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Minimum viable user experience: A framework for supporting product design in startups</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hokkanen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kuusinen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Väänänen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Agile Processes, in Software Engineering, and Extreme Programming</title>
		<title level="s">Lecture Notes in Business Information Processing</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Sharp</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cham, Switzerland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">251</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="78" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stability in competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Hotelling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">153</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="1929" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The value of &quot;bespoke&quot;: Demand learning, preference learning, and customer behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3129" to="3145" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Democracy in product design: Consumer participation and differentiation strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Katona</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="359" to="394" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Entrepreneurship as experimentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Kerr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Nanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rhodes-Kropf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Perspect</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="48" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Product development decisions: A review of the literature</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Krishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ulrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">User-generated content and competing firms&apos; product design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kwark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Raghunathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4608" to="4628" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Acquisition of project-specific assets with Bayesian updating</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Kwon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lippman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Oper. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1119" to="1130" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Market research and innovation strategy in a duopoly</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Lauga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ofek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="373" to="396" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Constrained Bayesian optimization with noisy experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Letham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Karrer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ottoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bakshy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://arxiv.org/abs/1706.07094" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-06-21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Preprint</note>
	<note>submitted</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning from experience, simply</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="19" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimizing product launches in the presence of strategic consumers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Lobel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Patel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Vulcano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1778" to="1779" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parallel and sequential testing of design alternatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Loch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Terwiesch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Thomke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="663" to="678" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Marketing and discontinuous innovation: The probe and learn process</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lynn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Paulson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Calif. Management Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8" to="37" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New product models: Practice, shortcomings and desired improvements</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wind</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Product Innovation Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="128" to="139" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The difference: Prototype vs MVP</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Merryweather</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://productschool.com/blog/product-management-2/difference-prototype-mvp/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-08-15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Financing entrepreneurial experimentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Nanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rhodes-Kropf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Innovation Policy Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Product line design and production technology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Netessine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="101" to="117" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Entrepreneurial Marketing: An Effectual Approach (Routledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Nijssen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A diffusion theory model of adoption and substitution for successive generations of high-technology products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Norton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1069" to="1086" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Huang</forename><surname>Yoo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arifoglu</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Theoretical Analysis of the Lean Start-up Method Marketing Science</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="395" to="412" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">To innovate or imitate? Entry strategy and the role of market research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ofek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Turut</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="575" to="592" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Four questions for developing a minimum viable product</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Patel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.geekwire.com/2011/questions-developing-minimum-viable-product/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Geekwire</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-11-22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How GE applies lean startup practices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Power</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://hbr.org/2014/04/how-ge-applies-lean-startup-practices" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-04-23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">HBR.org</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Read</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sarasvathy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Dew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Wiltbank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Ohlsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<pubPlace>Routledge, New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Effectual Entrepreneurship</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ries</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The Lean Startup</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Penguin Group</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing conjoint choice experiments using managers&apos; prior beliefs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Sandor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="430" to="444" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Causation and effectuation: Toward a theoretical shift from economic inevitability to entrepreneurial contingency</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Sarasvathy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acad. Management Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="243" to="263" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Selectionism and learning in projects with complexity and unforeseeable uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Sommer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Loch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1334" to="1347" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic capabilities and organizational agility: Risk, uncertainty, and strategy in the innovation economy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Teece</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Peteraf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Leih</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Calif. Management Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="35" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing experimentation in the design of new products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Thomke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="743" to="762" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Democratizing Innovation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Von Hippel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal search for the best alternative</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Weitzman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="641" to="654" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal entry timing for a product line extension</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Norton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individually adapted sequential Bayesian conjoint-choice designs in the presence of consumer heterogeneity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Goos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Vandebroek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Res. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="378" to="388" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Huang</forename><surname>Yoo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arifoglu</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Theoretical Analysis of the Lean Start-up Method Marketing Science</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="395" to="412" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
