<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2019-10-25">October 25, 2019</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
							<email>mike.lewis@emory.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Goizueta School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Emory University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>30322</postCode>
									<settlement>Atlanta</settlement>
									<country key="GE">Georgia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yanwen</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>yanwen.wang@sauder.ubc.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">UBC Sauder School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of British Columbia</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>V6T 1Z2</postCode>
									<settlement>Vancouver</settlement>
									<region>British Columbia</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Chunhua</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
							<email>chunhua.wu@sauder.ubc.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">UBC Sauder School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of British Columbia</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>V6T 1Z2</postCode>
									<settlement>Vancouver</settlement>
									<region>British Columbia</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 (print)</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2019-10-25">October 25, 2019</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.2019.1183</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: December 4, 2015 Revised: November 29, 2017; August 5, 2018; March 8, 2019 Accepted: June 10, 2019</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:25+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>secondary markets</term>
					<term>season ticket buyers</term>
					<term>ticket resale Lewis, Wang, and Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Abstract. Sports franchises derive significant portions of their revenues from season ticket holders. A development that may affect season ticket management is the growth of legal secondary markets. We develop a structural model that integrates both the supply and demand sides of the secondary market into season ticket buyers' ticket purchase and usage choices. We use a panel data set that combines season and single ticket purchase records with ticket usage data to investigate the value of secondary markets. We estimate that the secondary market increases the team's season ticket revenues by about $1 million per season. At the level of the individual season ticket customer, we estimate an increase in customer lifetime value ranging from $1,327 in the lowest quality seat tier to $2,553 in the highest. In terms of value to the customer, the average dollar value of having a secondary market is $138 per season ticket. Across segments, the secondary market provides the equivalent of a 4% discount in the premium seat tier versus an 11% discount in the economy seat tier. Whereas the secondary market creates more value in the premium-ticket tier segments, the secondary market has the most impact on behavior in the low price oriented segment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Season ticket customers of sports franchises often exhibit strong loyalty and are an important source of team revenues. However, consumer's decisions to purchase season tickets involve a complex set of expectations and options that complicate efforts to model consumer demand. For instance, season ticket buying decisions involve significant uncertainty about product quality because customers purchase season tickets in advance of the events <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Desiraju and Shugan 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">, Xie and Shugan 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">, Moe and Fader 2009</ref>. There are also issues related to bundling and quantity discounts. Consumers have the option to purchase either single game tickets at full price or season ticket packages at a discount.</p><p>A development that may have consequences for season ticket buyer management is the establishment of legal and easy to use secondary markets. While secondary markets have long been a feature of the sports industry, trusted and legal digital secondary markets such as StubHub are a relatively recent innovation. Markets like StubHub add further complexity to season ticket buyer management by creating additional options for consumers. First, a secondary market may have positive consequences on season ticket purchases because consumers can recoup costs by selling unneeded or valuable tickets. Alternatively, a secondary market might have a negative impact on season ticket sales if it creates an alternative supply of tickets that reduces the need to precommit to a bundle of tickets <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Tuchman 2015)</ref>. Furthermore, if many season ticket buyers utilize a secondary market, this may push down resale prices and make the resale option of season tickets less attractive. Whether an efficient secondary market adds value to season tickets depends on the consequences of these counteracting mechanisms. Therefore, it is not straightforward as to whether secondary markets provide an incentive or a deterrent for season ticket purchases.</p><p>The objective of our paper is to investigate how the increased options provided by a secondary market change the value proposition for potential season ticket buyers and how this change in value impacts the economic value of these customers to the team. We build a structural model of consumer demand and conduct several counterfactual analyses related to the operation and regulation of secondary markets.</p><p>The structural model is developed around the idea that at the start of season, season ticket purchase decisions are based on the expected utility from planned ticket usage in terms of attendance, reselling, or nonusage. It also allows sets of single game tickets to be purchased directly from the secondary market or the team to be a substitute for season ticket packages. It captures the key trade-off involved in encouraging secondary markets. Because of the temporal separation of season ticket purchase and actual games, we allow fans to form game quality expectations based on scheduled dates, home and opponent team performance in the previous season, and team payrolls for the upcoming season. The model considers the collective utility of the entire Major League Baseball (MLB) 81 game slate.</p><p>We assemble a panel data set that combines consumer ticket transactions with ticket usage records for the seasons from 2011 to 2016 for a Major League Baseball team. We augment the buying and usage data with secondary market listing and transaction data from a ticket broker. This provides a complete picture of season ticket holders' game-level usage, as we are able to observe whether each ticket was used for attendance, listed, resold, or forgone. We use actual quality preferences, based on ticket quality levels, as a source of observable heterogeneity.</p><p>A key challenge in this analysis is modeling the interdependence between the supply of and the demand for the secondary market ticket. Our research provides a contribution through the simultaneous modeling of secondary market ticket supply and demand. We also model the season ticket holder's pricing decision. Season ticket holders who decide to list a ticket for resale select a game-specific listing price that maximizes the utility of attempting to resell a ticket. We derive closed form expressions for the probability of listing tickets and the differentiated optimal prices on the secondary markets that are based on game quality, secondary market demand parameters, and each seller's price sensitivity and preferences for listing tickets on the exchange. The joint model of supply and demand in the secondary market facilitates the computation of market equilibriums in the counterfactual analyses.</p><p>The overall impact of the secondary market on the attractiveness of season ticket buying involves the trade-off between the value of the unbundling option provided by secondary markets versus the opportunity of constructing customized sets of single game tickets via the team and the secondary market. This trade-off depends on the interdependence between supply of and demand for tickets on the secondary markets. High secondary market demand increases the value of season tickets by increasing the option value of selling unneeded or valuable tickets. In contrast, increased secondary market supply decreases the appeal of season ticket purchases because season ticket bundles may be affordably replaced with single game tickets purchased on the secondary market. Identification of the secondary market demand and supply factors is achieved through two key sources of exogenous variation in the data. First, we leverage exogenous variation in revealed team quality to identify the willingness of season ticket holders to participate in the secondary market. Second, the ease of transacting in secondary markets may change over time due to more accessible secondary market mobile apps 1 or sellers' accumulated experience in listing on secondary markets. The trend toward greater ease or convenience provides an exogenous shifter of secondary market demand.</p><p>Substantively, we find that the secondary market creates incremental value for season ticket holders and thereby increases season ticket purchase and retention rates. The ability to resell tickets provides a means for season ticket buyers to benefit from unwanted or highly demanded tickets. In terms of the team's customer management metrics, our policy experiments suggest that the secondary market increases season ticket purchasing rates by 4.27 percentage points. The effect is smallest for customers that tend to choose the highest quality tickets and becomes more substantial for customers that choose lower quality tickets. We also estimate the dollar value of the secondary market by calculating the necessary discount to match the utility provided by secondary market's options. The dollar value of the secondary market varies across quality segments. For the highest quality ticket buyers, the dollar value is $160 per season ticket or about a 4% discount. For the lowest quality tickets, the secondary market provides the equivalent of 11% discount ($73 value).</p><p>When evaluating the economic value of the secondary market to season ticket revenues, we also consider the potential cannibalization of single game ticket sales due to the alternative supply of unbundled season tickets on secondary markets. If the secondary market provides a reliable source of tickets, the team may end up competing with the secondary market in terms of single game sales. We compute a conservative estimate of the impact of the secondary market on single game sales in a scenario that all season ticket holders' resale transactions replace purchases from the team. This is a conservative assumption, as it neglects the market expansion effects of the secondary market. Under this assumption, combining the revenue gains from season ticket package purchases and the potential cannibalization of single game gate ticket sales, the net revenue impact of the secondary market would be $6.1 million over six years.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Background</head><p>One key aspect of season ticket purchases is advance purchasing. Season tickets are usually purchased in advance of the season, whereas single game tickets are more often purchased within seasons. The marketing literature has considered the topic of advance buying with an emphasis on exploiting segment differences to maximize firm revenues <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Desiraju and Shugan 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">, Xie and Shugan 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">, Moe and Fader 2009</ref>. Advance buying is especially relevant in sports because bundles of tickets are purchased before the quality of the team is fully revealed. In this type of consumer decision making, it is important to model consumer expectations. One goal of our research is to develop a modeling framework that accounts for quality expectations across a bundle of heterogeneous items. This is a complex challenge given that MLB season tickets include 81 separate elements. In the context of season ticket holder management, expectations are likely focused on the quality of the home team. Models of season ticket buying should include factors correlated with winning rates such as past success and future payrolls <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Lewis 2008</ref>) and information on opponent quality.</p><p>As noted, season tickets are also distinct because they are bundles or collections of games. Previous researchers have focused on issues related to pricing bundles of tickets. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Hanson and Martin (1990)</ref> formulate the bundle pricing problem as a mixed integer programming problem and investigate a variety of scenarios related to customer reservation prices, firm costs, and number of components. <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Venkatesh and Mahajan (1993)</ref> propose a method for optimally pricing bundles of performances based on customers' time availability to attend events and reservation prices for musical performances. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Ansari et al. (1996)</ref> extend <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Venkatesh and Mahajan's (1993)</ref> model to also consider decisions regarding the number of events (components) to be held and for alternative objectives such as maximizing attendance. In these models, the primary focus is on the quantity discount aspect of season tickets. The key insight in this stream of research is that the valuation of the bundle should consider the cumulative value of the component parts.</p><p>The sports context includes a number of elements that complicate the analysis of bundling. First, organizations often pursue a mixed strategy where tickets may be purchased through season ticket packages or as single game tickets. This means that the analysis needs to consider the substitutability of subsets of single game tickets for season ticket packages. Second, there has been little discussion in the literature of contexts where product quality of the bundled components is uncertain. This type of structure complicates model development, as it becomes necessary to consider the role of consumer expectations. Third, the existence of a secondary market may provide a means for consumers to unbundle sets of products.</p><p>There is an established literature focused on how secondary markets in durable goods categories act as a competitor to firms' marketing efforts <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Desai and</ref><ref type="bibr">Purohit 1998, Hendel and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Lizzeri 1999)</ref>. In the sports context, there is a limited literature focused on secondary ticket markets. This literature has mainly focused on the topic of dynamic pricing. Using data from the 2007 Major League Baseball season, <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Sweeting (2012)</ref> finds that secondary market sellers cut prices by 40% as the time to event decreased. <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Zhu (2014)</ref> presents an aggregate structural model of consumer ticket purchase decisions of buying from StubHub versus teams. <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Zhu (2014)</ref> finds that optimal dynamic pricing by a team results in an increase in revenue of only 3.67%. <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Leslie and Sorensen (2014)</ref> examine ticket resale markets for single events. They focus on the welfare implications of ticket resale markets using data on rock concerts. However, they do not explicitly model the interdependence between resale prices and listing. This is an important omission because as resale prices increase, there is likely to be an endogenous increase in the utility of listing, which may increase the utility of buying season ticket packages. We propose a structural model to simultaneously consider ticket supply and aggregate demand in the secondary market. This structure facilitates counterfactual analyses related to the value of secondary markets to season ticket holders under different rules of market operation.</p><p>Two recent papers investigate the option value of secondary markets <ref type="bibr">(Shiller 2013, Ishihara and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Ching 2019)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Ishihara and Ching (2019)</ref> model the role of used markets on new goods sales in the context of Japanese video games. In this model, consumers decide to purchase new or used video games or not purchase. Conditional on previous purchase, consumers decide to sell or not. This model assumes consumers are forwardlooking in terms of expected resale value. Our context and model are different from those of <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Ishihara and Ching (2019)</ref> in key aspects. For example, season tickets are bundles of perishable items rather than a durable item such as a video game. This changes key elements of the decision related to purchase timing and requires that any modeling effort considers the option to separate the season ticket package into component parts. The common practice of discounting season tickets is also a relevant distinction. Season ticket prices are often cheaper than resale prices offered on secondary markets. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Lewis, Wang, and</ref><ref type="bibr">Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and</ref><ref type="bibr">Secondary Market Options Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 6, pp. 973-993, © 2019 INFORMS 3. Data, Model-Free Evidence, and</ref><ref type="bibr"></ref> Reduced-Form Analyses</p><p>Our data include transaction histories for season ticket buyers of a Major League Baseball team for the seasons from 2011 to 2016. The sample consists of 1,924 customers 2 who purchased season ticket packages at least once during the 2011 to 2016 seasons. Each customer has a unique account number that allows tracking each customer's season and single game ticket purchases over the six-year period. For each transaction, we observe the ticket type (quality tier) purchased and the price paid. The team also tracks ticket usage through bar codes and is able to monitor attendance and ticket resales conducted via StubHub.</p><p>The team data contain successful resale information but do not include information on listed tickets that do not sell. We augment the team data with ticket listing data from a data broker. We are, therefore, able to observe whether a ticket is used for attendance, listed, resold or forgone. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> In this section, we provide several sets of descriptive data and reduced-form analyses that provide insight into the relationship between the options afforded by the secondary market activity and customer behaviors such as retention. This material reveals basic patterns of consumer behavior and motivates the structure of our model in the next section. In these analyses, we also devote significant attention to segment-level differences based on ticket quality preferences. This material highlights important customer management issues faced by the team.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Descriptive Statistics</head><p>Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1 and 2</ref> illustrate several issues related to consumer demand over time. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows the distribution of ticket quality and purchase incidence decisions across seasons. The table is organized around the six ticket quality tiers defined by the team. The purchase incidence rate of season tickets for the sample was 66.4% during the six-year period. The table shows the proportion of customers purchasing within each of the quality tiers and the percentage of those not buying in a given season. In terms of ticket quality, about 11% of customers purchase in the highest priced tier (tier 1), whereas about 6% purchase in the lowest quality level (tier 6). The most common quality tier for season ticket holders is tier 2, which accounts for approximately 20% of customers. The proportion of the sample not purchasing season ticket packages increased over time, from 26% in the 2011 season to approximately 50% in the 2016 season due to declining on-field performance over the six years. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> shows the renewal rates for season ticket buyers, conditional on previous seat tier choice. There is a substantial stickiness in the purchase of season tickets. The year-to-year renewal rate of season tickets is over 83% in the highest quality seat tiers (tiers 1-4). Renewal rates for tiers 5 and 6 are about 75%. There is limited switching across seat tiers.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref> shows data related to pricing and the importance of season ticket sales across sections. The top of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref> presents average per game season ticket prices and single game ticket prices across tiers. There are several notable aspects of the pricing schedule. First, ticket prices are substantially different across seat tiers. The team under study classifies tickets into six quality tiers. The average season ticket price per ticket ranged from $54 in the highest quality tier to $8 in the lowest quality tier. Second, season tickets are discounted from 35% to 50% relative to single game tickets, with a smaller discount (35%) for high quality tier tickets. There is smaller variation in season ticket prices within each category relative to single game prices because the team varies the prices of single games based on opponent and time factors (weekend, day versus night). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> The bottom of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref> shows the percentage of season ticket sales per tier. For the two highest quality seat tiers, 80%-86% of seats are purchased by season ticket buyers. The percentage of tickets purchased by season ticket holders decreases as seat quality diminishes, with less than 30% for tiers 5 and 6. The concentration of season ticket purchases in the most expensive tiers highlights the economic importance of these customers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Secondary Market Behaviors and Segment-</head><p>Level Differences Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">4</ref> provides insights into the ticket usage options provided by the secondary market. The top portion of the table shows consumers' intended ticket usage as of the day before each game. We infer intention based on whether a ticket is listed prior to a given game. Specifically, if we observe that an individual has listed a ticket on the secondary market before the game, we interpret this as an intention to resell rather than attend the game. The attendance and forgoing rates reflect the usage decisions for nonlisted tickets. There is substantial variation in attending and reselling intentions across seat tiers. Higher quality ticket holders are more likely to plan on game attendance. For example, the intended attendance rates in tiers 1 and 2 are more than 70%, whereas the rate for tier 6 is only 50%. Broadly, resale listing rates tend to grow as ticket quality diminishes. The higher quality tier tickets (tier 2) have a listing rate of 6%, whereas the lowest quality tier tickets have a 12% rate.</p><p>Although listing may reflect consumer desires to sell, listings may fail if demand is weak or prices are set too high. If a ticket fails to sell, then the consumer makes an additional decision of whether to attend. The middle of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">4</ref> shows reselling success rates for listed tickets across seat tiers. On average, there is a 36% probability that a listed ticket will sell on the secondary market. The resale rates in high quality tiers are about 10% higher than in low quality tiers. There is also variation in the contingency behaviors across different quality tiers when resale attempts fail. When a listing does not sell, there is a 68.4% chance that tier 1 season ticket holders choose to attend instead of forgoing the ticket, versus 33% for tier 6 ticket holders.</p><p>These differences in reselling and usage rates suggest that season ticket holders with different quality ticket preferences differ in their resale motivations. High quality tier holders are less likely to list and more likely to attend when listings fail. These high value customers might have higher reservation values and therefore might price tickets higher. This also explains the lower listing frequency. For buyers of lower quality tickets, there seems to be less interest in attending games and greater interest in selling tickets. The "actual usage" section of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">4</ref> reports the ultimate ticket usage decisions by seat tier.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">5</ref> shows key pricing data including secondary market listing prices and resale transaction prices. List prices tend to be set at values close to single game ticket prices. The list-to-single price ratio ranges from about 1 for tier 1 to 0.84 for tier 6 tickets. Differences in responses to failed reselling attempts may explain the variation in season ticket holders' secondary market pricing decisions. If a customer is more likely to use a ticket that fails to sell, then that customer may be more likely to try for a higher price. The observed data are consistent with our speculation that the "residual" usage value of an unsuccessful resale could be a driver of the listing price. Actual resale prices (from successful transactions) are lower than the listing prices. Secondary market tickets tend to sell at values between the season ticket and single game prices.</p><p>Another key question is whether resale prices and probabilities are a function of the aggregate level of season ticket reselling. This is important because increased secondary market use might impact equilibrium list prices, resale prices, and resale probabilities. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">6</ref> reports the results of three analyses that investigate this issue. The first column reports a logistic regression of secondary market ticket resale success as a function of the percentage of season ticket holders listing tickets on the secondary market. We include the list price ratio (listed prices versus single game prices), seat tier, and game quality measures as control variables. As a proxy for game quality, we use  the total gate ticket revenues for the game. The second regression models ticket list price ratios on the percentage of season ticket holders listing, game quality, and seat tier. The third regression predicts the resale price ratio using the same explanatory variables. We find a significant negative effect of secondary market competition on the dependent variables in each analysis. This suggests that the value provided by the secondary market to season ticket holders may be limited by supply factors. As a secondary market attracts more season ticket holders, the increased supply can push down equilibrium prices and resale probabilities. 5</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Customer Retention</head><p>Although the preceding analyses highlight the options available to customers and differences in behavior across quality based segments, they do not speak directly to purchase and retention. We next attempt to link secondary market activities and single game purchasing activity to customer retention. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">7</ref> highlights the substitutability of single game tickets for season ticket packages. The first row of the table reports the number of single game tickets purchased by customers that did not renew season tickets. When customers allow season tickets to lapse, they often continue to attend games. In the observation period, lapsed season ticket buyers purchased approximately 14 games directly from the team. Far fewer games are purchased on the secondary market versus directly from the team (0.12 versus 14 games).</p><p>The second row shows single game buying patterns in the year prior to a season ticket purchase. On average, customers that became season ticket buyers purchased 23.48 games in the previous year. The higher single game purchases make sense, as these consumers were likely becoming more interested in the team over time. In comparison, these future season ticket buyers were relatively inactive on the secondary market, as this group purchased 0.23 games on StubHub. The segment of customers interested in season tickets has a strong preference for purchasing season and single game tickets from the team. These results guide our model development. First, the data show that season ticket packages and single game tickets operate as substitutes. Second, the secondary market is not a significant source for tickets for the season ticket-oriented segment of consumers, but it is important to accommodate the alternative supply of tickets from the secondary market. The impact of the secondary market on customer retention may also be viewed in terms of the potential incremental value that the secondary market provides to season ticket buyers. We next examine the relationship between efforts to recoup expenses and renewal rates. The "actual" recouping percentage is calculated as a dollar value of successful resales divided by the amount paid for season tickets. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows a scatter plot of the actual recoup percentage and season ticket purchase frequency. The figure   <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">8</ref>, show that the actual dollars recouped during a season have a significant positive impact on the renewal decision for the next season.</p><p>In addition to these bivariate relationships between renewal and dollars recouped, we also analyzed the link between individuals' secondary market activity, including listing attempts, sales, and season ticket renewal decisions. We model season ticket holders' renewal rates as a function of ticket reselling success on the secondary market. We estimated a logistic regression of the form</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Renew it β 0i + Season t β 1 + β 2 AttdRate i,t−1 + β 3 ListRate i,t−1 + β 4 ResaleRate i,t−1 + β 5 RPR i,t−1 + β 6 Resale• Rate i,t−1 ×RPR i,t−1 + ϵ it .</formula><p>The Renew it term indicates whether customer i purchases a season ticket package in season t, β oi controls for individual random effects, Season t controls for year fixed effects, AttdRate i,t−1 is last season's game attendance rates, ListRate i,t−1 is last season's ticket listing percentage, ResaleRate i,t−1 is the successful resale rate conditional on listing, and RPR i,t−1 measures the average ratio between individual i's resale prices and gate prices in season t − 1. This analysis leverages within-individual, across-season variations in renewal decisions, listing rates, and resale rates. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">9</ref> shows the panel logistic regression results. The first notable observation is that after controlling for attendance rate, a higher ticket listing percentage is a positive indicator for season ticket renewal. Second, resale success and listing prices matter. We find that the effect of successful resale rates is moderated by the resale price. At the average resale price ratio of 0.62, a 1% increase in resale rates will increase the renewal odds ratio by 1.3%. However, low resale prices can interact negatively with resale rates. If the resale price ratio is 0.11, a 1% increase in resale success will reduce the renewal odds ratio by 5.8%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.">Data Summary</head><p>The preceding descriptive statistics and reducedform analyses reveal important aspects of how a secondary market for tickets influences the behavior of season ticket customers. The data suggest that the secondary market provides options for ticket usage and provides value to season ticket buyers. Consumers have the option to sell tickets, attend games, or discard tickets. These options can also be conditional because some customers exercise the option to   attend if a resale attempt fails. We also observe that season packages and single game tickets can serve as substitutes. These findings suggest that econometric analyses of fan buying behavior should explicitly model the complex set of options available to consumers. There are also correlational data showing that greater success in disposing of tickets on the secondary market is positively related to renewing. However, this analysis also suggests that if consumers are able to obtain only very low prices, then renewal rates suffer. This analysis provides initial evidence of both the importance of the secondary market in providing incremental value to customers and also evidence that supply and demand forces can mitigate the value proposition. Finally, the differences in behavior across quality tiers highlights the importance of considering observable quality preference heterogeneity when implementing the model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Model</head><p>In this section, we develop a structural model of season ticket purchasing, single game buying, and game-level usage. At the core of our model are the various consumer options regarding ticket type choice and usage, and the interdependence between resale listing decisions and resale prices on the secondary markets. The overarching logic of the modeling approach is illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Usage Decision of Season Tickets</head><p>Given the temporal separation of season ticket purchases relative to the actual usage of tickets, we start by modeling consumer's utility of using each ticket prior to the game day. The core of this analysis is the utility of attending a given game. Consumer i's utility from attending game g with a quality tier j season ticket in season t is given in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">1</ref>):</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">u A igt|j Q igt|j + ε A igt|j ,<label>( 1 )</label></formula><p>where Q igt|j indicates consumer i s perceived game quality before the game day, and ε A igt|j is an error term that follows the standard type I extreme value distribution. We specify game quality as Q igt|j β 1ij + X gt β 2i + W gt β 3i + ξ 1gt , where β 1ij are seat tier preferences, X gt includes the set of game attributes known at the beginning of each season, and W gt includes variables that only become available as a given game approaches. The set of game attributes X gt include year fixed effects, game schedule type indicators (weekday, night, holiday), the opposing team's winning percentage from last season, and relative pay rates at the beginning of this season. The home team's quality level is captured through year fixed effects. The W gt variables include data that are learned as the season progresses, including the home and opposing teams' cumulative winning percentages from the beginning of the season to game g, the absolute difference between the home and visiting team's winning percentages, the home team's current winning or losing streak, and the home team's current divisional standing measured by "games back" from the division leader. We demean the components of W gt . Finally, we also include a game-specific unobserved shock term ξ 1gt . This term captures game quality factors not included in the observed game attributes {X gt , W gt }, such as competition from other entertainment events. The realized shock ξ 1gt is observed by consumers but not the researcher. Consumer i with a tier j season tickets can also forgo game g. We normalize the mean utility of forgoing a ticket to zero in Equation (2):</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">u F igt|j ε F igt|j ,<label>( 2 )</label></formula><p>where the error term ε F igt|j follows the standard type I extreme value distribution.</p><p>Next, we model the utility of listing a ticket for resale. We model listings rather than resale transactions, because not all listings are successful. The   <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">3</ref>)) is the cost associated with listing on the secondary market plus a weighted average of revenues from a successful resale and the maximum value of attending or forgoing a game when an attempt fails:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">u L igt|j −c it + q r igt|j ( ) • δβ 4i • r igt|j • GateP gt|j + ε L igt|j ( ) + 1 − q r igt|j ( ) ( ) • max u A igt|j , u F igt|j { } .<label>(3)</label></formula><p>In this equation, c it represents the costs (time and effort) incurred by consumer i when listing a ticket on the secondary market. We parameterize c it as In(c it )</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">Z it ρ i ρ 1i + ρ 2i In(Season t ) +ρ 3i In(CumListings i,t−1 + 1),</formula><p>as the online secondary markets become easier to use over time, and the listing cost may differ depending on individuals' listing experience with the secondary market. We include the logarithm of season trend and the logarithm of an individual's cumulating listings in the observed attributes Z it . The second component represents the utility from a successful resale, where q is the probability of a successful sale, and the expression in the parentheses is the revenue gain from the sale. The δ term captures the commission charged by the secondary market platform. We set δ to 0.90, as StubHub charges a 10% commission rate for sellers. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Parameter β 4i is the price coefficient that captures the marginal utility from a dollar gain for the consumer.</p><p>This specification allows us to measure each seller's listing cost in dollar form as c it β 4i</p><p>. We normalize the list prices by the tier-specific gate prices and model the ratio of list prices relative to gate prices, r igt|j , as the decision variable. As noted in the data section, gate prices per seat tier GateP jgt are set at various levels before the start of the season based on the team's perceptions of each opponent's box office appeal and the schedule time factors (i.e., day versus night, weekday). We include an error term ε L igt|j to reflect the unobserved utility from a successful resale. The last component of the equation reflects the utility associated with a failed resale attempt. When a season ticket holder cannot resell a ticket, he or she can still obtain utility by either attending a game or forgoing use of a ticket.</p><p>The utility of listing can be viewed in probabilistic terms. We illustrate the rationale behind resale attempts with two extreme scenarios. In the case that a listed ticket k has a 0% chance to be sold on the secondary market (q k,jgt 0) and consumer i has a schedule conflict where max{u A igt|j , u F igt|j } u F igt|j , then no attempt at resale should be made, as</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">u L igt|j −c it + u F igt|j &lt; u F igt|j .</formula><p>In contrast, if a listed ticket k can be sold for certain (q k,jgt 1), then the ticket should be listed as long as the revenue gain δβ 4i • r igt|j • GateP gt|j exceeds the listing cost c it .  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Resale Probability</head><p>We model secondary market demand through the resale probability q k,jgt of each listed ticket k of tier quality j for game g in season t using an aggregate logit form as in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_6">4</ref>):</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">q k,jgt exp γ 1j + γ 2 A gt + γ 3 L jgt − γ 4 r k,jgt + ξ 2gt ( ) 1 + exp γ 1j + γ 2 A gt + γ 3 L jgt − γ 4 r k,jgt + ξ 2gt ( ) ,<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where γ 1j are tier-specific intercepts, term A gt represents perceived game quality for game g an average fan, term L jgt is the observed percentage of season tickets listed on secondary markets, and term r k,jgt is the ratio of secondary market price relative to gate price. Coefficient γ 4 measures secondary market buyers' price sensitivity.</p><p>We specify the perceived game quality of an average secondary market ticket buyer as A gt X gtβ2 + W gtβ3 . The game quality is a function of the information available prior to the season, X gt , and the team and opponent performance data revealed as a season progresses, W gt . We use the average preference parameters to approximate the quality perception of an average fan. We also include an unobserved secondary market demand shock, ξ 2gt , and allow a covariance structure between ξ 1gt and ξ 2gt , where ξ gt~N (0, Σ ξ ). We allow correlation because the same unobserved factor could drive season ticket holders' attendance and secondary market demand for the game. For simplicity, we denote a jgt γ 1j + γ 2 A gt + γ 3 L jgt + ξ 2gt and write the probability q k,jgt exp a jgt − γ 4 r k,jgt ( )</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">1 + exp a jgt − γ 4 r k,jgt<label>(</label></formula><p>) .</p><p>(5)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Secondary Market Listing Prices</head><p>A critical component of the model is the customer's decision of the listing price when selling on the secondary market. Given the trade-off between recouping costs by making a sale and the utility of attending or forgoing following a failed resale, each customer decides on a game-specific list price ratio r * igt|j (list price relative to gate price) that maximizes utility. An expression for a consumer's optimal list price ratio r igt|j can be determined by taking the first-order condition of Equation (3). The optimal list price ratio is written as</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">r * igt|j max u A igt|j , u F igt|j { } − ε L igt|j δ × β 4i × GateP gt|j + q r * igt|j ( ) ∂q r * igt|j ( ) /∂r igt|j ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ ⃒ . (6)</formula><p>Depending on the shape of the secondary market demand curve q(r * igt|j ), there is a shared level of the optimal list price ratio q(r * igt|j ) |∂q(r * igt|j )/∂r igt|j | . However, every individual will have a different markup</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">max{u A igt|j , u F igt|j }−ε L igt| j δ × β 4i × GateP gt|j , as</formula><p>he or she has a different utility of attending or forgoing a game. This feature of the first-order condition explains why, conditional on seat tier and game attributes, there is still a distribution of list prices. If we insert the resale probability q k,jgt from Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_6">4</ref>) into Equation ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>), we obtain a closed-form expression for the optimal list price ratio (see Web Appendix B, Section B.1):</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">r * igt|j a jgt − In t igt|j + W t igt|j ( ) γ 4 ,<label>( 7 )</label></formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">t igt|j exp ( a gt|j − γ 4 × max u A igt|j , u F igt|j { } − ε L igt|j δ×β 4i ×GateP gt|j − 1 )</formula><p>, and W(•) is the Lambert W function. Given that the observed listing price ratio may be different from the analytical optimal list price, we add the random error and let r igt|j r * igt|j + ε r igt|j , where ε r igt|j~N (0, σ 2 r ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.">The Probability of Listing Season Tickets to Resell</head><p>Season ticket holders will list a ticket on secondary markets if the utility of listing is larger than the maximum utility from either attending or forgoing a game. This can be represented as</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">Pr [ −c it + q r igt|j ( ) • δβ 4i • r igt|j • GateP gt + ε L i|jgt ( ) + 1 − q r igt|j ( ) ( ) • max u A igt|j , u F igt|j { } ≥ max u A igt|j , u F igt|j { } ] .<label>(8)</label></formula><p>We can then insert the optimal list price ratio r * igt|j (Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_10">7</ref>)) to obtain the following expression:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">Pr [ δβ 4i • GateP gt|j γ 4 ( a gt|j − 1 − In γ 4 c it δβ 4i GateP gt|j ) − c it + ε L igt|j ≥ max u A igt|j , u F igt|j { } ] .<label>(9)</label></formula><p>Given that both the error terms in the attend and forgo utility specifications follow type I extreme value distributions, we can express the distribution of the maximum of the two as max{u </p><formula xml:id="formula_14">A igt|j , u F igt|j } v AF igt|j + ε AF igt|j ,</formula><formula xml:id="formula_15">Pr u L igt|j ≥ max u A igt|j , u F igt|j { } [ ] exp φ L igt|j ( ) exp φ L igt|j ( ) + exp v AF igt|j ( ),<label>(10)</label></formula><p>Lewis, Wang, and Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options where</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">φ L igt|j δβ 4i •GateP gt|j γ 4 a gt|j − 1 − In γ 4 c it δβ 4i GateP gt|j ( ) − c it .<label>(11)</label></formula><p>Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_15">10</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_16">11</ref>) show that the probability of listing a season ticket to resell is a function of secondary market demand parameters a gt|j and γ 4 , as well as the season ticket holder's price coefficient β 4i and listing cost c it . This allows for more resale listings as a season ticket holder's price coefficient β 4i increases.</p><p>Alternatively, the probability of listing will decrease if the listing cost c it increases or if secondary market buyers become more price sensitive γ 4 . The inclusion of this supply and demand structure is essential and particularly relevant for counterfactual analyses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5.">Season Ticket Purchase</head><p>The season ticket purchase decision is made prior to the start of the season. This introduces significant uncertainty, as consumers can make only probabilistic judgments about team quality over the season.</p><p>Our assumption is that consumers have rational expectations of game quality based on information {X gt } available before the start of the season. The expected game quality before the start of a season takes the form E(Q igt|j ) β 1ij + X gt β 2i , where X gt includes the set of game attributes known at the beginning of each season. In contrast to the usage decision information set, the terms for within season data W gt and ξ 1gt are not included. An important implication of our specification of game quality is that the expected quality of a game at the time of season ticket purchase may deviate from the revealed game quality at the time of ticket usage decisions (game day). The discounts provided for season ticket packages may be viewed as compensation for the consumer's precommitment for this uncertainty.</p><p>The expected usage utility of any single game is a function of the three usage options, to attend, forgo, or list a ticket to resell. Before the start of a season, consumers only have the information in {X gt } to inform a season ticket purchase decision. We replace the game quality perception Q igt|j with E(Q igt|j ) in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">1</ref>) and the secondary market game quality perception A gt with E(A gt ) in Equation (3). We denote the expected game attendance and listing utility before the start of a season asũ A igt|j andũ L igt|j where• reflects the expectation.</p><p>The expected overall usage utility for game g is the weighted average of the expected utility of attending game or forgoing a ticket, max{ũ A igt|j ,ũ F igt|j } and the expected listing utilityũ L igt|j , with the corresponding weights equal to Pr[max{ũ A igt|j ,ũ F igt|j }≥ũ L igt|j ] and Pr[ũ L igt|j ≥ max{ũ A igt|j ,ũ F igt|j }], respectively. We express the expected usage utility USE igt|j of a season ticket for game g in tier j in season t for consumer i as</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">USE igt|j ∫˜ε A igt|j ∫˜ε F igt|j ∫˜ε L igt|j Pr maxũ A igt|j ,ũ F igt|j { } ≥ũ L igt|j [ ] • maxũ A igt|j ,ũ F igt|j { } + Prũ L igt|j ≥ maxũ A igt|j ,ũ F igt|j { } [ ] •ũ L igt|j dε A igt|j dε F igt|j dε L igt|j .<label>(12)</label></formula><p>We show more details on the integration of error terms in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_35">19</ref>) in Web Appendix B, Section B.3. Given the expected usage utility USE igt|j , consumer i's utility of buying a season ticket follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">u S ijt k S i + τ i ∑ 81 g 1 USE igt|j − τ i β 4i SeasonP jt + ε S ijt , (<label>13</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_19">)</formula><p>where SeasonP jt refers to the season ticket price for a particular seat tier j in season t. SeasonP jt shares the same price coefficient β 4i as the resale revenue in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">3</ref>) as we assume the value of a dollar spent is the same as a dollar collected in the secondary market. We assume the value of the season ticket package depends on the additive sum of the usage utility from each game in a season, ∑ 81 g 1 USE igt|j . We acknowledge that our additive summation assumption helps alleviate the model calibration burden. Yet, it does not capture the possibility that different combinations of games attended may yield utilities beyond the pure additive summation. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> We include a scale parameter τ i for ∑ 81 g 1 USE igt|j and β 4i SeasonP jt , as they involve a summation over 81 games and are on a different scale from the additive unobserved term ε S ijt . Intercept k S i captures the intrinsic value of buying a season ticket as opposed to not committing to season ticket packages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.6.">Single Game Purchase</head><p>The model-free evidence shows that a collection of single tickets may be a substitute for a season ticket package. Rather than normalize the no-purchase option (j 0) to zero, we allow the utility of not committing to season tickets to be a function of consumers buying single game tickets. We use a nested decision process with the upper level representing the choice of buying a single game ticket from the team, from the secondary market, or not at all. The lower level involves the decision of which seat quality tier to buy.</p><p>Specifically, at the lower decision level, we model the utility of buying a tier j single ticket to game g in season t directly from the team as The game quality measure at the time of buying a gate ticket has the same specification as that in the season ticket attendance decision in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">1</ref>), as consumers have more revealed game quality information as the season rolls out. Similarly, we model the utility of buying a tier j single ticket to game g from secondary market as</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">u G ijgt Q ijgt − β 4i GateP jgt + ε G ijgt . (<label>14</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_21">u SD ijgt Q ijgt − β 4i SecondP jgt + ε SD ijgt . (<label>15</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_22">)</formula><p>The main difference between the equations is that in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_20">14</ref>), the consumer decision involves the gate price, whereas in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_21">15</ref>) consumers pay the secondary market price (SecondP jgt ). We make two simplifying assumptions. First, customers are guaranteed a ticket in the secondary market. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> Second, the secondary price, SecondP jgt , is a fraction of the gate price GateP jgt , where the fraction is the observed list price ratio relative to the gate prices for each game and seat tier under market equilibrium. These two assumptions allow us to incorporate the impact on season ticket buying of having secondary markets. The expanded choice options allow for the possibility that a secondary market may enhance the value of not committing to season ticket packages. We let both ε G ijgt and ε SD ijgt follow the standard type I extreme value distribution.</p><p>At the upper decision level, the utilities of buying from the team directly, u G igt , and from the secondary market, u SD igt , are given as</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">u G igt k G i + λ i In [ ∑ 6 j 1 exp ( v G ijgt λ i )] + ε G igt , (<label>16</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_24">)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_25">u SD igt k SD i + λ i In [ ∑ 6 j 1 exp ( v SD ijgt λ i )] + ε SD igt ,<label>(17)</label></formula><p>where v G ijgt and v SD ijgt are the deterministic parts in the utility functions in Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_20">14</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_21">15</ref>). The inclusive value of any seat tier choice is captured in a closed form with the scale parameter λ i . Intercepts k G i and k SD i indicate the intrinsic value of choosing the specific purchase outlet as compared with the outside option of not attending a game. We normalize the mean utility of the outside option to zero such that <ref type="figure">and ε</ref> O igt follow the standard type I extreme value distributions.</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">u O igt ε O igt . Terms ε G igt , ε SD igt ,</formula><p>Next, we model the expected utility of forgoing season tickets and instead waiting to buy single game gate tickets for any subset of the 81 games at the time of season ticket purchase. We replace the game quality perception Q ijgt with the expected game quality E(Q ijgt ), where E(Q ijgt ) β 1ij + X gt β 2i . The term X gt contains only game quality information that is available before the start of the season. We also replace the secondary price SecondP jgt with the expected market equilibrium secondary priceSecondP jgt under a rational expectation assumption. The expected secondary price is imputed via fixed point algorithms to match the calibrated listing probability with the observed season ticket holders' listing probability in the data (Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">3</ref>)). Assuming that the utility from attending games is an additive sum of the games attended, <ref type="bibr">9</ref> we write the utility of not buying a season ticket u S i,j 0,t as</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">u S i0t τ i ∑ 81 g 1 In 1 + expṽ G igt ( ) + expṽ SD igt ( ) [ ] + ε S i0t . (<label>18</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_28">)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_29">Termṽ G igt k G i + λ i In [ ∑ 6 j 1 exp(˜v G ijgt λ i ) ]</formula><p>is the deterministic part of the expected utility of buying a single ticket from the team in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_23">16</ref>), andṽ</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">SD igt k G i + λ i In [ ∑ 6 j 1 exp(˜v SD ijgt λ i ) ]</formula><p>is the deterministic part of the expected utility of buying a single ticket from secondary markets in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_25">17</ref>). Consistent with the season ticket utility part, we scale the inclusive value by the scale τ i in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_27">18</ref>). This structure captures the key trade-off involved in having a secondary market.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.7.">Heterogeneity</head><p>We model consumer heterogeneity using a hierarchical structure. We use θ i (β i , ρ i , k i , λ i , τ i ) to indicate the set of parameters that vary across individuals. We include both observed and unobserved individual heterogeneity as θ i θ + ΠD i + Σv i , where D i is a vector of observed demographics including individuals' tenure in years with the team, distance to the home stadium, and the median household income in individuals' zip codes (all three on the ln scale). The term Σ is the variance-covariance matrix of the unobserved heterogeneity, and v i 's are independent and identically distributed standard normal errors. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.8.">Likelihood</head><formula xml:id="formula_31">We let + it (d it , d igt |Ψ, β i , ρ i , k i , λ i , τ i , γ)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_32">d igt {d A igt|j , d F igt|j , d L igt|j , d G igt , d G ijgt , d SD igt , d SD ijgt , d N igt } for each game g in season t conditional on observed variables Ψ {X, W, Z, SeasonP, GateP}.</formula><p>This forms the likelihood of any given path of ticket purchase and usage choices in season t as</p><formula xml:id="formula_33">+ it ( d it , d igt |Ψ, β i , ρ i , k i , λ i , τ i , γ ) ∏ 6 j 1 P S ijt × ∏ 81 g P A igt|j ( ) d A igt|j × P F igt|j ( ) d F igt|j × P L igt|j ( ) d L igt|j [ ] d S ijt × P S iot × ∏ 81 g 1 ∏ 6 j 0 P G igt ( ) d G igt P G ijgt ( ) d G ijgt [ × P SD igt (<label>)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_34">d SD igt P SD ijgt (<label>)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_35">d SD ijgt × P N igt ( ) d N igt ] d S i0t . (<label>19</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_36">)</formula><p>Lewis, Wang, and Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options</p><p>The term + ijgt (r igt|j |d L igt|j , Ψ, β i , γ) is the likelihood of consumer i listing a game g tier j season ticket at a price ratio r igt|j on the secondary market. Taking the product over all games in season t,</p><formula xml:id="formula_37">+ it r igt|j |d L igt|j ,Ψ,β i ,γ ( ) ∏ 81 g 1 ∏ 6 j 1 + ijgt r igt|j |d L igt|j ,Ψ,β i ,γ ( ) .<label>(20)</label></formula><p>Next, we denote + k,jgt ( y k,jgt |Ψ, β i , γ)to be the likelihood of a listed ticket k being sold (y k,jgt 1) on a secondary market for game g tier j in season t as</p><formula xml:id="formula_38">+ t y k,jgt |Ψ, r k,jgt , β i , γ ( ) ∏ 81 g 1 ∏ 6 j 1 ∏ K k 1 q y k,jgt k,jgt × 1 − q k, jgt ( ) 1−y k,jgt . (<label>21</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_39">)</formula><p>We provide details for each likelihood component in Web Appendix C. The three likelihood elements are combined to form the overall log-likelihood over T seasons:</p><formula xml:id="formula_40">++ d it , d igt , r igt|j , y k,jgt ( ) ∑ T t 1 ∑ I i 1 In+ it d it , d igt ( ) + ∑ T t 1 ∑ I i 1</formula><p>In+ it r igt|j ( )</p><formula xml:id="formula_41">+ ∑ T t 1 + t y k,jgt ( ) .<label>(22)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Estimation</head><p>This section describes the identification strategy, endogeneity treatments, and estimation algorithm for the model detailed above. The data required to estimate the model consist of each consumer's season ticket purchase choice d it {d S ijt }, ticket usage and gate ticket purchase decisions</p><formula xml:id="formula_42">d igt {d A igt|j ,d F igt|j ,d L igt|j ,d G igt ,d G ijgt , d SD igt ,d SD ijgt ,d N igt }</formula><p>, the price ratio of each ticket listed for resale relative to the gate ticket prices {r igt|j }, resale transaction records of listed resale tickets {y k,jgt }, observed variables Ψ {X, W, Z, SeasonP, GateP}, and individual-specific demographics D i . Details of the estimation procedure are provided in Web Appendix D.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Identification</head><p>The unknown parameters in the model include</p><formula xml:id="formula_43">individual-level parameters {β 1ij , β 2i , β 3i , β 4i , ρ i , τ i , k S i , k G i , k SD i , λ i },</formula><p>secondary market demand parameters γ {γ 1j , γ 2 , γ 3 , γ 4 }, the variance-covariance matrix of the demand shocks Σ ξ , and the parameters governing the consumer heterogeneity in the hierarchical model (Π, Σ).</p><p>Parameters β 1ij , β 2i , β 3i are the coefficients of seat tiers and game attributes X gt and W gt , respectively. The observed pattern of varying attendance rates (relative to forgoing a game) informs tier-specific intercepts, β 1ij . The shape of the relationship between the game schedule X variables (i.e., weekends) and attendance rates influences the estimates of β 2i . Similarly, the relationship between the W variables (i.e., win loss record before game g) and attendance rates influences the estimates of β 3i . The game demand shocks ξ 1gt are essentially game-level random effects. Conditional on game attributes X gt and W gt , games with greater attendance imply a larger ξ 1gt .</p><p>We next consider the market-level parameters γ {γ 1j , γ 2 , γ 3 , γ 4 } in the resale equation. The higher the percentage of successful resale transactions in a tier, the larger the tier intercept γ 1j . Coefficients γ 2 , γ 3 , γ 4 are associated with market-level game quality, season ticket listing percentage, and the list price ratio, respectively. The exogenous variations in game attributes X gt and W gt shift the perceived game quality in the secondary market. The relationship between the average game quality and the successful resale identifies the coefficient γ 2 . Both the season ticket listing percentage and the secondary market list price ratio are endogenously determined through the season ticket holders' listing probabilities (Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">3</ref>)) and list prices (Equation ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>)). The listing cost variation over time and across individuals shifts the listed ticket volume on the secondary market. Thus, the exogenous proxies (Z it ) for listing cost serve as an exclusion restriction for the endogeneity of listing percentage. The relationship between listed ticket volumes and resale success identifies the coefficient γ 3 . Gate prices GateP jgt serve as the exclusion variable for the endogeneity of list price ratio. As noted, the team divides the 81 games in each season into six price blocks (see Web Appendix A, Section A.1). The block-level gate prices are determined before the start of the season based on factors such as opponent quality and day of the week. This variation in gate prices shifts the relative list price ratio. The relationship between the relative list price ratio and resale success rates influences the secondary market price coefficient γ 4 .</p><p>Along with the exclusion variables, we use a data augmentation approach in the Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) Bayesian estimation to uncover the realized demand shocks ξ 2gt <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Yang et al. 2003)</ref>. We treat the realizations of secondary market demand shocks ξ 2gt as augmented latent variables (to be drawn from the MCMC process). The augmented demand shocks ξ 2gt help control for the source of endogeneity. For example, a positive secondary market shock might lead to an increase in the average listing probability and list prices. The augmentation approach controls for the demand shocks and corrects the biased listing percentage and list price coefficients.</p><p>Conditional on the identification of game attribute coefficients {β 1ij , β 2i , β 3i } and the secondary market demand parameters γ, the observed list price ratio <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Lewis, Wang, and</ref><ref type="bibr">Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and</ref><ref type="bibr">Secondary Market Options Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 6, pp. 973-993, © 2019 INFORMS</ref> determines β 4i , where a more price-sensitive consumer will list the ticket at a higher price. Conditional on the identification of {β 1ij , β 2i , β 3i , β 4i } and γ, the propensity to list a season ticket is fully determined by the listing cost c it (Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">3</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_16">11</ref>)). The identification of listing costs c it is driven by each season ticket holder's relative propensity to list a ticket as compared with forgoing a ticket across games and seasons. A season ticket holder with a smaller listing cost will be more likely to list his or her ticket on the secondary market compared with forgoing the option. The listing cost c it is parameterized as exp(ρ 1i + ρ 2i In(Season t ) + ρ 3i In(CumList it + 1)). The baseline tendency of ticket listings identifies ρ 1i . The increase in market-level listing tendency over time identifies ρ 2i . The within-individual listing tendency changes over time identify ρ 3i .</p><p>When the consumer does not purchase season tickets, she or he faces a nested logit choice model. In the lower level, the variations in game attendance and seat tiers chosen across games with different game attributes and prices help identify the preference parameters for game quality attributes {β 1ij , β 2i , β 3i } and the price coefficient β 4i .The identification of the intercepts k G i and k SD i in the single ticket purchase relies on the frequency of single ticket purchase from the gate versus from the secondary market versus an outside option of not attending the game. Identification of the nested logit scale parameter λ i relies on the relationship of the inclusive value of purchasing any of the six seat tiers and the frequency of buying single ticket to game g.</p><p>The identification of the preference parameters {k S i , τ i } at the season ticket purchase stage relies on the temporal separation of ticket purchase and ticket usage. At the ticket purchase stage, the expected ticket usage value is exogenously determined given current available information (Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_17">12</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_27">18</ref>)). The season ticket purchase intercept k S i in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_18">13</ref>) is identified by season ticket purchase frequency across individuals and seasons. Identification of τ i comes from the relationship between season ticket purchase frequency and the sum of the expected usage utility across ticket tiers and seasons. Finally, the hierarchical parameters for consumer heterogeneity are identified based on the relationship between consumer decisions and the observed demographics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Simulation</head><p>We provide detailed simulation studies related to model identification in Web Appendix E. We simulated the season and single game ticket purchase decisions of 1,000 heterogeneous customers over multiple seasons. Conditional on season ticket purchase, we simulated game-level ticket usage decisions of attending, listing, or foregoing. In the case of listing, we also simulated pricing decisions and reselling results. The game-level shocks that enter the ticket attendance stage (Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">1</ref>), ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_20">14</ref>), and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_21">15</ref>)) and secondary market demand (Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_6">4</ref>)) are simulated as well. Overall, the simulated data structure follows the proposed model in Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">1</ref>)-( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_27">18</ref>). We are able to recover the true values within a 95% confidence interval and show that the model parameters are empirically identified. We also carry out two additional simulations with regard to two special cases. The first relates to the scale parameter τ i that connects the ticket usage decisions and season ticket purchase decisions. We are able to recover the scale parameter even when the true value is set at zero, a special case when the expected usage utility does not influence season ticket purchase. In the second special case, we show that we are able to recover the listing cost parameter when the true listing cost is set either very low or very high.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Results</head><p>We present the estimation results from 100,000 MCMC iterations in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">10</ref>. The first two blocks of results report the estimates for ticket attendance usage in Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">1</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_20">14</ref>). There are several things worth noting. First, the magnitudes of the tier coefficients are consistent with the order of the tier choice percentage of season tickets in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. Second, fans are more likely to attend games at night or on weekends. In terms of the game quality information, X gt , available before the start of a season, we find an intuitive pattern of results. The visiting team's winning percentage last season and relative pay rates in this season are both significant drivers of attendance. Third, we also obtain expected coefficient signs for the game quality information W gt that becomes available as the season progresses. We find that the cumulative winning percentages of the home and visiting teams are positively related to attendance. The negative sign for game competitiveness indicates that fans prefer closer matchups. Interestingly, winning and losing streaks are both related to increased attendance. The "games back" variable indicates higher attendance with higher divisional standing.</p><p>We are also able to measure each season ticket holder's listing cost in dollar form by dividing the implied listing cost by the price coefficient exp(c it ) exp(β 4i ) . The bottom 5%, 10%, 15%, and 20% of the implied listing costs are $3.6, $14.4, $34.7, and $78.5 in the 2011 season and $2.3, $9.1, $31.4, and $66.9 in the 2016 season, respectively. Our results confirm that the average listing costs decrease over seasons (−0.12) and with more listing experience (−0.10). Thus, the option value of secondary markets for season ticket holders is increasing overtime. The estimation results also reveal the intrinsic value of buying a season ticket Lewis, Wang, and Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options (Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_18">13</ref>)) as opposed to buying a collection of single tickets (Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_27">18</ref>)), where the mean estimate of the scale parameter is 0.224. In addition, we find the intercept of single ticket purchases from the secondary market (−10.61) to be much smaller than that from the gate (−4.64), indicating that the gate is the predominately preferred channel for these customers. Thus, the presence of online secondary markets does not bring in significant incentives for these customers to switch away from season ticket purchases. The scale parameter in the nested logit model is small (0.13), indicating the necessity of modeling in a nested decision framework.</p><p>The bottom two blocks of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">10</ref> report the parameters in the demand equation for the secondary market and the demand shock variances. The estimated intercepts range from 1.095 for tier 3 to −0.004 for tier 6. The game quality coefficient is significantly positive (1.01). When controlling for the game quality, we find a negative relationship between list price ratio and resale probability (−3.03). We also find a negative relationship between the percentage of season tickets listed on secondary markets and the resale probability (−0.12). Controlling for endogeneity through game quality and augmented demand shocks ξ 1gt and ξ 2gt is necessary because the listing decisions are largely driven by the demand in secondary markets. If a particular game has a positive secondary market shock, this will increase the average listing probability as well as list prices. Our augmentation step controls for the unobserved demand shocks and corrects for the biases in the listing and price coefficients. In addition, the estimated correlation of the two augmented demand shocks ξ 1gt and ξ 2gt is 0.580. This provides evidence that the unobserved shock to season ticket holders' perceived game quality ξ 1gt and the unobserved shock to secondary market demand ξ 2gt are related but not identical.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">11</ref> reports how observed individual heterogeneity-distance, years as a customer (tenure), and income-affects the individual-level coefficients. We find that fans who live far away from the stadium are more price sensitive. Our speculation is that this result is due to idiosyncratic features of the team's  Notes. We ran a total of 100,000 MCMC iterations and report the posterior distributions of the parameters based on the last 20,000 iterations. The model has an 89.06% hit rate for the season ticket purchase decisions, with the hit rates of season ticket tier choices range from 79% to 95%. Price coefficients are reparameterized as −exp(•), cost coefficients are reparameterized as −exp(•), and scale coefficient λ and τ are reparameterized as exp( • ) 1 + exp( • ) . In the estimation, we use tier 1 as the baseline and estimate the differences between the other five tiers and tier 1. This allows the Bayesian MCMC algorithm to be more efficient in convergence. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Lewis, Wang, and</ref><ref type="bibr">Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and</ref><ref type="bibr">Secondary Market Options Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 6, pp. 973-993, © 2019 INFORMS</ref> history and market position. The team under study has a unique history in several respects. They were essentially the only team located in a large geographic region, and the team was prominently featured in the early days of cable television. This may have created a situation where the team's fan base is more geographically dispersed than other teams'. Our speculation is that distance to the stadium operates differentially based on whether fans are located in the team's metropolitan area. Within the metro area, we suspect that distance operates as expected, with greater distances being associated with higher costs of attendance. However, for fans outside of the metro area, distance may be positively correlated with preferences. We find lower listing costs for those who live far away and for those who have shorter tenures. Our identification strategy for listing costs ensures that we control for game attendance utility across individuals. We can separate out whether the low listing frequency is due to high listing costs, higher game attendance utility, or lower price sensitivity. Finally, the matched zip code-level median income does not seem to affect most coefficients.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">Policy Analysis</head><p>In this section, we report the results from simulation studies that use the preceding models to study how the secondary market influences season ticket purchases and revenues. The specific policy experiments are motivated by the legal and marketing landscapes related to secondary markets. For example, the state of Michigan recently decriminalized the practice of selling tickets above market value <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Oosting 2015)</ref>. Leagues and teams are also interested in regulating secondary markets for marketing purposes. For instance, the Yankees insisted on an agreement with StubHub that prohibited resales below a minimum price (USA Today 2016). Additionally, several teams have attempted to require fans to use preferred or team-owned ticket exchanges <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Rovell 2015)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> The first simulation eliminates the secondary market and quantifies the overall economic impact. The second and third scenarios set a minimum or maximum price for listed tickets on the secondary market. The fourth scenario reduces listing cost. In the simulations, we set team performance, game characteristics, and season and gate ticket prices to the levels observed in the data. The simulation predicts purchasing rates and reselling activity. These probabilities are also used to calculate estimates of five-year customer lifetime (revenue) value (CLV) and the overall impact of the secondary market. The simulation procedure is outlined in Web Appendix F.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">12</ref> reports the results of these policy experiments. Considering both the positive unbundling option value and the negative secondary market cannibalization, we find that the absence of the secondary market decreases season ticket purchase rates by 4.27 percentage points. The tier-level results are presented in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3</ref>. Consistent with the data pattern in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">4</ref>, we see the smallest impact for the highest quality tier and a steadily increasing effect on lower quality tiers. We further calculate that the purchase rate increase provides a $4,424,346 revenue increase over six years from season ticket buyers.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">13</ref> reports the season ticket price decreases needed to maintain consumer utility levels if the secondary market was removed. This calculation essentially measures the value of the options provided by the secondary markets to season ticket holders. On a segment level, the secondary market provides $1.98 in value per ticket to the tier 1 segment and $0.91 value per ticket for the tier 6 segment. This represents a 4% price reduction in the highest quality tier to a more than 11% price reduction for lowest quality tier tickets (tier 6). The simulations are also useful for estimating longterm customer revenue contributions to the team. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">14</ref> reports the estimated customer lifetime values (five years) and the changes in CLV when the secondary market is eliminated. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> CLVs are significantly different based on ticket quality tier. The average five-year CLV in the highest quality tier is $94,799 versus only $15,456 in the lowest quality tier. The elimination of the secondary market has a significant impact across all the tiers. The largest impact is in tier 1 (−$2,553), and the smallest impact occurs in the lowest quality tier (−$1,327). However, on a percentage basis, the impact is largest for the low quality segment (−8.584%) and the smallest for the highest quality tier (−2.693%).</p><p>Extending our analyses beyond season ticket holders, we also consider the potential cannibalization of single game ticket sales on nonseason ticket buyers due to the alternative supply of unbundled season tickets on secondary markets. If the secondary market provides a reliable source of tickets, the team  The second set of simulations investigates minimum and maximum listing price policies. For example, the Yankees resisted partnering with StubHub until they were able to require a minimum price for resale tickets on StubHub. For the simulation, we set the minimum list price at half of the single gate ticket price and the maximum list price to the level of the single game ticket face value. We find that the minimum list price policy reduces season ticket purchase rates by 1.53 percentage points. This is equivalent to a $1,309,880 revenue loss from season ticket holders. Not surprisingly, the impact is the largest on low quality tier season tickets. This is also consistent with the data in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">5</ref> that show that lower quality tier tickets are listed at lower price ratios on the secondary market. We find a minimal impact of capping secondary prices at the ticket face value. This may be due to the market position of the team under study. This maximum list price policy might have greater impact on teams that tend to be more constrained by capacity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.">Discussion</head><p>Our research focuses on how secondary market options affect sports fans' preferences for purchasing season tickets. In our case, consumers have the option to directly use a ticket, resell a ticket, forgo a ticket, or purchase unbundled single game tickets from either the team or the secondary markets. These postpurchase options and decisions highlight an important aspect of our research. Academic researchers often focus on data created by transaction processing systems, although decisions related to product usage are not observable to researchers. In the case of tickets, it is increasingly possible to observe significant details related to consumption.</p><p>We find that the options created by the secondary market increase the value of purchasing ticket packages. Our results suggest that the net impact of the secondary market is to increase revenue by about $6.1 million over six years for the team under study. Given that sports organizations have high fixed costs, low marginal costs, and perishable inventory <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Cross 1997)</ref> this revenue increase may have significant implications for profit rates for some clubs. In the time period in question, Forbes (Ozanian 2018) estimated operating income of about $15 million per year for teams located in markets similar to that of the focal club. This suggests that the secondary market increases profitability by about 7% per year. This is a conservative estimate, as it does not include incremental sources of revenue such as parking, concessions, or merchandise. However, the importance of a result of this magnitude will be dependent on a team's market and cost structure. Across Major League Baseball, estimates of team's revenues vary from about $200 million for small market teams to over $600 million for teams in major markets <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Ozanian 2018)</ref>. Estimated operating incomes range from $100 million to net  losses. The importance of an incremental $1 million in revenues therefore varies by market.</p><p>Our policy experiments have important implications for teams, leagues, and legislatures. We find that policies that create constraints such as minimum price floors have an adverse impact on season ticket sales. This is a complex issue because price floors may be motivated by a desire to protect brand equity. Leagues and regulators must balance these brand maintenance goals against the benefits of providing more value to teams' most valuable customers.</p><p>Our results also have implications for segment-level customer management. We observe significant economic and behavioral differences based on the quality of tickets purchased. One interesting aspect is that the secondary market is least impactful for buyers of the highest quality seat tier. Given the lower renewal rates for buyers of the two lowest quality seat tiers, these results suggest that increasing options and value may be a particularly useful strategy for managing more marginal customers. These types of results could be used to refine pricing policies or to devise segmentlevel promotions. Our calculations of the equivalent discount value provided by the secondary market are an example of this type of analysis.</p><p>Our findings should be interpreted based on limitations inherent to our data. For example, although we are able to observe significant postpurchase activities, we do not have complete transparency. Season ticket holders may also distribute tickets through more informal markets such as selling directly to friends or giving away tickets to family members. These types of informal transfers provide an additional option value to consumers. These options existed prior to the creation of the secondary market. It is an open research question as to how the decision to use these types of informal markets or to gift tickets is influenced by the secondary market.</p><p>Our current model framework includes significant complexity in order to account for reselling decisions, secondary market pricing decisions, demand and supply factors, and the substitutability of single game bundles for season tickets. The value of incorporating these factors is that the model can speak to a number of issues related to the impact of secondary markets' existence and to evaluate potential market restrictions. However, given the complexity of the model, we chose not to include several relevant aspects of the season ticket market. First, we focus only on full-season packages. In practice, teams may offer a wide variety of packages such as half-season or customer-selected bundles. Extensions to incorporate alternative packages may require further modeling efforts under our framework. For example, future research could consider multiple discreteness choice models that allow customers to simultaneously cherry-pick single games along with a smaller package of fixed games. Quantity aspects could also be included with multiple discreteness choices.</p><p>Second, we have also assumed that the value of a dollar is the same when consumers are buying and selling tickets. This decision was made to facilitate model estimation. However, it is entirely possible that consumers may have different price sensitivities when buying versus selling <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Kahneman et al. 1991)</ref>.</p><p>Furthermore, although our data include multiple years of data for a large number of consumers, the data are sourced from a single team. Teams vary in terms of local support and on-field performance. Although the direction of the findings related to the option value provided by the secondary market are likely robust, the magnitude of effects may change based on underlying demand levels across markets. For example, if a team has frequent sellouts, then the value provided by the secondary market may be even greater if fans can frequently sell tickets above face value. The issue of demand constraints also highlights a possible modeling extension. For teams with significant capacity constraints, expectations of ticket availability may become more salient.</p><p>One limitation of our study that suggests an avenue for future research is the single-category nature of our study. Although we study the sports category, secondary ticket markets also do significant business in performing arts categories. Our basic modeling structure is largely applicable to nonsports contexts in that packages are purchased based on expected value and expected resale possibilities. However, there are likely some salient differences in performing arts categories relative to sports. For example, although in sports contexts events may be differentiated based on opponents, the products might be viewed as largely similar. In contrast, a theater organization might offer very different types of plays and collections of actors across a season. It might also be more difficult for consumers to form expectations about performance quality because there is a lack of objective data such as winning rates and payrolls.</p><p>There are significant opportunities for future research. For example, the dynamic nature of these secondary markets can provide information about willingness to pay for different types of tickets. One area for future research might be to focus on how the secondary market information can inform a team's pricing decisions. It is also possible that as consumers become more familiar with the secondary market in terms of usage and in terms of expectations of selling and buying opportunities, consumer behavior might evolve over time. However, given that we have data from only a single team, it is difficult to separate out team quality factors from time trends. A data set that includes multiple teams and consumer experiences in the market would be needed to study the full impact <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Lewis, Wang, and</ref><ref type="bibr">Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and</ref><ref type="bibr">Secondary Market Options Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 6, pp. 973-993, © 2019 INFORMS</ref> of consumer learning. Finally, there are contexts related to season tickets that would call for a dynamic programming model. If a club had a waiting list or a seniority system, the consumer's renewal decision would need to consider the long-term benefits of buying tickets in terms of gaining access to better tickets and that cancellations might limit buying opportunities in subsequent years.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. Intended Usage Percentage and Retention Rate</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. (Color online) Illustration of the Decision Process</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3. (Color online) Policy Experiment Results by Tier</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Season Ticket Tier Choices, Percentage by Season</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="7">Lewis, Wang, and Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Season</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>2011</cell><cell>2012</cell><cell>2013</cell><cell>2014</cell><cell>2015</cell><cell>2016</cell></row><row><cell>Tier 1</cell><cell>12.47</cell><cell>11.54</cell><cell>10.97</cell><cell>11.64</cell><cell>11.07</cell><cell>7.95</cell></row><row><cell>Tier 2</cell><cell>21.21</cell><cell>20.06</cell><cell>20.01</cell><cell>19.59</cell><cell>18.40</cell><cell>14.66</cell></row><row><cell>Tier 3</cell><cell>13.05</cell><cell>11.49</cell><cell>11.02</cell><cell>11.07</cell><cell>10.45</cell><cell>8.75</cell></row><row><cell>Tier 4</cell><cell>11.22</cell><cell>10.55</cell><cell>11.28</cell><cell>11.80</cell><cell>11.17</cell><cell>8.94</cell></row><row><cell>Tier 5</cell><cell>9.15</cell><cell>9.56</cell><cell>9.36</cell><cell>9.62</cell><cell>7.54</cell><cell>5.72</cell></row><row><cell>Tier 6</cell><cell>6.60</cell><cell>7.28</cell><cell>7.07</cell><cell>6.44</cell><cell>5.41</cell><cell>4.26</cell></row><row><cell>No purchase</cell><cell>26.30</cell><cell>29.52</cell><cell>30.30</cell><cell>29.83</cell><cell>35.97</cell><cell>49.74</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Season Ticket Renewal Rate, Percentage by Tier</figDesc><table><row><cell>Last season</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Season and Single Ticket Price (in Dollars) per Game by Tier</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Tier 1</cell><cell>Tier 2</cell><cell>Tier 3</cell><cell>Tier 4</cell><cell>Tier 5</cell><cell>Tier 6</cell></row><row><cell>Season ticket price per game ($)</cell><cell>54.30 (1.97)</cell><cell>46.14 (1.25)</cell><cell>31.80 (1.32)</cell><cell>22.33 (3.12)</cell><cell>12.47 (0.60)</cell><cell>8.19 (0.43)</cell></row><row><cell>Gate ticket price per game ($)</cell><cell>85.18 (13.78)</cell><cell>75.92 (13.00)</cell><cell>52.24 (11.45)</cell><cell>41.31 (9.94)</cell><cell>29.86 (8.25)</cell><cell>17.92 (5.48)</cell></row><row><cell>Percentage of sales</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Season tickets (%)</cell><cell>86.7</cell><cell>83.5</cell><cell>66.0</cell><cell>60.2</cell><cell>30.8</cell><cell>25.1</cell></row><row><cell>Nonseason tickets (%)</cell><cell>13.3</cell><cell>16.5</cell><cell>34.0</cell><cell>39.8</cell><cell>69.2</cell><cell>74.9</cell></row></table><note>Notes. Standard deviations are in parentheses. Variations of season ticket prices come from across seasons, whereas variations in single gate ticket price come from both across seasons and across games within a season.<ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Lewis, Wang, and</ref> Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options   Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 6, pp. 973-993, © 2019 INFORMS   </note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Season Ticket Intended and Actual Usage Patterns by Tier (in Percentage)</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Tier 1</cell><cell>Tier 2</cell><cell>Tier 3</cell><cell>Tier 4</cell><cell>Tier 5</cell><cell>Tier 6</cell></row><row><cell>Intended usage</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Attend (%)</cell><cell>71.21</cell><cell>70.31</cell><cell>68.34</cell><cell>66.02</cell><cell>57.54</cell><cell>50.42</cell></row><row><cell>Forgo (%)</cell><cell>21.80</cell><cell>23.86</cell><cell>25.03</cell><cell>29.78</cell><cell>34.53</cell><cell>37.59</cell></row><row><cell>List (%)</cell><cell>7.00</cell><cell>5.82</cell><cell>6.62</cell><cell>4.19</cell><cell>7.92</cell><cell>11.99</cell></row><row><cell>Conditional usage</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Successful resale rates (%)</cell><cell>30.07</cell><cell>31.26</cell><cell>30.14</cell><cell>39.04</cell><cell>41.06</cell><cell>41.12</cell></row><row><cell>Not sold but choose to attend (%)</cell><cell>47.83</cell><cell>46.98</cell><cell>49.70</cell><cell>33.33</cell><cell>25.86</cell><cell>19.39</cell></row><row><cell>Not sold but choose to forgo (%)</cell><cell>22.10</cell><cell>21.77</cell><cell>20.17</cell><cell>27.62</cell><cell>33.08</cell><cell>39.49</cell></row><row><cell>Actual usage</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Attended (%)</cell><cell>74.55</cell><cell>73.05</cell><cell>71.64</cell><cell>67.42</cell><cell>59.59</cell><cell>52.75</cell></row><row><cell>Forwent (%)</cell><cell>23.34</cell><cell>25.14</cell><cell>26.37</cell><cell>30.94</cell><cell>37.16</cell><cell>42.32</cell></row><row><cell>Resold (%)</cell><cell>2.10</cell><cell>1.82</cell><cell>2.00</cell><cell>1.64</cell><cell>3.25</cell><cell>4.93</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Ticket List and Resale Transaction Prices (in Dollars) per Game by Tier</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Tier 1</cell><cell>Tier 2</cell><cell>Tier 3</cell><cell>Tier 4</cell><cell>Tier 5</cell><cell>Tier 6</cell></row><row><cell>List price per game ($)</cell><cell>83.08 (21.86)</cell><cell>72.79 (22.28)</cell><cell>49.51 (17.32)</cell><cell>38.37 (15.32)</cell><cell>27.09 (12.30)</cell><cell>15.16 (8.32)</cell></row><row><cell>Resale price per game ($)</cell><cell>54.65 (18.43)</cell><cell>51.47 (18.64)</cell><cell>34.31 (13.92)</cell><cell>27.15 (12.80)</cell><cell>18.42 (9.90)</cell><cell>9.93 (6.30)</cell></row><row><cell>Season-to-single price ratio</cell><cell>0.65 (0.11)</cell><cell>0.63 (0.11)</cell><cell>0.64 (0.14)</cell><cell>0.57 (0.16)</cell><cell>0.46 (0.14)</cell><cell>0.51 (0.19)</cell></row><row><cell>List-to-single price ratio</cell><cell>0.97 (0.17)</cell><cell>0.95 (0.19)</cell><cell>0.94 (0.20)</cell><cell>0.92 (0.23)</cell><cell>0.89 (0.25)</cell><cell>0.84 (0.31)</cell></row><row><cell>Resale-to-single price ratio</cell><cell>0.64 (0.16)</cell><cell>0.67 (0.17)</cell><cell>0.65 (0.18)</cell><cell>0.64 (0.24)</cell><cell>0.60 (0.25)</cell><cell>0.55 (0.32)</cell></row></table><note>Notes. Standard deviations are in parentheses. The variation in list and resale prices comes from across seasons, across games within a season, and across individuals.Lewis, Wang, and Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options reveals a positive correlation between dollars generated in the secondary market and customer retention. The scatter plot also reveals that many customers do not attempt to recoup costs. Next, we estimate a panel logistic regression to investigate within-individual variation in renewal decisions versus actual recouping activities. In this analysis, we control for individual renewal tendencies via random effects. The results, in Table</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Secondary Market Prices and Sales</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Logistic regression</cell><cell cols="2">Linear regression on</cell><cell cols="2">Linear regression on</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">on resale</cell><cell cols="2">listing price ratio</cell><cell cols="2">resale price ratio</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>S.E.</cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>S.E.</cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>S.E.</cell></row><row><cell>Game quality index</cell><cell>0.720</cell><cell>0.012***</cell><cell>0.067</cell><cell>0.008***</cell><cell>0.127</cell><cell>0.008***</cell></row><row><cell>Percentage of ticket holders</cell><cell>−0.182</cell><cell>0.025***</cell><cell>−0.023</cell><cell>0.005***</cell><cell>−0.073</cell><cell>0.008***</cell></row><row><cell>listing (ln)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>List price ratio</cell><cell>−3.238</cell><cell>0.033***</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Seat tier dummies</cell><cell cols="2">Included</cell><cell cols="2">Included</cell><cell cols="2">Included</cell></row><row><cell>Game random effect</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Included</cell><cell cols="2">Included</cell></row><row><cell>Number of observations</cell><cell cols="2">41,681</cell><cell cols="2">41,681</cell><cell cols="2">14,496</cell></row><row><cell>R 2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0.071</cell><cell cols="2">0.072</cell></row><row><cell>Note. S.E., standard error.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>***p &lt; 0.01.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Average Number of Games Purchased When Not Purchasing Season Tickets Lewis, Wang, and Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market OptionsMarketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 6, pp. 973-993, © 2019 </figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Average # games</cell><cell>Average # games</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>purchased via</cell><cell>purchased via online</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>primary market</cell><cell>secondary market</cell></row><row><cell>In the year not renewing</cell><cell>14.20</cell><cell>0.12</cell></row><row><cell>a season ticket</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>In the year prior to a</cell><cell>23.48</cell><cell>0.23</cell></row><row><cell>season ticket purchase</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Panel Logistic Regression of Season Ticket Renewal and Secondary Market Usage Note. S.D., standard deviation; S.E., standard error. **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>S.E.</cell><cell>T-value</cell><cell>p-value</cell></row><row><cell>ActualRecoupDollar% last season</cell><cell>0.107</cell><cell>0.047</cell><cell>2.296</cell><cell>&lt;0.05**</cell></row><row><cell>S.D. β 0i</cell><cell>0.326</cell><cell>0.006</cell><cell>50.238</cell><cell>&lt;0.01***</cell></row><row><cell>S.D. ε it</cell><cell>0.349</cell><cell>0.003</cell><cell>126.394</cell><cell>&lt;0.01***</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 9 .</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Panel Logistic Regression of Season Ticket Renewal and Secondary Markets</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>S.E.</cell><cell cols="2">T-value p-value</cell></row><row><cell>AttdRate</cell><cell>0.688</cell><cell>0.015</cell><cell cols="2">45.542 &lt;0.01***</cell></row><row><cell>ListRate</cell><cell>0.152</cell><cell>0.032</cell><cell cols="2">4.717 &lt;0.01***</cell></row><row><cell>ResaleRate</cell><cell>−0.075</cell><cell>0.055</cell><cell>−1.365</cell><cell>0.172</cell></row><row><cell>ResalePriceRatio</cell><cell>−0.022</cell><cell>0.025</cell><cell>−0.885</cell><cell>0.376</cell></row><row><cell>ResaleRate × ResalePriceRatio</cell><cell>0.141</cell><cell>0.078</cell><cell>1.800</cell><cell>0.072*</cell></row><row><cell>S.D. β 0i</cell><cell>0.156</cell><cell>0.006</cell><cell cols="2">24.913 &lt;0.01***</cell></row><row><cell>S.D. ε it</cell><cell>0.343</cell><cell cols="3">0.003 121.763 &lt;0.01***</cell></row><row><cell>Season dummies</cell><cell>Included</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>Note. S.D., standard deviation; S.E., standard error. *p &lt; 0.1; ***p &lt; 0.01.Lewis, Wang, and Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options utility of listing (Equation (</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Lewis, Wang, and</ref> Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options   Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 6, pp. 973-993, © 2019 INFORMS   </figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>where v AF igt|j exp(Q igt|j ) + 1.0, and ε AF igt|j also follows the standard type I extreme value distribution. Because both ε AF igt|j and ε L igt|j are distributed as standard type I extreme values, we can derive the probability of listing a season ticket to resell as (for details, see Web Appendix C, Sections C.1 and C.2)</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>)</head><label></label><figDesc>Lewis, Wang, and Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options    </figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 6, pp. 973-993, © 2019 INFORMS</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>be the likelihood of observing consumer i making season ticket purchase choice d it {d S ijt } for season t, ticket usage, and gate ticket purchase decisions</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_13"><head>Table 10 .</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Estimation Results</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>2.5th</cell><cell>97.5th</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>percentile</cell><cell>percentile</cell></row><row><cell>Game attendance variables X gt</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>available at season ticket</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>purchase stage</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Tier 1</cell><cell>−2.946</cell><cell>−3.092</cell><cell>−2.793</cell></row><row><cell>Difference between tier 1 and tier 2</cell><cell>0.394</cell><cell>0.332</cell><cell>0.453</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Difference between tier 1 and tier 3 −0.320</cell><cell>−0.400</cell><cell>−0.215</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Difference between tier 1 and tier 4 −0.811</cell><cell>−0.913</cell><cell>−0.728</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Difference between tier 1 and tier 5 −1.407</cell><cell>−1.518</cell><cell>−1.323</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Difference between tier 1 and tier 6 −3.250</cell><cell>−3.347</cell><cell>−3.159</cell></row><row><cell>Season 2012</cell><cell>0.162</cell><cell>0.126</cell><cell>0.205</cell></row><row><cell>Season 2013</cell><cell>0.181</cell><cell>0.145</cell><cell>0.226</cell></row><row><cell>Season 2014</cell><cell>0.091</cell><cell>0.050</cell><cell>0.138</cell></row><row><cell>Season 2015</cell><cell>−0.374</cell><cell>−0.418</cell><cell>−0.330</cell></row><row><cell>Season 2016</cell><cell>−0.628</cell><cell>−0.705</cell><cell>−0.569</cell></row><row><cell>Weekend</cell><cell>0.627</cell><cell>0.612</cell><cell>0.641</cell></row><row><cell>Night</cell><cell>0.429</cell><cell>0.414</cell><cell>0.445</cell></row><row><cell>Holiday</cell><cell>0.117</cell><cell>0.093</cell><cell>0.138</cell></row><row><cell>OppWin% (t − 1)</cell><cell>2.298</cell><cell>2.072</cell><cell>2.530</cell></row><row><cell>OppRelPay (t)</cell><cell>0.334</cell><cell>0.316</cell><cell>0.356</cell></row><row><cell>Game attendance variables W gt</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>available at ticket usage stage</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>HomeCumWinPt (gt)</cell><cell>0.451</cell><cell>0.365</cell><cell>0.541</cell></row><row><cell>OppCumWinPt (gt)</cell><cell>1.774</cell><cell>1.543</cell><cell>1.967</cell></row><row><cell>Competitiveness (gt)</cell><cell>−0.503</cell><cell>−0.622</cell><cell>−0.398</cell></row><row><cell>StreatkWin (gt)</cell><cell>0.029</cell><cell>0.024</cell><cell>0.034</cell></row><row><cell>StreakLoss (gt)</cell><cell>0.021</cell><cell>0.015</cell><cell>0.028</cell></row><row><cell>GoBack (gt)</cell><cell>−0.288</cell><cell>−0.301</cell><cell>−0.274</cell></row><row><cell>Game listing variables</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Listing cost intercept ρ 1 Cost time trend ρ 2 Cost cumulative listing ρ 3</cell><cell>1.944 −0.118 −0.102</cell><cell>1.856 −0.179 −0.119</cell><cell>2.032 −0.049 −0.073</cell></row><row><cell>Season ticket price coefficient</cell><cell>0.403</cell><cell>0.377</cell><cell>0.432</cell></row><row><cell>(ln scale)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Ticket purchase intercept and scale</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Season ticket intercept</cell><cell>−2.146</cell><cell>−2.291</cell><cell>−1.983</cell></row><row><cell>Single gate ticket intercept</cell><cell>−4.640</cell><cell>−4.755</cell><cell>−4.563</cell></row><row><cell>Single secondary ticket intercept</cell><cell cols="2">−10.608 −10.954</cell><cell>−10.041</cell></row><row><cell>81 game scale τ i (logit scale)</cell><cell>−1.242</cell><cell>−1.327</cell><cell>−1.116</cell></row><row><cell>Nested logit scale (logit scale)</cell><cell>−1.926</cell><cell>−2.010</cell><cell>−1.846</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_14"><head>Table 10</head><label>10</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>. (Continued)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>2.5th</cell><cell>97.5th</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>percentile</cell><cell>percentile</cell></row><row><cell>Secondary market parameters</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Tier 1</cell><cell>0.928</cell><cell>0.614</cell><cell>1.247</cell></row><row><cell>Difference between tier 1 and tier 2</cell><cell>0.105</cell><cell>0.001</cell><cell>0.215</cell></row><row><cell>Difference between tier 1 and tier 3</cell><cell>0.167</cell><cell>0.067</cell><cell>0.275</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Difference between tier 1 and tier 4 −0.056</cell><cell>−0.167</cell><cell>0.059</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Difference between tier 1 and tier 5 −0.289</cell><cell>−0.382</cell><cell>−0.184</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Difference between tier 1 and tier 6 −0.932</cell><cell>−1.037</cell><cell>−0.815</cell></row><row><cell>Quality coefficient A gt</cell><cell>1.008</cell><cell>0.877</cell><cell>1.128</cell></row><row><cell>% of season tickets listed L jgt</cell><cell>−0.121</cell><cell>−0.207</cell><cell>−0.051</cell></row><row><cell>Price coefficient of secondary market</cell><cell>1.117</cell><cell>1.091</cell><cell>1.142</cell></row><row><cell>(ln scale)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Variance of ξ 1gt</cell><cell>0.198</cell><cell>0.179</cell><cell>0.227</cell></row><row><cell>Variance of ξ 2gt</cell><cell>1.710</cell><cell>1.479</cell><cell>1.958</cell></row><row><cell>Correlation between the two shocks</cell><cell>0.580</cell><cell>0.550</cell><cell>0.611</cell></row><row><cell>ξ 1gt and ξ 2gt</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Error variance in the list price</cell><cell>0.183</cell><cell>0.160</cell><cell>0.213</cell></row><row><cell>Log-likelihood</cell><cell>−621,560</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_15"><head>Table 11 .</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Observed Individual HeterogeneityNote. Bold indicates that the 95% credit interval does not cover zero.Lewis, Wang, and Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Demeaned</cell><cell>Demeaned</cell><cell>Demeaned</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>distance</cell><cell>tenure</cell><cell>income</cell></row><row><cell>Tier 1</cell><cell>0.081</cell><cell>1.423</cell><cell>−0.075</cell></row><row><cell>Difference between tier 1 and</cell><cell>−0.049</cell><cell>0.140</cell><cell>0.154</cell></row><row><cell>tier 2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Difference between tier 1 and</cell><cell>0.357</cell><cell>0.028</cell><cell>−0.020</cell></row><row><cell>tier 3</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Difference between tier 1 and</cell><cell>0.104</cell><cell>−0.184</cell><cell>−0.229</cell></row><row><cell>tier 4</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Difference between tier 1 and</cell><cell>0.400</cell><cell>−0.677</cell><cell>−0.798</cell></row><row><cell>tier 5</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Difference between tier 1 and</cell><cell>−0.009</cell><cell>−0.265</cell><cell>0.081</cell></row><row><cell>tier 6</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Season 2012</cell><cell>0.099</cell><cell>−0.481</cell><cell>−0.177</cell></row><row><cell>Season 2013</cell><cell>0.010</cell><cell>−1.307</cell><cell>−0.010</cell></row><row><cell>Season 2014</cell><cell>−0.097</cell><cell>−1.402</cell><cell>0.056</cell></row><row><cell>Season 2015</cell><cell>−0.119</cell><cell>−1.517</cell><cell>0.151</cell></row><row><cell>Season 2016</cell><cell>−0.151</cell><cell>−1.264</cell><cell>0.102</cell></row><row><cell>Weekend</cell><cell>0.093</cell><cell>−0.084</cell><cell>−0.145</cell></row><row><cell>Night</cell><cell>−0.033</cell><cell>0.049</cell><cell>0.068</cell></row><row><cell>Holiday</cell><cell>0.047</cell><cell>0.016</cell><cell>−0.057</cell></row><row><cell>OppWin% (t − 1)</cell><cell>−0.293</cell><cell>0.993</cell><cell>0.199</cell></row><row><cell>OppRelPay (t)</cell><cell>0.005</cell><cell>−0.037</cell><cell>0.028</cell></row><row><cell>HomeCumWinPt (gt)</cell><cell>0.028</cell><cell>0.123</cell><cell>−0.020</cell></row><row><cell>OppCumWinPt (gt)</cell><cell>−0.258</cell><cell>0.695</cell><cell>−0.055</cell></row><row><cell>Competitiveness (gt)</cell><cell>−0.038</cell><cell>−0.156</cell><cell>−0.255</cell></row><row><cell>StreatkWin (gt)</cell><cell>0.001</cell><cell>0.010</cell><cell>−0.003</cell></row><row><cell>StreakLoss (gt)</cell><cell>0.005</cell><cell>−0.001</cell><cell>−0.007</cell></row><row><cell>GoBack (gt)</cell><cell>−0.004</cell><cell>0.007</cell><cell>−0.006</cell></row><row><cell>Listing cost intercept</cell><cell>−0.498</cell><cell>0.247</cell><cell>−0.309</cell></row><row><cell>Cost time trend (ln)</cell><cell>0.236</cell><cell>−0.133</cell><cell>0.056</cell></row><row><cell>Cost cumulative listings (ln)</cell><cell>−0.115</cell><cell>0.171</cell><cell>−0.094</cell></row><row><cell>Price coefficient of season ticket</cell><cell>0.197</cell><cell>−0.223</cell><cell>−0.019</cell></row><row><cell>holders</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Season ticket intercept</cell><cell>−0.072</cell><cell>0.925</cell><cell>−0.036</cell></row><row><cell>Single gate ticket intercept</cell><cell>0.232</cell><cell>−0.251</cell><cell>0.556</cell></row><row><cell>Single secondary ticket</cell><cell>0.091</cell><cell>−0.309</cell><cell>0.077</cell></row><row><cell>intercept</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>81 game scale</cell><cell>−0.222</cell><cell>1.203</cell><cell>−0.375</cell></row><row><cell>Nested logit scale</cell><cell>−0.012</cell><cell>0.208</cell><cell>0.084</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_16"><head>Table 12 .</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Policy ExperimentsNote. The rate difference refers to purchase rate percentage point differences in the counterfactual setting and the baseline prediction setting, whereas the rate percentage change refers to the percentage changes.Lewis, Wang, and Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="4">Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 6, pp. 973-993, © 2019 INFORMS</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Season ticket</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Season ticket</cell><cell>purchase rate</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>purchase rate</cell><cell>percentage</cell><cell>Revenue</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>difference (%)</cell><cell>change (%)</cell><cell>change ($)</cell></row><row><cell>No secondary market</cell><cell>−4.27</cell><cell>−6.45</cell><cell>−4,424,346</cell></row><row><cell>Minimum list price policy</cell><cell>−1.53</cell><cell>−2.32</cell><cell>−1,309,880</cell></row><row><cell>Maximum list price policy</cell><cell>−0.15</cell><cell>−0.23</cell><cell>−350,639</cell></row><row><cell>Listing cost reduced to 50%</cell><cell>1.63</cell><cell>2.46</cell><cell>1,092,011</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_17"><head>Table 13 .</head><label>13</label><figDesc>Certainty Equivalence in Season Ticket Price Changes Without Secondary MarketsNote. Certainty equivalence refers to how much season ticket price drop is needed to keep the usage utility equivalent when secondary markets do not exist.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Tier 1</cell><cell>Tier 2</cell><cell>Tier 3</cell><cell>Tier 4</cell><cell>Tier 5</cell><cell>Tier 6</cell></row><row><cell>Certainty equivalence, in season prices ($)</cell><cell>160.34</cell><cell>196.59</cell><cell>133.69</cell><cell>118.48</cell><cell>57.73</cell><cell>73.87</cell></row><row><cell>Certainty equivalence per season game ($)</cell><cell>1.98</cell><cell>2.43</cell><cell>1.65</cell><cell>1.46</cell><cell>0.71</cell><cell>0.91</cell></row><row><cell>Certainty equivalence, out of season price (%)</cell><cell>3.65</cell><cell>5.26</cell><cell>5.19</cell><cell>6.55</cell><cell>5.72</cell><cell>11.14</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_18"><head>Table 14 .</head><label>14</label><figDesc>Customer Lifetime Value with/without Secondary Markets Lewis, Wang, and Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options</figDesc><table><row><cell>Tier 1</cell><cell>Tier 2</cell><cell>Tier 3</cell><cell>Tier 4</cell><cell>Tier 5</cell><cell>Tier 6</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">MarketingScience, 2019, vol. 38, no. 6, pp. 973-993, © 2019 </note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The paper benefited from constructive feedback from seminar participants at the University of Colorado Boulder ( <ref type="formula">2014</ref> </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Endnotes <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The growth in secondary market activity is revealed by StubHub's public financial statements. StubHub's successfully closed transaction revenue increased from $3,109 million in 2013 to $4,310 in 2016. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> The estimation sample is a sample of the population of season ticket holders. Ticket brokers and customers for whom matching across databases was imperfect are excluded from the sample.</p><p>3 Although the use of bar code technology and the observability of the secondary market provide unprecedented levels of ticket usage monitoring, the club's ability to monitor fan behavior is still imperfect. The team does not know whether tickets are given away or sold via private transactions. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Gate prices were set prior to the start of the season based on factors such as opponent quality and day of the week. The team divides the 81 games in a season into six blocks based on management's judgment of opposing team appeal and schedule time factors (i.e. day versus night, weekday). The industry generally refers to this as variable pricing. There are approximately 10-20 games in each block. Prices also vary based on quality tier (Web Appendix A, Section A.1). 5 In Web Appendix A, Section A.2, we explore whether season ticket holders exhibit forward-looking behavior in ticket usage. We find no evidence that secondary market listing are affected by future games. 6 StubHub charges 10% from sellers and another 25% commission from buyers. For example, if the listing price is $100, sellers get $90 out of $100, and buyers pay $125. StubHub makes $35 from the transaction. 7 Fans may derive higher attendance utility from attending a subset of games. We partially account for the interdependence across games by allowing for game preferences to be correlated in our hierarchical modeling approach. However, it is also possible that the utility of attending a subset of games may be higher than the additive utility of each game because of game complementarity beyond what is captured in the correlated game preference. Unfortunately, there is a dimensionality problem given the large number of games in a season (3 81 = 4.4e+38 ticket usage combinations in a season). Literatures on product complementarity has tended to be limited to small numbers of products and limited discrete quantities <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Wales and Woodland 1983</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">, Chiang 1991</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">, Chintagunta 1993</ref>). <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Lee et al. (2013)</ref> deals with more than two products but imposes strict conditional independence assumptions. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> The first simplifying assumption likely results in a conservative estimated impact of the secondary market. The assumption that tickets are available reduces the appeal of buying a season ticket to obtain tickets to high-demand events (Yankees, Cubs, etc.). 9 Although the additive utility summation assumption is used to alleviate the model calibration challenge, we have conducted a variety of model-free analyses related to game bundling decisions. These analyses focus on questions related to whether single game tickets are purchased simultaneously as bundles or sequentially as single games. The appendix also explores whether there are patterns in the sets of games attended by consumers (Web Appendix A, Section A.3). In general, there does not appear to be systematic evidence that consumers are creating their own customized bundles. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> We acknowledge that our counterfactual policy analyses may be subject to the Lucas critique, as a no-secondary-market scenario goes beyond the range of estimation sample. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> In the discussion, we use the term CLV for convenience. Our estimates are better described as customer revenue estimates. These estimates do not include revenues related to ancillary purchases or revenues generated before the 2011 season. We also assume that the marginal cost of serving a fan is zero.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CORRECTION</head><p>In this article, "Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options" by Michael Lewis, Yanwen Wang, and Chunhua Wu (first published online in Articles in Advance, October 25, 2019, Marketing Science, DOI: 10.1287/ mksc.2019.1183), Chunhua Wu's affiliation was incorrectly indicated as the Goizueta School of Business at Emory University. This has been updated to indicate his correct affiliation: UBC Sauder School of Business, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, British Columbia V6T 1Z2, Canada. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Lewis, Wang, and</ref><ref type="bibr">Wu: Season Ticket Buyer Value and</ref><ref type="bibr">Secondary Market Options Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 6, pp. 973-993, © 2019 INFORMS</ref> </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pricing a bundle of products or services: The case of nonprofits</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ansari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Siddarth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Weinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="86" to="93" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A simultaneous approach to the whether, what and how much to buy questions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="315" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating purchase incidence, brand choice and purchase quantity decisions of households</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="184" to="208" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Revenue Management: Hard Core Tactics for Market Domination</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>Crown Business</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leasing and selling: Optimal marketing strategies for a durable goods firm</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Desai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Purohit</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="34" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategic service pricing and yield management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Desiraju</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="56" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal bundle pricing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hanson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="174" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interfering with secondary markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Hendel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lizzeri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">RAND J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic demand for new and used durable goods without physical depreciation: The case of Japanese video games</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ishihara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ching</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="392" to="416" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anomalies: The endowment effect, loss aversion, and status quo bias</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Knetsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Perspect</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="193" to="206" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A direct utility model for asymmetric complements</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="454" to="470" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resale and rent-seeking: An application to ticket markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Leslie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sorensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="266" to="300" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual team incentives and managing competitive balance in sports leagues: An empirical analysis of Major League Baseball</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="535" to="549" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of price tiers in advance purchasing of event tickets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Moe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Service Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="86" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ticket scalping decriminalization proposal wins approval in Michigan House</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Oosting</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.mlive.com/lansingnews/index.ssf/2015/03/michigan_house_votes_to_life_t.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">MLive</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-03-25" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Baseball team values</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ozanian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.forbes.com/sites/mikeozanian/2018/04/11/baseball-team-values-2018/#454d04863fc0" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Forbes</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-04-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rovell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://espn.go.com/nba/story/_/id/12584885/StubHub-sues-golden-state-warriors-alleging-monopoly" />
		<title level="m">StubHub files suit against Warriors. ESPN</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-03-31" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Season Ticket Buyer Value and Secondary Market Options Shiller B (2013) Digital distribution and the prohibition of resale markets for information goods</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wang</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="403" to="435" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic pricing behavior in perishable goods markets: Evidence from secondary markets for Major League Baseball tickets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sweeting</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1133" to="1172" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why sports teams still selling season tickets are doomed</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Tuchman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.forbes.com/sites/roberttuchman/2015/10/08/why-sports-teams-still-selling-season-tickets-are-doomed/print/#2d9333985777" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Forbes</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-10-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Yankees, StubHub strike deal, set resale and price floor</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.usatoday.com/story/sports/mlb/2016/06/27/yankees-stubhub-strike-deal-set-resale-ad-price-floor/86436464/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">USA Today</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-06-27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>USA Today</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A probabilistic approach to pricing a bundle of products or services</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Venkatesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="494" to="508" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimation of consumer demand systems with binding non-negativity constraints</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wales</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Woodland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="285" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electronic tickets, smart cards, and online prepayments: When and how to advance sell</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="219" to="243" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian analysis of simultaneous demand and supply</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="275" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Effect of resale on optimal ticket pricing: Evidence from Major League Baseball tickets. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<pubPlace>College Station</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Texas A&amp;M University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
