<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Multimarket Value Creation and Competition</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2019-02-08">February 8, 2019</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Qiang</forename><surname>Fu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>119245</postCode>
									<settlement>Singapore</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Republic of Singapore</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Ganesh</forename><surname>Iyer</surname></persName>
							<email>giyer@haas.berkeley.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94720</postCode>
									<settlement>Berkeley, Berkeley</settlement>
									<region>California</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Multimarket Value Creation and Competition</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 (print)</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2019-02-08">February 8, 2019</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.2018.1127</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: June 12, 2017 Revised: March 25, 2018; June 22, 2018 Accepted: July 10, 2018</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:31+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>value creation</term>
					<term>rent seeking</term>
					<term>multi-market competition</term>
					<term>contests</term>
					<term>home-market bias</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We analyze multimarket interactions between firms that must invest limited budgets in value (surplus) creation and in competitive rent-seeking activities. Firms are horizontally differentiated on a line segment and compete for multiple markets and prizes that differ in the relative effectiveness of each firm's competitive rent-seeking spending. Each firm faces a dual trade-off: First, they must choose how much to invest in value creation versus how much to spend in rent-seeking competition. Second, they must decide on how to allocate resources across the different markets. When the market values are exogenous (and identical across markets), the intensity of competition is highest for the market in the middle, rather than in (advantaged) markets that are close or in (disadvantaged) markets that are closer to the rival. Counter to what one would expect, greater firm differentiation actually intensifies the competition in the middle markets. When firms endogenously invest in value creation, they invest more in value creation in closer markets and the investments decline toward the middle. This results in the most intense competition moving away from the middle to a market in each firm's turf. The analysis also provides a competitive perspective on the home-turf bias phenomenon.</p><p>History: K. Sudhir served as the editor-in-chief and Sanjay Jain served as associate editor for this article.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Many important business, economic, and political contexts involve rivals who must compete by allocating limited resources across multiple markets or prizes. They must decide not only how much to invest in building different markets but also the extent to which they compete in each market. Consider the following examples:</p><p>• Drug companies spent an estimated $5.2 billion in 2015 in direct-to-consumer advertising. For new drugs such advertising may induce patients to ask their doctors about their suitability and thus potentially expand the market. The pharmaceutical industry deploys even larger amounts (e.g., $15 billion in 2012) to conduct detailing and promotional activities to doctors across different geographical markets. Detailing activities by medical representatives not only provides information to doctors about the basic drug action, but also involve efforts to persuade doctors to prescribe the firm's drugs over those of rivals.</p><p>• In the mobile phone market leading firms like Samsung and HTC invest in promoting the Android platform to convince consumers to adopt the platform over the iPhone. However, they also compete for market share in large Asian markets. HTC's advertising campaign is more effective in its home market in Taiwan than in South Korea, and vice versa for Samsung. Advertising campaigns in this product category can work to increase the generic demand for the product category, or it can persuade consumers about the advantages of a firm's product over its rival(s). Samsung and HTC would have to decide on allocating advertising budgets based on the relative preference for their product in each market.</p><p>These examples represent some general aspects of competitive interactions in a variety of contexts: First, the players/firms have limited resources (advertising budgets, sales force size), and they compete in multiple markets. This means that they have to decide on how much of the resource to allocate to each market, resulting in the decisions across markets to be affiliated. Allocating more to one market means less to others. Second, the markets can be differentiated (as in the mobile phone market), with each firm having home markets with relatively higher consumer preference. Should firms deploy more or fewer resources in markets in which they are stronger?</p><p>Second, the examples also highlight a basic business strategy trade-off: firms have to choose between surplus or value creation in each market versus competing for the value. In other words, the pie that firms will fight for is in itself endogenous. Further, a firm's investment in creating value in a market can be subject to free-riding by the competitor who can deploy competitive resources to win the market. For example, pharmaceutical reps have to decide how much to focus their efforts on providing information about the basic drug action versus on persuading doctors that their drug is relatively superior. Efforts to inform doctors about the basic drug action may also end up benefiting competitors in a category. Similarly, direct to consumer advertising for a new class of drugs by one firm can expand the potential market benefiting all the firms in the category. This feature is also related to the classic guns versus butter trade-off described in the conflict literature. That is, in competitive markets economic agents may face a trade-off between investing in producing goods of value versus investing to appropriate the value created by other agents <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Hirshleifer 1988)</ref>. Except, in this paper, we examine the trade-off in the context of multimarket interactions between players with limited resources.</p><p>We construct a framework to analyze multimarket value creation and the competition for that value. The anatomy of the game is as follows: two firms (players) with limited resources simultaneously compete for different markets that are evenly located on a unit line. Firms are located at the ends of the line and are differentiated, and each firm's relative strength in a market depends on the distance between the firm's location and that of the market: the further a market is from a firm's location the less effective is the firm's competitive rentseeking spending. Firms simultaneously choose an allocation of their resource endowment among the markets in order to maximize their expected overall payoffs. In each market they simultaneously choose the investment that will determine the size of the market (value or surplus creation) as well as the competitive outlay to win the market from the rival (competitive rent seeking). Firms' outlays in surplus creation are substitutable and they jointly determine the size of the value pie. This then allows for the possibility that the investments in surplus creation by one firm is subject to free-riding by the other. In each market firms' competitive spending jointly determine the winner through a Tullock contest success function <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Tullock, 1980)</ref>. What would the equilibrium allocations be for the players be in terms of the surplus creation and the rent-seeking allocations across the different markets?</p><p>First, consider the case in which each market has the same size, and the size is exogenously fixed, implying that firms only face the competitive rent-seeking incentive across the markets. Should a firm defend closer markets on its home turf, or should it spend resources to win markets that are farther away and more difficult to win? We find that each firm's equilibrium resource distribution has a nonmonotonic inverted U-shaped profile: each firm spends relatively fewer resources, both in closer markets and in markets that are closer to the firm's competitor. That firms' outlays peak at a market in the middle implies that competition will be the most intense for the middle market. It is particularly interesting and counter to intuition that greater market differentiation leads to a more concentrated resource distribution profile with even more intense competition in the middle markets. These results are consistent with the empirical studies of electoral competition in U.S. presidential elections <ref type="bibr">(Stromberg 2008, Gordon and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Hartmann 2016)</ref>, which show evidence of greater advertising spending in the most competitive markets.</p><p>We then analyze the general case in which market value is endogenously determined. Firms' choose not only the allocation across the markets, but also how to split the spending in each market between investments in market creation and in competitive rent seeking: the former builds the market value or surplus, whereas the latter allows a firm to compete for the value that is created. Consider the case in which the efficiency of the productive investment of a firm is the same across all markets, implying that firms do not have a home-turf advantage in more proximate markets. With substitutable value creation efforts, the equilibrium market values are polarized: the home turfs of both firms; that is, markets closest to the firm's locations have the highest equilibrium investments, and markets that are closer to the middle have lower values. The firms' allocations of competitive rent-seeking outlays are different from the pattern in the exogenous market size case. Firms' competitive spending no longer peak in the middle, but rather in each firm's turf. Firms do not compete most intensely in the most valuable markets, rather the intensity of competition is determined by the trade-off between the equilibrium size of the markets and the ease with which the markets are contestable.</p><p>Greater market differentiation leads firms to invest relatively more in their home turfs at the expense of the middle markets and to reduce the overall amount of competitive spending. With asymmetric budgets, the firm with the budget advantage balances its equilibrium actions such that it invests more in value creation and also deploys more in competitive spending. This result contrasts with what might be obtained in a single market value creation and competition model: in that case, it is possible that the firm with the lower budget may deploy greater competitive spending even as the firm with the budget advantage invests more in value creation. Finally, as the budget asymmetry increases, the firm with the advantage invests in more markets closer to the weaker firm.</p><p>Our results also provide a competitive perspective on the effects home market advantage, that is, a systematic preference of consumers to purchase local products. The interesting question is when does this lead to hometurf bias in the equilibrium spending or investments by firms. When the market values are exogenous, the spending in competitive rent seeking is actually higher in the middle markets rather than in the home turfs of the firms. In contrast, with endogenous market values, the value creation investments of the firms are higher in their home turfs even if all markets have the same productivity/effectiveness in value creation. Thus, we have the interesting point that even in the absence of any home-turf advantage in value creation, the presence of differentiation in competitive rent seeking can lead to home-turf bias in the equilibrium value creation. When firms have a home-turf advantage, this predictably leads to greater equilibrium investment in closer markets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Related Research</head><p>This paper is related to the guns versus butter literature initiated by <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Hirshleifer (1988)</ref>. In that literature rival agents can acquire surplus either by producing goods or by appropriating the output produced by others. Therefore, they must strategically allocate their resource endowment between output-creating investments (butter) or appropriative technologies (guns), and doing so helps to seize the output of others or defend one's own output. Our paper examines the resource allocation choice of players between value creating investments and competitive rent-seeking actions. This can be seen as the incentives and the trade-offs faced by firms to collaborate in joint production of value and to compete for that value at the same time. Several papers [e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Skaperdas (1992)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Hirshleifer (1994)</ref>] have been developed along this line to investigate how firms' resource position might affect their allocation strategies [see <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Garfinkel and Skaperdas (2007)</ref> for a review]. Our analysis contributes by considering value creation and competition in multimarket interactions and therefore jointly considers dual trade-offs: the allocation of resources between value creation and competition and the allocation of resources to different markets. In marketing, <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bass et al. (2005)</ref> analyze a form of the guns versus butter trade-off in single market over time in model of dynamic competition in generic and brand advertising. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Amaldoss et al. (2000)</ref> present a different type trade-off in the context of R&amp;D alliances: firms in an alliance jointly invest to develop products of higher values in order to compete against rival alliances.</p><p>Our analysis is also related to the contest literature and can be seen as new form of multidimensional proportional prize contest in which firms allocate resources over a set of differentiated markets. This enriches and qualitatively generalizes the framework of the Colonel Blotto game of duopoly conflicts in multiple battlefields in which firms allocate their resources among these battlefields to maximize the sum of rents. The game was first proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Borel (1921)</ref> and analyzed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Borel and Ville (1938)</ref> in a special case of three markets. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> We highlight the strategic effects of an important aspect that is missing in the literature: the Colonel Blotto game assumes a zero-sum payoff structure. Our analysis obviously considers both the creation of the pie as well as competition for it. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> To our knowledge, the existing literature on Colonel Blotto games has not considered a game that incorporates the trade-off between market creation and rent seeking as well as firms' strategic interaction in multiple differentiated markets. Within the standard Colonel Blotto class of games allowing for endogenous market creation as well as allocation across multiple differentiated contests is analytically challenging. The game form developed in the paper contributes by providing a tractable proportional prize setup to analyze the guns versus butter decisions in multimarket contests.</p><p>The paper is also related to a growing literature that applies contest/tournament-type models of competition to marketing and industrial organization issues, such as research and development (R&amp;D) and product development and sales force allocation and incentives. The application of contest-like models in marketing goes back to the attraction models literature originating in <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bell et al. (1975)</ref>, who deals with marketing and promotional effort competition for market shares. Recent work in marketing strategy includes <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Ridlon and Shin (2013)</ref>, who examine whether a firm should favor weaker employees in an attempt to maximize the total sales effort output in a repeated contest model. <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Iyer and Katona (2016)</ref> analyze competition as a contest for consumer attention in social communication markets, whereas <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Katona et al. (2017)</ref> model a contest between news providers who can strategically choose news topics. Literature on sales contests focuses on the optimal design of the prize structure to elicit sales agents efforts (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Kalra and</ref><ref type="bibr">Shi 2001, Lim et al. 2009</ref>). Finally, <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Amaldoss and Staelin (2010)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Chen and Lim (2013)</ref> study contests between teams/alliances instead of between individual players.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">The Model</head><p>Consider two firms/players indexed by i 1, 2, that are located at the two ends of a unit line segment with firm 1 located at zero (left edge) and the other firm at location 1 (right edge). Each firm is endowed with a fixed competitive resource budget m i . Without loss of generality, assume that m 1 ≥ m 2 &gt; 0. Suppose that the line segment has a set of 2n + 1 markets (or prizes) that are equally spaced and indexed by k 1, . . . , 2n + 1. Market k 1 is at firm 1's location, while the market k 2n + 1 is at firm 2's location. Each of these k's could represent consumer market for a product, or an electoral market in a political contest, or different R&amp;D projects that firms may invest in.</p><p>Firms utilize their endowment by simultaneously choosing the amount b ik to invest in surplus creation in market k as well as the amount x ik with which to compete for the market. The decisions b ik can represent investments in awareness advertising or marketing activity to build primary/product category demand. For example in pharmaceutical markets several studies have established the role of direct to consumer advertising (DCTA) in informing the market about the basic drug or about increasing patient visits to doctors <ref type="bibr">Iyer: Multimarket Value Creation and</ref><ref type="bibr">Competition Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 1, pp. 129-149, © 2019 INFORMS</ref> thereby expanding primary demand (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Berndt et al. 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, Iizuka and Jin 2005</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">, Liu and Gupta 2011</ref>. The decisions x ik represent competitive or rent-seeking activities that are directed at winning the market from the rival. These could include comparative advertising or competitive promotional spending to convince consumers to buy from a firm rather than from the rival.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Exogenous Market Values</head><p>We begin with a basic analysis of competition between the firms when each market or prize has a fixed exogenous value v &gt; 0. This means that each firm would choose a competitive allocation strategy and firm i's allocation strategy can be represented by a vector x i (x I,1 , . . . , x i,2n+1 ), subject to its budget constraints, that is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">2n+1 k 1 x i,k ≤ m i .</formula><p>The effectiveness of a firm's competitive allocation in a market depends on the distance between its own location and the targeted market. For an arbitrary market k given the firms' choice of competitive outlays x i,k effective outlays y i,k are given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">y 1,k 1 − t(k − 1) 2n + 1 x r 1,k and (1) y 2,k 1 − t(2n + 1 − k) 2n + 1 x r 2,k .<label>(2)</label></formula><p>Thus, a firm's competitive outlay is relatively more effective in a market that is closer to it than to its rival. The effectiveness of a firm's spending depends on the distance between the firm and the market, and t ∈ (0, 1] measures the effectiveness loss caused by distance. In other words, it measures the extent of differentiation between the firms in their ability to compete for the different markets. Therefore, in this competition, each firm is favored in its own turf because its spending has greater relative effectiveness. Thus markets {1, . . . , n} are the "turf" of firm 1, and markets {n + 2, . . . , 2n + 1} those of firm 2.</p><p>In each market k the outcome of the competition is determined by a Tullock contest success function: each firm i wins a proportion of the market:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">p i,k y i,k y 1,k + y 2,k .<label>(3)</label></formula><p>Note that ties are broken fairly if both firms place zero outlays in any market; that is, each firm secures half of the market. Like in the marketing literature based on contest-like models (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bell et al. 1975)</ref>, the function p i,k can be interpreted as a share of market value firm i secures from market k. The allocation decisions can be seen as determining the market shares in each market in a proportional and smooth manner. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> We assume that the power term r ∈ (0, 1), which implies the effective outlays y i are a concave function that captures the standard idea of decreasing returns to additional marketing investments. Note also that this assumption of r ≤ 1 ensures a pure strategy equilibrium of the proportional prize contest interpreted as the competition for market share in our model <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Gradstein and</ref><ref type="bibr">Konrad 1999, Konrad 2009</ref>). 4 Each firm chooses its allocation strategy to maximize its aggregate payoff from all the markets π i (</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">x i ; x j ) 2n+1 k 1 (y i,k /(y 1,k + y 2,k ))v.</formula><p>For a given allocation strategy x j by its rival, a firm i will solve a constrained maximization problem given by max</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">x i π i (x i ; x j ), s.t. 2n+1 k 1 x i,k ≤ m i , x i,k ≥ 0, ∀k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1}.</formula><p>The firm's allocation problem to maximize payoffs embeds some important trade-offs: First, given that the resource endowment is limited, investing more in any given market necessarily means reducing the allocation for one or more of the other markets. Second, the market differentiation represented by t implies that each firm has to decide how much to invest in its home turf versus attack its rival's turf. We establish the unique pure strategy equilibrium of this multimarket game. Because unused budgets do not have any outside option value each firm will exhaust its budget and 2n+1 k 1 x i,k m i . In Section 3.2.1, we will consider the role of outside options. The first step in identifying the equilibrium is the following Lemma: Lemma 1. There exists no equilibrium in which a firm places zero outlay in any market; that is, x i,k &gt; 0, ∀k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1}.</p><p>Suppose there were to exist a market where both firms did not allocate any resources, then it will be optimal for one of the firms to shift an infinitesimal amount of resource from elsewhere to this market. Doing so would provide the firm with an incremental payoff of v while having a negligible effect on the payoff of the firm from the alternative market. Similarly, if only one firm were to not allocate any resources in a given market, the other firm would want to reduce its outlay to be negligibly small. Thus, in equilibrium, both firms compete for each one of the available markets by deploying positive resource allocation.</p><p>We now proceed to describe the interior equilibrium of the game in which x i,k &gt; 0, ∀k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1}. Define λ m 2 m 1 . The following proposition characterizes the equilibrium. Proposition 1. There exists a unique pure strategy Nash equilibrium in the game with fixed market values. In each market k, firms' allocate x 1,k</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">m 1 φ(k) 2n+1 k 1 φ(k) and x 2,k m 2 φ(k) 2n+1 k 1 φ(k)</formula><p>, where φ(k) is given by Firms spend the same proportion φ(k)/ 2n+1 k 1 φ(k) of their resource budget in each market. Hence, the ratio between firms' bids remains constant across markets, that is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">φ(k) r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 λ r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 λ r 2 .</formula><formula xml:id="formula_7">x 2,k x 1,k λ m 2 m 1 .</formula><p>One might think that a firm has fewer incentives to spend in a market that is farther away and in the rival's home turf. But it is easier for the rival to defend a closer market, because its spending in such a market is more efficient. The rival strategically lowers its spending in its home turf. These opposing incentives cancel out leading firms to choose a constant ratio of resource allocation across markets. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> The main point of interest in this proposition is the manner in which the firms split their resource budgets among the 2n + 1 markets. Defineφ(k) , φ(</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">k | t)/ 2n+1 k 1 φ(k | t)</formula><p>, which is the portion of resource each firm allocates in equilibrium to a market k. In the following proposition, we explore the properties of the functioñ φ(k) with respect to k.</p><p>Proposition 2.</p><p>1. The functionφ(k) first increases with k and peaks at a cutoff k * ≥ n + 1. It then decreases if k * &lt; 2n + 1.</p><p>2. When firms are symmetric (m 1 m 2 ), the peak k * is located at the middle market; that is, k * n + 1; when firms are asymmetric, that is, m 1 &gt; m 2 , the peak k * is located right to the midpoint; that is, k * &gt; n + 1.</p><p>The resource allocation functionφ(k) is nonmonotonic in k. Consider the case of symmetric firms (m 1 m 2 ). Each firm's allocation increases as it moves toward the center on its home-turf peaking at the market n + 1 in the middle and so the firms compete most intensely in the middle of the market. In markets close to its location a firm strategically withdraws and allocates fewer resources, because its spending is more effective. Whereas it also allocates fewer resources in markets that are farther away and in the competitor's turf precisely because its spending is relatively less effective. This leads to an inverted U-shaped equilibrium resource allocation profile with the maximum allocation by both firms in the middle.</p><p>The above result can be related to empirical studies in political markets. In the U.S. presidential elections, rival candidates must decide how to allocate their advertising budgets and their campaigning time across electoral markets that are differentiated according to Democratic and Republican preferences. <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Stromberg (2008)</ref> shows that presidential candidates in the 2000 and 2004 elections do not allocate their visits to states simply based on the size of the state, but rather based on the relative degree of competitiveness (closeness) of the race, with closer races getting greater allocations. More recently, <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Gordon and Hartmann (2016)</ref> analyze multimarket advertising competition in the 2000 and the 2004 presidential elections to show evidence of greater concentration of spending in the most competitive/ battleground markets relative to the nonbattleground markets, both under the electoral college rules and in a proportional direct vote counterfactual case.</p><p>When the firms are asymmetric and m 1 &gt; m 2 , the spending peak, k * , shifts to firm 2's turf. The most intense competition takes place in a market in the weaker firm 2's turf and the greater the asymmetry between the firms the closer is the peak to firm 2's location. The general result in the contest literature is that a more balanced playing field leads to more competition. In any given market k, the balance in the playing field depends on (1) the effectiveness of the firm's spending, which is determined by the distance between the market k and each firm, and (2) the firm's budgets. Symmetric firms have an advantage in their own turfs, and therefore the highest spending and competition occurs at the midpoint. When they are asymmetric, the most intense competition occurs in a market in firm 2's home turf, where the closer distance of the market to firm 2 can counteract the disadvantage of its smaller budget.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.1.">Effect of Market Differentiation and Other</head><p>Comparative Statics. How does the extent of differentiation of the market affect the equilibrium strategies? We turn our attention to this question in the next proposition: Proposition 3.</p><p>1. For symmetric budgets, the ratioφ</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">( k+1 { }| t) φ( k { } | t)</formula><p>strictly increases with t for k &lt; n + 1, while it strictly decreases for k ≥ n + 1; that is, competitive rent-seeking resources are increasingly spent in the markets closer to the middle.</p><p>2. For asymmetric budgets, ∂k * ∂t ≤ 0, the spending peak k * shifts to the left side of the line.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Note thatφ</head><formula xml:id="formula_10">( k+1 { }| t) φ( k { } | t)</formula><p>is the ratio of spending on market k + 1 as compared with market k and this ratio strictly increases with market differentiation for k &lt; n + 1, while it strictly decreases for k ≥ n + 1. As t increases, distance of a market from a firm causes a greater attenuation of the firm's spending effectiveness and so each firm gets a greater advantage in markets on its own home turf. This reduces a firm's spending in more remote markets and therefore provides incentives for the rival to also spend less in protecting closer markets. Thus, we get the unexpected result that greater t leads to increasingly intense competition in marginal markets in the middle. This result is noteworthy precisely because an increase in t is equivalent to the market being more differentiated between the firms. And greater differentiation leads firms to compete more in the middle, rather than in closer markets where they have a natural advantage. The direct vote counterfactual analysis in <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Gordon and Hartmann (2016)</ref> indicate that in the 2000 presidential election the overall national vote margin between the candidates was much <ref type="bibr">Iyer: Multimarket Value Creation and</ref><ref type="bibr">Competition Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 1, pp. 129-149, © 2019 INFORMS</ref> smaller when compared with that in the 2004 election suggesting that the election was more competitive (less differentiated) in 2000. And the relative spending by the candidates in the nonbattleground states was higher in 2000 and this can be seen as being consistent with the result in Proposition 3 that greater differentiation leads to more concentration of spending in the middle markets.</p><p>When firms have asymmetric budgets the location of the spending peak k * depends on several factors, such as the extent of market differentiation, the asymmetry between their budgets (λ), and the competitive technology. It is interesting to note that ∂k * ∂t ≤ 0. Increasing differentiation leads firms to spend more on the markets on the left: firm 1 "retreats" as t increases and concentrates more spending in closer markets. Therefore, the market with the most intense competition moves closer to firm 1, which has the budget advantage. Greater differentiation reduces firm 1's spending effectiveness in markets that are farther away.</p><p>We can also show that ∂k * ∂λ ≤ 0. In other words, as the asymmetry between the firms increases (i.e., λ m 2 m 1 decreases), the spending peak k * is pushed rightward into firm 2's turf, and firms increasingly concentrate their resources to compete in markets that are on the right. Intuitively, the weaker firm (firm 2) is induced to focus its limited budget on closer markets. This allows firm 1 to divert its spending from its home turf and move them to markets closer to firm 2. Thus, firm 2 substitutes for its lack of resources by the effectiveness of its spending in closer markets. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">1</ref> illustrates the comparative statics. Finally, increases of r leads k * to move rightward: as r increases, the competition for the markets becomes more discriminatory, and this magnifies firm 2's disadvantage, forcing it to focus more on closer markets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Endogenous Budget Choices</head><p>We now extend the basic model by allowing firms to endogenously choose their budgets and therefore the amount of spending they would want to deploy in the market competition. The incentive of firms to choose budgets can be represented in two important ways: First, firms might have an alternative use or outside option for their budget endowments m i . In this case firms must decide how much of their budget endowment to deploy in the market versus on the outside opportunity. Second, firms may choose the amount of budget resources to deploy given that they have increasing costs. Both these possibilities are examined below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1">Budget</head><p>Choice with Outside Options. Suppose that each firm has a potential alternative use for its budget: Specifically, each firm i can invest its endowment in a numeraire good x i,0 , which has unit marginal utility. As before, firm 2 has a (weakly) larger endowment of m 2 ≥ m 1 . Each firm's strategy is given by a vector</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">x i (x i,0 , x i,1 , . . . , x i,2n+1</formula><p>) and the following maximization problem:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">max x i u i (x i ; x j ) π i (x i ; x j ) + x i,0 , s.t. 2n+1 k 0 x ik ≤ m i , x i,k ≥ 0, ∀k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1}, with π i (x i ; x j ) 2n+1 k 1 y i,k y 1,k +y 2,k v.</formula><p>As before in equilibrium each firm will allocate its budget across the markets k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1} such that they yield the same level of marginal utility. Obviously, there exists no equilibrium in which either of the firms invests zero resources in competitive rent-seeking activities. Definem i 2n+1 k 1 x i,k , that is, firm i's endogenously determined total spending on competition across all markets. Further, define</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">τ ≡ τ(m i |m 1 ,m 2 ) 2n+1 k 1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m 1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m 1 r 2 m i .</formula><p>Proposition 4. The following characterizes the equilibrium of the game with outside options:</p><p>1. (Corner equilibrium) When</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">1 v ≤ τ(m 2 |m 1 , m 2 ) |m 1 m 1 ,m 2 m 2 , both firms deploy their entire budget on market competition, that is, x * i,0 0 andm * i m i . 2. (Interior equilibrium) When the condition τ(m 1 |m 1 , m 2 ) |m 1 m 2 m 1 &lt; 1 v ,</formula><p>then neither firm invests all of its budget in market competition. There exists a uniquem * that satisfies </p><formula xml:id="formula_15">1 v 2n+1 k 1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_16">τ(m 2 |m 1 ,m 2 )|m 1 m 1 ,m 2 m 2 &lt; 1 v ≤ τ(m 1 |m 1 ,m 2</formula><p>)|m 1 m 2 m 1 holds, firm 1 exhausts its budget on rent-seeking activities, whereas firm 2 does not. There exists a uniquem * 2 that satisfies</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">1 v 2n+1 k 1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m 1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m 1 r 2 m * 2 .</formula><p>Firm 2 spends in totalm * 2 on competitive rent-seeking activities and m 2 −m * 2 on the numeraire good. Proof. See the appendix. ■</p><p>The endogenous choice of the firms to invest in market competition in the presence of outside options depends on the value of the market relative to the size of the budget endowments of the firms. When the value of the market (v) is relatively large, but the budgets endowments of both firms are not too large</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">( 1 v ≤ τ(m 2 |m 1 ,m 2 ) |m 1 m 1 ,m 2 m 2 )</formula><p>, we have a corner equilibrium in which both firms exhaust their entire budgets in market competition and thus do not spend on the outside option. This case reduces to our basic model in the previous section with fixed budgets, and the presence of outside options does not affect the results.</p><p>In contrast, when</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">( 1 v &gt; τ(m 1 |m 1 ,m 2 ) |m 1 m 1 ,m 2 m 2 )</formula><p>, then neither firm will exhaust its entire budget because the market value is relatively small while the budget endowments of both firms are sufficiently large. Ex post symmetry in the equilibrium is interesting to observe, in the sense that firms spend the same amount of resources on competitive rent-seeking, despite the asymmetry in their budgets. Thus, in this case, both firms deploy some part of their budgets on their outside opportunity. Finally, we have a hybrid equilibrium, in the sense that the firm with the smaller budget, spends all its resources on rent-seeking activities, while the firm with the larger budget divides its budget between rent seeking and the numeraire good. This happens when v falls in an intermediate range or when the differential between m 1 and m 2 is sufficiently large.</p><p>It is also useful to explore how the extent of market differentiation (t) affects the amount of the budget allocated to market competition versus the outside opportunity.</p><p>Corollary 1. When t increases, (1) the corner equilibrium is more likely to emerge, in which case both firms spend all their budget resources on competitive rent-seeking, (2) in the fully interior equilibrium, firms spend more budget resources on competitive rent-seeking compared with the outside option, and (3) in the hybrid equilibrium, firm 2 spends more of its budget resources on competitive rent seeking.</p><p>We have the interesting finding that greater market differentiation actually leads firms to tilt their resource allocation more toward rent-seeking market competition. This result may be seen as contrary to intuition because one might think that an increase in t should lead to a less effective competitive rent-seeking technology. However, with increasing t a firm's advantage in closer markets increases, while its incentive to invest in remote markets goes down, which leads to a reduction in rent dissipation (wasted spending). Consequently, firms end up with a higher marginal benefit from their competitive rent-seeking activities. In turn, this leads them to divert more resources toward market competition, rather than the outside opportunity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2.">Costly</head><p>Budgets. Another natural way to relax the fixed budget assumption is to consider the endogenous choices of firms when the budget decisions are costly <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Snyder 1989)</ref>. Specifically, suppose that a firm's choice of x i,k involves a constant marginal cost c i . Without loss of generality, let firm 1 have a cost advantage, such that c 2 ≥ c 1 &gt; 0. Such a cost may represent the firm's cost of raising additional capital or productive resources (e.g., sales force size) that is required for the market. Recall that firms' effective outlays in a k are given by (1), and firm i, at market segment k, wins with a probability given by the contest success function in (3).</p><p>Firms simultaneously commit to their distributions of spending outlays in the 2n + 1 segments. For each segment k, firms' marginal benefits are</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">∂π 1 ∂x 1,k r 1 − (k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x r−1 1,k x r−1 2,k x 2,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x r 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x r 2,k 2 v; ∂π 2 ∂x 2,k r 1 − (k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x r−1 1,k x r−1 2,k x 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x r 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x r 2,k 2 v.</formula><p>The equilibrium is determined by the following conditions:</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">∂π 1 ∂x 1,k ∂π 1 ∂x 1,k c 1 ; ∂π 2 ∂x 2,k ∂π 2 ∂x 2,k c 2 .</formula><p>From this we have that in equilibrium</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">x 2,k x 1,k c 1 c 2 . Define c c 2 c 1 .</formula><p>We have the following proposition. Proposition 5. In the equilibrium, firm i will deploy a competitive spending allocation given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">x i,k r 1 − (k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 c r c i 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 c r + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 2 v in each market k, i ∈ {1, 2}, k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1}.</formula><p>It can be seen that x * i,k peaks in a market k * ≥ n + 1, and each firm has an inverse U-shaped distribution of competitive spending outlays similar to what is described in Proposition 2 for the case of fixed budgets. Thus, with endogenous budget choices all the results</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fu and Iyer: Multimarket Value Creation and Competition</head><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2019</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 38, no. 1, pp. 129-149, © 2019</ref> obtained in section 3 for the case of exogenously fixed budgets are robust with the lower cost firm being analogous to the firm with the higher budget.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Endogenous Value Creation: Guns vs. Butter</head><p>We now consider the full model in which the firms compete by spending in both value creation as well as rent seeking. Firm i's spending in each market k is a pair (b i,k , x i,k ): recall that b i,k is a productive investment that increases the surplus or value created in market k, whereas x i,k is the firm's competitive rent-seeking spending that helps it to get a larger share of the surplus in the market. Firms simultaneously commit to their strategy (b i , x i ), where b i is the vector</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">(b i,1 , . . . , b i,2n+1 ), with 2n+1 k 1 b i,k + 2n+1 k 1 x i,k ≤ m i . The surplus created in market is given by v k v k (b 1,k , b 2,k )</formula><p>and is increasing and strictly concave in each argument. Further, v k (0, 0) 0 and</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">v k (b 1,k , b 2,k ) &gt; 0 if max(b 1,k , b 2,k ) &gt; 0.</formula><p>We can then show that Lemma 2. There exists no equilibrium in which both firms do not make positive productive investments in a market k, that is, v k &gt; 0, ∀k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1}.</p><p>Suppose there were to be a market in which neither firm invests. In that case both firms do not have to deploy competitive rent-seeking spending in that market. This means that one of the firms can gain from decreasing its investment in some other market where it faces competition and shifting it to this market. Thus we have that all markets will have positive surplus, and given this we know that the competitive rent-seeking spending must be positive everywhere as well.</p><p>To carry the analysis further we assume that v k b 1,k + b 2,k . This functional form represents the contexts of multimarket competition, which motivate our analysis about which the investments in value creation are substitutable and hence subject to free riding. For example, in pharmaceutical markets the firms might invest in DCTA to inform consumers and increase visits to doctors creating primary demand for the product category. Similarly, major cell phone manufacturers like Samsung and HTC have promoted the Android platform to move consumers from the iPhone to Android. The incremental demand for Android phones created by these promotional activities can be appropriated by rivals in a market. As another example, in the early days of the nascent satellite radio market, both the major competitors Sirius and XM invested in advertising that jointly expanded the overall category, in addition to brand-specific advertising (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bass et al. 2005</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Symmetric Budgets</head><p>This game described above highlights two simultaneous and related trade-offs: how to allocate the limited budget between value (surplus) creation and competition.</p><p>And how to allocate the budget across the different markets. To explore these trade-offs, consider first the case in which firms are ex ante symmetric, with m 1 m 2 m. For simplicity, we consider the case of r 1. The following proposition characterizes the unique symmetric equilibrium of this game. Proposition 6. There exists a unique symmetric equilibrium. In the equilibrium, firm 1 makes a positive investment b 1,k in surplus creation only for markets k ≤ n + 1 (firm 2's strategy is symmetric for markets k</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">≥ n + 1) given by b 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ 2 if k ≤ n; 1 − t n 2n+1 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ 2 2 if k n + 1; 0 if k &gt; n + 1, ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ (4)</formula><p>whereμ is the Kuhn-Tucker multiplier as defined in the appendix.</p><p>The equilibrium surplus created in market k is</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">v k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ , if k ≤ n + 1; 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ if k ≥ n + 1. ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩</formula><p>Finally, the two firms choose the same equilibrium competitive rent-seeking spending in each market given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">x i,k 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 2μ v k .</formula><p>The proposition identifies the trade-off between value creation and competition. Firms have the incentive to invest in value creation only in markets that are on their own home turf and in the middle (n + 1) market, but they compete for every market. Specifically, firm 1's investments in creating value decreases with k for k for k &lt; n + 1, whereas firm 2's investments decrease between from market 2n + 1 to k &gt; n + 1. Thus, firms concentrate more on building value in closer markets, and markets 1 and 2n + 1 have the highest value, whereas the middle market n + 1 generates the least amount of equilibrium surplus. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2</ref>(a) shows the distribution of surplus across the markets in equilibrium. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> This result also can be viewed in the context of the idea of home market advantage; that is, a systematic preference of the market/consumers to purchase local products. The natural question is when does this lead to home-turf bias in the investments made by firms. With endogenous market values, the value creation investments of the firms are higher in their home turfs even if all markets have the same productivity/effectiveness in value creation. Thus, we have the result that even in the absence of any home-turf advantage in value creation, the Fu and Iyer: Multimarket Value Creation and Competition presence of differentiation in competitive rent-seeking can lead to home-turf bias in equilibrium value creation. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> Clearly the endogenous market creation profile will affect the competitive rent-seeking spending incentives as the value of each market is no longer the same. Markets that are closer to each firm are larger, creating an incentive for firms to invest more in defending them from the rival's competitive spending. However, there is also the countervailing incentive to compete more intensely for markets that are closer to the middle, where each firm's relative dis/advantage in spending effectiveness is not too large. The tension between these two forces determines the equilibrium competitive spending profile x i,k .</p><p>We can note from the Proposition that the competitive spending (rent-dissipation) rate for market k is</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">1 − t(2n + 1 − k) 2n + 1 1 − t(k − 1) 2n + 1 μ 1 − t(k − 1) 2n + 1 + 1 − t(2n + 1 − k) 2n + 1 2 .</formula><p>As in the exogenous market value case, it strictly increases with k for k &lt; n + 1 and strictly decreases for k ≥ n + 1. But the equilibrium investment in value creation has an opposite profile leading to the highest amount of surplus v k created at the market coincident with the firms, while the middle market has the lowest surplus size. Thus, the incentive to compete most intensely for the middle market is offset by the fact that in equilibrium it will have the smallest size. Hence, the distribution of competitive rent-seeking bids is no longer single peaked, like in the case of fixed market values. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2</ref>(b) shows the distribution of competitive rent-seeking expenditures.</p><p>To examine the distribution of the competitive spending further, note that by symmetry, we will have in equilibrium that x i,k x i,((2n+1)−(k−1)) , and so without loss of generality, we focus on the left side of the line for firm 1, that is, k ≤ n + 1. Recall</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">x i,k 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 2μ and v k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ , which give x i,k 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 2 2μ 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 3 .</formula><p>We want to evaluate how x i,k changes with k. Because</p><formula xml:id="formula_31">1 − t(k − 1) 2n + 1 + 1 − t(2n + 1 − k) 2n + 1 2 − t • 2n 2n + 1 &gt; 0,</formula><p>to evaluate x i,k with respect to k, it is sufficient to examine the numerator, and it can be shown that its sign depends on t(4n</p><formula xml:id="formula_32">+ 3 − 3k) − (2n + 1) [ ] .</formula><p>Corollary 2.</p><p>a. Within each half of the line, the distribution of firms' competitive rent-seeking expenditures is in general nonmonotonic. The competitive spending x i,k reach their peak symmetrically in two marketsk 1 andk 2 , withk 1 2(n + 1) −k 2 &lt; n + 1 and correspondinglyk 2 2(n + 1) −k 1 &gt; n + 1.</p><p>b. The locations of the peak competitive spending move toward the midpoint as t increases and the firms becomes more differentiated.</p><p>The distribution of competitive spending is no longer monotonic within each firm's turf. As described earlier, the middle market no longer faces the most intense competition. Rather in an interesting contrast to the case of exogenous market values, we get that each firm chooses the highest the competitive spending at two symmetrically located markets on either side of the middle market k n + 1. Thus, when firms endogenously create the market, the most intense competition shifts to each firm turf, and this reflects the balance between fighting in markets where there is more surplus versus in markets in which competitive spending is more effective in winning the market from the rival.</p><p>The particular pattern depends on the size of t. Consider, for instance, the case of t 1. The expression  </p><formula xml:id="formula_33">t(4n + 3 − 3k) − (2n + 1) [</formula><p>] reduces to 2(n + 1) − 3k. The competitive spending x i,k increases and then decreases after reaching an interior peak. In contrast, suppose that t is sufficiently small, that is, t ≤ 2n+1 4n , the most intense competition simply occur in each firm's home court because in this case, t(4n + 3 − 3k) − (2n + 1)</p><p>[ ] k 1 ≤ 0. The second part of the corollary shows the interesting effect of firm differentiation on the competitive spending. The markets with the most intense competition are closer to the middle even as differentiation increases.</p><p>We now examine how market differentiation affects the extent to which firms invest in value creation versus spending on competitive rent seeking. This analysis is tractable for the three-market case, for which we obtain the following.</p><p>Proposition 7. Consider a three-market case with n 1. When t increases, firms invest less in the middle market and invest more on their home markets; that is, dv 2 dt &lt; 0 and dv 1 dt , dv 3 dt &gt; 0. They deploy fewer resources in competitive rent-seeking activities in all markets; that is, dx k dt &lt; 0, ∀k ∈ {1, 2, 3}. The degree of market differentiation affects both (1) firms' division of resources between rent-seeking activities and value-creating investments and (2) their resource allocation across market. With greater market differentiation both firms invest less in the middle market and more in their own turfs. A more differentiated market leads to lower effectiveness of a firm's competitive spending in the remote market and strengthens its advantage at its own turf. This increases the return to the firm's investment in its own turf, as it is more able to protect it from possible predation. Hence, firms shift investments in value creation to closer markets in their own turfs. At the same time, the greater advantage in the home market reduces the rival firm's ability to win those markets, which leads each firm to reduce its competitive expenditure accordingly. Further, because firms invest less in the middle market, the reduced value also elicits less competitive spending in the middle.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Asymmetric Budgets</head><p>Finally, consider the general case that allows firms to be endowed with asymmetric budgets with m 1 &gt; m 2 . Despite the asymmetry, Lemma 2 continues to hold: there exists no equilibrium in which a market ends up with zero surplus. As a result, both firms will invest in competitive rent-seeking activities in all markets, that is, x i,k &gt; 0, ∀i ∈ {1, 2}, k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1}. While a closedform solution to the equilibrium cannot be obtained, because of the nonlinearity of the production function and the budget asymmetry, it is still possible for us to characterize important properties of the equilibrium.</p><p>Proposition 8. When m 1 &gt; m 2 , we have that in equilibrium: a. Firm 1 invests more in value creation and deploys higher competitive rent-seeking spending.</p><p>b. The equilibrium surplus across markets, v k , is distributed as a U-shaped curve, strictly decreasing first and then strictly increasing.</p><p>c. A firm makes more investments in value creation in markets closer to its own location.</p><p>d. Firm 1 makes investment in value creation in markets 1 tok, withk ≥ n + 1, whereas only firm 2 invests in markets k + 1 to 2n + 1. Firm 2 also may invest ink (in a knife-edge case), but for markets 1, . . . , 2n + 1 { } \{k}, only one firm invests in equilibrium.</p><p>In the equilibrium, the ratio between firms' competitive rent-seeking expenditures remains constant across all markets (i.e.,</p><formula xml:id="formula_34">x 1,k x 2,k μ 2 μ 1 )</formula><p>, where μ 1 and μ 2 are the Kuhn-Tucker multipliers for firm 1 and 2's constrained maximization problem. This leads to the result in part (a) of the proposition that the firm with the budget advantage spends more in the rent-seeking competition. At the same time, it also invests more in value creation. This contrasts with the finding in the literature on single-market guns and butter competition that the firm with the budget advantage may invest more in value creation (butter) while the weaker firm with the smaller budget invests more in guns (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Skaperdas 1992)</ref>. Because the joint surplus is subject to competition, this leads to the firm with the smaller budget ending up with larger expected payoffs. In contrast, part (a) of the proposition shows that this result does not carry over to value creation competition in multimarket settings. With multiple markets and with market differentiation, firms have to trade-off, where to invest as well as how much to invest in value creation and in rent seeking competition. This allows for greater productive investments in closer markets by firm 1, where firm 2's competitive spending is less efficient.</p><p>As shown in the proposition, in general, in each market only one firm makes productive investments and so the equilibrium value creation profiles of the two firms are mutually exclusive. This can be seen as a strategic attempt by each firm to reduce free-riding of their value creation investments. This is different from the symmetric case, where we see (minimal) overlap. That is, both firms overlap in a single market in the middle (n + 1). The overlap is thus an artifact of symmetry.</p><p>In the asymmetric case, firm 1 invests on strictly more number of markets than firm 2. The distribution of value creation is similar to that in the symmetric case and each firm is more willing to invest in markets closer to its own position. As a result, the market values are distributed as a U-shape curve: firm 1's investments strictly decrease toward the other end of the line until it stops investing; in contrast, firm 2's investments pick up in markets closer to the right end of the line. This observation is qualitatively similar to that in the symmetric case. In the symmetric case, equilibrium productive investment is minimized at the middle market, i.e., n + 1. In the asymmetric case, as expected, it is minimized at a market to the right of the middle point, because of the asymmetry. In fact, if the asymmetry is sufficiently large, firm 2 may stop investing in value creation, and focus its resource only on competitive rent-seeking activities.</p><p>We can also establish some comparative statics pertaining to how the extent of asymmetry in the firms' budgets affect their strategies: specifically, greater asymmetry in the budget between the firms ( m 1 m 2 ) leads to increases in the equilibriumk; that is, firm 1 makes productive investments in more markets, whereas firm 2 invests in fewer markets. Consistent with this result greater budget asymmetry also leads to increases the ratio of firms' competitive expenditure (</p><formula xml:id="formula_35">x 1,k</formula><p>x 2,k ). Firm 1 therefore deploys relatively higher spending in rent seeking. Thus, the overall message is that in the presence of market differentiation and multimarket interactions greater budget advantage leads a firm to balance its actions such that it not only invests relatively more in value creation but also competes with greater resources.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Efficiency Differences in</head><p>Productive Investments Until this point we assumed that the market differentiation pertains to the competitive rent seeking efforts of the firms, and not to the productive investments. This may be seen as consistent with the contexts that motivate this paper. For example, generic advertising, which informs new consumers about the objective characteristics of the product category, should have similar effects on whether customers consider purchasing in the category, regardless of their relative preference for that firm. In this section we consider an extension in which a firm's efficiency in productive investments declines as the distance of the market from the firm increases. Specifically, we assume that by investing an amount b i,k , a firm's effective investment in a market segment k is given bỹ</p><formula xml:id="formula_36">b 1,k 1 − d(k − 1) 2n + 1 b 1,k and b 2,k 1 − d(2n + 1 − k) 2n + 1 b 2,k , with d ∈ (0, 1].</formula><p>We consider only sufficiently small d to ensure the existence of well-behaved equilibrium.</p><p>Like in the basic model, we derive symmetric equilibrium, with</p><formula xml:id="formula_37">x 1,k x 2,k x 1,2n+1−(k−1) x 2,2n+1−(k−1) and b 1,k b 2,2n+1−(k−1) .</formula><p>Proposition 9. In the symmetric equilibrium, each firm deploys competitive rent-seeking spending</p><formula xml:id="formula_38">x * k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 2μ * v * k in market k,</formula><p>where v * k is the equilibrium market value andμ * is a constant specified in the appendix. Firm 1 makes positive productive investments in markets 1, . . . , n + 1, whereas firm 2 invests in markets n + 1, . . . , 2n + 1. Each market has an equilibrium value</p><formula xml:id="formula_39">v * k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − d(k−1) 2n+1 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ * , k ∈ {1, . . . , n + 1} 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 − d(2n+1−k) 2n+1 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ * , k ∈ {n + 1, . . . , 2n + 1}. ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩</formula><p>Further, we obtain the following observations in the equilibrium.</p><p>Corollary 3. In the symmetric equilibrium, 1. v k strictly decreases with k for k ∈ {1, . . . , n + 1} and strictly increases for k ∈ {n + 1, . . . , 2n + 1}.</p><p>2. The rent-dissipation rate, that is, x * k /v * k , strictly increases with k ∈ {1, . . . , n + 1} and strictly increases for k ∈ {n + 1, . . . , 2n + 1}.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Proof. See the appendix. ■</head><p>Even if the efficiency of productive investments declines with distance, the equilibrium yields similar implications to those obtained in the baseline model. Firms invest more in segments closer to their own turfs, and market rents bottom out at midpoint. However, firms continue to compete more intensely in the middle. The same trade-off occurs in the extended setting: competition dissipates a larger portion of rents in the middle even as the value creation is smaller.</p><p>Finally, it is useful to consider the limiting case in which t 0. This is the opposite to our baseline model: firms no longer have home-turf advantage in competitive rent seeking in closer markets, but they are more productive in creating value in these closer markets. The analysis reveals the following:</p><formula xml:id="formula_40">x k 1 4μ * v k , and v k 1 − d(k−1) 2n+1 4μ * , k ≤ n + 1.</formula><p>The rent-dissipation rate, 1 4μ * , now becomes uniform across the different markets. However, the equilibrium market values v * k are strictly decreasing with k for k ≤ n + 1, and increasing for k ≥ n + 1. As a result, competitive rent-seeking spending x k also decreases with k for k ≤ n + 1 and then increases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusion</head><p>This paper develops a theory of multimarket interactions joins two basic trade-offs common to many important economic and business contexts: First, firms must invest resources in value creation that they can profitably extract. But, in competitive markets, they also have to compete for the market with rivals. This <ref type="bibr">Iyer: Multimarket Value Creation and</ref><ref type="bibr">Competition Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 1, pp. 129-149, © 2019 INFORMS</ref> leads to the trade-off of allocating limited resources to creating the market versus competing for it. Second, firms competing in differentiated markets must also decide how to allocate resources between different markets where they have a more or a less competitive advantage. In this paper, we develop and analyze a model of multimarket competition that captures these trade-offs and their effects on firm strategies.</p><p>When the market size is fixed, then the firms' allocation strategies are only governed by the competitive rent-seeking incentives, and each firm's equilibrium resource allocation strategies follow an inverted Ushaped profile. A firm spends less in closer markets in which its spending is relatively more effective, because it is easier to defend these markets from competition. At the same time, it also spends relatively less in faraway markets precisely because its spending is relatively less effective, and it is difficult to win these markets from competition. Thus, the most intense competition is for a market in the middle. Further, and counter to intuition, the competition for the marginal market in the middle becomes more intense even as the firms become more differentiated.</p><p>Next, the paper considers the dual trade-off in which firms decide how much to invest in creating value in each market as well as how much to spend in competing for the markets. In equilibrium a firm invests more in closer markets and the investment profile declines monotonically. For symmetric firms this leads to the most intense competition to move away from the middle market to one in each firm's home turf. We also find that with asymmetric budgets the firm with the advantage invests more in both value creation and in competitive rent-seeking spending. As the budget asymmetry increases the firm with the advantage invests in more markets closer to the weaker firm. Greater market differentiation leads to more value creation by firms in their home turfs and a reduction in the overall amount of competitive spending.</p><p>In the standard tradition of contest models, our study assumes that firms' strategic decisions are resource investments rather than prices. Thus, our model can be seen as representing market situations in which prices are either nonstrategic while firms make advertising or selling allocations (e.g., in the pharmaceutical and health market), or markets where prices are not relevant (for example political markets). There exist no analytically tractable models in the contest literature with pricing. This is because if firms' ability to price depends on the outcome of the rent-seeking (advertising) competition, this could potentially lead to endogenously determined market rents. A contest model with pricing is definitely worth studying. One possible micro foundation is to consider a logit like consumer choice formulation, but such a setup might require numerical analysis. Suppose we have a model such that a firm is able to increase its product's value to consumers if the firm prevails in advertising competition. Then compared with our analysis with fixed and uniform market values, a firm is more able to protect its existing advantage at closer market segments, which deters the rival firm from aggressive spending. In contrast, in middle markets where neither firm has a clear advantage, a firm should be able to price higher once it prevails in the advertising competition. This would compel both firms to step up spending efforts. We would therefore expect a qualitatively similar prediction that firms spend less in markets closer to the ends of line, while competing more in markets toward the middle.</p><p>An aspect of the problem that we have not explored is the role of potential uncertainty of firms about their rivals. For instance, a firm might be uncertain about the size of its rival's resource budget and the nature of this uncertainty should have a bearing on the extent to which firms invest in value creation versus rent seeking. The analysis of multimarket guns and butter competitions under incomplete information is a challenging problem that may be investigated in future work.</p><p>Proof of Lemma 1. The proof is by contradiction. Suppose there exists a market k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1} such that x i,k</p><p>x j,k 0. Then let firm i deviate by finding an infinitesimal «, such that it places an outlay of « in market k , but reduces its bid in some other market k by «. In this case, it will gain v at market k with probability one, but its probability of winning v in market k decreases negligibly. By continuity, that the firm must get strictly better with such a deviation establishes the contradiction.</p><p>Suppose now that x j,k &gt; 0 and x i,k 0. Now firm j can always gain by reducing x j,k to an infinitesimally small « and reallocating to other markets. This means that firm i has the incentive to deviate from x i,k 0, which establishes a contradiction.</p><p>Proof of Proposition 1. Evaluating π i with respect to an arbitrary x i,k yields</p><formula xml:id="formula_41">∂π 1 ∂x 1,k r 1 − (k−1) 2n+1 k 2n+1 x r−1 1,k x r−1 2,k x 2k 1 − (k−1) 2n+1 x r 1,k + k 2n+1 x r 2,k 2 v; ∂π 2 ∂x 2,k r 1 − (k−1) 2n+1 k 2n+1 x r−1 1,k x r−1 2,k x 1k 1− (k−1) 2n+1 x r 1,k + k 2n+1 x r 2,k 2 v.</formula><p>An interior optimum must satisfy ∂π1 </p><formula xml:id="formula_42">∂x 1,k ∂π 1k ∂x 1,k μ 1 , and ∂π ∂x 2,k ∂π2 ∂x 2,k μ 2 , ∀k, k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1}, k k . Hence, we must have x 2,k x 1,k x 2,k x 1,k μ1 μ2 , ∀k, k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1}, k k .</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>140</head><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2019</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 38, no. 1, pp. 129-149, © 2019</ref> Define λ ≡ μ1 μ2 . We then have x 2,k λx 1,k for all k. We can then rewrite ∂πi ∂x i,k as</p><formula xml:id="formula_43">∂π i ∂x i,k r 1 − (k−1) 2n+1 k 2n+1 λ r 1 − (k−1) 2n+1 + k 2n+1 λ r 2 v x i,k . Define φ(k) ≡ r 1 − (k−1) 2n+1 k 2n+1 λ r 1 − (k−1) 2n+1 + k 2n+1 λ r 2 .</formula><p>We then have x i,k φ(k) φ(k ) x i,k , and we must recursively obtain</p><formula xml:id="formula_44">x i,k φ(k) φ(1) x i,1 .</formula><p>Further, the resource (budget) constraints can be rewritten as</p><formula xml:id="formula_45">2n+1 k 1 x 1, k 2n+1 k 1 φ(k) φ(1) x 1,1 m 1 ; 2n+1 k 1 x 2,k λ 2n+1 k 1 x 1,k λ 2n+1 k 1 φ(k) φ(1) x 1,1 m 2 .</formula><p>As a result, we have λ m2 m1 and x 1,1 <ref type="bibr">k)</ref> , and, therefore, <ref type="bibr">(k)</ref> . This proves the proposition.</p><formula xml:id="formula_46">m1φ(1) 2n+1 k 1 φ(</formula><formula xml:id="formula_47">x 1,k m1φ(k) 2n+1 k 1 φ(k) and x 2k m2φ(k) 2n+1 k 1 φ</formula><p>Proof of Proposition 2. Apparently,φ(k | t) continues to be single-peaked, as the sign is determined by the term</p><formula xml:id="formula_48">(2n + 1) 2 − t(2n + 1)(n − 1) − t 2 n −(2n + 1)λ r (2n + 1) − t(3n + 1) + t 2 n −t(1 + λ r ) (2n + 1) − tn [ ] k ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ . Definek (2n+1) 2 −t(2n+1)(n−1)−t 2 n [ ] −(2n+1)λ r (2n+1)−t(3n+1)+t 2 n [ ] t(1+λ r ) (2n+1)−tn [ ]</formula><p>. If k is treated as a continuous variable, the functionφ(k | t) is then maximized at k k . Hence,φ(k | t) reaches its peak at</p><formula xml:id="formula_49">k * 0 i fk ≤ 0 2n + 1 i fk ≥ 2n + 1 arg max (int(k),int(k)+1)φ (k). if otherwise. ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩</formula><p>Obviously,k decreases with λ. It has a value of precisely</p><formula xml:id="formula_50">(2n + 1) 2 − t(2n + 1)(n − 1) − t 2 n − (2n + 1) (2n + 1) − t(3n + 1) + t 2 n 2t (2n + 1) − tn [ ] −(2n + 1)(n − 1) − tn [ ] −(2n + 1) −(3n + 1) + tn 2 (2n + 1) − tn [ ] 4n 2 + 6n + 2 − 2tn 2 − 2tn 2 (2n + 1) − tn [ ] 2n 2 + 3n + 1 − tn 2 − tn (2n + 1) − tn [ ] n + 1.</formula><p>This implies that in the asymmetric case, the peak appears to the right of n + 1.</p><p>Because λ &lt; 1, λ r decreases with r. As a result,k increases with r.</p><p>Proof of Proposition 3. Evaluatingk with respect to t leads to</p><formula xml:id="formula_51">∂k ∂t 1 t(1 + λ r ) (2n + 1) − tn [ ] { } 2 × −(2n + 1)(n − 1) − 2tn +(2n + 1)(3n + 1)λ r − 2tn(2n + 1) t(1 + λ r ) (2n + 1) − tn [ ] − (2n + 1) 2 − t(2n + 1)(n − 1) − t 2 n −(2n + 1)λ r (2n + 1) − t(3n + 1) + t 2 n ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ (1 + λ r ) (2n + 1) − tn [ ] + (2n + 1) 2 − t(2n + 1)(n − 1) − t 2 n −(2n + 1)λ r (2n + 1) − t(3n + 1) + t 2 n tn(1 + λ r ) ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ .</formula><p>Let ϕ(t) denote the numerator. We have ϕ(t) rewritten as</p><formula xml:id="formula_52">ϕ(t) −t(2n + 1)(n − 1) − 2t 2 n +t(2n + 1)(3n + 1)λ r −2t 2 n(2n + 1)λ r ⎡ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎣ ⎤ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎦ (1 + λ r ) (2n + 1) − tn [ ] { } − −t(2n + 1)(n − 1) − t 2 n +t(2n + 1)(3n + 1)λ r −t 2 n(2n + 1)(2n + 1)λ r ⎡ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎣ ⎤ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎦ (1 + λ r ) (2n + 1) − tn [ ] − (2n + 1) 2 − (2n + 1) 2 λ r (1 + λ r ) (2n + 1) − tn [ ] + (2n + 1) 2 − t(2n + 1)(n − 1) − t 2 n −(2n + 1)λ r (2n + 1) − t(3n + 1) + t 2 n tn(1 + λ r ) ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ (2n + 1) 2 λ r − (2n + 1) 2 − t 2 n −t 2 n(2n + 1)λ r (1 + λ r ) (2n + 1) − tn [ ] { } + (2n + 1) 2 − t(2n + 1)(n − 1) − t 2 n −(2n + 1)λ r (2n + 1) − t(3n + 1) + t 2 n tn(1 + λ r ) ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ .</formula><p>This is further rewritten as</p><formula xml:id="formula_53">(1 + λ r ) (2n + 1) 2 λ r − (2n + 1) 2 − t 2 n −t 2 n(2n + 1)λ r (2n + 1) + 2(2n + 1) 2 − t(2n + 1)(n − 1) −(2n + 1)λ r 2(2n + 1) − t(3n + 1) [ ] tn ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ (1 + λ r ) (2n + 1) 2 (λ r − 1) (2n + 1) − 2tn [ ] +t 2 n 2 (2n + 1)(λ r − 1)</formula><p>.</p><p>It is negative because λ &lt; 1.</p><p>Proof of Proposition 4. An optimum requires</p><formula xml:id="formula_54">∂π 1,k ∂x 1,k ∂π 1,k ∂x 1,k λ 1 ; ∂π 2,k ∂x 2,k ∂π 2,k ∂x 2,k λ 2 ,</formula><p>∀k, k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1}, k k . Hence, we continue to have</p><formula xml:id="formula_55">x 2,k x 1,k x 2,k x 1,k<label>λ1</label></formula><p>λ2 , ∀k, k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1}, k k . Analogous to the baseline setting, we must obtain recursively x i,k</p><formula xml:id="formula_56">φ(k) φ(1) x i,1 , with φ(k) ≡ r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m1 r 2 .</formula><p>Firm i's marginal utility from its advertising in market segment 1 is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_57">∂πi ∂xi1 xi1 x * i1 φ(1)v</formula><p>xi1 , which further leads to <ref type="bibr">Iyer: Multimarket Value Creation and</ref><ref type="bibr">Competition Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 1, pp. 129-149, © 2019</ref> </p><formula xml:id="formula_58">INFORMS ∂π i ∂x i1 x i1 x * i1 v φ(1)</formula><p>xi1 . Note</p><formula xml:id="formula_59">φ(1) xi,1 2n+1 k 1 φ(k) mi</formula><p>. We then rewrite the condition to obtain a firm's marginal utility from rent-seeking activities:</p><formula xml:id="formula_60">∂π i ∂x i,1 xi,1 x * i,1 2n+1 k 1 φ(k) m i v τ(m i |m 1 ,m 2 )v.</formula><p>Before we proceed, we first verify the following.</p><p>Claim 1. The function τ strictly decreases withm i .</p><p>Rewrite τ as</p><formula xml:id="formula_61">τ ≡ τ(m i |m 1 ,m 2 ) 2n+1 k 1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m1 r 2 m i ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ .</formula><p>We first verify the negative effect ofm 2 . Consider each item in the sum</p><formula xml:id="formula_62">r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m1 r 2 m 2 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 m1 rm r−1 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m1 r 2 .</formula><p>Because r ≤ 1, the numerator is nonincreasing withm 2 ; the denominator strictly increases with it. Hence, the sum must strictly decrease withm 2 . We then considerm 1 . Consider the inverse of each item in the sum:m</p><formula xml:id="formula_63">1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m1 r 2 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m1 r 1 − (k−1) 2n+1 m 1+r 2 1 + k 2n+1m r 2 m 1−r 2 1 2 r 1 − (k−1) 2n+1 k 2n+1m r 2 .</formula><p>The numerator strictly increases withm 1 , whereas the denominator is independent of it. Hence, the item in the sum must be strictly decreasing with it, so is the sum.</p><p>Our main claim then can be verified. Altogether, there are three cases. Recall ∂πi ∂xi1 xi1 x * i1 τ(m i |m 1 ,m 2 )v, which indicates a firm's marginal utility obtained from rent-seeking activities.</p><p>Case 1. 1 v ≤ τ(m 2 |m 1 ,m 2 ) |m 1 m1,m2 m2 . In this case, τ(m 1 | m 1 ,m 2 ) |m 1 m1,m2 m2 v ≥ τ(m 2 |m 1 ,m 2 ) |m 1 m1,m2 m2 v ≥ 1, which implies that both firms obtain higher marginal utilities from rent-seeking activities even if they spend all their resources on those. Then the numeraire good will be ignored entirely.</p><p>Case 2. τ(m 2 |m 1 ,m 2 ) |m 1 m1,m2 m2 v ≤ τ(m 1 |m 1 ,m 2 ) |m 1 m 2 m1 v &lt; 1. In this case, both firms end up with lower marginal utilities from rent-seeking activities than the numeraire good when they allocate all resources to rent seeking. Then investment in the numeraire good cannot be zero, and interior equilibrium emerges. The interior equilibrium requires</p><formula xml:id="formula_64">2n+1 k 1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m1 r 2 m 1 2n+1 k 1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 m 2 m1 r 2 m 2 1,</formula><p>which thus impliesm 1 m 2 m. Then we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_65">τ(m 1 |m 1 ,m 2 ) τ(m 2 |m 1 ,m 2 ) 2n+1 k 1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 2 m .</formula><p>It strictly decreases withm. There must exist a unique interior solutionm * , which satisfies</p><formula xml:id="formula_66">2n+1 k 1 r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 2 m * v 1. Case 3. τ(m 2 |m 1 ,m 2 )|m 1 m1,m2 m2 v &lt;1≤τ(m 1 |m 1 ,m 2 )|m 1 m 2 m1 v.</formula><p>In this case, firm 2 obtains a lower marginal utility from rent seeking when all resources go to such activities than the numeraire good. So firm 2 must divide its resources between rent seeking and the numeraire good. Firm 1, however, prefers to spend all its resources on rent-seeking activities. ■ Proof of Corollary 1. We first take first-order derivative of the term</p><formula xml:id="formula_67">r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 λ r 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 λ r 2</formula><p>with respect to t for an arbitrary k. The sign of this derivative is the same as that of</p><formula xml:id="formula_68">1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 λ r 2 .</formula><p>We have</p><formula xml:id="formula_69">d 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 λ r 2 dt − (k−1) 2n+1 t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 + (2n+1−k) 2n+1 t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 λ r ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ +2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 (k−1) 2n+1 + (2n+1−k) 2n+1 λ r ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 λ r 3</formula><p>Fu and Iyer: Multimarket Value Creation and Competition</p><formula xml:id="formula_70">− 2t(k−1)(2n+1−k) (2n+1) 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 λ r +2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 (k−1) 2n+1 + (2n+1−k) 2n+1 λ r ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 λ r 3 .</formula><p>We only need to look at the sign of the numerator. Rewrite it as <ref type="bibr">3</ref> .</p><formula xml:id="formula_71">− 2t(k−1)(2n+1−k) (2n+1) 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 λ r +2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 (k−1) 2n+1 + (2n+1−k) 2n+1 λ r ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ −2 2t(k − 1)(2n + 1 − k) (2n + 1) 2 + 2 (2n + 1) − t • 2n [ ] (k − 1) + (2n + 1 − k)λ r [ ] (2n + 1) 2 + 2 2t 2 (k − 1)(2n + 1 − k) (k − 1) + (2n + 1 − k)λ r [ ] (2n + 1)</formula><p>The sum is positive when t 0. Evaluating it with respect to t yields</p><formula xml:id="formula_72">− 2 2(k − 1)(2n + 1 − k) (2n + 1) 2 − 2 2n (k − 1) + (2n + 1 − k)λ r [ ] (2n + 1) 2 + 2 4t(k − 1)(2n + 1 − k) (k − 1) + (2n + 1 − k)λ r [ ] (2n + 1) 3 − 2 (2n + 1) 2 2(k − 1)(2n + 1 − k) + 2n (k − 1) +(2n + 1 − k)λ r − 4t(k−1)(2n+1−k) (k−1)+(2n+1−k)λ r [ ] (2n + 1) ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ . This is negative because 2n (k − 1) + (2n + 1 − k)λ r [ ] − 4t(k − 1)(2n + 1 − k) (k − 1) + (2n + 1 − k)λ r [ ] (2n + 1) 2 (k − 1) + (2n + 1 − k)λ r [ ] (2n + 1) n(2n + 1) − 2t(k − 1)(2n + 1 − k) [ ] &gt; 0. To see that, note (k − 1)(2n + 1 − k) ≤ n 2 .</formula><p>We now consider the situation of t 1. In this case, the sum is rewritten as</p><formula xml:id="formula_73">−2 2(k − 1)(2n + 1 − k) (2n + 1) 2 + 2 (k − 1) + (2n + 1 − k)λ r [ ] (2n + 1) 2 + 2 2(k − 1)(2n + 1 − k) (k − 1) + (2n + 1 − k)λ r [ ] (2n + 1) 3 2 (2n + 1) 3 −2(k − 1)(2n + 1 − k)(2n + 1) + (k − 1) + (2n + 1 − k)λ r (2n + 1) +2(k − 1)(2n + 1 − k) (k − 1) + (2n + 1 − k)λ r [ ] ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ .</formula><p>It increases with λ. Let λ 1. In this case, the terms in braces can be written as</p><formula xml:id="formula_74">− 2(k − 1)(2n + 1 − k)(2n + 1) + 2n(2n + 1) + 2(k − 1)(2n + 1 − k)2n −2(k − 1)(2n + 1 − k) + 2n(2n + 1) &gt; 0,</formula><p>which verifies the claim. ■ Proof of Lemma 2. Suppose otherwise. Then neither firm would exert competitive rent-seeking effort in a market with no surplus. Hence, a firm can strictly increase its payoff by decreasing its investment from other markets, where its rival also invests, but increase its investment in this market, where it is the sole claimant of the market surplus.</p><p>Proof of Proposition 6. We first demonstrate that in any symmetric equilibrium, firms exert the same amount of rent-seeking effort on every market, that is, x 1,k x 2,k , ∀k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1}.</p><p>Symmetric equilibrium, with</p><formula xml:id="formula_75">(b 1,k , x 1,k ) (b 2,2n+1−(k−1) , x 2,2n+1−(k−1) ), leads to μ 1 μ 2 . Hence, 1 − t(k − 1) 2n + 1 1 − t(2n + 1 − k) 2n + 1 x 2,k 1 − t(k − 1) 2n + 1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n + 1 − k) 2n + 1 x 2,k 2 1 − t(k − 1) 2n + 1 1 − t(2n + 1 − k) 2n + 1 x 1,k 1 − t(k − 1) 2n + 1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n + 1 − k) 2n + 1 x 2,k 2 , which gives x 1,k x 2,k .</formula><p>Defineμ μ 1 μ 2 and x k x 1,k x 2,k . The Kuhn-Tucker conditions can be rewritten as</p><formula xml:id="formula_76">∂π 1 ∂x 1,k ∂π 2 ∂x 2,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 2 x k b 1,k + b 2,k μ; ∂π 1 ∂b 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k ≤μ; ∂π 1 ∂b 2,k 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k ≤μ.</formula><p>It is impossible to have ∂π1 ∂b 1,k ∂π1 ∂b 2,k μ for k n + 1. Hence, except for the midpoint, no market has both firms make positive productive investment. In any symmetric equilibrium, v k v 2n+1−(k−1) . We must have ∂π1</p><formula xml:id="formula_77">∂b 1,k &gt; ∂π1 ∂b 1,2n+1−(k−1) and ∂π1 ∂b 2,k &lt; ∂π1 ∂b 1,2n+1−(k−1) . That is, for k &lt; ( &gt; ) n + 1, only firm 1 (2) invests.</formula><p>We then consider the midpoint, that is, k n + 1. Firms must both invest positively here, because ∂π1</p><formula xml:id="formula_78">∂b 1,k ∂π1 ∂b 2,k 1 n k 1 v 2 k + 4 n k 1 x k 2 n k 1 2n + 1 − t(k − 1) [ ] 2 4μ 2 (2n + 1) − tn [ ] 2 • 1 4 + 2 2n + 1 − t(2n + 1 − k) [ ] 2 (2n + 1) − tn [ ] . Further, v 2 n+1 1 16μ 2 and 2x n+1 2( 1 4μ 1 4μ ) 1 8μ 2 . We then have 2 n k 1 v 2 k + 4 n k 1 x k + v 2 n+1 + 2x n+1 . 1 μ 2 n k 1 2n + 1 − t(k − 1) [ ] 2 (2n + 1) − tn [ ] 2 1 2 + 2 2n + 1 − t(2n + 1 − k) [ ] (2n + 1) − tn [ ] + 3 16 . Hence,μ n k 1 2n+1−t(k−1) [ ] 2 (2n+1)−tn [ ] 2 1 4 + 2n+1−t(2n+1−k) [ ] (2n+1)−tn [ ] + 3 32 m .</formula><p>Proof of Proposition 7. Consider the special case of n 1. We havẽ</p><formula xml:id="formula_79">μ n k 1 2n+1−t(k−1) [ ] 2 (2n+1)−tn [ ] 2 1 4 + 2n+1−t(2n+1−k) [ ] (2n+1)−tn [ ] + 3 32 m 9 (3−t) 2 1 4 + 9 3−t + 3 32 m . We can then calculate v k by v k 1 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ , k ≤ n + 1. We have v 1 1 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ 3 4 1 9 39−t ( ) 4 + 3(3−t) 32 m ,</formula><p>which is increasing in t. So is v 3 . For v 2 , we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_80">v 2 1 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ 1 4μ ,</formula><p>which is decreasing in t, becauseμ increases with it.</p><p>Proof of Proposition 8. Note that the Kuhn-Tucker conditions laid out above continue to hold in the asymmetric case:</p><formula xml:id="formula_81">∂π 1 ∂x 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 2 b 1,k + b 2,k μ 1 ; ∂π 1 ∂b 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k ≤ μ 1 ; ∂π 2 ∂x 2,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 2 b 1,k + b 2,k μ 2 ; ∂π 1 ∂b 2,k 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k ≤ μ 2 .</formula><p>By the argument laid out above, the ratio between the firms' competitive rent-seeking outlays is constant across all markets,</p><formula xml:id="formula_82">x 1,k x 2,k<label>μ2</label></formula><p>μ1 . As a result, in each market k, firm 1 win with a probability</p><formula xml:id="formula_83">p 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 μ 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 μ 2 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ 1 ,</formula><p>and firm 2 wins with the complementary probability. Obviously, as k increases, that is, on a market further away from the left end, p 1,k strictly decreases and p 2,k strictly increases. We now lay out the following arguments successively, which build the proof for the proposition.</p><p>Claim 1. There exists at most one market in which both firms make positive productive investments.</p><p>Otherwise, assume that there are markets k, k ∈ {1, . . .</p><formula xml:id="formula_84">, 2n + 1}, such that b I,k , b i,k &gt; 0, ∀i ∈ {1, 2}. This implies 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k ) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k μ 1 ; 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k 1 − t(2n+1−k ) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k ) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k μ 2 ; this further leads to 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k</formula><p>Fu and Iyer: Multimarket Value Creation and Competition</p><formula xml:id="formula_85">1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k ) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k ) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k ) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k , which gives b 1,k + b 2,k b 1,k + b 2,k . However, 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k ) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k implies b 1,k + b 2,k b 1,k + b 2,k because 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k ) 2n+1</formula><p>x 2,k by the fact</p><formula xml:id="formula_86">x 1,k x 2,k x 1,k x 2,k μ2 μ1</formula><p>. This is a contradiction.</p><p>Claim 2. In the equilibrium, market rents are distributed as a Ushaped curve: it strictly decreases with k until a pointk and then strictly increases. Claim 3. Suppose that there exists a k 0 , with b 1,k0 , b 2,k0 &gt; 0, then we must have (1) for all k &lt; k 0 , b 1,k &gt; 0 and b 2,k 0 and (2) for all k &gt; k 0 , b 2,k &gt; 0 and b 1,k 0.</p><p>Otherwise, suppose k &lt; k 0 , with b 2,k &gt; 0. Then we must have b 1,k 0 by claim 1. Because firm 2 has positive productive investment at both k and k 0 , we must have</p><formula xml:id="formula_87">1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 2,k 1 − t(2n+1−k0) 2n+1 x 2,k0 1 − t(k0−1) 2n+1 x 1,k0 + 1 − t(2n+1−k0) 2n+1 x 2,k0 1 2 b 1,k0 + b 2,k0 μ 2 , which implies b 2,k &lt; b 1,k0 + b 2,k0 , because 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k &lt; 1 − t(2n+1−k0) 2n+1</formula><p>x 2,k0 1 − t(k0−1) 2n+1 x 1,k0 + 1 − t(2n+1−k0) 2n+1</p><p>x 2,k0</p><p>.</p><p>However, because firm 1 invests zero on k, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_88">1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 2,k &lt; 1 − t(k0−1) 2n+1 x 1,k0 1 − t(k0−1) 2n+1 x 1,k0 + 1 − t(2n+1−k0) 2n+1 x 2,k0 1 2 b 1,k0 + b 2,k0 μ 1 , which implies b 2,k &gt; b 1,k0 + b 2,k0 , because 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k &gt; 1 − t(k0−1) 2n+1 x 1,k0</formula><p>1 − t(k0−1) 2n+1 x 1,k0 + 1 − t(2n+1−k0) 2n+1</p><p>x 2,k0 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Contradiction.</head><p>The same argument applies to the second part of the claim. </p><formula xml:id="formula_89">1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 2,k &lt; 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k ) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k μ 1 . This implies b 2,k &gt; b 1,k + b 2,k because 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k &gt; 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k ) 2n+1 x 2,k . However, b 2,k &gt; 0 implies μ 2 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 2,k ≥ 1 − t(2n+1−k ) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k ) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 2 b 1,k + b 2,k , which implies b 2,k &lt; b 1,k + b 2,k because 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 x 2,k &lt; 1 − t(2n+1−k ) 2n+1 x 2,k 1 − t(k −1) 2n+1 x 1,k + 1 − t(2n+1−k ) 2n+1 x 2,k .</formula><p>Contradiction.</p><p>The same argument applies to the second part of the claim. Suppose μ 1 ≥ μ 2 . This implies that firm 1's spending on rent seeking is no more than firm 2's on every market. As a result, ∂π1 ∂b 1,k ≤ ∂π1 ∂b 1,2n+1−(k−1) . This implies that k 1 ≤ 2n + 1; that is, firm 1 makes productive investments in a smaller number of markets than does firm 2. At the same time, v 1,k ≤ v 2,2n+1−(k−1) must hold to make sure that firm 1 invests for k ≤ k 1 .</p><p>These facts imply that firm 1 spend less than does firm 2 on both rent seeking and productive investment, which contradicts the fact that firm 1 has a bigger budget, because a firm in this game has no reason to leave resource unused.</p><p>Claim 8. k 1 ≥ 2n + 1 Given μ 1 &lt; μ 2 , the claim is self-evident by the same argument that proves claim 7.</p><p>Assume that k 0 does not exist. We have for k</p><formula xml:id="formula_90">≤ k 1 , 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ 1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 μ 2 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ 1 2b 1,k x 1,k μ 2 μ 1 x 2,k ;</formula><p>We have yet to verify that b i,k strictly decreases with k for k ≤ n + 1. We consider two arbitrary consecutive segments, k, k + 1 with k &lt; n. The equilibrium requires</p><formula xml:id="formula_91">v k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − d(k−1) 2n+1 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ ; v k+1 1 − tk 2n+1 1 − dk 2n+1 2 1 − tk 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n−k) 2n+1 μ .</formula><p>These can be rewritten as</p><formula xml:id="formula_92">1 − d(k − 1) 2n + 1 b 1,k 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − d(k−1) 2n+1 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ ; 1 − dk 2n + 1 b 1,k+1 1 − tk 2n+1 1 − dk 2n+1 2 1 − tk 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n−k) 2n+1 μ . Thus, b 1,k 1 − d(k − 1) 2n + 1 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 2 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 μ ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ 2 ; b 1,k+1 1 − dk 2n + 1 1 − tk 2n+1 2 1 − tk 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n−k) 2n+1 μ ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ 2 . Because 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n+1−k) 2n+1 1 − tk 2n+1 + 1 − t(2n−k)</formula><p>2n+1 and 1 − t(k−1) 2n+1 &gt; 1 − tk 2n+1 , b 1,k &lt; b 1,k+1 .</p><p>We then consider the case k n. Consider the two segments n, n + 1. Because at the midpoint, b 1,n+1 b 2,n+1 , we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_93">1 − d(n − 1) 2n + 1 b 1,n 1 − t(n−1) 2n+1 1 − d(n−1) 2n+1 2 1 − t(n−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(n+1) 2n+1 μ ; 2 1 − dn 2n + 1 b 1,n+1 1 − tn 2n+1 1 − dn 2n+1 2 1 − tn 2n+1 + 1 − tn 2n+1 μ . These lead to b 1,n 1 − d(n − 1) 2n + 1 1 − t(n−1) 2n+1 2 1 − t(n−1) 2n+1 + 1 − t(n+1) 2n+1 μ ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ 2 ; 2b 1,n+1 1 − dn 2n + 1 1 − tn 2n+1 2 1 − tn 2n+1 + 1 − tn 2n+1 μ ⎧ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎨ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎩ ⎫ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎬ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎪ ⎭ 2 .</formula><p>It is obvious to see that b 1,n &gt; 2b 1,n+1 . We now calculate the sum of the firm's rent-seeking expenditures. By symmetry, the sum can be given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_94">2 2n+1 k 1 x k 4 n k 1</formula><p>x k + 2x n+1 . <ref type="bibr">Iyer: Multimarket Value Creation and</ref><ref type="bibr">Competition Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 1, pp. 129-149, © 2019 INFORMS</ref> </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Each firm spends x * i0 m i −m * on the numeraire good and m * i m * on market competition. 3. (Hybrid equilibrium) When m 2 &gt; m 1 and the condition</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. (Color online) Distribution of Competitive Spending</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. Distribution of Market Values and Competitive Outlays</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fu and Iyer :</head><label>Iyer</label><figDesc>Multimarket Value Creation and Competition</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Consider three arbitrary adjacent markets, k − 1, k andk + 1. Assume that b 1,k−1 + b 2,k−1 , b 1,k+1 + b 2,k+1 ≤ b 1,k + b 2,k .Recall the Kuhn-Tucker conditions. Because p 1,k strictly decreases with k, and p 2,k strictly increases with k, we must have the following: if firm 1 makes a productive investment in k − 1, then it cannot invest in k; if firm 2 makes a productive investment in k + 1, then it cannot invest in k.Supposeb 1,k−1 &gt; 0, b 2,k+1 &gt; 0, then b 1,k + b 2,k 0. This is a contradiction.Suppose b 1,k−1 0 and b 2,k+1 &gt; 0. Then only firm 1 has productive investment in k. This implies b 2,k−1 &gt; 0. By the Kuhn-Tucker condition, it also implies b 2,k−1 &gt; b 1,k , which leads to a contradiction. By the same logic, we conclude that it is impossible to have b 2,k+1 0 and b1,k−1 &gt; 0. Suppose b 1,k−1 b 2,k+1 0. This implies b 2,k−1 , b 1,k+1 &gt; 0. Because firm 1 positively invests in k + 1, but not k − 1, we must have b 1,k+1 &lt; b 2,k−1 .Because firm 2 positively invests in k − 1, but not k + 1, we must have b 1,k+1 &gt; b 2,k−1 . This is a contradiction.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Claim 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Suppose there does not exist a k 0 as described in claim 3.Consider two arbitrary markets k, k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1}, k &lt; k . If b 1,k 0, then b 1,k 0; similarly, if b 2,k 0, then b 2,k 0. Suppose b 1,k 0, then b 1,k &gt; 0.Then we must have b 2,k &gt; 0. The Khun-Tucker condition requires</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Claim 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Suppose there exist two markets k, k ∈ {1, . . ., 2n + 1}, k &lt; k , with b 1,k , b 1,k &gt; 0, then b 1,k &gt; b 1,k .Because p 1,k strictly decreases, by the Kuhn-Tucker condition, we must haveb 1,k + b 2,k &gt; b 1,k + b 2,k . By claims 1, 3, and 4, we have b 1,k &gt; b 1,k + b 2,k . Claim 6. Suppose there exist two markets k, k ∈ {1, . . . , 2n + 1}, k &lt; k , with b 2,k , b 2,k &gt; 0, then b 2,k &lt; b 2,k .This is implied by the proof of claim 5.Define k 1 max(k | b 1,k &gt; 0, b 2,k 0) and k 2 max(k | b 1,k 0, b 2,k &gt; 0). If k 0 exists, by definition, k 0 k 1 + 1 k 2 − 1; if k 0 does not exist, k 2 k 1 + 1. Claim 7. μ 1 &lt; μ 2 .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc> Iyer: Multimarket Value Creation and Competition   Marketing Science, 2019, vol. 38, no. 1, pp. 129-149, © 2019 INFORMS   </figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">MarketingScience, 2019, vol. 38, no. 1, pp. 129-149, © 2019 </note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">− t(k−1) 2n+1 1 − d(k−1) 2n+1 4 (2n+1)−tn 2n+1μ, which strictly decreases with t. However, as in the baseline model, the rent-dissipation rate strictly increases with k for k ≤ n + 1 and strictly decreases for k ≥ n + 1.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1"><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Gross and Wagner (1950)</ref> generalize the analysis to a finite number of markets. A number of studies apply the model to various contexts, for example, campaign financing allocations<ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Lake 1978)</ref>, advertising<ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Friedman 1958)</ref>, and military defense<ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Clark and Konrad 2007</ref>).2<ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Kvasov (2007)</ref> and<ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Roberson and Kvasov (2012)</ref> relax the usual assumption that resources are forfeited if they are not used for rentseeking competitions.3 Alternatively, the function p i,k also can be interpreted as a firm's probability of winning the entire market k in a winner-take-all competition,</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank Jinfeng Lu, Amit Pazgal, Shubhranshu Singh, and Hema Yoganarasimhan and seminar and conference participants at the University of Wisconsin and 2015 SAET Meeting (Cambridge) for comments.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Appendix as formulated in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Tullock (1980)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Konrad (2009)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Sheremeta et al. (2018)</ref> provide additional discussion of these two standard ways to interpret the contest model. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> More generally a unique pure-strategy equilibrium exists in a N player contest when r ≤ NN − 1, whereas a unique mixed-strategy equilibrium with continuously distributed spending/bids exists when r→' resulting in an all-pay auction like outcome, in which case an infinitesimal amount of overbidding by a player leads to a sure win. There is a limited characterization of the equilibrium behavior when r takes intermediate values: for 0 &lt; r ≤ 2, with two firms there is a pure strategy Nash equilibrium, but, for r &gt; 2, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Baye et al. (1994)</ref> show the existence of only a mixed-strategy equilibrium that fully dissipates the rent. There are also no general results if we change the contest structure. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Fu and Lu (2012)</ref> show that the pure strategy equilibrium breaks down when r &gt; 1 in a multistage sequential elimination contest. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> The equilibrium specified in Proposition 1 remains the same even in a sequential move game in which one firm first commits to its spending allocation and then the rival firm chooses its allocation strategy upon observing the first mover's strategy. In other words, the possibility of commitment by one of the firms does not change the equilibrium incentives. See the appendix for details. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> This can be compared with the literature on targeted advertising <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Iyer et al. 2005)</ref>, where two firms invest more in advertising in their (closer) high preference markets but relatively less in the more competitive markets, where the latter incentive comes from wanting to reducing price competition. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> In a different context of product line expansion, <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Joshi et al. (2016)</ref> show an equilibrium in which one firm expands its product line and doing so allows for better surplus extraction through the basic product from its core consumers.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-function and same-function alliances: How does alliance structure affect the behavior of partnering firms?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Amaldoss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Staelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="302" to="317" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collaborating to compete</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Amaldoss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Raju</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rapoport</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="126" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generic and brand advertising strategies in a dynamic duopoly</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Prasad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Sethi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="556" to="568" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The solution to the Tullock rent-seeking game when R &gt; 2: Mixed-strategy equilibria and mean dissipation rates</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Baye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kovenock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>De Vries</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Public Choice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3/4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="363" to="380" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A market share theorem</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Bell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Keeney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jdc</forename><surname>Little</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="136" to="141" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information, marketing, and pricing in the U.S. antiulcer drug market</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Berndt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Reiley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Urban</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="100" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">English translation by Savage L (1953) The theory of play and integral equations with skew symmetric kernels</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Borel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comptes Rendus de l&apos;Académie</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">173</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="100" />
			<date type="published" when="1921" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Econometrica</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Application de la théorie des probabilitiés aux jeux de hasard</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Borel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ville</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>Borel E, Chéron A eds. Théorie Mathematique du Bridgeà la Portée de Tous</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1938" />
			<publisher>Editions Jacques Gabay</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Paris; Paris</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Should managers use team-based contests?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2823" to="2836" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contests with multi-tasking. Scandinavian</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Konrad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="303" to="319" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Game-theory models in the allocation of advertising expenditures</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Oper. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="699" to="709" />
			<date type="published" when="1958" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Iyer</forename><surname>Fu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Multimarket Value Creation and Competition</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The optimal multi-stage contests</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Fu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="351" to="382" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Economics of conflict: An overview</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Garfinkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Skaperdas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Defense Economics</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sandler</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hartley</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="649" to="709" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advertising competition in presidential elections</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Gordon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hartmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Orchestrating rent seeking contests</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gradstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Konrad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">458</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="536" to="545" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A continuous Colonel Blotto game</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>RM-408</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1950" />
			<publisher>RAND Corporation</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Santa Monica, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The analytics of continuing conflict</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hirshleifer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Synthese</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="233" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The dark side of the force</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hirshleifer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of prescription drug advertising on doctor visits</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Iizuka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Management Strategy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="701" to="727" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competing for attention in social communication markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Iyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Katona</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2304" to="2320" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The targeting of advertising</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Iyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Soberman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Villas-Boas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="461" to="476" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Turf wars: Product line strategies in competitive markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Reibstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="128" to="141" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing optimal sales contests: A theoretical perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kalra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="170" to="193" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Agenda chasing and contests among news providers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Katona</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Knee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sarvary</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="783" to="809" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Konrad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Strategy and Dynamics in Contests</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Oxford, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contests with limited resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kvasov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">136</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="738" to="748" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new campaign resource allocation model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lake</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Applied Game Theory</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Brams</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Schotter</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Schwodiauer</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Wurzburg, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Physica</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Reprinted in</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing sales contests: Does the prize structure matter?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ahearne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="356" to="371" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of direct-to-consumer advertising of prescription drugs on physician visits and drug requests: Empirical findings and public policy implications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Res. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="205" to="217" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Favoring the winner or loser in repeated contests</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ridlon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="768" to="785" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The non-constant-sum Colonel Blotto game</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Roberson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kvasov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="397" to="433" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Winner-take-all and proportional-prize contests: Theory and experimental results</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sheremeta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Masters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Cason</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jebo.2018.01.023</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jebo.2018.01.023" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ePub ahead of print February 5</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cooperation, conflict, and power in the absence of property rights</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Skaperdas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="720" to="739" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Election goals and the allocation of campaign resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Snyder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="637" to="660" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How the electoral college influences campaigns and policy: The probability of being Florida</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Stromberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="769" to="807" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient rent seseking</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tullock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Towards a Theory of the Rent-Seeking Society</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Buchanan</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Tollison</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tullock</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>College Station</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Texas A&amp;M University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="112" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Iyer</forename><surname>Fu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Multimarket Value Creation and Competition Marketing Science</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="149" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
