<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Target the Ego or Target the Group: Evidence from a Randomized Experiment in Proactive Churn Management</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2018-08-28">August 28, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><surname>Godinho De Matos</surname></persName>
							<email>miguel.godinhomatos@clsbe.lisboa.ucp.pt</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Católica Lisbon School of Business and Economics</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>1649-023</postCode>
									<settlement>Lisbon</settlement>
									<country key="PT">Portugal</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Pedro</forename><surname>Ferreira</surname></persName>
							<email>pedrof@cmu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Engineering and Public Policy</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Heinz College</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>15213</postCode>
									<settlement>Pittsburgh</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Rodrigo</forename><surname>Belo</surname></persName>
							<email>rbelo@rsm.nl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Rotterdam School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Erasmus University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>3062 PA</postCode>
									<settlement>Rotterdam</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">Zuid-Holland</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="NL">Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Target the Ego or Target the Group: Evidence from a Randomized Experiment in Proactive Churn Management</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 (print)</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2018-08-28">August 28, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.2018.1099</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: September 8, 2016 Revised: September 28, 2017; February 16, 2018 Accepted: March 1, 2018 History: Avi Goldfarb served as the senior editor and Peter Verhoef served as associate editor for this article. Funding: M. Godinho de Matos acknowledges support from the Portuguese Foundation for Science and Technology [Grant UID/GES/00407/2013] and Fundação para a Ciência e a Tecnologia [Grant 10.13039/501100001871.3].</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:26+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>churn management</term>
					<term>client lifetime value</term>
					<term>social networks</term>
					<term>randomized experiment</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We propose a new strategy for proactive churn management that actively uses social network information to help retain consumers. We collaborate with a major telecommunications provider to design, deploy, and analyze the outcomes of a randomized control trial at the household level to evaluate the effectiveness of this strategy. A random subset of likely churners were selected to be called by the firm. We also randomly selected whether their friends would be called. We find that listing likely churners to be called reduced their propensity to churn by 1.9 percentage points from a baseline of 17.2%. When their friends were also listed to be called, their likelihood of churn reduced an additional 1.3 percentage points. The client lifetime value of likely churners increased 2.1% with traditional proactive churn management, and this statistic becomes 6.4% when their friends were also listed to be called by the firm. We show that, in our setting, likely churners receive a signal from their friends that reduces churn among the former. We also discuss how this signal may trigger mechanisms akin to both financial comparisons and conformity that may explain our findings.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Customer retention is a central concern in many industries, in particular in IT-related markets, in which churn rates are considerably high. For example, cell phone companies report churn rates as high as 2% per month <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Bensoussan et al. 2014</ref>) and pay-TV firms experience churn rates of about 1% per month <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Green 2016)</ref>. Such high churn rates have a significant impact on the value and profitability of firms <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Gupta et al. 2004)</ref>. As a consequence, customer retention is a fundamental issue in marketing research. In general, there are two main approaches to manage customer churn: firms can either wait for consumers to request service to be disconnected and extend them aggressive retention deals when this happens-reactive churn management-or they can try to anticipate which consumers are likely to churn and reach out to them before they do-proactive churn management. Reactive churn management focuses on users who have already signaled their willingness to leave the firm. However, at that stage, it might be too late to convince them to stay. With proactive churn management, firms reach consumers sooner, which may be cheaper, but they may also extend deals to users who were unlikely to leave.</p><p>Proactive churn management is often viewed as a more sophisticated approach potentially leading to better results for the firm. However, it is still hard to generalize the effects of proactive churn management even within the telecommunications industry. Although some studies found that proactive churn management helps retain consumers, such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Burez and Van den Poel (2007)</ref> in the context of pay-TV services, others report an increase in the churn rate of the targeted consumers, such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ascarza et al. (2016)</ref> in the context of prepaid mobile. In parallel, a number of studies have looked at the role of social networks in consumer decision making in the context of IT. However, only a few studies have looked at the impact of peer effects on churn. <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Nitzan and Libai (2011)</ref> analyzed a large data set from a cell phone provider and found that exposure to a churner is positively associated with churn. In a more recent study, <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Ascarza et al. (2017a)</ref> identified customers at risk in another cell phone provider and found that giving them a monetary credit increased usage and lowered churn across both the treated consumers and their connections. The authors attribute this result to the explicit network externalities associated to how consumers can use the gifted credit to place calls.</p><p>In this paper, we study a new strategy to retain consumers and compare its performance to that of traditional proactive churn management. Once proactive churn management may be profitable in pay-TV markets and IT-related services may benefit from peer influence, we ask whether it may be profitable for a telecommunications firm that offers triple-play service to combine churn management with peer effects. In particular, and in a context without explicit network externalities, does it help to reach out to the friends of likely churners as a way to create "goodwill" around the latter to retain them? The contribution of our paper relies on actively using the social network to design a profitable intervention for the firm as opposed to the previous literature that only used the social network to find peer effects a posteriori. We call this new strategy, in which the friends of likely churners are also contacted by the firm, socially based proactive churn management. This strategy proposes a "group-centric" approach to manage churn as traditional proactive churn management is usually focused on targeting consumers independently.</p><p>We collaborate with a major telecommunications provider to design, implement, and analyze outcomes of a randomized control trial at the household level. We use data from pay-TV subscriptions to develop a model to predict likely churners and data from call detailed records (CDRs) to draw a social graph across households. On a monthly basis, and during eight consecutive months, we select a random set of likely churners and their friends and allocate them randomly across four different experimental conditions. In particular, we randomly and independently select whether both the former and the latter are listed to be called by a firm's call center. The goal of these calls is to identify likely churners and extend them retention deals to demote them from churning.</p><p>We find that, in our setting, traditional proactive churn management decreases the churn rate of likely churners by 1.9 percentage points (p &lt; 0.01), from a baseline of 17.2%. The latter is the churn rate observed with reactive retention only. We also find that socially based proactive churn management decreases this statistic by an additional 1.3 percentage points (p &lt; 0.05) and increases customer lifetime value relative to traditional proactive churn management, thus improving the firm's bottom line. In addition, we also find no significant change in the churn rate of the friends of likely churners across all our treatment conditions. Our results show that, in our setting, likely churners receive a signal from their friends that lowers their likelihood of churn, which the firm can use to its benefit by targeting consumers along with their friends. This signal may trigger mechanisms akin to conformity and financial comparisons, which are likely to explain the results we observe in our setting. The remainder of this paper is organized as follows. Section 2 reviews the relevant literature. Section 3 describes the context of our study, and Section 4 explains our experiment in detail. Section 5 shows our results, and Section 6 concludes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Relevant Background</head><p>Customer retention has been a central issue in marketing research since the late 1990s. The early studies focused on identifying the drivers of consumer churn and highlighted that customer demographics, such as age, gender and tenure, satisfaction, and perception of fairness, affect the length of stay (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Bolton 1998, Bolton and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Lemon 1999)</ref>. Customer retention has been studied in many different contexts, such as loyalty programs, switching costs, customer self-service channels, pricing policies and advertising expenditure, and management of firmcustomer interactions <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Reinartz and Kumar 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">, Venkatesan and Kumar 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">, Reinartz et al. 2005</ref>). In general, these studies show that the drivers of customer churn are similar across industries and over time. Customer retention has also become a fundamental concern for practitioners because it has been directly linked to firm profitability <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Anderson et al. 1994</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">, Rust et al. 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">, Villanueva et al. 2008</ref>. Even small increases in retention rates have been shown to yield significant increases in profits <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Reichheld and</ref><ref type="bibr">Sasser 1990, Reichheld 2003</ref>) because existing consumers tend to be more loyal and generate more revenue <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Reichheld and</ref><ref type="bibr">Sasser 1990, Reichheld 2003)</ref>.</p><p>Firms pursue two main approaches to manage customer churn <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Winer 2001)</ref>, namely reactive churn management, whereby they wait for consumers to signal their intention to leave and at that time they try to avoid so by offering them aggressive retention deals, and proactive churn management, whereby firms try to contact likely churners early to extend them deals to retain them. Proactive churn management may yield higher profits because firms reach consumers at a point in time at which they are cheaper to retain, for example, before contracts expire when consumers have not yet surveyed the market to learn about alternatives. However, the firm needs to identify customers at risk to implement proactive churn management. In particular, the firm needs to reach true churners to avoid losing too much profit with false positives. Therefore, proactive churn management typically starts by identifying likely churners, which has been an exercise that attracted significant Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group research effort in the churn management literature. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Neslin et al. (2006)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Lemmens and Croux (2006)</ref> were among the first to study data-intensive algorithms to predict churn. Please refer to <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Ascarza et al. (2017b)</ref> for a detailed review of more recent papers on this topic.</p><p>The traditional approach to proactive churn management suggests that firms should target individuals with high probability of churn <ref type="bibr">(Blattberg et al. 2008, p. 632)</ref>. However, the literature provides mixed results in this respect. In the context of pay-TV, <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Burez and Van den Poel (2007)</ref> find a positive effect of proactive churn management on profit. The authors study churn using data from a company that experiences a churn rate of 15%/year, select the top 30% likely churners, and gift them with an invitation to a unique event or free movie tickets or simply ask them to fill in a satisfaction survey. All treatment conditions lead to significant lower churn rate (reductions between 3% and 5% from the aforementioned statistic) with the latter condition being the most efficient in terms of profit to the firm given its low implementation cost (essentially, not extending offers to consumers). In contrast, <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ascarza et al. (2016)</ref> study churn in a market for prepaid mobile service-experiencing a 6% average churn rate per quarter-and find a negative effect of proactive churn management. The authors select users predicted to benefit from upgrades in their tariff plan and offer a random subset of them a $15 credit for a period of three months, conditional on them upgrading their tariff plan. They find that the churn rate across treated consumers increases to 10% per quarter. The authors provide additional evidence showing that the intervention might have reduced the customers' inertia to change and increased the saliency of usage, potentially leading some customers to search for services from competitors that could better fit their calling needs.</p><p>These studies pertain to very different contexts. The former looks at a market in which consumers become locked in before they can churn without paying a financial penalty. The latter looks at a prepaid service from which consumers could churn by simply winding down their account balance. These differences alone may account for the different churn rates observed in these markets, the differences in the observed behavior of consumers, and the differences in the mechanisms that led to such behavior, but they highlight that the question of who to target is far from trivial. More recently, a number of studies propose to choose targets based on their expected profitability <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Lemmens and Gupta 2017)</ref> or on their likelihood of changing behavior if targeted, also known as uplift <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Ascarza 2017)</ref>, rather than on their absolute level of risk because such approaches are likely to better maximize client lifetime value <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Gupta et al. 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">, Blattberg et al. 2008</ref>. The argument used in these papers is that optimizing targeting algorithms only to identify the individuals who are most likely to churn may end up targeting less profitable ones, that is, those who would always stay with the firm, those who never stay with the firm, or those who may be induced to leave because of targeting.</p><p>All studies mentioned before assume that consumers make independent decisions about which services to abandon. In these studies, consumers are described as independent agents who make decisions based on their individual experience with the services to which they subscribe, their personal profile, and the marketing they receive <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Peres et al. 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">, Solomon 2014</ref>. Accordingly, marketing campaigns have been largely designed to target consumers one by one. However, in recent times, researchers began collecting evidence showing that social networks play an important role in many consumer decisions, including churn. <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Nitzan and Libai (2011)</ref> ran an observational study over one million customers of a cellular company and found that exposure to a churner is associated with an increase of 80% on the hazard of churn. The authors found this result after controlling for a number of individual-level covariates that proxy social, personal, and purchaserelated traits, which lessen concerns with endogeneity. They also discuss how this effect is economically large by comparing it with those found in the literature on adoption. In addition, they also found that the effect of social influence depends on the number of ties, tie strength, customer loyalty, and that it decays exponentially over time. Highly connected customers are more affected by neighbor defection, and loyal customers are less so. This study provides a thorough analysis of how communication across consumers affects churn and shows why studying the relationship between peer effects and churn is paramount for managers in the field. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Ascarza et al. (2017a)</ref> complements our knowledge of peer influence on churn. The authors report the existence of spillovers in churn behavior by looking at the outcomes of a randomized field experiment in prepaid mobile. They found that proactively targeting likely churners has a positive effect not only on the targeted individuals, but also on their friends. The authors identified customers at risk as those who would have their accounts suspended if they did not top up their balance in one week. They sampled 961 such customers and treated 67% of them, selected at random, with a credit incentive that could be used to place calls. The authors found that their intervention increased usage by 35% on the targeted consumers and 10% on the neighbors of the targeted consumers. They also found that the friends of targeted consumers churn less, a spillover effect that they attribute to the nature of the product studied. Their setting is one with explicit network externalities, whereby consumers can place an unlimited number of in-network calls and use their balance to pay for out-of-network and international Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group <ref type="bibr">Marketing Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 5, pp. 793-811, © 2018</ref> calls. Therefore, in their setting, peer influence was likely to be triggered by this economic principle.</p><p>Our paper contributes to both these lines of research by testing whether peer effects can be exploited to improve the performance of proactive churn management. We propose that firms can actively use the social network to design profitable interventions as opposed to the previous literature that only used the social network to find peer effects a posteriori. In particular, we test whether targeting likely churners and their friends in the same proactive retention campaign with the same menu of nonreferral retention deals reduces churn. Unlike <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Nitzan and Libai (2011)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Ascarza et al. (2017a)</ref>, we study a context in which the way consumers use the service does not involve explicit network externalities, and thus, it is unclear whether peer effects would arise in such a setting and, if so, whether they would be economically significant. Finally, and in line with the suggestions in <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Reichheld and Sasser (1990)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Berger and Nasr (1998)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Jain and Singh (2002)</ref>, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Rust et al. (2004)</ref>, we use customer lifetime value to compare the performance of our strategy with that of traditional proactive churn management, thus measuring its effect on the firm's bottom line.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Context and Historical Data Sources</head><p>We study whether the peer effects in churn decisions discussed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Nitzan and Libai (2011)</ref> and in <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Ascarza et al. (2017a)</ref> in cell phone markets may also arise in the context of triple-play markets without explicit network externalities and, if so, whether firms can use them to improve churn management. Therefore, our setting is closer in nature to that studied in <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Burez and Van den Poel (2007)</ref>, but these authors did not analyze peer effects. The relevance of studying triple-play markets, as opposed to cell phone service and pay-TV service separately, stems from the fact that triple play is now becoming the dominant mode of consumption for telecommunications services. According to Digital TV Research, global triple-play subscriptions will reach 400 million by the end of 2017, up by nearly 300 million from the end of 2011. In addition, firms experience churn rates as high as 1% per month in these markets <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Green 2016)</ref>.</p><p>We collaborate with a large multinational telecommunications provider, hereinafter called TELCO. In the geography we analyze, TELCO serves more than one million households with TV, Internet, and telephony. In this setting, households become locked in when they contract service. We have anonymized data from TELCO between January 2013 and March 2015 and then for the month of January 2016. These data contain monthly snapshots of all TELCO products subscribed to by all TELCO households. We also know each household's monthly bill and the price charged by competitors for similar services in the same region. In April 2014, the average monthly bill at TELCO was $54.70/month. Therefore, choosing whether to stay with TELCO or churn is a decision that has significant financial implications for consumers in our setting.</p><p>We also have anonymized call detailed records for all landline calls served by TELCO between July 2012 and June 2013. This data set contains more than 600 million records. We use these data to define an undirected graph of communications across households. We build this graph by matching all anonymized phone numbers to their corresponding anonymized pay-TV accounts. We discard all CDRs in which one of the calling parties is a number with no counterpart in the anonymized pay-TV database. An edge between two households is included in this graph if all of the following conditions are met: (1) there are two or more calls between them, (2) at least one of the calls took place after 7 pm, (3) at least one of the calls occurred during the weekend, and (4) there are calls between them in at least two months. Our criteria to add edges to this graph ensure that households contacted each other over landlines, after normal working hours, on weekends, and more than once. Thus, edges in our graph proxy real proximity between households and possibly family ties. The resulting social graph contains 1.2 million nodes and 2.63 million edges. The average and the median degree are 4.3 and 3, respectively. The household in the 99th percentile is connected to 20 households.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Our Experiment</head><p>The best way to determine whether proactive churn management may help TELCO retain customers is to implement a randomized control trial in which a random set of likely churners are listed to be called by the firm and another random set of likely churners is held out for control purposes. This setup allows us to control for all unobserved effects that may lead likely churners to churn and that could otherwise be related to proactive churn management had the firm selectively chosen households to call. In addition, we are also interested in learning whether the social network can be used to increase the efficiency of proactive churn management by leveraging potential peer effects. However, many unobserved factors that lead households to churn from TELCO are likely to be correlated among households connected in the social graph because of homophily. In fact, it is well known that empirically measuring the effect of peer influence is a hard task because of the confounding effects introduced by unobserved covariates that simultaneously drive friendship and behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Manski 1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">, McPherson et al. 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">, Shalizi and Thomas 2011</ref>. We use a carefully designed randomized experiment to measure peer effects in our setting as described in the following. Our experiment is inspired by what has been done in the previous literature in other settings, such as Facebook (Aral and Walker 2011), news aggregators <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Muchnik et al. 2013)</ref>, and music recommendations <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Bapna and Umyarov 2015)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Initial Setup</head><p>The initial setup of our experiment took place in the end of April 2014 and consisted of developing a model to predict churn. Using the monthly panel of households served by TELCO, we developed a model that maps a vector of household characteristics to likelihood of churn. This model was constructed using state-of-the-art data-mining algorithms for classification tasks. Its details, training parameters, cross-validation, and performance metrics are all presented in Online Appendix B. This churn prediction model shows that tenure, an active lockin period, the amount billed, the age of the contract holder, and how much the household is off price are among the most important predictors of churn at TELCO. How much the household is off price is measured by the difference between the monthly bill and the lowest monthly bill offered by competitors for a similar bundle of services in the same region. Building this churn prediction model implements step one in the framework proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Blattberg et al. (2008)</ref> to measure the effect of proactive churn management. This churn prediction model allows us to focus our experiment on likely churners. As a consequence, our results generalize only to TELCO's likely churners, which is the subpopulation of interest for churn management purposes.</p><p>In addition, and also in April of 2014, we identified the ego network of each household in our social graph. In social network analysis, the ego network of a node in a social graph is the subgraph containing that node, called the ego; all nodes connected directly to it, called alters; and all the edges between them <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Wasserman 1994)</ref>. Panel (1) in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows an example of an ego network. Finally, and also in April 2014, we also determined the sample size required to identify an effect that would render proactive churn management profitable on egos. Finding an effect that does not generate profit would be uninteresting from an economic point of view. Online Appendix C provides the details of the calculations that we performed for this purpose, which allowed us to determine that our experiment should run for at least eight consecutive months.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Monthly Operations</head><p>Every month, starting from May 2014, TELCO provided us access to a data set with a collection of covariates that allowed us to determine whether a household initiates churn. Households can initiate churn through several channels: by phone, mail, email, or visiting a TELCO store. A household that signals its intention to churn using any of these channels is marked as so in our data set. Every month, we run our churn prediction model for households that did not initiate churn in the previous three months. TELCO refers to this period as "mourning." Its purpose is to ensure that households do not receive multiple contacts when parallel negotiations may already be underway. We note that our churn prediction model was retrained twice during our experiment, namely in May and October 2014, when TELCO refreshed our data sets on household-level covariates. Table <ref type="table">1</ref> shows a timeline of our experiment and which data were used when and for what purpose.</p><p>Each month during the experiment, we randomly placed the ego network of each top (as defined in Online Appendix C) likely churner in one of four conditions: Call No One-the ego and its alters are all listed not to be called by the firm; Call Ego-the ego is listed to be called by the firm and all its alters are listed not to be called by the firm; Call Alter-the ego is listed not to be called by the firm and all its alters are listed to be called by the firm; and Call Ego and Alter-both the ego and all its alters are listed to be called by the firm. We choose to list either no alter or all alters to be called by the firm to maximize our chance of finding an effect of peer influence. If there is no effect when all alters are listed to be called by the firm, then it is very unlikely that an effect arises when fewer alters are listed to be called.</p><p>Panel (2) in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows an example of a network in which each ego network is randomly placed in one of these four different conditions. This panel in this figure shows how considering ego networks introduces separation between egos in different treatment conditions, which reduces the likelihood of violating the stable unit treatment value assumption (SUTVA) <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Rosenbaum 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">, Wooldridge 2010</ref>). Violating SUTVA would hamper our ability to identify causal treatment effects resulting from interference across conditions. This is a common concern in network settings (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Manski 1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">, McPherson et al. 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">, Shalizi and Thomas 2011</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">, and Eckles et al. 2014</ref>. Randomizing treatment assignment to ego networks addresses this concern as suggested in <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Ugander et al. (2013)</ref>. Considering ego networks in our setting ensures that egos in different treatment conditions are at least two hops away from each other. Assuming only one-hop peer influence is a common practice in the literature in peer effects (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Aral and Walker 2011</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">, Bapna and Umyarov 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">, and Ugander et al. 2012</ref>. In our setting, only 2.8% of the egos are connected to egos in a different cluster by two hops. Moreover, less than 2% of the egos are connected by two hops to egos in clusters with different treatment conditions. Furthermore, we find no evidence of peer influence over two hops in our case (results available upon request).</p><p>Complex situations arise when ego networks overlap, such as in panel (3) of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>, in which two egos share one alter. To ensure consistency, in this case, we merge the two ego networks into a larger cluster, assign Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 5, pp. 793-811, © 2018</ref> the same condition to both egos in this cluster, and assign the same condition to all alters in the cluster. Therefore, alters in this cluster will either all be listed to be called by the firm or all be listed not to be called by the firm. In other words, once clusters are formed (and, without overlap, clusters are just ego networks), each cluster is randomly placed in one of the four treatment conditions referred to earlier. Finally, we note that our experiment took place over several months. Therefore, when we select an ego to be included in the experiment, it may be the case that it is connected to households that were already assigned to different treatment conditions in previous months. According to our experimental design, this would require us to merge clusters that were assigned to different treatment conditions, such as in panel (4) in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>. We circumvent this limitation of our experimental design by discarding from our analysis all households in the new cluster. This limitation led us to discard only 1% of the households in our sample.</p><p>After the experimental procedure described previously, the monthly random assignment of clusters to the four treatment conditions resulted in lists of households to be called by the firm and lists of households not to be called by the firm that we provided to TELCO's call center every month. We note that, in our setting, reactive retention is modeled by the condition Call No One, under which households still churn organically by calling the firm. Our other three treatment conditions embody an element of proactive churn management given that the firm is the party initiating contact. We followed households for a period of 120 days after treatment assignment and again in January 2016, that is, one year after our experiment ended. We note that from historical data, 95% of true positives listed by our predictive model request to disconnect their service (that is, enter the reactive retention) in the first 120 days after being identified by our model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Descriptive Statistics and Balance Across</head><p>Treatment Conditions Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref> plots the number of clusters in each treatment condition. There are many more clusters in the Call Ego condition because TELCO required us to focus its call center efforts on likely churners. In fact, TELCO increased the capacity of the call center allocated to our experiment one month after it started and added more slots to call likely churners. This did not raise problems to our experiment because, overall, we still assigned enough households to each treatment condition to identify the desired effects. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">2</ref> provides precise definitions for all covariates used throughout our paper. Tables 3-5 provide descriptive statistics for the most important covariates that, in our setting, shape consumer behavior-churn score, monthly bill, and lock-in period-for all egos, all alters, and all clusters in Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group our experiment, respectively. The average degree of egos and alters in our experiment is 1.84 and 6.36, respectively. Their average churn scores are 0.71 and 0.24, respectively. As expected, the churn score of egos is much higher in our setting. The average monthly bill and lock-in period for egos 30 days before treatment assignment were $56.20 and 31.1 days, respectively. These statistics are $54.70 and 132.2 for alters, respectively. Therefore, in our setting, alters are much less inclined to churn because they enjoy lower monthly bills and face longer lock-in periods. Online Appendix D provides additional evidence of balance in these covariates across treatment conditions on a monthly basis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.">Offers, Potential Outcomes, and</head><p>Compliance Levels Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3</ref> describes the decision stages and possible outcomes for households included in the experiment. At the start of each month, lists of households to be included in the experiment were sent to the call center. Some of these households, selected at random as described in Section 4.2, were marked to be called by the call center dialer. The remaining households were marked not to be called, which helped ensure compliance with the hold-out conditions. The latter households do not change their service conditions unless they call the firm to leave, in which case they enter reactive retention. Call center operators were not told which households were egos nor alters. They did not know the churn scores from our churn prediction model, and they were not told that some households in these lists were connected in the social graph. The operations of TELCO's call center are based on automatic dialers that randomize the order and time at which households are contacted and recontacted when previous calls fail. In short, in our setting, there is no selection bias in terms of how calls were attempted. Yet a number of unknown reasons may result in missed calls. It is still up to each household to pick up the phone from TELCO. This introduces a first layer of selection in our experiment. The top left and top right panels in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4</ref> show that egos listed to be called by the firm were reached 51% of the time and that alters listed to be called by the firm were reached 57% of the time.</p><p>When a call is established, the call center operator tries to assess whether the household reached is likely Table <ref type="table">1</ref>. Experimental Timeline Indicating the Calibration of Our Churn Prediction Model and the Data Used to Select Households for the Experiment to churn. A satisfaction survey is used to do so. All call center operators follow the same survey, that is, the same questions in the same order were asked during each and every call made. If the call center operator determines that the household is unlikely to churn the operator explains why the current contract and service fit the needs of that household and wraps up the call with no offer, and thus, there is no change in the household's contractual conditions. If, on the other hand, the call center operator determines that the household is likely to churn, then a deal is offered to try to retain the household. A menu with three different levels of offers was available to call center operators for this purpose: (i) offer A-reduced quality of service (such as fewer TV channels or lower Internet speed) for a lower price, (ii) offer B-a discount of $3 in the monthly bill corresponding to the free rental of the settop box, and (iii) offer C-a $7 discount in the monthly bill. This menu of offers was the same for each and every call made during our experiment. Yet call center operators were free to negotiate which offer to extend on a case-by-case basis but asked to try to retain the consumer at the least possible cost for the firm. In fact, call center operators were paid more if they were able to increase the household's contractual commitments and particularly high cash bonuses were paid when they were able to convince households to increase their monthly bill (which is extremely rare). The freedom given to call center operators to negotiate as best as possible with consumers introduces a second layer of selection in our experiment. The bottom left and bottom right panels in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4</ref> show that egos listed to be called by the firm were given a retention offer 34% of the time. Alters listed to be called by the firm received such offers 30% of the time. Obtaining an offer is conditional on getting a phone call from the call center. Therefore, roughly two thirds of the households that  were reached during our experiment were given a retention offer. Online Appendix A provides additional descriptive statistics about which offers were accepted and not by households in the experiment. When an offer is made, the household decides to accept or reject it on the spot. If the household accepts an offer from the call center operator, then its conditions are updated and the call ends. However, the consumer has 15 days to call back and ask to revert to the previous conditions. If this is the case, then the consumer enters reactive retention, and the firm will try to retain the consumer. If the household rejects the offer from the call center operator, no change is made to the household's conditions and the call ends. However, a consumer who rejects such an offer also has 15 days to call back to accept it. All offers extended by TELCO under this type of campaign are registered in TELCO's information system, and the company typically honors offers that it had previously extended to consumers. If this happens, the conditions of that household change. Finally, we note that whenever households are on the phone with a call center agent, they may ask for the service to be disconnected. In that case, consumers are routed toward the reactive retention team and the firm initiates all churn-related procedures.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Results</head><p>In this section, we measure the effect of proactive churn management in our setting by comparing the behavior of egos in the Call No One condition and in the Call Ego condition. We also measure the effect of socially based proactive churn management by comparing the behavior of egos in the Call Ego condition and in the Call Ego and Alter condition. All these results measure the  impact of our randomized assignment of households to treatment conditions before any selection occurs. This yields the effect of the intention-to-treat households proactively across the population of likely churners at TELCO, which provides causal evidence of the effect of listing them to call. Online Appendix F provides estimates for the effect of treatment across the subpopulation of egos that pick up the call from the firm. We also note that the probability of treatment assignment changed from month to month during our experiment. For example, the number of slots that were allocated to our experiment changed every month and in particular in June 2014. This means that the results that we present are precision-weighted averages of monthly effects.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Effect of Churn Management on Entering Retention and Churn</head><p>We start by pooling all observations together to find whether there is some indication that our treatments yielded some effect. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">5</ref> illustrates the results obtained for egos and alters in the top and bottom panels, respectively. The vertical axes on the left panels measure entry into reactive retention 120 days after treatment assignment. The vertical axes on the right panels measure churn in January 2016. The top panels show preliminary evidence that listing only alters to call does not change the likelihood at which egos enter reactive retention or churn. However, listing egos to call reduces their likelihood of doing so, and listing both egos and alters to call seems to yield even a larger effect. The bottom panels show that none of our treatments affected the likelihood at which alters enter reactive retention or churn. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">6</ref> illustrates what happens to monthly bills and to lock-in periods during our experiments. The top panels are for egos, and the bottom panels are for alters. The vertical axes on the left panels measure changes in monthly bills. The vertical axes on the right panels measure changes in lock-in periods. The left top panel shows that listing only alters to call does not change the monthly bills of egos. Listing egos to call reduces their monthly bills. Listing their alters to call reduces the monthly bills of egos by a similar amount on average. The left bottom panel shows that listing egos to call does not change the monthly bill of alters. Listing alters to call reduces their monthly bills. The panels on the right show similar results for lock-in periods.</p><p>We estimate the magnitude of the causal effects of our treatments using the following model:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Y j ζ 0 + churn_score j α 1 + treatment j α 2 + θ t + j (1)</formula><p>where j is a household in our experiment, Y j represents either entering reactive retention 120 days after treatment assignment or churn in January 2016, treatment j is a vector of indicators for our treatment conditions, and α 2 is a vector of parameters indicating the corresponding levels of our dependent variable. Differences among these parameters readily measure the effect of proactive churn management and of socially based proactive churn management on our dependent variable. We use a linear probability model (LPM) to estimate this equation. LPM is appropriate to identify the average causal effect of treatment assignment in randomized experiments with binary outcomes when the covariates of interest are sparse and discrete as in our case <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Angrist 1991</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">, Angrist et al. 1996</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">, Angrist 2001</ref>. For completeness, we present results using probit in Online Appendix E, which are both qualitatively and quantitatively similar to the ones discussed in the following.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">6</ref> shows the effect of treatment assignment on egos during our experiment. Columns (1) and (3) show that listing alters to call does not change the likelihood at which egos enter reactive retention or churn. However, listing egos to call reduces the former by 1.7 percentage points, from a baseline of 20.7%, and reduces the latter by 1.9 percentage points, from a baseline of 17.2%. Columns (2) and ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>) show that listing alters to call in addition to listing egos to call reduces the likelihood at which egos enter reactive retention by an additional 1.4 percentage points and the likelihood of churn by an additional 1.3 percentage points. Online Appendix G shows that these effects are not affected by tie strength or by the degree Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group centrality of the ego. Instead, in our setting, these effects are moderated by the proportion of alters who pick up the phone from the call center as shown in Online Appendix F. Finally, Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">7</ref> shows results for the case of alters. All treatment conditions yield a similar likelihood of entering reactive retention and a similar churn rate.</p><p>Our results show that calling only likely churners does not yield a spillover effect to alters, and that calling only alters does not have a spillover effect to egos. This is different from <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Ascarza et al. (2017a)</ref>, in which the authors found evidence of spillover effects. However, they studied a product with explicit network externalities, which, as the authors argue, drives the results that they observed. Our case is different. We analyze a market without explicit network externalities and, in our setting, spillover effects arise only when both parties-the likely churner and the churner's friends-are listed to be called by the firm. This shows that one must be very careful when generalizing spillover effects and that the effects identified in <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Ascarza et al. (2017a)</ref> may not generalize even within the telecommunications industry. More important, our findings show that, in our setting, a signal flows from alters to egos that lowers the likelihood at which the latter enter reactive retention and churn (in January 2016). This follows from the fact that with random assignment egos in the Call Ego and in the Call Ego and Alter conditions are, on average, similar on everything except for the fact that their alters were also listed to be called by the firm under the latter condition. We cannot identify the channel used to transmit this signal, nor can we be sure of what the signal is because we do not observe the messages exchanged between Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group egos and alters. Yet such a signal is certainly present in our setting and is responsible for the effects observed with socially based proactive churn management.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Mechanisms at Play in Socially Based Proactive</head><p>Churn Management Proactive churn management triggers a number of mechanisms that have been already discussed in the prior literature and that may arise in our setting. For example, egos go through a satisfaction survey when they pick up the call from the firm, which may reduce their likelihood of churn. As pointed out by <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Burez and Van den Poel (2007)</ref>, satisfaction surveys may lead to positive evaluations that help retain consumers. However, this does not seem to be the case in our setting as explained in detail in Online Appendix H. The egos who accept offers from the firm reduce their monthly bills (from $59.80/month on average 30 days before being included in the experiment to $56.20/month on average 30 days after being included in the experiment), which may, just per se, also lower their likelihood of churn. In addition, the offers that egos receive from the firm allow them to align their monthly bills with those of their alters (the average monthly bill of alters is $55.30/month 30 days before being included in the experiment), which is likely to increase their perception of fairness, thus potentially leading them also to churn less. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Bolton (1998)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Bolton and Lemon (1999)</ref> provide evidence that the perception of fairness reduces defection in environments in which consumers can easily and meaningfully compare the prices that they are charged with those charged to their friends.</p><p>The mechanisms referred to here can be at play in traditional proactive churn management and, thus, may explain the difference in the churn rates that we observe between egos in the Call No One and in the Call Ego conditions. The advantage of our study is that none of them are likely to play a role in explaining the lower churn rate of egos under socially based proactive churn management. To see this, consider  Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group egos in the Call Ego and in the Call Ego and Alter conditions. Column (1) shows that egos in these two conditions pick up the phone from the firm at the same rate during our experiment. All egos who pick up the phone from the firm in these conditions go through the same satisfaction survey, that is, the survey included the same questions in the same order for each and every call made by any call center agent during our experiment. Column (2) in this table shows that egos in these two conditions not only pick up the phone from the firm at the same rate, but that they also get offers from the firm at the same rate during the experiment. Columns (3)-(5) in this same table show that they even get the same offers equally often. Therefore, on average, egos in these two conditions have the same opportunities to lower their monthly bills if they accept the offers from the firm (note that even the monthly bill 30 days after treatment assignment for egos that accept offers and remain with the firm is similar, on average, for egos in these two treatment conditions: $56.20/month under the Call Ego condition and $56.50/month under the Call Ego and Alter condition). Furthermore, recall that, also on average, egos in these two conditions have the same monthly bills to begin with (as shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">3</ref>) and so do alters (as shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">4</ref>). Hence, reductions in the monthly bills of egos are very unlikely to explain the difference in their churn rates across these two conditions. Some alters under the Call Ego and Alter condition obtain and accept offers from the firm (which is unlikely under the Call Ego condition when alters are not listed to be called by the firm). Therefore, with respect to financial comparisons, if anything, the gaps in monthly bills between egos and alters reduce slightly less under socially based proactive churn management, which would likely lead to a higher churn rate across egos under the Call Ego and Alter condition, which is not what we observe in our setting.</p><p>This discussion provides evidence that other mechanisms must be at play in the case of socially based proactive churn management. The local average treatment effects reported in Online Appendix F show that the effect of socially based proactive churn management is associated with the alters who pick up the phone from the firm. However, in our setup, we are unable to split this effect into the one associated with Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group <ref type="bibr">Marketing Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 5, pp. 793-811, © 2018</ref> the alters who get offers from the firm and the one associated with the alters who do not. Please refer to Online Appendix I for more details on why this is the case. It is possible that, in our setting, (part of) the effect of listing alters to call on the churn rate of egos is associated with the alters who only get a satisfaction survey, which, according to the preceding arguments, may improve their opinion about the firm, resulting in a more positive signal that they transmit to egos. This can trigger mechanisms associated with both conformity and financial comparisons. <ref type="bibr">Cialdini and Goldstein (2004, p. 606</ref>) define conformity as "the act of changing one's behavior to match the responses of others." If, in our setting, egos have a propensity to conform with their alters, the improved opinion that alters may have about the firm after going through the satisfaction survey may lead egos to stay more often with the firm under the Call Ego and Alter condition compared with what happens under the Call Ego condition (given that alters do not go through this survey under the latter condition). However, it may also be the fact that these alters did not get offers from the firm that provides an additional signal to egos under the Call Ego and Alter condition. Namely, egos have the same opportunities to align their monthly bills with those of their alters under the Call Ego condition and under the Call Ego and Alter condition. However, under the latter condition, the alters who picked up the phone from the firm and did not get an offer may have conveyed to egos that their monthly bills (that is, the monthly bills that egos can obtain if they accept the offers from the firm) seem hard to improve upon (because they were just recently on the phone with the firm and were unable to get a better deal). This type of mechanism, which we may call "on price" with low monthly bills for short, may also explain, in part, the observed lower churn rate across egos in our setting when alters are also listed to be called by the firm.</p><p>Finally, it is also possible that (part of) the effect of listing alters to call on the churn rate of egos is associated with the alters who get offers from the firm after they go through the satisfaction survey. Getting such an offer might again improve their opinion about the firm, resulting in a more positive signal that they transmit to egos. Furthermore, the alters that accept these offers-and, thus, renew their contracts with the Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group firm-have just made (recent conscious) decisions to stay, which egos may copy, leading them to churn less under the Call Ego and Alter condition. In sum, both conformity and being on price with low monthly bills may lead egos to churn less with socially based proactive churn management. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Blattberg et al. (2008)</ref> discuss reasons why proactive churn management may be effective at keeping consumers but may, at the same time, fail to improve firm profits. In short, the firm tries to rescue likely churners, offering them good deals. However, and along this process, the firm may also end up delighting unlikely churners, who obtain lower monthly bills although they would have not churned even if they were not given such good deals. The former improves firm profit, and the latter does not. This trade-off is even trickier in the case of socially based proactive churn management because, in this case, the firm also calls alters, who are unlikely to churn, and thus, the likelihood of extending additional unnecessary deals may lower the profit of the firm even further. The appropriate way to determine the true effect of proactive churn management on firm profit is to measure its impact on customer lifetime value (CLV), which is what we do in our case. CLV is a function of the monthly bill, the survival with the firm, and the discount rate. In our analysis, we set the monthly bill of each household in our experiment to its observed level 120 days after treatment assignment. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> We estimate survival as a function of treatment assignment using probabilistic continuous time models, which allow for churn rates to change over time <ref type="bibr">Hardie 2007, Schweidel et al. 2008)</ref>. Online Appendix J provides the details of these computations and the results obtained. As expected, we find that the survival of egos increases when they are listed to be called by the firm and much more so when their alters are also listed to the called by the firm. The survival of alters does not change, on average, with treatment assignment. Finally, we set the discount rate to TELCO's weighted average cost of capital of 0.7%/month as reported to us by company managers. We use these data to compute CLV over a 10year horizon (the average TELCO household stays 62 months with the firm).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.">The Effect of Churn Management on Firm Profit</head><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">9</ref> shows the results obtained from regressing CLV on treatment assignment, which, in our randomized setting, allows for immediately identifying the effect of socially based proactive churn management on the profit of the firm. Columns (1) and (2) show results for egos and columns (3) and ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>) show results for alters. Column (1) shows that listing only alters to call does not change the CLV of egos in our setting. This column also shows that when only egos are listed to be called by the firm their CLV increases, on average, by 2.1% (51.1/(2861 − 663 × 0.7), where 0.7 is the average churn score across  <ref type="bibr">, , vol. 37, no. 5, pp. 793-811, © 2018</ref> egos in our sample). This column also shows that, when alters are listed to be called by the firm in addition to egos, the CLV of egos increases, on average, by 6.4% (154.3/(2861 − 663 × 0.7)). <ref type="bibr">Column (2)</ref> shows that the difference between these statistics is statistically significant: 4.3% (given by 103.2/(2911 − 663 × 0.7)). This difference is the spillover effect associated with socially based proactive churn management, here measured in dollar terms for the firm. Columns (3) and ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>) show that listing alters to be called by the firm, irrespective of whether egos are listed too, does not change their CLV, which is consistent with the fact that alters are unlikely to churn in our setting. Finally, and for robustness sake, columns ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>) show the effects of our treatments over the clusters used in our experiment. The dependent variable in these regressions is the average CLV across egos and alters in each cluster (which adjusts for the fact that different clusters may have different sizes). The results in these columns confirm that, in our setting, listing likely churners to call is profitable for the firm and more so when their alters are also listed to be called.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusions</head><p>This paper studies whether firms can actively use social network data to design an intervention that retains more consumers and increases profits compared with traditional proactive churn management. We do so in the context of triple play services, which is now becoming the standard mode of consumption in the telecommunications industry. In these markets, consumers become locked in for several months before they can churn without paying financial penalties, and there are no explicit network externalities in the way that they use services. Therefore, and at the outset, it was unclear whether peer effects would play a role in this type of market and, if so, whether they would be economically significant to lead firms to consider them when retaining consumers. The main contribution of our work is to suggest a new type of intervention to help firms retain likely churners. In particular, we suggest that firms should also contact their friends. This strategy, which we call socially based proactive churn management, is different from all previous approaches studied in the literature to perform proactive churn management, which involve contacting only likely churners. Yet socially based proactive churn management may work well if peer effects are  sufficiently strong to create enough goodwill around likely churners to help retain them. However, strong peer effects may not be sufficient for a firm to take advantage of this strategy because, in the process of creating such goodwill, the company might extend good deals to an unreasonable number of friends of likely churners (who could be unlikely to churn). This may hurt the firm's profit. If, however, a strong effect of peer influence can be achieved without losing too much revenue on the friends of the likely churners, then it is possible that reaching out to the latter becomes profitable for the firm.</p><p>We collaborated with a major telecommunications provider to design, implement, and analyze outcomes of a randomized control trial at the household level, allowing us to study the effects associated with socially based proactive churn management. We started by using data from call detailed records to draw a social graph across households and data from pay-TV subscriptions to develop a model to predict likely churners. Subsequently, and on a monthly basis during eight consecutive months, we selected a random set of likely churners and their friends and we allocated them randomly across four different experimental conditions. In the Call No One condition, all households were listed not to be called by the firm. In the Call Ego condition, likely churners were listed to be called by the firm and their friends were listed not to be called by the firm. In the Call Alter condition, the friends of likely churners were listed to be called by the firm and likely churners were listed not to be called by the firm. Finally, all households in the Call Ego and Alter condition were listed to be called by the firm. All calls were routed through the firm's call center, and the call center agent associated to each call was also randomized. Randomly assigning households to these conditions allows us to immediately identify both the effect of proactive churn management-by comparing churn rates across the Call Ego and the Call No One conditions-and the effect of socially based proactive churn management by comparing churn rates across the Call Ego and Alter and the Call Ego conditions. On average, we find that likely churners listed to be called by the firm whose friends were listed not to be called reduce their likelihood of churn by 1.9 percentage points ( p &lt; 0.01) from a baseline of 17.2%. The likelihood of likely churners listed to be called by the firm whose friends were also listed to be called reduce the likelihood of churn by an additional 1.3 percentage points ( p &lt; 0.05). Notes. Columns ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>)-( <ref type="formula">4</ref>): Cluster robust and heteroskedastic consistent standard errors in parentheses. Columns ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>)-( <ref type="formula">4</ref>): Observations clustered by social network treatment cluster. Columns ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>): Heteroskedastic consistent standard errors in parentheses. Household survival projected using log-logistic model. CF, monthly bill 120 days after listing in the experiment; CLV, customer lifetime value; WACC, weighted average cost of capital. *p &lt; 0.1; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.</p><p>Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group</p><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 5, pp. 793-811, © 2018</ref> Our findings show that, in our setting, a signal flows from alters to egos that lowers the likelihood at which the latter enter reactive retention and churn. This signal may trigger several mechanisms that may lead egos to churn less with socially based proactive churn management. The satisfaction survey that alters go through when they pick up the phone from the call center may, just per se, improve their opinion about the firm, which may lead them to transmit a more positive signal to egos-likewise for alters who obtain and accept offers from the firm. If, in our setting, egos have a propensity to conform with their alters, that is, if they exhibit a tendency to align their opinion with those of their alters and copy their behavior, then these improved signals may lower the churn rate of egos when alters are also listed to be called by the firm compared with when they are not. However, a lower churn rate across these egos may also arise because of the signal transmitted by the alters who pick up the phone from the firm and do not obtain offers. These alters may convey to their egos that if they accept the offers that they get from the firm then they obtain monthly bills that seem hard to improve upon. This idea of on price with low monthly bills may also decrease the likelihood of churn across egos whose alters have been listed to be called by the firm.</p><p>In addition, we use the framework proposed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Blattberg et al. (2008)</ref> to measure the effect of our interventions on firm profit using customer lifetime value. The additional CLV associated with traditional proactive churn management is $51.10 per likely churner, which represents an increase of 2.1% compared with reactive retention. These statistics are $154.30 and 6.4%, respectively, for the case of socially based proactive churn management. Furthermore, we find no changes in the CLV of the friends of likely churners relative to reactive retention both with traditional and socially based proactive churn management. Therefore, we show that, in our context, socially based proactive churn management reduces churn among likely churners and increases firm profits. Although a single empirical case is not enough to generalize results, we believe that our findings may extend to other contexts similar to ours, namely to subscription-based settings without explicit network externalities, in which mechanisms akin to financial comparisons and conformity play a role. Our paper suggests a new direction to enrich the firms' current portfolios of churn management strategies. Therefore, our results have significant implications for churn managers at firms that know, or that can proxy, the social network across their consumers and shows one way in which they can apportion value to these data.</p><p>Finally, we note that our work does not come without limitations. First, we do not observe the messages exchanged by egos and their friends. We have evidence that, in our setting, a signal flows from the latter to the former that reduces the churn rates of likely churners, but we are unsure about what this signal is, when is it transmitted, or what communication medium is used to transmit it. Second, part of the success of the churn management interventions that we test with our experiment is associated with the performance of the call center agents. This is not a special feature of our setting but rather an attribute common to all churn management exercises; in other words, one cannot expect to obtain good results from proactive churn management with unskilled call center agents. Third, our experiment did not attempt to identify which offers provided by the firm maximized the additional effect associated with socially based proactive churn management. A field experiment that randomizes the offers extended by the firm at the household level would be an appropriate next step to further the analysis that we performed in this paper. Fourth, we acknowledge that there are many ways in which one can identify customers at risk; in particular, the most likely churners might not be the most valuable customers to the firm or the ones that are easier to retain. Therefore, the value generated by socially based proactive churn management may even be higher that what we report in our paper if one combines targeting groups of consumers with more appropriate models to identify profitable targets.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. (Color online) Cluster Setup, Randomized Assignment, and Conflict Resolution</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. Number of Clusters per Treatment Condition over Time During the Experiment</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3. Decision Stages and Possible Outcomes for Households Contacted by the Firm During Our Experiment</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4. Compliance with Treatment Assignment During the Experiment</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5. Likelihood of Entering Reactive Retention During the Mourning Period (Left) and Likelihood of Churn by January 2016 (Right) per Treatment Condition</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6. Change in the Monthly Bill (Left) and Lock-in (Right) of Egos (Top) and Alters (Bottom) over a Period of 60 Days from 30 Days Before Listing Them to Call to 30 Days After Listing Them to Call</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Definition of Variables Used in the Paper</figDesc><table><row><cell>Name</cell><cell>Type</cell><cell>Description</cell></row><row><cell>Call No One</cell><cell>Dummy variable</cell><cell>1 for households in clusters assigned to the Call No</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>One condition</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>Dummy variable</cell><cell>1 for households in clusters assigned to the Call Alter</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>condition</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>Dummy variable</cell><cell>1 for households in clusters assigned to the Call Ego</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>condition</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>Dummy variable</cell><cell>1 for households in clusters assigned to the Call Ego</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>and Alter condition</cell></row><row><cell>Churn Score</cell><cell>Continuous variable</cell><cell>Churn score calculated by the predictive churn model</cell></row><row><cell>Reactive retention After 120 Days</cell><cell>Dummy variable</cell><cell>1 for households that request to churn within 120</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>days after treatment assignment</cell></row><row><cell>Churn by Jan. 2016</cell><cell>Dummy variable</cell><cell>1 for households that churned by January 2016</cell></row><row><cell>Lock-in Period</cell><cell>Continuous variable</cell><cell>Number of days to current contact expiry</cell></row><row><cell>Monthly Bill</cell><cell>Continuous variable</cell><cell>Monthly bill associated with all telecommunication</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>services ( 0 for households who churn)</cell></row><row><cell>Gets Call</cell><cell>Dummy variable</cell><cell>1 for households that got a call from the call center</cell></row><row><cell>Fraction of Friends Get Call</cell><cell>Continuous variable</cell><cell>Proportion of household's friends that got a call from</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>the call center</cell></row><row><cell>Gets Offer</cell><cell>Dummy variable</cell><cell>1 for households that got a retention offer from the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>call center</cell></row><row><cell>Fraction of Friends Get Offer</cell><cell>Continuous variable</cell><cell>Proportion of household's friends that got an offer from</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>the call center</cell></row><row><cell>Offer A</cell><cell>Dummy variable</cell><cell>1 for households that got a retention offer A from the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>call center</cell></row><row><cell>Offer B</cell><cell>Dummy variable</cell><cell>1 for households that got a retention offer B from the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>call center</cell></row><row><cell>Offer C</cell><cell>Dummy variable</cell><cell>1 for households that got a retention offer C from the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>call center</cell></row></table><note>Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Descriptive Statistics for Egos in the Experiment per Treatment Condition</figDesc><table><row><cell>Treatment</cell><cell>Variable</cell><cell>Observations (egos)</cell><cell>Average</cell><cell>Standard deviation</cell></row><row><cell>Call No One</cell><cell>N. alters</cell><cell>3,996</cell><cell>1.890</cell><cell>1.067</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>N. alters</cell><cell>3,895</cell><cell>1.890</cell><cell>1.080</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>N. alters</cell><cell>33,312</cell><cell>1.830</cell><cell>1.045</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>N. alters</cell><cell>3,820</cell><cell>1.849</cell><cell>1.018</cell></row><row><cell>Call No One</cell><cell>Churn score</cell><cell>3,996</cell><cell>0.689</cell><cell>0.274</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>Churn score</cell><cell>3,895</cell><cell>0.689</cell><cell>0.271</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>Churn score</cell><cell>33,312</cell><cell>0.715</cell><cell>0.276</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>Churn score</cell><cell>3,820</cell><cell>0.691</cell><cell>0.273</cell></row><row><cell>Call No One</cell><cell>Monthly bill</cell><cell>3,996</cell><cell>55.722</cell><cell>13.951</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>Monthly bill</cell><cell>3,895</cell><cell>55.824</cell><cell>13.846</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>Monthly bill</cell><cell>33,312</cell><cell>56.300</cell><cell>13.593</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>Monthly bill</cell><cell>3,820</cell><cell>55.637</cell><cell>14.001</cell></row><row><cell>Call No One</cell><cell>Lock-in period</cell><cell>3,996</cell><cell>30.801</cell><cell>77.817</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>Lock-in period</cell><cell>3,895</cell><cell>33.937</cell><cell>87.800</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>Lock-in period</cell><cell>33,312</cell><cell>30.814</cell><cell>79.083</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>Lock-in period</cell><cell>3,820</cell><cell>30.863</cell><cell>80.765</cell></row></table><note>Note. Monthly bill and lock-in period computed 30 days before treatment assignment.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Descriptive Statistics for Alters in the Experiment per Treatment Condition</figDesc><table><row><cell>Treatment</cell><cell>Variable</cell><cell>Observations (alters)</cell><cell>Average</cell><cell>Standard deviation</cell></row><row><cell>Call No One</cell><cell>N. alters</cell><cell>6,545</cell><cell>7.677</cell><cell>32.444</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>N. alters</cell><cell>6,235</cell><cell>6.150</cell><cell>9.633</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>N. alters</cell><cell>55,925</cell><cell>6.272</cell><cell>9.093</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>N. alters</cell><cell>6,043</cell><cell>5.923</cell><cell>5.561</cell></row><row><cell>Call No One</cell><cell>Churn score</cell><cell>6,545</cell><cell>0.230</cell><cell>0.268</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>Churn score</cell><cell>6,235</cell><cell>0.222</cell><cell>0.262</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>Churn score</cell><cell>55,925</cell><cell>0.240</cell><cell>0.275</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>Churn score</cell><cell>6,043</cell><cell>0.224</cell><cell>0.261</cell></row><row><cell>Call No One</cell><cell>Monthly bill</cell><cell>6,545</cell><cell>54.420</cell><cell>23.603</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>Monthly bill</cell><cell>6,235</cell><cell>54.846</cell><cell>23.513</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>Monthly Bill</cell><cell>55,925</cell><cell>54.761</cell><cell>24.040</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>Monthly bill</cell><cell>6,043</cell><cell>54.704</cell><cell>23.624</cell></row><row><cell>Call No One</cell><cell>Lock-in period</cell><cell>6,545</cell><cell>128.649</cell><cell>232.783</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>Lock-in period</cell><cell>6,235</cell><cell>131.182</cell><cell>234.552</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>Lock-in period</cell><cell>55,925</cell><cell>132.666</cell><cell>235.551</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>Lock-in period</cell><cell>6,043</cell><cell>132.708</cell><cell>234.636</cell></row></table><note>Note. Monthly bill and lock-in period computed 30 days before treatment assignment.Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Descriptive Statistics for Clusters in the Experiment per Treatment Condition</figDesc><table><row><cell>Treatment</cell><cell>Variable</cell><cell>Observations (n clusters)</cell><cell>Average</cell><cell>Standard deviation</cell></row><row><cell>Call No One</cell><cell>N. egos</cell><cell>3,831</cell><cell>1.043</cell><cell>0.250</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>N. egos</cell><cell>3,774</cell><cell>1.032</cell><cell>0.192</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>N. egos</cell><cell>32,270</cell><cell>1.032</cell><cell>0.197</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>N. egos</cell><cell>3,707</cell><cell>1.030</cell><cell>0.180</cell></row><row><cell>Call No One</cell><cell>N. alters</cell><cell>3,831</cell><cell>1.972</cell><cell>1.284</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>N. alters</cell><cell>3,774</cell><cell>1.950</cell><cell>1.237</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>N. alters</cell><cell>32,270</cell><cell>1.889</cell><cell>1.178</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>N. alters</cell><cell>3,707</cell><cell>1.905</cell><cell>1.128</cell></row><row><cell>Call No One</cell><cell>Cluster size</cell><cell>3,831</cell><cell>3.015</cell><cell>1.433</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>Cluster size</cell><cell>3,774</cell><cell>2.983</cell><cell>1.337</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>Cluster size</cell><cell>32,270</cell><cell>2.921</cell><cell>1.277</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>Cluster size</cell><cell>3,707</cell><cell>2.936</cell><cell>1.210</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 8</head><label>8</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note>, which compares</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Effect of Intention to Treat on Egos Controlling for Period Dummies and Churn ScoreGodinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group</figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Dependent variable</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">RR after 120 days</cell><cell cols="2">Churn by Jan. 2016</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>LPM</cell><cell></cell><cell>LPM</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(1)</cell><cell>(2)</cell><cell>(3)</cell><cell>(4)</cell></row><row><cell>Call No One</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.017  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.019  *  *  *</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(0.007)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(0.006)</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>0.020  *  *  *</cell><cell>−0.007</cell><cell>0.013  *  *</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.009)</cell><cell>(0.007)</cell><cell>(0.008)</cell><cell>(0.006)</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>−0.017  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell>−0.019  *  *  *</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.007)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(0.006)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>−0.032  *  *  *</cell><cell>−0.014  *  *</cell><cell>−0.032  *  *  *</cell><cell>−0.013  *  *</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.009)</cell><cell>(0.007)</cell><cell>(0.008)</cell><cell>(0.006)</cell></row><row><cell>Churn score</cell><cell>0.127  *  *  *</cell><cell>0.127  *  *  *</cell><cell>0.050</cell><cell>0.050</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.035)</cell><cell>(0.035)</cell><cell>(0.032)</cell><cell>(0.032)</cell></row><row><cell>Constant</cell><cell>0.103  *  *  *</cell><cell>0.085  *  *  *</cell><cell>0.172  *  *  *</cell><cell>0.153  *  *  *</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.022)</cell><cell>(0.022)</cell><cell>(0.021)</cell><cell>(0.020)</cell></row><row><cell>Period dummies</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell></row><row><cell>Observations</cell><cell>45,023</cell><cell>45,023</cell><cell>45,023</cell><cell>45,023</cell></row><row><cell>R 2</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>0.003</cell><cell>0.003</cell></row><row><cell>Adjusted R 2</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>0.003</cell><cell>0.003</cell></row><row><cell>Residual standard error</cell><cell>0.391</cell><cell>0.391</cell><cell>0.355</cell><cell>0.355</cell></row><row><cell>F-statistic</cell><cell>8.123  *  *  *</cell><cell>8.123  *  *  *</cell><cell>12.570  *  *  *</cell><cell>12.570  *  *  *</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Notes. Cluster robust and heteroskedastic consistent standard errors in parentheses. Observations</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">clustered by social network treatment cluster. LPM, linear probability model; RR, reactive retention.</cell></row><row><cell>*p &lt; 0.1; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Effect of the Intention to Treat on Alters Controlling for Period Dummies and Churn Score Notes. Cluster robust and heteroskedastic consistent standard errors in parentheses. Observations clustered by social network treatment cluster. LPM, linear probability model; RR, reactive retention.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Dependent variable</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>RR after</cell><cell>Churn by</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>120 days (1)</cell><cell>Jan. 2016 (2)</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>−0.006</cell><cell>−0.004</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.005)</cell><cell>(0.005)</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>0.005</cell><cell>0.001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.004)</cell><cell>(0.004)</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>−0.001</cell><cell>−0.003</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.006)</cell><cell>(0.005)</cell></row><row><cell>Churn score</cell><cell>0.113  *  *  *</cell><cell>0.093  *  *  *</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.005)</cell><cell>(0.005)</cell></row><row><cell>Flg. no churn score</cell><cell>0.038  *  *  *</cell><cell>0.048  *  *  *</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.003)</cell><cell>(0.003)</cell></row><row><cell>Constant</cell><cell>0.101  *  *  *</cell><cell>0.085  *  *  *</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.005)</cell><cell>(0.005)</cell></row><row><cell>Period dummies</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell></row><row><cell>Observations</cell><cell>74,748</cell><cell>74,748</cell></row><row><cell>R 2</cell><cell>0.007</cell><cell>0.008</cell></row><row><cell>Adjusted R 2</cell><cell>0.007</cell><cell>0.008</cell></row><row><cell>Residual standard error</cell><cell>0.314</cell><cell>0.272</cell></row><row><cell>F-statistic</cell><cell>44.269  *  *  *</cell><cell>53.035  *  *  *</cell></row></table><note>*p &lt; 0.1; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Comparing Egos in the Call Ego and Call Ego and Alter Conditions in Terms of Picking up the Phone and Obtaining Offers from TELCO Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Get call (1)</cell><cell>Get offer (2)</cell><cell>Offer A (3)</cell><cell>Offer B (4)</cell><cell>Offer C (5)</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>0.004</cell><cell>−0.002</cell><cell>−0.001</cell><cell>0.002</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.008)</cell><cell>(0.008)</cell><cell>(0.002)</cell><cell>(0.005)</cell><cell>(0.007)</cell></row><row><cell>Churn score</cell><cell>−0.119  *  *</cell><cell>−0.132  *  *  *</cell><cell>−0.009</cell><cell>−0.109  *  *  *</cell><cell>−0.020</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.047)</cell><cell>(0.044)</cell><cell>(0.011)</cell><cell>(0.030)</cell><cell>(0.039)</cell></row><row><cell>Constant</cell><cell>0.565  *  *  *</cell><cell>0.411  *  *  *</cell><cell>0.040  *  *  *</cell><cell>0.170  *  *  *</cell><cell>0.207  *  *  *</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.030)</cell><cell>(0.028)</cell><cell>(0.008)</cell><cell>(0.019)</cell><cell>(0.025)</cell></row><row><cell>Period dummies</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell></row><row><cell>Observations</cell><cell>37,132</cell><cell>37,132</cell><cell>37,132</cell><cell>37,132</cell><cell>37,132</cell></row><row><cell>R 2</cell><cell>0.083</cell><cell>0.060</cell><cell>0.007</cell><cell>0.062</cell><cell>0.047</cell></row><row><cell>Adjusted R 2</cell><cell>0.083</cell><cell>0.060</cell><cell>0.006</cell><cell>0.062</cell><cell>0.047</cell></row><row><cell>Residual standard error</cell><cell>0.479</cell><cell>0.460</cell><cell>0.097</cell><cell>0.275</cell><cell>0.426</cell></row><row><cell>F-statistic</cell><cell>372.823  *  *  *</cell><cell>264.260  *  *  *</cell><cell>27.357  *  *  *</cell><cell>271.390  *  *  *</cell><cell>204.269  *  *</cell></row></table><note>* Notes. Cluster robust and heteroskedastic consistent standard errors in parentheses. Observations clustered by social network treatment cluster. *p &lt; 0.1; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 9 .</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Effect of Treatment Assignment on the Expected Lifetime Value of Egos, Alters, and Clusters in Our Experiment</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Dependent variable</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">CLV(CF, WACC = 0.7%, T = 120)</cell><cell cols="3">CLV(CF Cluster, WACC = 0.7%, T = 120)/Size</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Egos (1)</cell><cell>Egos (2)</cell><cell>Alters (3)</cell><cell>Alters (4)</cell><cell>Cluster (5)</cell><cell>Cluster (6)</cell></row><row><cell>Call No One</cell><cell></cell><cell>−51.089  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell>−27.926</cell><cell></cell><cell>−35.646  *</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(23.115)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(23.848)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(18.957)</cell></row><row><cell>Call Alter</cell><cell>46.915</cell><cell>−4.174</cell><cell>36.463</cell><cell>8.536</cell><cell>39.456</cell><cell>3.810</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(31.224)</cell><cell>(23.729)</cell><cell>(32.328)</cell><cell>(24.670)</cell><cell>(25.479)</cell><cell>(19.212)</cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego</cell><cell>51.089  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell>27.926</cell><cell></cell><cell>35.646  *</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(23.115)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(23.848)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(18.957)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Call Ego and Alter</cell><cell>154.289  *  *  *</cell><cell>103.200  *  *  *</cell><cell>11.668</cell><cell>−16.258</cell><cell>85.095  *  *  *</cell><cell>49.449  *  *</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(31.390)</cell><cell>(23.913)</cell><cell>(32.745)</cell><cell>(25.195)</cell><cell>(25.812)</cell><cell>(19.632)</cell></row><row><cell>Churn score</cell><cell>−663.122  *  *  *</cell><cell>−663.122  *  *  *</cell><cell>−1,874.305  *  *  *</cell><cell>−1,874.305  *  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(132.104)</cell><cell>(132.104)</cell><cell>(28.438)</cell><cell>(28.438)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Flg. no churn score</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>−1,069.167  *  *  *</cell><cell>−1,069.167  *  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(23.209)</cell><cell>(23.209)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Cluster churn score</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>−1,134.396  *  *  *</cell><cell>−1,134.396  *  *  *</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(36.951)</cell><cell>(36.951)</cell></row><row><cell>Constant</cell><cell>2,860.568  *  *  *</cell><cell>2,911.657  *  *  *</cell><cell>3,757.427  *  *  *</cell><cell>3,785.354  *  *  *</cell><cell>3,381.876  *  *  *</cell><cell>3,417.522  *  *  *</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(82.575)</cell><cell>(80.583)</cell><cell>(30.052)</cell><cell>(23.259)</cell><cell>(26.204)</cell><cell>(21.030)</cell></row><row><cell>Period dummies</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell></row><row><cell>Observations</cell><cell>45,023</cell><cell>45,023</cell><cell>74,748</cell><cell>74,748</cell><cell>43,582</cell><cell>43,582</cell></row><row><cell>R 2</cell><cell>0.033</cell><cell>0.033</cell><cell>0.066</cell><cell>0.066</cell><cell>0.045</cell><cell>0.045</cell></row><row><cell>Adjusted R 2</cell><cell>0.033</cell><cell>0.033</cell><cell>0.066</cell><cell>0.066</cell><cell>0.044</cell><cell>0.044</cell></row><row><cell>Residual standard error</cell><cell>1,382.494</cell><cell>1,382.494</cell><cell>1,825.165</cell><cell>1,825.165</cell><cell>1,105.293</cell><cell>1,105.293</cell></row><row><cell>F-statistic</cell><cell>138.898  *  *  *</cell><cell>138.898  *  *  *</cell><cell>440.860  *  *  *</cell><cell>440.860  *  *  *</cell><cell>185.412  *  *  *</cell><cell>185.412  *  *  *</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">MarketingScience, 2018, vol. 37, no. 5, pp. 793-811, © 2018 </note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank the senior editor, associate editor, and two anonymous reviewers for valuable suggestions on how to improve this paper; our industry partner for its support; and all the participants of the 13th ZEW Conference on the Economics of Information and Communication Technologies, the 2nd Conference on Digital Experimentation at MIT, the Heinz Research Seminar Series, the Research Seminar Series at the Stern School of Management, NYU, and the Research Seminar Series at the Sloan School of Management, MIT, for comments and feedback on previous versions of this work. All remaining errors are the authors' own. The authors declare equal contribution to the manuscript.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Endnotes</head><p>1 About 95% of true positives listed by our predictive model request to disconnect their service (that is, enter the reactive retention) in the first 120 days after being identified by our model. 2 Of true positives listed by our predictive model, 95% request to disconnect their service (that is, enter the reactive retention) in the first 120 days after being identified by our model.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Customer satisfaction, market share, and profitability: Findings from Sweden</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Fornell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="53" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Instrumental variables estimation of average treatment effects in econometrics and epidemiology. Technical Godinho de Matos, Ferreira, and Belo: Target the Ego or Target the Group working paper no</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Angrist</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">National Bureau of Economic Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">115</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimation of limited dependent variable models with dummy endogenous regressors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Angrist</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Econom. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identification of causal effects using instrumental variables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Angrist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Imbens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">434</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="444" to="455" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Creating social contagion through viral product design: A randomized trial of peer influence in networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Aral</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1623" to="1639" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Retention futility: Targeting high risk customers might be ineffective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ascarza</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="98" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The perils of proactive churn prevention using plan recommendations: Evidence from a field experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ascarza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Iyengar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schleicher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="46" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond the target customer: Social effects of CRM campaigns</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ascarza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ebbes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Netzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Danielson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="347" to="363" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">In pursuit of enhanced customer retention management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ascarza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Neslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Netzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do your online friends make you pay? A randomized field experiment in an online music social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bapna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Umyarov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1902" to="1920" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Churn value management: How can companies retain customers in an increasingly volatile world</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bensoussan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Del</forename><surname>Bosch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Naud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Benichou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.oliverwyman.com/content/dam/oliver-wyman/global/en/2014/oct/201408_Churn_value_management_Screen.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-07-24" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Customer lifetime value: Marketing models and applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Berger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Nasr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Interactive Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="30" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Blattberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B-D</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Neslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Blattberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B-D</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Neslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Database Marketing: Analyzing and Managing Customers</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accounting for no-shows in experimental evaluation designs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bloom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eval. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="246" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dynamic model of the duration of the customer&apos;s relationship with a continuous service provider: The role of satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Bolton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="65" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dynamic model of customers&apos; usage of services: Usage as an antecedent and consequence of satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Bolton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Lemon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="171" to="186" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CRM at a pay-TV company: Using analytical models to reduce customer attrition by targeted marketing for subscription services</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Burez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Van Den Poel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Expert Systems Appl</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="277" to="288" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social influence: Compliance and conformity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Cialdini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Goldstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annu. Rev. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="591" to="621" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Design and analysis of experiments in networks: Reducing bias from interference</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Eckles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Karrer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ugander</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1404.7530</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Cornell University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to project customer retention</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Hardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Interactive Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="76" to="90" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Greedy function approximation: A gradient boosting machine</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1189" to="1232" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Economic analysis of proposed Sky/Vodafone merger</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Axiom Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Valuing customers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Stuart</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="18" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Customer lifetime value research in marketing: A review and future directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Jain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Interactive Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="34" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building predictive models in R using the caret package</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kuhn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Statist. Software</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bagging and boosting classification trees to predict churn</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lemmens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Croux</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="276" to="286" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Managing churn to maximize profits</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lemmens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<pubPlace>Harvard Business School; Boston</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Working paper no. 14-020</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identification of endogenous social effects: The reflection problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Manski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="531" to="542" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Birds of a feather: Homophily in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mcpherson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Smith-Lovin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Cook</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Rev. Sociol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="415" to="444" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social influence bias: A randomized experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Muchnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Aral</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">341</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6146</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="647" to="651" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Defection detection: Measuring and understanding the predictive accuracy of customer churn models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Neslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Kamakura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Mason</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="204" to="211" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social effects on customer retention</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Nitzan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Libai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="38" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Innovation diffusion and new product growth models: A critical review and research directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Peres</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Res. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The one number you need to grow</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Reichheld</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Harvard Bus. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="46" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Zero defections: Quality comes to service</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Reichheld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Sasser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Harvard Bus. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="111" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Balancing acquisition and retention resources to maximize customer profitability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Reinartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of customer relationship characteristics on profitable lifetime duration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Reinartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="99" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interference between units in randomized experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Rosenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">477</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="191" to="200" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Return on marketing: Using customer equity to focus marketing strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Rust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Lemon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Zeithaml</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="127" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding service retention within and across cohorts using limited information</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Schweidel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Bradlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="82" to="94" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Homophily and contagion are generically confounded in observational social network studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Shalizi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sociol. Methods Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="239" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Solomon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Consumer Behavior: Buying, Having, and Being</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Engelwood Cliffs, NJ</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structural diversity in social contagion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ugander</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Backstrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Marlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5962" to="5966" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Graph cluster randomization: Network exposure to multiple universes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ugander</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Karrer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Backstrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 19th ACM SIGKDD Internat. Conf. on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
				<meeting>19th ACM SIGKDD Internat. Conf. on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining<address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="329" to="337" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A customer lifetime value framework for customer selection and resource allocation strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Venkatesan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="106" to="125" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of marketinginduced versus word-of-mouth customer acquisition on customer equity growth</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Villanueva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yoo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hanssens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="48" to="59" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wasserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Social Network Analysis: Methods and Applications</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A framework for customer relationship management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Winer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Calif. Management Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Econometric Analysis of Cross Section and Panel Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wooldridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ferreira</forename><surname>Godinho De Matos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Belo</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Target the Ego or Target the Group Marketing Science</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="793" to="811" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
