<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Two Centuries of Innovations and Stock Market Bubbles</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2018-07-16">July 16, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Alina</forename><surname>Sorescu</surname></persName>
							<email>asorescu@tamu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Mays Business School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Texas A&amp;M University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>77843</postCode>
									<settlement>College Station, Texas</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sorin</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sorescu</surname></persName>
							<email>ssorescu@tamu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Will</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Armstrong</surname></persName>
							<email>will.armstrong@ttu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Mays Business School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Texas A&amp;M University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>77843</postCode>
									<settlement>College Station, Texas</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Rawls College of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Texas Tech University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>79409</postCode>
									<settlement>Lubbock</settlement>
									<region>Texas</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Bart</forename><surname>Devoldere</surname></persName>
							<email>bart.devoldere@vlerick.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Vlerick Business School</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>9000</postCode>
									<settlement>Ghent</settlement>
									<country key="BE">Belgium</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">Netherlands Organisation for Applied Scientific Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>2595 DA</postCode>
									<settlement>The Hague</settlement>
									<country key="NL">Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="laboratory">TomorrowLab</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>1800</postCode>
									<settlement>Vilvoorde</settlement>
									<country key="BE">Belgium</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Two Centuries of Innovations and Stock Market Bubbles</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 (print)</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2018-07-16">July 16, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.2018.1095</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: April 22, 2016 Revised: October 12, 2017; January 27, 2018 Accepted: February 4, 2018</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:24+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>radical innovation</term>
					<term>stock market bubbles</term>
					<term>capital raised</term>
					<term>diffusion</term>
					<term>visibility</term>
					<term>network effects</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The interplay between innovation and the stock market has been extensively studied by scholars across all business disciplines. However, one phenomenon remains understudied: the association between innovation and stock market bubbles. Bubblesdefined as rapid increases and subsequent declines in stock prices-have been primarily examined by economists who generally do not focus on individual characteristics of innovations or on the consequences of bubbles for their parent firms. We set out to fill this gap in our paper. Using a sample of 51 major innovations introduced between 1825 and 2000, we test for bubbles in the stock prices of parent firms subsequent to the commercialization of these innovations. We identify bubbles in 73% of the cases. The magnitude of these bubbles increases with the radicalness of innovations, with their potential to generate indirect network effects, and with their public visibility at the time of commercialization. Moreover, we find that parent firms typically raise new equity capital during bubble periods and that the amount of equity raised is proportional to the magnitude of the bubble. Finally, we show that the buy-and-hold abnormal returns of parent firms are significantly positive between the beginning and the end of the bubble, suggesting that these innovations add value to their firm and to the economy, in spite of the bubble. Our findings have important implications for managers interested in commercializing innovations and for policy makers concerned with the stability of the financial system. History: K. Sudhir served as the editor-in-chief and Harald van Heerde served as associate editor for this article. Funding: The authors gratefully acknowledge financial support from the Marketing Science Institute and from the Mays Business School at Texas A&amp;M University. B. Devoldere acknowledges financial support from the Belgian Intercollegiate Centre for Management Science.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>A sizable stream of research has examined the interplay between innovation and the stock market. In marketing, the focus has been on short-and longterm abnormal returns associated with new product introductions. The marketing literature generally finds a positive impact of innovation on stock prices (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Pauwels et al. 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">, Sood and Tellis 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">, Warren and Sorescu 2017</ref> and concludes that many new products and technological innovations have spurred the growth of their parent firms and even of entire industries and countries <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Tellis et al. 2009)</ref>.</p><p>In turn, the literature in financial economics tends to take a more macro view of innovation. A significant part of this literature has studied the causes and consequences of technological revolutions-periods when technological advances bring abrupt and long-lasting changes to our society <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Lamoreaux et al. 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">, Perez 2002</ref>. A few authors working in this domain suggest that the stock market plays a critical role in financing innovations launched during technological revolutions, particularly beginning with the 1920s <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Hsu et al. 2014</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">, Neal and Davis 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">, O'Sullivan 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">, Perez 2002</ref>. Others observe that such revolutions tend to be associated with stock market bubbles-a rapid increase and subsequent decline in stock prices-citing, as examples, radio stock prices during <ref type="bibr">1929</ref><ref type="bibr">-1930</ref><ref type="bibr">and Internet stock prices during 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(DeMarzo et al. 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">, Pástor and Veronesi 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">, Shiller 2015</ref>.</p><p>Are certain types of innovations more likely to be associated with stock market bubbles than others? If an innovation produces a bubble, are firms that commercialize it affected by the bubble, and if so, in what way? Can firms raise new capital during bubble periods and use it to accelerate the diffusion of the innovation? Extant literature does not provide clear answers to these questions. The lack of insight is due, in part, to the fact that the bubble literature in financial economics tends to view innovation as an undifferentiated output generated by an aggregate production function, </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>508</head><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 507-529, © 2018</ref> rather than a collection of products with distinct characteristics. Moreover, studies in this area rarely incorporate a formal statistical measurement of bubbles, using instead ex post observations of sudden rises and declines in stock prices, and little attempt is made to link such price movements to specific innovations. A notable exception is by <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Frehen et al. (2013)</ref>, who show that the South Sea Bubble of 1720-commonly thought of as a single occurrence by historians-actually consisted of two separate bubbles, each associated with contemporaneous innovations in two distinct industries: insurance and the Atlantic trade. Finally, most papers that study bubbles tend to focus on only one or two salient innovations, such as rail <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Campbell 2012)</ref> or the Internet <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Pástor and Veronesi 2009)</ref>.</p><p>Overall, the academic literature in marketing and financial economics provides little systematic evidence of the link between external financing, innovation, and bubbles. However, understanding the extent to which the stock market plays a role in helping new industries develop and flourish is a topic of high relevance to managers seeking to finance innovation and to policy makers who seek to foster economic growth while maintaining the stability of the financial system. Managers might also be interested in learning whether certain types of innovations are more likely to be associated with disruptive patterns in their firm's stock price, and whether such patterns impact the eventual diffusion of the innovation. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Our paper seeks to fill this gap through a study positioned at the interface of marketing, finance, and economics. Using the list of radical innovations identified by <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Chandy and Tellis (2000)</ref> as a starting point, we assemble a sample of 51 major innovations introduced between the years 1825 and 2000. For each of these innovations, we collect data on firms that commercialized it-which we call parent firms-and test whether these firms experienced bubbles in their stock prices following commercialization.</p><p>To detect bubbles, we look for significant differences between stock market prices and intrinsic values, using the econometric method proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">West (1987)</ref>. We then estimate a number of cross-sectional models to understand how these bubbles relate to various characteristics of each innovation. Next, we measure the amount of new equity capital raised by parent firms during bubble periods. Finally, we estimate the relation between this new capital raised and the subsequent visibility of the innovation in the public domain.</p><p>We present six important findings. First, we detect bubbles in approximately 73% of the innovations studied (37 out of 51). By contrast, the largest collection of innovations previously associated with bubbles can be found in the book by <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Shiller (2015)</ref>, who describes nine possible bubbles, and argues that they tend to be associated with major shifts in technological paradigms. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Second, we show that the magnitude of these bubbles is positively related to the contemporaneous level of visibility of each innovation. To measure this visibility, we obtain from the Google Books Ngram Viewer the annual frequency with which the innovation is mentioned in public books, through time. Third, we find that bubbles are more likely to occur for innovations that have a higher degree of radicalness and for innovations that are more likely to generate indirect network effects. Fourth, we find that parent firms raise significantly more equity capital during bubble periods compared to the average firm in the market, and the amount of this new capital is proportional to the magnitude of the bubble. Fifth, we show that the new capital raised during bubble periods is positively associated with a faster and stronger increase in the visibility of the innovation after the bubble. Finally, we show that the buy-and-hold abnormal returns of parent firms are significantly positive between the beginning and the end of the bubble, suggesting that these innovations add value to their firms and to the economy, in spite of the bubble.</p><p>These findings have important implications for managers and policy makers. Managers of firms commercializing innovations that are radical <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Chandy and Tellis 1998)</ref> or innovations that can generate indirect network effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Stremersch et al. 2007</ref>) should be aware of a potentially disruptive pattern in their stock prices in the form of bubbles. At the same time, these bubbles may create a short window of opportunity during which equity capital could be raised on favorable terms. If this capital is judiciously invested, it can help accelerate the diffusion of the innovation. In terms of policy implications, our results suggest that bubbles might allow for faster building of the infrastructure needed for innovation to achieve its full economic potential. Therefore, at least from this narrow perspective, bubbles appear to act as an indirect, voluntary tax that some people pay to invest in what is essentially a public good. This implication is consistent with <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Olivier (2000)</ref>, whose mathematical model predicts that stock market bubbles are beneficial to value creation, investment, and growth.</p><p>Our results also support the views expressed by former Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan, who opined that while bubbles are precipitated by exaggerated perceptions of economic growth, they also fuel the diffusion of the underlying innovation by providing the capital required for its commercialization <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lansing 2008)</ref>. Without a bubble, he argued, a major innovation might not take off or achieve its full potential. Observing that "there were no bubbles in the Soviet Union," Greenspan concluded that policy makers should not attempt to quash bubbles since doing so could impede innovation and lead to suppressed economic activity over the long term <ref type="bibr">(Guha 2008, p.</ref> 2).</p><p>We do not claim to establish causal relations in our paper. Instead, our goal is to provide a number of statistical tests to study stock market bubbles across the largest set of innovations used in this literature. As is the case with most papers that focus on first-order research questions, we are only able to answer a subset of questions that readers might deem important. The data collection for this project was laborious and extensive. Data for innovations from the 19th century and from the earlier part of the 20th century were challenging to obtain, and in many cases extensive manual searches had to be performed in newspapers and other contemporaneous sources. We nevertheless hope that our insights into the economic consequences of innovation will serve as impetus for additional research in this area.</p><p>The rest of the paper proceeds as follows. In Section 2, we present an overview of the theory that supports the existence of stock market bubbles, and we review the literature that links innovations with bubbles. We also present theoretical arguments that support the relation between individual innovation characteristics, stock market bubbles, and external financing. In Section 3, we discuss the economic consequences of bubbles. In Section 4, we describe the data collection process and empirical methodology. Section 5 presents the results, and Section 6 concludes with a discussion of the implications of our findings for researchers, managers, and policy makers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Innovation and Stock Market Bubbles</head><p>We begin this section with a discussion of the economic theory of bubbles. We continue with a brief overview of the literature that links innovation and bubbles, and conclude with a set of empirical predictions that link bubbles with specific innovation characteristics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Asset Price Bubbles</head><p>Bubbles occur when the price of an asset exceeds its intrinsic value by a significant amount and for a sufficiently long period of time. The literature in financial economics distinguishes between "behavioral" bubbles and "rational" bubbles <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Scherbina and Schlusche 2014)</ref>. Behavioral bubbles occur when investors deviate from the rational expectations model, perhaps because they overreact to news or fail to update their beliefs in a Bayesian manner. By contrast, rational bubbles occur despite all agents being perfectly rational and having access to the same information set.</p><p>We adopt the rational bubble approach because it is based on the rational expectations paradigm prevailing in financial economics. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Fama (1998)</ref> argues that researchers should not reject rational expectations until (or unless) the alternative (behavioral) paradigm can do a better job at explaining existing empirical observations within a unified body of knowledge. While the literature in behavioral finance has evolved over the past 20 years, to our knowledge, there is no unified behavioral theory of bubbles. Indeed, <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Scherbina and Schlusche (2014)</ref> discuss no fewer than 18 papers grouped into four different categories of behavioralbased models of bubbles. In turn, each category is based on a unique set of underlying cognitive biases (such as self-attribution or conservatism). Collectively, these 18 papers provide little guidance for our research because there is no systematic way to determine, ex ante, which cognitive biases apply to various innovations or time periods. By contrast, the rational bubble approach allows us to develop a parsimonious set of testable predictions that apply uniformly to all innovations in our sample.</p><p>A common theoretical explanation for rational bubbles is the mathematical, discrete-time model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Blanchard and Fischer (1989)</ref>. Versions of this model have been used in other papers, including those by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Blanchard and Watson (1982)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Froot and Obstfeld (1991)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Rappoport and White (1993)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">White (1990)</ref>, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Scherbina and Schlusche (2014)</ref>. The model explains how bubbles may arise even if all economic agents act rationally. <ref type="bibr">Blanchard and Fischer (1989, pp. 213-223)</ref> posit that the price of an asset in one period is equal to the discounted value of its expected price and cash flows during the next period. They then seek to find the theoretical value of the price during the current period, expressed only in terms of future cash flows and discount rates. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Blanchard and Fischer (1989)</ref> show that the solution to their model is not unique. There are, in fact, an infinite number of solutions. One of them (the fundamental solution) is the well-known present value of future cash flows, which defines the intrinsic value of an asset. All other solutions include a "bubble" component: a positive quantity that is artificially added to the intrinsic value. We know very little about this bubble component. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Blanchard and Fischer's (1989)</ref> theory tells us only that it is expected to grow at a rate r, equal to the discount rate of the asset. This property is not very useful because it allows for an infinite number of outcomes. For example, any random number that grows through time at rate r is a potential bubble. Ideally, we would like to obtain more specific properties for this bubble so that we may learn something about its magnitude and determinants.</p><p>Fortunately, a special case of the rational bubble theory allows us to narrow down the set of bubble solutions and obtain useful testable implications. This special case was proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Froot and Obstfeld (1991)</ref>, who introduced the concept of intrinsic bubbles, a subset of rational bubbles. With intrinsic bubbles, the magnitude of the bubble component is proportional to the contemporaneous value of the asset's cash flows (or to the value of another proxy that is correlated with cash flows).</p><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 507-529, © 2018</ref> We mentioned earlier that the solution to the <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Blanchard and Fischer (1989)</ref> model may or may not include a bubble. While both scenarios are theoretically possible, only one of them will be observed in realityeither the asset price includes a bubble or it does not. Mathematics alone cannot help us determine which of these scenarios will prevail. For this, we need to know more about the underlying economic conditions.</p><p>In Web Appendix A, we provide a simplified version of the <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Blanchard and Fischer (1989)</ref> model, along with an economic interpretation of their solution. We also discuss the intuition behind <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Froot and Obstfeld's (1991)</ref> theory of intrinsic bubbles and explain how its predictions relate to our paper. We argue that bubbles are more likely to occur when the following four conditions are met: (1) the asset is expected to live for an indefinite period of time (as is the case with stocks), (2) no bubble-free close substitute exists for the asset, (3) investors have exploding expectations about the future cash flows generated by the asset, and (4) short selling is costly or subject to constraints. When we overlay the theory of intrinsic bubbles on the basic model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Blanchard and Fischer (1989)</ref>, we obtain the additional prediction that the magnitude of a bubble is proportional to a proxy for the cash flows generated by the asset at the time when the bubble occurs. These economic implications form the basis for our predictions about the determinants and consequences of bubbles associated with innovations. We present these predictions in Sections 2.3 and 3, respectively. 3</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Relation Between Innovation, External</head><p>Financing, and Bubbles A review of the bubble literature reveals several aspects that warrant further inquiry. First, a few authors note that stock market bubbles occur during industrial revolutions; however, this observation is made primarily in case studies, books, and in the popular press <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Gross 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">, Kindleberger and Aliber 2005</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">, Perez 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">, Shiller 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">, Wood 2006</ref>). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Perhaps because of the tendency to look for bubbles during these periods of intense technological progress, only a limited set of bubbles has been examined in academic studies. For instance, <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Campbell (2012)</ref> studies the British railway bubble of the 1840s, <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Ofek and Richardson (2003)</ref> study the Internet bubble of <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">, and Pástor and Veronesi (2009</ref> study the Internet bubble and the American railroads before the Civil War, while <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Frehen et al. (2013)</ref> establish a link between the stock market bubbles of 1720 and innovations that at the time were taking place in the insurance and Atlantic trade industries.</p><p>Second, with the exceptions mentioned above, this literature tends to focus on marketwide bubbles, rather than on industry-specific bubbles spurred by individual innovations. Moreover, academic papers in this stream tend to view innovation as an undifferentiated aggregate output, which precludes the study of product-specific characteristics. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Nicholas (2008)</ref> evaluates the extent to which the stock market during the 1920s responded to contemporaneous changes in the intellectual capital of U.S. firms, measured using citation-weighted patents assigned to each firm. He finds that excess stock returns during 1928-1929 are positively related to firms' intellectual capital, but does not evaluate the relation between stock returns and specific products.</p><p>Third, the literature does not provide a unified view on why bubbles might be associated with innovations, and why some bubbles might be larger than others. This could be a consequence of different philosophical perspectives regarding the underlying causes of bubbles. For example, several authors take the view that bubbles are caused by irrational investors (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Ferguson 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">, Perez 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">, Shiller 2015</ref>. Others adopt a more rational view of bubbles but tend to focus on only one or two bubbles and, therefore, lack context to systematically examine common patterns across innovations. As a result, the rationale presented in support of the bubble varies from investor myopia <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Campbell 2012)</ref> to changes in the systematic risk of parent firms <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Pástor and Veronesi 2009)</ref>.</p><p>A number of questions remain unanswered. Perhaps the most salient relates to the scale of the relation between innovation and bubbles: Does this relation extend to all innovations or is it confined to technological revolutions? Because innovations vary on a continuum in terms of technological advances and benefits they bring to consumers, it is important to understand where on this continuum the boundary that could trigger a bubble might lie.</p><p>What happens after the bubble is also of interest. A number of authors have argued that the collapse of bubbles is disruptive to economic activity <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Perez 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">, Wood 2006</ref>), but are there other, more desirable outcomes? <ref type="bibr">Rapp (2014, p. 21)</ref> proposed that "when stock prices increase, firms can raise cash from existing and new investors at lower costs." Thus, bubbles could create a favorable environment for firms to raise new equity capital during the commercialization phase of new products. However, there is no systematic evidence that supports this assertion. Finally, we know very little about the longer-term prospects of products whose parent firms are subject to bubbles. Do bubbles help or hurt the visibility and eventual diffusion of innovations?</p><p>We address some of these open questions using a novel data set that spans multiple industries across the 19th and 20th centuries. In Section 2.3, we leverage the theories proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Blanchard and Fischer (1989)</ref> and by <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Froot and Obstfeld (1991)</ref> to make predictions on the determinants and consequences of bubbles associated with innovation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Which Innovations Are More Likely to Be</head><p>Associated with Bubbles? We mentioned earlier that the literature in financial economics has not examined how differences in innovation characteristics may impact stock prices. By contrast, research in marketing has examined the differential effect of radical versus incremental innovation on stock prices. When compared with incremental innovations, radical innovations-defined as "new products that (1) incorporate substantially different technology from existing products and (2) can fulfill key customer needs better than existing products" <ref type="bibr">(Chandy and Tellis 1998, p. 475</ref>)-are associated with stronger longterm stock performance and also with higher firm risk <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Pauwels et al. 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">, Sood and Tellis 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">, Sorescu and Spanjol 2008</ref>. The overarching conclusion from this stream of research is that the superior benefits provided by radical innovation eventually result in a broader adoption of these products, which translates into higher revenues and profits.</p><p>To understand the relation between bubbles and specific innovation characteristics, we return to the theoretical framework of intrinsic rational bubbles presented in Section 2.1. Recall that from <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Blanchard and Fischer (1989)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Froot and Obstfeld (1991)</ref> we had derived a set of conditions that are more conducive to the emergence of bubbles. We now turn to interpreting these conditions within the context of our current research.</p><p>Two of the four conditions that underlie the formation of bubbles are met by all innovations in our sample. Specifically, the first condition-indefinitely lived assets-is met by all stocks. Unless a firm is in bankruptcy, the expectation is that it will continue to operate for the foreseeable future. The fourth condition-costly short selling-is also likely to be met by all stocks in our sample. <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Danielsen and Sorescu (2001)</ref> provide several reasons why investors find it difficult to establish short positions in the stock market. For example, investors do not immediately get access to the proceeds from short selling, investors face high search costs for finding a willing security lender, and there is always a risk of a "short squeeze," that is, of a premature request to liquidate the short position before investors can earn a profit (also see <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Akbas et al. 2017)</ref>.</p><p>The second and third conditions are met by some but not all firms. The second condition-the absence of a close substitute in the stock market-is more likely to be met in the case of innovations whose characteristics are very different from those of existing products. By definition, radical innovations meet these criteria (at the product category level), since they provide significantly higher consumer benefits and incorporate a new technology relative to existing products. Because of these characteristics, parent firms that commercialize radical innovations are exposed to risks previously unknown to investors, which cannot be easily hedged using existing assets. The more radical the innovation, the fewer close-substitute stocks are available in the stock market. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Because close-substitute stocks are necessary to arbitrage away mispricing and prevent the bubble from growing, a lower number of closesubstitute stocks may lead to bigger bubbles. Thus, our first prediction is that the higher the level of radicalness of innovations, the larger the magnitude of the innovation bubble.</p><p>The third condition-exploding expectations of future cash flows-is more likely to be satisfied by innovations believed to offer quasi-unlimited revenue potential. We propose that network goods meet this condition. Network goods and services are those whose value to adopters increases as a function of the number of other people who use them (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Gupta et al. 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">, Hall 2005</ref>. Direct and indirect network externalities have been distinguished in the literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Katz and Shapiro 1986)</ref>. The steam engine exemplifies direct externalities, because the utility derived from rail transportation increased along with its diffusion (the size and geographic reach of the rail network). A good example of indirect externalities is given by the recent growth in the app industry, spurred by smartphones and tablets. In turn, apps provide smart devices with increased functionality, arguably broadening those devices' appeal and potentially strengthening their diffusion (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Stremersch et al. 2007)</ref>.</p><p>Assessing the future cash flows of an innovation is particularly difficult if it requires an estimation of the magnitude of network effects. Network effects could exponentially increase the adoption of a technology within and across industries, indicating that the innovation has the potential to generate exploding future cash flows. Investors-particularly optimistic oneswill factor this possibility into their valuation. Therefore, we suggest that the magnitude of a bubble increases with an innovation's potential for network externalities.</p><p>Finally, we derive a third testable implication from the intrinsic bubble model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Froot and Obstfeld (1991)</ref>. Their research suggests that the magnitude of an intrinsic bubble is proportional to the contemporaneous cash flows generated by the underlying innovation, or to any exogenous variable that is correlated to these cash flows. In support of this prediction, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Froot and Obstfeld (1991)</ref> provide macro-level evidence of intrinsic bubbles obtained from aggregate stock returns and dividends in the United States during the period from 1900 to 1988.</p><p>Recall that the intrinsic bubble theory requires that we measure innovation-specific cash flows that are contemporaneous with the bubble. In the absence of specific information about cash flows-which are not directly observable-investors are likely to anchor their valuations on metrics that are visible and that, in their opinion, might be correlated to cash flows. We propose that <ref type="bibr">Marketing Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 507-529, © 2018</ref> the public visibility of the innovation around the time of the bubble is a good exogenous proxy for the extent to which it has been adopted by the public, and therefore for the cash flows that it generates. To develop this proxy, we use the Google Books Ngram Viewer, an Internet search engine that provides annual frequencies of any search terms that appear in print up to 2008. We obtain from Google Ngram the annual frequencies for each innovation at the time of the bubble.</p><p>While admittedly imperfect, the Google Ngram proxy has the distinct advantage of not suffering from retrospective bias because it contains information that was publicly known at the outset of the bubble. In addition, Google Ngram data are available for all innovations in our sample, which provides us with a consistent proxy for cash flows that is comparable across several innovations and time periods. In turn, this consistency facilitates cross-sectional analysis in a sample that is otherwise quite heterogeneous. Thus, our third prediction is that the magnitude of a bubble increases with the public visibility of the innovation as captured by its contemporaneous Google Ngram frequency of mentions in printed books.</p><p>In sum, we predict that the magnitude of innovation bubbles is increasing in the degree of radicalness, in the potential for network externalities, and in the contemporaneous visibility of the innovation. In Section 3, we examine the consequences of bubbles for the parent firms and for the public visibility and eventual diffusion of the innovation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">What Are the Consequences of</head><p>Bubbles?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">The Economic Value Added of Bubbles</head><p>The intrinsic bubble theory of <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Froot and Obstfeld (1991)</ref> is based on the premise that when bubbles occur, they do so because the underlying asset-in this case, the stocks of parent firms-adds significant value to the economy. This prediction is corroborated by <ref type="bibr">Olivier (2000, p. 133)</ref>, who argues that "the real impact of a [rational] bubble depends on the type of asset that is being speculated on. Speculative bubbles on equity raise the market value of firms, thus encouraging entrepreneurship, firm creation, investment, and growth." Therefore, we expect innovations that are subject to bubbles to have, on average, positive net present value NPV despite the presence of bubbles. We test this prediction in our paper, with NPV measured as the abnormal returns earned by the stocks of parent firms, from the beginning to the end of the bubble.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Capital Raised in the Stock Market</head><p>A critical question of interest to managers is how to raise the capital needed to finance innovations. This is particularly true for innovations that are fueled by new technologies, which require significant capital investment. While it might be natural today to assume that this new capital could be easily raised by issuing new equity, historical evidence suggests that this was not always the case. Indeed, prior to the mid-1920s, innovations were financed mostly with private capital raised from the owners' personal network <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Lamoreaux et al. 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">, O'Sullivan 2007</ref>. The stock market began to play a more significant role in financing innovation beginning with the aircraft and radio industries in the 1920s (O'Sullivan 2007). Since that time, firms have increasingly relied on equity capital raised from public sources.</p><p>We expect that the presence of bubbles could make it easier for parent firms to raise equity capital because one consequence of overvalued stocks is a temporary reduction in the firm's cost of equity during the bubble period. In turn, this could make it attractive for managers to raise new equity capital in the form of initial public offerings (IPOs) or seasoned equity offerings (SEOs). This new capital would be raised by issuing overvalued shares, which is favorable to the firm's existing shareholders, but not to its new shareholders.</p><p>Although managers would normally want to issue new equity when their stock is overvalued, most of the time they are not able to do so without paying a penalty because of adverse selection. Indeed, investors usually view SEOs as a signal of overvaluation, and a mere announcement of an SEO typically results in an immediate decline in the market value of the firm (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Myers and Majluf 1984)</ref>. In a nonbubble environment, this decline would offset any benefits obtained from issuing overvalued stock. The bubble environment, however, might be different: it might provide a unique opportunity for managers to raise cheap equity capital without worrying about sending negative signals to the market. If this were true, we would expect parent firms to raise an abnormally high amount of equity capital during bubble periods. We provide empirical evidence on this issue in our paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Postbubble Trajectory of Innovation</head><p>We have so far focused on the consequences of bubbles for parent firms. We now turn to the potential consequences of bubbles for the innovations themselves. Can a bubble affect the public visibility, and ultimately the diffusion, of an innovation, and if so, in what way?</p><p>The diffusion literature has examined several milestones in the life cycle of a new product. The first milestone is the takeoff time, defined by <ref type="bibr">Golder and Tellis (1997, p. 257)</ref> as "the point of transition from the introductory stage to the growth stage of the product life cycle," a point when a dramatic increase in sales occurs. Determinants of the takeoff time include a reduction in the price of the innovation and the level of market penetration <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Golder and Tellis 1997)</ref>. Another determinant of takeoff that is particularly relevant to our context is the performance of the parent firm's stock in the early commercialization stages: a strong positive abnormal stock performance has been found to predict takeoff in the subsequent year <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Markovitch and Golder 2008)</ref>, suggesting that takeoff could follow shortly after a bubble has emerged. Finally, the parent firm's ability to raise cheap equity capital during a bubble essentially reduces the cost of the innovation, which can potentially reduce its price and shorten its time to takeoff <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Golder and Tellis 1997)</ref>. Therefore, we expect that the magnitude of the bubble and the capital raised during the bubble are positively related to how quickly takeoff occurs.</p><p>We do not measure diffusion directly. Rather, we use as a proxy the time series of visibility obtained from Google Ngram, beginning with the commercialization date of each innovation. Just as visibility could serve as an ex ante proxy for the innovation's cash flows, it can also serve as an ex post proxy for its diffusion. Using this proxy, we estimate the takeoff of each innovation as the inflection point in the time series of Google Ngram visibility. In Web Appendix D we show, for a subsample of 25 innovations, that the takeoff estimated from visibility correlates highly with the takeoff estimated from product adoption data.</p><p>The literature on new product diffusion also makes predictions about the shape of the diffusion curve after takeoff. Initial models predicted a monotonic increase in sales up to the peak of growth, followed by a slowdown (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Peres et al. 2010)</ref>. Other authors have argued that the diffusion curve follows a chasm and saddle pattern, where sudden decreases in sales follow the initial rise <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Golder and</ref><ref type="bibr">Tellis 2004, Mahajan and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Muller 1998)</ref>. In all cases, as newer technologies become available, the diffusion curve eventually plateaus and starts declining. The point at which it plateaus has been assumed to be the point of market saturation, but researchers have focused less on this saturation point compared to the takeoff point.</p><p>We argue that the same characteristics of a bubble that lead to an accelerated takeoff are also associated with a higher market saturation point. A lower innovation cost obtained from the parent firm's ability to raise cheap capital will not only lead to a faster takeoff but also to a broader adoption of the innovation. Thus, we expect that the magnitude of the bubble and the capital raised during the bubble are positively related to the visibility that the innovation achieves after takeoff. This visibility is proxied by the maximum Google Ngram value that the innovation attains in its lifetime.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Data and Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Selection of Innovations Included in</head><p>Our Sample Assembling a comprehensive data set of innovations introduced during the last two centuries is a challenging task. We start with the largest set of radical innovations documented in the literature, a list of 64 new products introduced between 1864 and 1998 provided in <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Chandy and Tellis (2000)</ref>. The authors used the historical approach to data collection <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Golder 2000)</ref> and consulted "more than 250 books and 500 articles in periodicals" to construct their sample <ref type="bibr">(Chandy and Tellis 2000, p. 5)</ref>. Therefore, we believe that this list constitutes a good initial sampling frame for our study. Of the 64 innovations mentioned in <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Chandy and Tellis (2000)</ref>, we were able to identify and collect data for 43 innovations commercialized between <ref type="bibr">1886 and 1998. 6</ref> In our review of the literature on technological revolutions, we also encountered a few additional innovations that have been singled out by economists as being notable in their ability to spur economic growth. For instance, <ref type="bibr">Shiller (2015, p. 125</ref>) mentions the steam engine train, motion pictures, and the Internet (or, more specifically, the World Wide Web) as major innovations that ushered what he calls "a new era." Through this archival process, we add eight additional innovations to the <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Chandy and Tellis (2000)</ref> list: the steam engine train, the telegraph, motion pictures, rayon, the airplane, the Internet, the GPS receiver, and the smartphone. Table WA-B3 in Web Appendix B details the sources used to identify these innovations. Our final sample consists of 51 innovations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Identifications of Parent Firms and of</head><p>Financial Data Used for the Bubble Tests After assembling our sample of innovations, we identify the date when each innovation was commercialized, as well as the parent firms involved in the commercialization process. To do so we use extensive archival searches encompassing a large number of books and articles on the history of technology, major U.S. and UK journals that date back to the 19th century (such as the Wall Street Journal and the London Times), and academic articles that examine the diffusion of innovations (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Agarwal and</ref><ref type="bibr">Bayus 2002, Golder and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Tellis 1997)</ref>.</p><p>From the set of parent firms, we select those with available stock and dividend data. For most innovations in the 20th century, company-specific data are available from the Center for Research in Security Prices (CRSP) beginning with the year 1925. For earlier innovations, we turn to the Cowles Foundation database (https://som.yale.edu/faculty-research/our -centers-initiatives/international-center-finance/data/ historical-cowles), which covers the period from 1871 to 1938. Unlike the CRSP, Cowles provides data on industry indices, not on individual companies. If we are able to identify a clear industry index that corresponds to a particular innovation (for example, "automobile"), we use the Cowles price and dividend data for that index, and the set of parent firms for that particular innovation is deemed to be the set that the Cowles researchers had chosen to include in their index.</p><p>If the Cowles index is too broad (for example, "appliances" instead of "refrigerator"), we identify parent  price index and monthly dividend series for each innovation. The monthly price index is constructed using the value-weighted average return (excluding dividends) of the stocks included in the index. The monthly dividend series for each index is constructed by first computing each stock's monthly dividend yield as the difference between its total monthly return and its monthly return excluding dividends. The monthly dividend yield of the index is then computed as the value-weighted average of the component stocks' dividend yields. Monthly dividends in terms of the price index are computed as the product of the index's dividend yield and the value of the price index at the end of the prior month. London Stock Exchange (Old LSE data set)</p><p>The Old LSE data set was produced by compiling hard copy entries from the Investors Monthly Manual, a record of the London Stock Exchange for the period from 1871 to 1930. Common stock prices and dividends from this data set are used to construct the required price indexes and dividend series in a manner consistent with those that are based on CRSP data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Cowles Commission for Research in Economics</head><p>The Cowles data set, produced from the Cowles Commission's third monograph <ref type="bibr">(1939)</ref>, contains industry-level common stock data series for the period 1871 to 1938. We use two price indexes from these data: a price index that excludes dividends and a total return index that includes both dividends and price appreciation. As we do with the CRSP data, we use the difference in the returns of these two indexes to construct a monthly, industry-level dividend series denominated in terms of the price index.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Compustat Global</head><p>Monthly, stock-level data for foreign stocks are available from Compustat Global from January 1985 to the present. Variables constructed from this data set are computed in the same manner as described above for the CRSP data. This data set was used to collect stock price and dividend data for Japanese firms that did not trade in the United States during the time period of interest. New York Stock Exchange (Old NYSE data set)</p><p>The Old NYSE data set was produced from data used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Goetzmann et al. (2001)</ref>. Common stock prices and dividends from this data set are used to construct the required price indexes and dividend series in a manner consistent with those that are based on the CRSP data.</p><p>Note. This table presents the data sources used to collect stock and dividend data for the bubble tests.</p><p>companies from historical sources and collect data on individual stocks from the Historical London Stock Exchange and Historical New York Stock Exchange databases, both of which are available at Yale University in electronic format. Finally, data not available in electronic format are hand collected from contemporaneous newspapers in the United States and the United Kingdom. One exception is the data set on the UK railroad industry from the 19th century, which was provided to us by Gareth Campbell <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Campbell 2012)</ref>. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref> describes our data sources, and Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">2</ref> provides a list of the 51 innovations in our sample, along with the years of commercialization and the corresponding portfolios of parent firms. A full description of the history of these innovations is available on request from the authors. For innovations not covered by the CRSP or Cowles, we occasionally have to confine our analysis to a single firm, because of data availability. For example, for the telegraph industry, we study only the stock of Western Union, as we are unable to identify data for other companies. Our results are not likely to be biased by these single-firm portfolios. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> Our portfolios do not contain the complete set of early entrants in each industry. While this is a limitation caused by data availability, our goal here is to create clean portfolios for the measurement of bubbles, rather than to extensively study the entry process into new industries. As a result, we are primarily concerned with building portfolios that have significant exposure to the focal innovation (and little exposure to everything else), rather than to make the portfolios as comprehensive as possible. To accomplish this goal, we endeavor as much as possible to include in our test portfolios only firms that are pure plays, in the sense that their product portfolio includes primarily the innovation and not much else. To the extent to which our test portfolios may occasionally include firms that are not pure plays (such as multiproduct firms that commercialize other products in addition to the focal innovation), the inclusion of such firms would merely bias our results toward zero, because these firms would have a smaller exposure to the economic forces that ignite the bubble. 8</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Characteristics of Innovations That Are More</head><p>Likely to Be Associated with Bubbles Previously, we identified three innovation characteristics that increase the probability of a bubble: the innovation's degree of radicalness, its potential to generate network effects, and the extent of its public visibility. Ideally, we would like to collect contemporaneous data for each of these three characteristics to minimize the risk of a retrospective bias. However, we could only do so in the case of visibility. We measure contemporaneous visibility using the Google Ngram data, which  Notes. This table presents the names of the firm(s) included in the test portfolio of each innovation. The year of each firm's entry into the portfolio is included in parentheses. For the Internet industry, we provide the source of the index employed. The first column shows the name of each innovation and the second column shows the year of commercialization.</p><p>a Because the electric blanket and the electric dishwasher were introduced in the same year <ref type="bibr">(1930)</ref>, and because the test portfolio for both products is limited to General Electric, we can only perform a joint bubble test for these two products. If a bubble is detected, it could be attributed to either one of the two innovations or to both. <ref type="bibr">b</ref> We use the term Internet to refer to the World Wide Web (WWW) enhancement to the Internet technology. Tim Berners-Lee invented the WWW in 1990, and the concept was first commercialized in 1991. Berners-Lee's invention consisted of three new technologies that remain in place today: HTML, URL, and HTTP. These technologies allowed for a user-friendly communication among computers, which made the Internet accessible to the general public.</p><p>shows the frequency with which a search term appears in published books through time. To measure radicalness and the potential for network effects, we use ratings obtained from participants in a Mechanical Turk (MTurk) study. While these ratings are provided post hoc (and could be affected by memory bias), they provide a consistent measure across our diverse sample of innovations. We describe below the MTurk and Google Ngram measures and the two data sources used to obtain them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.1.">MTurk Study.</head><p>We asked 100 participants in an MTurk study to rate the 51 innovations included in our sample on several dimensions relevant to our research. We requested that the participants be U.S. based, have a Human Intelligence Task (HIT) approval rate of 95% or higher, and have "masters" qualifications in MTurk. Participants were each paid $5 and took an average of 52 minutes to complete the survey.</p><p>At the beginning of the survey, we provided specific definitions for our characteristics of interest, along with examples of innovations that were not part of the list to be evaluated. We provided the most commonly referenced definitions of radical innovation, direct and indirect network effects, and disruptive innovation. We present these definitions in Web Appendix C. Disruptive innovations are initially inferior to existing products. However, through time, they improve and become the dominant players in the market <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Sood and Tellis 2011)</ref>. The "disruptive" dimension has not been studied previously in relation to stock prices, and is not part of our theoretical framework that links innovation with bubbles. We include this dimension in the MTurk survey to control for the possibility that any new product that is fundamentally different from the status quo might be associated with a bubble, not just radical innovations. Disruptive innovations, when introduced, do not provide higher consumer benefits than existing alternatives (unlike radical innovations). Therefore, comparing the effects of disruptive and radical innovation in relation to bubbles can yield interesting insights on how investors value products that provide significant increases in consumer benefits.</p><p>After providing the definitions and examples of radical, disruptive, direct network effect, and indirect network effect, we instructed participants to evaluate each innovation in relation to the existing technology at the time of its commercialization. For instance, we told participants that when they evaluate the color TV on the radical dimension, they should do so in relation to the black and white TV that was the standard when the color TV was commercialized. To facilitate this task, we listed innovations in the order of commercialization. For each characteristic, we presented respondents with our list of innovations and asked them to rate their agreement on a one-to-five scale (where 1 is "strongly disagree" and 5 is "strongly agree") that each innovation has that particular characteristic. We also allowed respondents to choose the following option: "I am not able to make an assessment." The survey included four reading checks. Only respondents who correctly completed all reading checks were able to finish the survey and obtain payment.</p><p>We use the average ratings across the 100 participants to measure the characteristics of the 51 innovations in our sample. The sample average of these average ratings is as follows: 4.10 for the radical dimension, 3.51 for disruptive, 3.44 for indirect network effects, and 3.25 for direct network effects. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> We acknowledge that these post hoc ratings might not fully capture the consumer perceptions of these products at the time when they were introduced. However, we hope that this preliminary effort, which allows us to present some cross-sectional evidence on the association between innovation characteristics and stock market bubbles, will stimulate additional research on the valuation of distinct types of innovations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2.">Google Ngram Data.</head><p>Given the span and scope of our sample, data on a single measure of diffusionsuch as product-level sales-would be very difficult to obtain. Instead, to gain preliminary insight into the adoption of each innovation, we measure its contemporaneous visibility in the public domain using the annual frequency with which the innovation is mentioned in printed books. The numerator of this frequency measure is the number of times that a given word appears in print in all books digitized by Google in a given year. The denominator includes the total number of words in all books during the same year. For example, the Ngram value for the word "radio" in 1929 is 1.92 × 10 −5 . Thus, the word "radio" represents one in every 52,035 words across all books published that year.</p><p>We use Google Ngram data to compute three measures of visibility of relevance to our study. 10 First, to test the intrinsic bubble model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Froot and Obstfeld (1991)</ref>, we use Ngram frequencies measured during the year when the bubble is detected as a proxy for contemporaneous cash flows. Second, to measure the magnitude of postbubble visibility, we use the maximum value of Ngram frequencies achieved during the lifetime of the innovation, regardless of date, which is a proxy for the market saturation point. Third, the rate of increase in visibility is measured as the distance in time between the commercialization date and the inflection point in the time plot of Ngram frequencies. The inflection point, a proxy for takeoff, is the year with the largest positive change in the Ngram frequencies. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> To evaluate the extent to which visibility is an appropriate proxy for diffusion, we collect product adoption data for a subsample of 25 innovations. Adoption data for 24 of these innovations are obtained from the Statistical Abstract of the United States, published annually by the Bureau of the Census. In addition, we obtain adoption data for the Internet from the World Bank, which publishes annual measures of Internet usage per 100 inhabitants. We then compare the adoption data with the visibility data previously obtained from Google Ngram. The results are presented in Web Appendix D and in Table WA-D1. Panel A of Table <ref type="table">WA</ref>-D1 shows our data sources and the particular measure of product adoption obtained for each of these 25 innovations. Panel B of Table WA-D1 compares the takeoff dates computed from visibility data with the takeoff dates computed from product adoption data. The two measures correlate very highly. Overall, the results presented in Web Appendix D suggest that the visibility measure computed from Google Ngram data is a good proxy for product adoption.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.">Detecting Stock Market Bubbles</head><p>We use the statistical method developed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">West (1987)</ref> to detect the presence of bubbles in the time series of stock prices. For each innovation, we form a single test portfolio containing all firms shown in the rightmost column of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">2</ref>. For each test portfolio, we compute a monthly value-weighted price index and, separately, a monthly value-weighted dividend index, using as weights the market capitalization of each stock at the end of the previous month. The Cowles data set already comes in the form of value-weighted test portfolios. In the end, this process produces 102 different time series, two series (dividends and prices) for each of the 51 innovations.</p><p>We perform a bubble test for each innovation using the price and dividend time series of its respective test portfolio. We require a minimum of 24 months to estimate the parameters of the model. After a bubble is detected, we continue the process until the model indicates that a bubble is no longer present. Our empirical specification is motivated by the model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">West (1987)</ref>, which begins with the no-arbitrage condition that the current-period stock price is equal to the discounted value of the next-period stock price and dividends</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">P t ρ t E t [P t+1 +d t+1 ] + t ,<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where E t is the expectation operator, ρ t 1/(1 + k t ), and k t is the discount rate for the stock at time t. <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">West's (1987)</ref> model further assumes that the aggregate dividend of each test portfolio follows a zero-mean, AR(1) process d t ϕ t d t−1 + ν t .</p><p>(2)</p><p>From Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">1</ref>) and (2), we obtain F * t , the fundamental value of the stock</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">F * t δ t d t ,<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">δ t ρ t ϕ t 1 − ρ t ϕ t .<label>(4)</label></formula><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 507-529, © 2018</ref> If no bubble is present, the price of the stock, P t , equals its fundamental value, F * t . Thus, P t δ t d t .</p><p>(5)</p><p>According to Equation ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>), in the absence of bubbles, the observed stock price, P t , should equal to a multiple δ t of the current dividend d t , where δ t depends, as shown in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_2">4</ref>), only on the fundamental parameters that govern the stock's law of motion: ρ t and ϕ t . <ref type="bibr">12</ref> However, if bubbles are present, the observed stock price P t could be significantly higher. The bubble test consists of comparing δ t estimated in Equation ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>) with its intrinsic value estimated in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_2">4</ref>). If δ t exceeds this intrinsic value, the stock price P t is higher than the present value of its future dividends, implying that a bubble is present.</p><p>Empirically, the bubble test examines whetherδ t [ρ tφt /(1 −ρ tφt )]. This test requires that we computê δ t ,ρ t , andφ t , the empirical estimates of parameters δ t , ρ t , and ϕ t , and that we do so for all values of t. We estimateρ t from Equation (1),φ t from Equation (2), andδ t from Equation (4). The empirical specification for each of these equations includes an intercept and an error term.</p><p>We define H t , a test statistic for detecting bubbles, as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">H t δ t − ρ tφt /(1−ρ tφt ) σ t ,<label>(6)</label></formula><p>whereσ t , the standard error of the H t statistic, is computed using the heteroskedasticity-adjusted method of <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Newey and West (1987)</ref>. This test statistic follows a chisquare distribution with two degrees of freedom <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(West 1987)</ref>. We estimate H t each month, t, for each innovation, beginning with the 25th month in the time series of returns and dividends.</p><p>Detecting the Beginning and End of the Bubble. A bubble is deemed to form in month t if the H t statistic is significantly positive at the 10% level (two-tail test) during months t, t + 1, and t + 2. The bubble is deemed to continue beyond month t + 2 so long as the H t statistic remains significantly positive. Once a bubble is detected, we allow up to two consecutive months of insignificant H statistics before concluding that the bubble has ended. The bubble is deemed to end when the H statistic is no longer significantly positive and remains so for at least two months.</p><p>Measuring the Magnitude of a Bubble. We define mispricing as the difference between the observed price of the test portfolio and the fundamental value predicted by Equation (3). For each innovation, we compute mispricing for each month, t, during the bubble's existence. The peak of the bubble is deemed to occur when mispricing is highest. We measure the magnitude of the bubble as the ratio of mispricing to the fundamental value of the test portfolio, computed at the peak of the bubble. Its statistical significance is the p-value of the contemporaneous H t statistic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Results</head><p>We begin by performing a bubble test for each of the 51 innovations in our sample. The results are presented in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref>. Our method identifies bubbles in approximately 73% of the innovations studied (37 out of 51 innovations). The results corroborate the presence of bubbles in a number of cases that had been conjectured in books and in the popular press. For example, we identify bubbles in the rail, telegraph, automobile, radio, airplane, and Internet industries. We also identify bubbles in innovations that had not been mentioned previously in the literature, such as the personal computer or the microwave oven. Finally, we find no evidence of bubbles in the remaining 14 innovations, which include the color TV and the electronic watch.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Economic Value Added</head><p>To measure the economic value added of each innovation, we compute the buy-and-hold abnormal returns (BHARs) of each innovation's test portfolio from the beginning to the end of the bubble. BHARs are obtained by subtracting the buy-and-hold returns of the stock market from the buy-and-hold returns of the test portfolio. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> We compute this measure for each innovation. The statistical significance is obtained from the monthly time series variation using a t-test of paired differences. The results are presented in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">4</ref>. The first column in Table 4 lists all 37 innovations for which we have previously identified bubbles, and the second column provides the year of commercialization. The third column in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">4</ref> shows the buy-and-hold returns of parent firms from the beginning to the end of the bubble. The fourth column shows the buy-and-hold returns of the market during that same period. The fifth column shows the BHARs, computed as the difference between the previous two columns. The last column shows the p-value for all positive values of BHAR.</p><p>Despite the presence of bubbles, we find evidence of positive economic value added for innovations in our sample. On average, firms in our test portfolios did well during the bubbles, both in absolute terms and by comparison to the market. A hypothetical investor who purchased a typical test portfolio immediately prior to the start of the bubble and remained invested throughout the bubble would have earned, at the end of the bubble, an average return of 65.01%, compared to an average market return of only 20.42%. The average difference of 44.58% is statistically larger than zero (p 0.0054). In approximately 76% of the cases studied (28 out of 37), the test portfolio was worth more (in market-adjusted terms) at the end of the bubble than it was at the beginning. This fraction is statistically different from 1 2 (p 0.0233).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Do Bubbles Lead or Lag Visibility</head><p>We compare the start date of each innovation bubble with the takeoff in visibility (computed as the inflection Notes. The table shows the extent to which firms associated with each innovation experience stock price bubbles. Each bubble is identified using <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">West's (1987)</ref> model, described in this paper. When the model detects a bubble, we show the start, peak, and end dates (year/month) of each bubble. The bubble peak date is the month with the largest difference between the observed price index of the test portfolio and its predicted price index from the model. At each peak date, we show the bubble magnitude as the percentage difference between observed prices and predicted values, and the corresponding p-value of the H-statistic from the bubble test.</p><p>a Because the electric blanket and the electric dishwasher were introduced in the same year <ref type="bibr">(1930)</ref>, and because the test portfolios for both products consist of the same firm (General Electric), we are only able to perform a joint bubble test for these two innovations. The bubble detected here could be attributed to either one of the two innovations or to both. We chose to attribute the bubble in the analysis to both innovations, but the results remain substantively the same if we attribute it to either one of the two innovations.</p><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 507-529, © 2018</ref>  Notes. For each innovation where a bubble has been detected, the table shows the buy-and-hold returns realized by firms associated with the innovation, the buy-and-hold returns of the stock market during the same period, and the buy-and-hold abnormal returns (BHARs), consisting of the difference between the previous two variables. These abnormal returns provide a measure of the economic value added by the innovation during the bubble period. The last column provides the p-value of a test that each BHAR is significantly higher than zero (for positive BHARs). The last row in the table shows the sample mean of all variables, as well as the p-value of a test that the sample mean BHAR is equal to zero.</p><p>point in the Google Ngram data). On average, bubbles lead the takeoff in visibility, which is what we would expect if market investors are forward looking.</p><p>Of the 37 innovation bubbles in our sample, 28 start no later than the takeoff in visibility. For a formal statistical test, we calculate the difference (in years) between the year when the bubble starts and the year when the visibility takes off. We then average this difference across the 37 innovation bubbles in our sample. On average, bubbles lead visibility by approximately 4.5 years, and this difference is statistically different from zero (t 2.90).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.">Determinants of Bubbles</head><p>We now turn to examining the determinants of bubbles. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">5</ref> presents the results. The dependent variable in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">5</ref> is the magnitude of the bubble for innovations where bubbles were detected. For the remaining innovations, the dependent variable is set to zero. We use a Tobit model to account for the fact that the magnitude of the bubble is left-censored to zero. The first four independent variables in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">5</ref> are the characteristics of innovations previously mentioned: radical, disruptive, indirect network effects, and direct network effects. These variables represent the Notes. The table shows the results of six models that relate the magnitude of the innovation bubble (Bubble_Mag) to two different categories of independent variables. The first category evaluates the extent to which the innovation (i) is Radical, (ii) is Disruptive, (iii) has Direct Network Effects, and (iv) has Indirect Network Effects. This evaluation is performed through an MTurk survey of 100 qualified respondents. The second category is the extent to which the innovation has been featured in books-as captured by Google Ngram frequencies-(i) up to the time when a bubble is detected (Ngram_Start) and (ii) up to the year of the peak of the bubble (Ngram_Peak). When no bubbles are detected, we compute estimated start and peak dates for the bubble based on the year of product commercialization. In such cases, Ngram_Start and Ngram_Peak are computed using Ngram frequencies based on the estimated (rather than actual) start and peak years of the bubble. Models 1 and 3-6 are estimated using the entire sample of 51 innovations. Model 2 is confined to the sample of radical innovations included in <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Chandy and Tellis (2000)</ref>. The dependent variable is the Bubble_Mag when a bubble is detected. When a bubble is not detected, Bubble_Mag is set to zero. All models are estimated using a Tobit specification, which accounts for the magnitude of the bubble being censored at zero. The t-statistics are shown in italics under each coefficient. * , * * , and * * * denote coefficients that are statistically significant at the 10%, 5%, and 1% levels, respectively.</p><p>average ratings provided by MTurk respondents on each characteristic. The remaining independent variables are two alternative proxies for the contemporaneous visibility of the innovation. They are obtained using the Ngram frequencies at the start of the bubble, and, alternatively, using the Ngram frequencies at the peak of the bubble.</p><p>In Model 1 we show that the magnitude of the bubble is positively related to the radical innovation measure (β 82.92, p &lt; 0.05) and negatively related to the disruptive innovation measure (β −86.92, p &lt; 0.05). The negative effect of the disruptive characteristic suggests that it is difficult for investors to forecast whether a new technology that is initially inferior to existing alternatives might one day improve and surpass these alternatives in performance. In regard to network effects, we find a significant positive association between the magnitude of the bubble and the presence of indirect network effects (β 55.33, p &lt; 0.10). However, the relation with direct network effects is insignificant. This could be due in part to the high correlation between indirect and direct network effects, but it is also possible that indirect network effects might be more closely aligned with the concept of exploding expectations mentioned in Section 2. Investor enthusiasm will be heightened if an innovation not only has the potential to generate significant growth in its own industry, but could also gain additional functionality through complementary products that would enhance its consumer benefits. Accurately determining all categories in which complementary products may be introduced, as well as the demand for these complementary products, could be even more difficult than assessing the primary demand for the focal innovation; optimism toward the innovation's potential could be compounded by optimism about complementary products. In Model 2 we show that these results also hold for the subset of radical innovations listed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Chandy and Tellis (2000)</ref>, which constitute a more conservative subsample for our study.</p><p>The Ngram visibility variables are introduced in Models 3 through 6. As conjectured previously, we find a significantly positive relation between the bubble magnitude and the visibility of the innovation measured at the beginning of the bubble (β 3.70, p &lt; 0.05 in Model 3 and β 4.14, p &lt; 0.05 in Model 5) and at the peak of the bubble (β 3.93, p &lt; 0.05 in Model 4 and β 4.37, p &lt; 0.05 in Model 6). These results are consistent with the intrinsic bubble theory of <ref type="bibr">Froot and Obstfeld (1991). 14</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4.">Capital Raised and Postbubble</head><p>Visibility of Innovations In our next set of tests, we measure the amount of new equity capital raised during the bubble period and Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 507-529, © 2018</ref>  Notes. The table shows an analysis of net capital raised and postbubble visibility for the 38 innovations in our sample that were commercialized in 1919 and later, beginning with the radio and the airplane. CapRaised is the percentage of capital raised during the bubble period divided by the market value of equity before the bubble. DCapRaised is the difference between CapRaised and the percentage capital raised by the entire stock market during that same period. DCapRaised2 is the same as DCapRaised except that it is measured beginning with the commercialization date through the end of the bubble. All three values are winsorized at the 99th percentile to mitigate the effect of outliers. The postbubble visibility is measured with Ngram_Inflex (the difference, in years, between the commercialization date and the date when the Ngram time series reaches its inflection point) and with Ngram_Max (the maximum value of the Google Ngram frequency during the lifetime of an innovation). Bubble_Mag is the magnitude of the innovation bubble; when a bubble is not detected, Bubble_Mag is set to zero. Panel A shows univariate descriptive statistics, and panel B presents cross-sectional regressions. Standard errors in Models 9 through 18 are corrected for heteroskedasticity using <ref type="bibr">White's method (1980)</ref>. The t-statistics are shown in italics in panel B. * , * * , and * * * denote statistical significance at the 10%, 5%, and 1% levels, respectively (two-tailed test); ∆ denotes a coefficient that is marginally insignificant (p 0.1064).</p><p>examine how this new capital relates to the postbubble visibility of innovations. The results are presented in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">6</ref>.</p><p>Panel A of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">6</ref> provides univariate statistics for the dependent variables. The first two variables in panel A are measures of market-adjusted equity raised by parent firms around the bubble period. The first of these variables, DCapRaised, measures equity raised during the bubble period only. The second variable, DCapRaised , measures the equity raised between the commercialization date and the end of the bubble. Both variables are computed as the amount of new equity raised by parent firms divided by the market value of equity of these parent firms at the beginning of the bubble, minus the equivalent ratio of equity capital raised by the broader stock market during the same period. <ref type="bibr">15</ref> On average, firms in our sample are able to raise new equity capital during the bubble corresponding to 18.57% of these firms' market value of equity at the beginning of the bubble. The result is borderline insignificant (p 0.1064), perhaps because of the low power of the small sample size (N 38). Better statistical significance is achieved when the new equity raised is measured over a longer period-from the commercialization date until the end of the bubble. In this case, the average equity capital raised is 27.95% (p 0.0602). <ref type="bibr">16</ref> Turning now to the postbubble visibility of the innovation, the third variable in panel A, Ngram_Max, shows the difference between the average of the highest value of Ngram frequencies achieved by innovations with bubbles and the same average achieved by innovations without bubbles. As conjectured, this difference is positive and statistically significant (p 0.0256), suggesting that innovations with bubbles become significantly more visible during the postbubble period.</p><p>The fourth variable in panel A, Ngram_Inflex, measures the length of time between commercialization and the Ngram inflection point computed for innovations with bubbles, minus that for innovations without bubbles. As conjectured, innovations with bubbles have a higher rate of increase in postbubble visibility: the Ngram inflection point is achieved 4.59 years earlier, on average, when compared to innovations without bubbles. This result, however, is not statistically different from zero, perhaps because of the low power of the test. Another possibility is that the capital raised during the bubble may be the factor that leads to a faster takeoff rather than the magnitude of the bubble itself. We examine this possibility in our cross-sectional analysis.</p><p>The results of the cross-sectional analysis are shown in panel B of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">6</ref>. The first two models in panel B examine the relation between new equity capital raised during the bubble (the dependent variable) and the magnitude of the bubble. In Model 7, the dependent variable is the actual amount of equity capital raised (as a fraction of prebubble capital) without any market adjustment. In Model 8, the capital raised is market adjusted. The independent variable in both models is the magnitude of the bubble. As discussed previously, the magnitude of the bubble could be inversely proportional to the cost of equity during the bubble. The results in Models 7 and 8 show that, on average, firms raise more equity capital when the magnitude of the bubble is higher (β 0.00523, p &lt; 0.05 in Model 7 and β 0.00575, p &lt; 0.01 in Model 8), perhaps taking advantage of temporarily lower funding costs.</p><p>In Models 9 through 13 of panel B, the dependent variable is the maximum level of visibility achieved by each innovation subsequent to the bubble (measured using Ngram frequencies). In Models 14 through 18, the dependent variable is the time distance between commercialization and the inflection point of the Ngram time series. This time distance is the inverse of the rate of increase in postbubble visibility. The independent variables in Models 9 through 18 are the magnitude of the bubble and the two measures of equity capital that had been previously used as dependent variables (in Models 7 and 8).</p><p>The results from Models 9 through 13 show that the maximum postbubble visibility is positively related to the new capital raised during the bubble (β 1.5275, p &lt; 0.01 in Model 9 and β 1.4806, p &lt; 0.01 in Model 10) and to the magnitude of the bubble (β 0.0224, p &lt; 0.05 in Model 11). When both independent variables are included (Models 12 and 13), the coefficients remain statistically significant.</p><p>The results from Models 14 through 18 show that the time lag between commercialization and the Ngram inflection point is negatively related to the amount of new capital raised during the bubble, but not to the magnitude of the bubble. The coefficient of the new capital raised is β −4.1631, p &lt; 0.05, in Model 14; β −3.9418, p &lt; 0.05, in Model 15; β −3.5719, p &lt; 0.05, in Model 17; and β −3.2794, p &lt; 0.05, in Model 18. This suggests that the effect of the bubble magnitude on the rate of increase in visibility is channeled through the new capital raised during the bubble, rather than through the bubble itself.</p><p>Overall, the results in panel B of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">6</ref> suggest that parent firms faced with larger stock market bubbles raise more capital, on average. In turn, this capital is positively related to the maximum visibility achieved by each innovation (postbubble) and to the rate of increase in this visibility.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.5.">Macroeconomic Factors Impacting Bubbles</head><p>A common hypothesis in the popular press is that bubbles are fueled by the availability of cheap credit <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Kindleberger and</ref><ref type="bibr">Aliber 2005, Wood 2006</ref>) and by the collective frenzy afflicting investors during good economic times <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Perez 2002)</ref>. We find no support for this hypothesis. We use two different approaches to determine whether macroeconomic conditions explain the occurrence of innovation bubbles. First, we estimate a negative binomial model in which the dependent variable is the number of innovation bubbles encountered each year during the period from 1800 to 2010. 17 Independent variables include the level of interest rates that year, the growth rate in gross domestic product (GDP) over the previous year, the ratio of national debt to GDP, and the ratio of the monetary base to GDP. None of these independent variables are statistically significant (the results are available from the authors on request).</p><p>Second, we evaluate the possibility that innovation bubbles in our sample might be caused by contemporaneous marketwide bubbles. To do so, we use <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">West's (1987)</ref> model to determine whether marketwide bubbles occur during the same time periods as the innovation bubbles detected in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref>. The results are presented in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">7</ref>. We detect simultaneous stock market bubbles in 50% of the innovations studied (18 out of 36). <ref type="bibr">18</ref> This fraction is significantly different from unity (p &lt; 0.0001). Moreover, in 83% of the cases (15 out of 18), the magnitude of the marketwide bubble is smaller than the magnitude of the innovation bubble. This fraction is significantly different from 1 2 (p 0.0365).</p><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 507-529, © 2018</ref>   <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">West's (1987)</ref> bubble test applied to the entire stock market at the time of the innovation bubble. When a marketwide bubble is detected, the table provides the magnitude of the market bubble (in percentage points). We are unable to conduct a market bubble test for the telegraph because of the absence of market dividend data during that period. The last column of the table shows the difference between the magnitude of the innovation bubble and the magnitude of the marketwide bubble. When no marketwide bubble is detected, the magnitude of the marketwide bubble is assumed to be zero for the purpose of computing this difference. The last row in the table shows the sample mean of the following bubble magnitudes: (i) all innovation bubbles, (ii) all market bubbles (including the values of zero previously mentioned), and (iii) the difference between the innovation bubble and the market bubble.</p><p>In addition, the difference in magnitude between marketwide bubbles and innovation bubbles is significantly negative (p 0.0699). Finally, innovation bubbles tend to lead market bubbles, on average. Of the 18 market bubble cases, the innovation bubble leads the market bubble in 10 cases and lags the market bubble in 4 cases. In the remaining four cases, the innovation bubble begins at the same time as the market bubble. These results suggest that innovations are the ones spurring bubbles in the overall market, not the other way around. <ref type="bibr">19</ref> In short, we find no evidence that innovation bubbles are driven by low interest rates, by expansion in the monetary base, by high GDP growth, or by bubbles in the broader stock market. While it is entirely possible that other types of bubbles could be ignited by such macroeconomic conditions, innovation bubbles appear to be ignited by the innovation per se. This conclusion is consistent with the findings of <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Frehen et al. (2013)</ref>, who show that the Dutch wind trade and South Sea Bubbles of 1720 were driven by innovation. The conclusion is also corroborated by the fact that we are detecting two innovation bubbles during the Great Depression of the 1930s, a period known for tight monetary policy and low economic growth.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Discussion and Conclusion</head><p>We explore a new facet of the interaction between the stock market and the consumer product market-the association between innovation and stock market bubbles. We examine 51 major innovations that were commercialized during the 19th and 20th centuries. In 37 of these 51 cases, we detect the presence of bubbles in the stock price of parent firms. We show that these bubbles are more likely to occur for innovations that are radical and that have the potential to generate indirect network effects. Moreover, the magnitude of these bubbles is proportional to the visibility of the underlying innovation at the time of the bubble, as measured by the contemporaneous frequency with which the innovation appears in books, obtained from Google Ngram. Parent firms that experience bubbles are shown to raise additional equity capital during the bubble period. In turn, this new equity capital is positively related to the magnitude and to the rate of increase in the visibility of the innovation after the bubble. Below we summarize our paper's contribution to theory, practice, and policy making; discuss the limitations of our research; and provide a set of implications and directions for future research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.">Contributions to Theory, Practice, and</head><p>Policy Making To our knowledge, our study presents the most comprehensive evidence of a systematic association between innovations and bubbles. The popular press has long conjectured that technological revolutions and bubbles seem to go hand in hand, often attributing the cause of these bubbles to investor irrationality. However, there is insufficient academic evidence to support this conjecture. While a few studies in financial economics evaluate the presence of bubbles around innovations, these studies tend to focus on one or two industries and generally treat innovation as an undifferentiated output of the aggregate production function. Moreover, most studies do not provide formal statistical tests for bubbles, and there is still a significant degree of disagreement among authors about the causes and economic consequences of bubbles.</p><p>On the other hand, marketing studies do a better job at recognizing heterogeneity among various types of innovation and their impact on shareholder value (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Pauwels et al. 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">, Sood and Tellis 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">, Sorescu and Spanjol 2008</ref>. However, the marketing literature does not explore the association between innovation, bubbles, and capital raised, or, more generally, the manner in which the new product market interacts with the stock market. Our paper seeks to bridge the gap between the innovation literatures in marketing and in financial economics by illustrating one way in which the marketing and finance functions come together to create and support economically significant innovation.</p><p>The financial consequences we document in this paper are noteworthy additions to the marketing literature and provide managers with actionable guidelines when major innovations appear on their radar screens. While these innovations are expected to be associated with stock price bubbles, they are also expected to add significant value to the parent firm after bubbles deflate. Thus, investing in the commercialization of innovations appears to be worthwhile, especially since bubbles seem to create a favorable environment for firms to raise cheap equity capital without sending negative signals to the market.</p><p>Our results challenge some of the views expressed in the popular press about the association of innovations with bubbles. We show that innovation bubbles are not confined to "technological revolutions." Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref> shows a number of bubbles surrounding radical innovations (such as the microwave oven) in time periods that are not normally associated with technological revolutions. Moreover, we find no evidence that bubbles are fueled by strong GDP growth or by loose monetary policy. For example, we document two bubbles during the 1930s, a period of declining GDP and tight monetary policy. In short, innovation bubbles appear to be intrinsic to the innovation per se, and seem to be unrelated to aggregate macroeconomic conditions.</p><p>While more research is needed to fully understand the relation between bubbles, issuance of new equity capital, and the diffusion of innovations, the evidence presented in this paper suggests that bubbles could actually foster economic growth by facilitating the development of new infrastructure. This finding is consistent with the predictions of <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Olivier (2000)</ref>. In spite of bubbles, innovating firms have higher stock market gains at the end of a bubble compared to the gains realized by the stock market as a whole during the same period. The negative consequences of bubbles are most likely confined to new investors who buy overvalued stocks close to the height of the bubble. These findings suggest that economic policies designed to suppress bubbles might be misguided. These implications are limited to bubbles that are spurred by important technological breakthroughs and cannot be extended to other types of bubbles, such as bubbles on intrinsically useless assets (e.g., tulip bulbs), bubbles caused by fraud (e.g., Enron), or bubbles possibly fueled by loose monetary policy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.">Limitations</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.1.">A Caveat on the Econometric Measurement of</head><p>Bubbles. All econometric models that attempt to detect <ref type="bibr">Marketing Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 507-529, © 2018</ref> the presence of bubbles (including West 1987) are testing a joint null hypothesis that (i) no bubble is present and (ii) the correct dividend expectation model is used.</p><p>Rejecting the null hypothesis implies either that a bubble is present or that we are using the wrong dividend expectations model. While this problem does not have an econometric resolution, we offer a conceptual argument in favor of the bubble interpretation: the alternative interpretation-the wrong dividend model-carries the embedded assumption that the 37 innovations for which we detect bubbles could have generated even higher cash flows, but did not do so because of bad luck; that is, from an ex ante perspective, these innovations must have offered a nonzero probability of a subsequent increase in earnings at a rate significantly higher than what was actually observed in reality. Yet, by bad luck, this possibility never materialized. By contrast, the bubble explanation does not require this type of assumption and appears, at least to us, to be more credible. We acknowledge, however, that despite the weight of the evidence presented, one can never be certain that the price patterns shown in this paper are true bubbles as opposed to bubble-free valuations in anticipation of extraordinary events that never materialized.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.2.">Discussion of Causality.</head><p>We do not claim that we can unequivocally establish a causal relation between innovation and bubbles. We mainly aim to provide formal statistical tests that document stock market bubbles across the largest set of innovations identified to date. It is difficult to establish a causal relation between innovation and bubbles because the nature of our data-rare historical events-is not conducive to a formal statistical test of causality. Thus, we cannot exclude the alternative interpretation that bubbles and innovations might be jointly caused by a third, unknown factor, such as periodic changes in social norms that could foster both creativity in the product market and optimism in the stock market.</p><p>We note, however, that our paper's managerial implications do not change under this alternative hypothesis. To the extent that firms can take advantage of bubbles to raise equity capital on favorable terms, and to the extent that this new capital can facilitate the diffusion of the innovation, it does not matter whether bubbles are caused by innovation or whether both are jointly caused by a third factor, so long as both phenomena occur simultaneously. In both cases, our recommendations to policy makers and managers remain the same.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.3.">Data Limitations.</head><p>Despite the significant effort invested into assembling our data, the sample is not without limitations. First, our sampling scheme consists of a set of commercially successful innovations. Over the time span of our sample, there could have been other new products introduced that had the potential to be radical and generate network effects but eventually failed in the marketplace. However, we note that this type of selection bias is a limitation that is common in the radical innovation and diffusion literatures, whereby most authors take a post hoc view in assembling the sample. Second, we were not able to control for the sales of each innovation as a percentage of the parent firm sales. We used archival data to qualitatively determine the extent to which each innovation was an important part of the firm's product portfolio at the time of commercialization. We endeavored to limit our test portfolios, as much as possible, to pure-play firms. However, we recognize that, despite our best efforts, there will be some variation in our sample in terms of the importance that the focal innovation plays in the product portfolio of its parent firm. This variation leads to an error in measurement problem that attenuates the coefficients in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">6</ref> toward zero. Thus, the results presented in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">6</ref> should be viewed as conservative.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3.">Directions for Future Research</head><p>Our paper suggests five promising avenues for future research. First, our results imply that publicly traded firms might have a resource advantage when it comes to commercializing innovation because of the ease of access to new equity capital, particularly during bubble periods. If so, are privately held corporations at a disadvantage? Does the pattern of venture capital investment in private firms follow the patterns observed in the public equity markets?</p><p>Second, while we provide first-order evidence of the association between bubbles, external financing, and innovation, additional studies are needed to understand specifically how this new capital is actually deployed and how it affects the diffusion of the new product.</p><p>Third, the theory on intrinsic bubbles suggests that marketing metrics may play a critical role in determining the market value of firms in new industries. An important implication of this theory is that in the absence of accurate forecasts about long-term cash flows, investors are likely to anchor their valuation on observable short-term metrics of performance, and valuations are likely to exceed intrinsic values for a period of time. These short-term metrics most likely come from the product market, as opposed to the financial market, because information from the product market is typically the first to become available to investors. This is evidenced by examples in the dot.com era, where valuations were multiples of website traffic, or from more recent examples in the social media domain, where valuations are multiples of the number of users. Therefore, marketing metrics could play a critical role in determining the market value of companies in new industries. While our findings are certainly consistent with this interpretation, additional research is needed to provide a more direct link between marketing metrics and the valuation of companies that pursue a significant innovation strategy.</p><p>Fourth, the extent to which firms can appropriate gains from innovations associated with bubbles requires additional study. While we show in our paper that these innovations have a positive economic value added, we have not controlled for variations that may arise from firms' differential ability to protect their innovations through patents. Should a firm be able, through a strong patenting effort, to prevent competitors from commercializing the same technology, the firm might obtain monopolistic profits, but might also miss out on the network effects that arise when competitors leverage the same technology. These trade-offs are a fruitful area of future research.</p><p>Fifth, the social benefits of cheap equity financing provided by innovation bubbles must be evaluated against their social costs. The magnitude of these social costs depends, in part, on how these bubbles affect the aggregate disparity of wealth in the society. <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Shiller (2015)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Perez (2002)</ref> both hypothesize that bubbles have contributed to a significant increase in the disparity of wealth observed during the past 100 years, and Piketty (2013) presents evidence consistent with this prediction. If true, there is perhaps a significant hidden social cost of innovation bubbles, as no stable society appears to have survived over the long term when the levels of wealth became extremely concentrated. <ref type="bibr">20</ref> Future research is needed to understand the relation between innovation bubbles and wealth inequality.</p><p>We hope that our research provides an impetus for others to further study the effects of innovation at the macro level, including their relation to the stock market, to economic growth, and to economic policy. At the micro level, we hope that our research can help managers better navigate through the perils of major shifts in technological paradigms and even learn how to profit from periods of temporary overvaluation that might provide windows of opportunity to obtain external financing on favorable terms.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Sorescu et al.: Two Centuries of Innovations and Stock Market Bubbles</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>MarketingScience, 2018, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 507-529, © 2018 </figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Sources of Stock and Dividend Data Data source Description CRSP data set Monthly, stock-level data are available from the Center for Research in Security Prices at the University of Chicago from December 1925 to the present. Stock-level data are used to construct a</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Firms Included in the Bubble Analysis of Each Innovation</figDesc><table><row><cell>Innovation</cell><cell>Comm. year</cell><cell>Firms (and initial year) included in index</cell></row><row><cell>Steam engine train</cell><cell>1825</cell><cell>Campbell (2000) Railway Index</cell></row><row><cell>Telegraph</cell><cell>1845</cell><cell>Western Union (1865)</cell></row><row><cell>Incandescent vacuum lamp</cell><cell>1880</cell><cell>Cowles Electrical Equipment Index components: Edison General Electric/General Electric</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(1890)</cell></row><row><cell>Automobile</cell><cell>1886</cell><cell>Cowles Automobiles and Trucks Index components: General Motors (1912), Chrysler (1914),</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Studebaker (1912), Willys-Overland (1915), Chandler Motor Car (1916), Saxon Motor Car</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(1916), Stutz Motor Car (1916), White Motor (1916), Pierce-Arrow Motor Car (1917), Fisher</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Body (1918), Hupp Motor (1918), Mack Trucks (1920), Packard Motor Car (1920)</cell></row><row><cell>Portable camera</cell><cell>1888</cell><cell>Eastman Kodak (1904)</cell></row><row><cell>Disk phonograph</cell><cell>1894</cell><cell>Gramophone company (1904)</cell></row><row><cell>Motion pictures</cell><cell>1898</cell><cell>Cowles Theater and Motion Picture Index components: Famous Players-Lasky (1919, later</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>renamed to Paramount Publix), Loew's (1920), Radio-Keith-Orpheum (1920)</cell></row><row><cell>Photoelectric scanning fax</cell><cell>1907</cell><cell>Cowles Utilities-Telephone and Telegraph Index Components: American Telephone and</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Telegraph (1907), New York and New Jersey Telephone (1907), Central South America</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Telegraph (1907), Mackay Companies (1907), Pacific Telephone and Telegraph (1909), All</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>America Cables (1918)</cell></row><row><cell>Electric clothes washer</cell><cell>1908</cell><cell>Cowles Electrical Equipment Index components: General Electric (1908), Electric Storage</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Battery Co. (1915), National Conduit and Cable (1917), Westinghouse Electric and</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Manufacturing (1918)</cell></row><row><cell>Electric percolator</cell><cell>1908</cell><cell>Cowles Electrical Equipment Index components: General Electric (1908), Electric Storage</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Battery Co. (1915), National Conduit and Cable (1917), Westinghouse Electric and</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Manufacturing (1918)</cell></row><row><cell>Electric toaster</cell><cell>1908</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(1930)</cell></row><row><cell>Refrigerator</cell><cell>1916</cell><cell>General Electric (1925), Kelvinator (1926)</cell></row><row><cell>Airplane</cell><cell>1919</cell><cell>Bendix Aviation (1925), Curtiss Aeroplane (1927), Wright Aeronautical (1925), Curtiss</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Wright Corporation (1929), National Air Transport (1929), United Aircraft and Transport</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(1929)</cell></row><row><cell>Radio</cell><cell>1919</cell><cell>RCA (1925), AT&amp;T (1925), Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing (1925)</cell></row><row><cell>Electric typewriter</cell><cell>1920</cell><cell>IBM (1928)</cell></row><row><cell>Electric blanket a</cell><cell>1930</cell><cell>General Electric (1928)</cell></row><row><cell>Electric dishwasher a</cell><cell>1930</cell><cell>General Electric (1928)</cell></row><row><cell>Electric shaver</cell><cell>1930</cell><cell>Remington Rand (1928)</cell></row><row><cell>Electric garbage disposer</cell><cell>1935</cell><cell>General Electric (1928)</cell></row><row><cell>TV</cell><cell>1936</cell><cell>Admiral (1945), Crosley (1940), Emerson (1945), Farnsworth Television and Radio (1943),</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>General Electric (1940), Galvin Manufacturing/Motorola (1946), Philco (1940), RCA</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(1940), Westinghouse Electric (1940), Zenith (1940)</cell></row><row><cell>Fluorescent light bulb</cell><cell>1938</cell><cell>General Electric (1936), Westinghouse Electric and Mfg (1936)</cell></row><row><cell>FM radio</cell><cell>1940</cell><cell>RCA (1935), Westinghouse Electric and Mfg (1935), Zenith Radio (1935), Philco (1940),</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Galvin Manufacturing/Motorola (1946)</cell></row><row><cell>Ballpoint pen</cell><cell>1945</cell><cell>Eversharp (1946)</cell></row><row><cell>Magnetic tape player</cell><cell>1947</cell><cell>Minnesota, Mining and Mfg (1946)</cell></row><row><cell>Microwave oven</cell><cell>1947</cell><cell>Raytheon (1958), Litton (1958)</cell></row><row><cell>NTSC color TV</cell><cell>1954</cell><cell>General Electric (1952), Philco (1952), RCA (1952), Raytheon (1952), Hoffman Electronics</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(1955)</cell></row><row><cell>Electric can opener</cell><cell>1956</cell><cell>Westinghouse Electric (1950)</cell></row><row><cell>Videocassette recorder</cell><cell>1956</cell><cell>North American Phillips (1950), RCA (1950), Magnavox (1950), Ampex (1959)</cell></row><row><cell>Electronic watch</cell><cell>1957</cell><cell>Bulova Watch (1955), Hamilton Watch (1955), Elgin National Watch (1955)</cell></row><row><cell>Cassette</cell><cell>1964</cell><cell>North American Phillips (1962), Memorex (1968), Sony (1970), Fuji (1972), Hitachi (1972),</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>TDK Electronics (1975)</cell></row><row><cell>Electronic desktop calculator</cell><cell>1964</cell><cell>Texas Instruments (1959), Hewlett-Packard (1959), Friden (1959), Wang Laboratories (1968)</cell></row><row><cell>Electronic pocket calculator</cell><cell>1968</cell><cell>Texas Instruments (1965), Hewlett-Packard (1965), Canon (1965), Bowmar Instrument</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(1965), Craig (1969), Toshiba (1972)</cell></row><row><cell>Dot-matrix printer</cell><cell>1970</cell><cell>Centronix Data Computer (1972)</cell></row><row><cell>Single-player video game</cell><cell>1972</cell><cell>Magnavox (1969), General Instrument (1969), Centuri (1972), Bally Manufacturing (1972),</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Williams Electronics (1981)</cell></row><row><cell>Digital LED watch</cell><cell>1975</cell><cell>Texas Instruments (1973)</cell></row><row><cell>Disposable shaver</cell><cell>1975</cell><cell>Gillette (1975), Schick (1975), Bic Pen (1975)</cell></row></table><note>Cowles Electrical Equipment Index components: General Electric (1908), Electric Storage Battery Co. (1915), National Conduit and Cable (1917), Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing (1918) Rayon 1910 Cowles index: Industrial Rayon Corp. (1926), Tubize Artificial Silk Co. of America (1926), Snia Viscosa Co. (1926), Celanese Corp. of America (1927), Tubize Chatillon Corp.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>(Continued)    </figDesc><table><row><cell>Innovation</cell><cell>Comm. year</cell><cell>Firms (and initial year) included in index</cell></row><row><cell>Personal computer</cell><cell>1975</cell><cell>Apple (1980), Commodore (1978), IBM (1978), Intel (1978), RadioShack (1978), Lotus</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Development (1983), Ashton Tate (1983), Compaq (1983)</cell></row><row><cell>Laser printer</cell><cell>1976</cell><cell>Hewlett-Packard (1974), IBM (1974), Xerox (1974), Canon (1974)</cell></row><row><cell>Laser disc player</cell><cell>1978</cell><cell>MCA (1976), Pioneer (1976), Sony (1976), Phillips (1976)</cell></row><row><cell>Mobile phone</cell><cell>1979</cell><cell>AT&amp;T (1980), Motorola (1980), Ericsson (1981), Interdigital (1981), SBC (1984), Nokia (1988),</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Qualcomm (1991)</cell></row><row><cell>Camcorder</cell><cell>1983</cell><cell>Hitatchi (1983), JVC (1983), Panasonic (1983), Sony (1983)</cell></row><row><cell>Compact disc player</cell><cell>1983</cell><cell>Panasonic (1981), Philips (1981), Sony (1981), Toshiba (1981)</cell></row><row><cell>Portable computer</cell><cell>1983</cell><cell>IBM (1975), Radioshack (1975), Hewlett-Packard (1975)</cell></row><row><cell>Digital camera</cell><cell>1989</cell><cell>Fuji (1986), Nikon (1986), Casio (1986), Olympus (1986)</cell></row><row><cell>Internet b</cell><cell>1991</cell><cell>List of Internet IPOs included in Loughran and Ritter (2004)</cell></row><row><cell>Minidisc player</cell><cell>1992</cell><cell>Sony (1990)</cell></row><row><cell>Digital video disc player</cell><cell>1997</cell><cell>Sony (1990)</cell></row><row><cell>Digital high-definition TV</cell><cell>1998</cell><cell>Zenith (1990), Sony (1990), Panasonic (1990), Hitatchi (1990), Technicolor (1999)</cell></row><row><cell>GPS receiver</cell><cell>2000</cell><cell>Garmin (2000), Lowrance (2000), Trimble (2000)</cell></row><row><cell>Smartphone</cell><cell>2000</cell><cell>Apple (2002), Ericsson (2002), Handspring (2002), Nokia (2002), Research in Motion (2002),</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Google (2004)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Bubbles Associated with the Stock Prices of Innovating Companies</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Bubble</cell><cell>Bubble</cell><cell>Bubble</cell><cell cols="2">Bubble magnitude</cell><cell>Bubble</cell></row><row><cell>Innovation</cell><cell>Comm. year</cell><cell>detected?</cell><cell>start date</cell><cell>peak date</cell><cell>Value (%)</cell><cell>p-value</cell><cell>end date</cell></row><row><cell>Steam engine train</cell><cell>1825</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>8/1843</cell><cell>3/1844</cell><cell>31.1</cell><cell>0.0001</cell><cell>2/1845</cell></row><row><cell>Telegraph</cell><cell>1845</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>12/1870</cell><cell>2/1873</cell><cell>75.6</cell><cell>0.0123</cell><cell>9/1873</cell></row><row><cell>Incandescent vacuum lamp</cell><cell>1880</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>6/1892</cell><cell>10/1892</cell><cell>16.3</cell><cell>0.0410</cell><cell>4/1893</cell></row><row><cell>Automobile</cell><cell>1886</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>3/1919</cell><cell>11/1919</cell><cell>119.5</cell><cell>0.0166</cell><cell>9/1920</cell></row><row><cell>Portable camera</cell><cell>1888</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>7/1918</cell><cell>4/1921</cell><cell>101.1</cell><cell>0.0753</cell><cell>4/1921</cell></row><row><cell>Disk phonograph</cell><cell>1894</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>7/1906</cell><cell>4/1907</cell><cell>102.6</cell><cell>0.0014</cell><cell>1/1908</cell></row><row><cell>Motion pictures</cell><cell>1898</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>9/1921</cell><cell>9/1922</cell><cell>49.8</cell><cell>0.0002</cell><cell>5/1923</cell></row><row><cell>Photoelectric scanning fax</cell><cell>1907</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Electric clothes washer</cell><cell>1908</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Electric percolator</cell><cell>1908</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Electric toaster</cell><cell>1908</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Rayon</cell><cell>1910</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>2/1928</cell><cell>4/1928</cell><cell>24.4</cell><cell>0.0001</cell><cell>7/1928</cell></row><row><cell>Refrigerator</cell><cell>1916</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>4/1928</cell><cell>8/1929</cell><cell>369.3</cell><cell>0.0009</cell><cell>9/1930</cell></row><row><cell>Airplane</cell><cell>1919</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>1/1928</cell><cell>2/1929</cell><cell>183.9</cell><cell>0.0024</cell><cell>9/1929</cell></row><row><cell>Radio</cell><cell>1919</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>1/1928</cell><cell>8/1929</cell><cell>86.5</cell><cell>0.0252</cell><cell>11/1930</cell></row><row><cell>Electric typewriter</cell><cell>1920</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>4/1933</cell><cell>7/1935</cell><cell>51.8</cell><cell>0.0063</cell><cell>12/1935</cell></row><row><cell>Electric blanket</cell><cell>1930</cell><cell>Yes a</cell><cell>11/1938</cell><cell>11/1938</cell><cell>41.2</cell><cell>0.0972</cell><cell>10/1939</cell></row><row><cell>Electric dishwasher</cell><cell>1930</cell><cell>Yes a</cell><cell>11/1938</cell><cell>11/1938</cell><cell>41.2</cell><cell>0.0972</cell><cell>10/1939</cell></row><row><cell>Electric shaver</cell><cell>1930</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Electric garbage disposer</cell><cell>1935</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>11/1944</cell><cell>5/1945</cell><cell>12.0</cell><cell>0.0931</cell><cell>7/1945</cell></row><row><cell>TV</cell><cell>1936</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>2/1943</cell><cell>1/1946</cell><cell>50.3</cell><cell>0.0012</cell><cell>9/1946</cell></row><row><cell>Fluorescent light bulb</cell><cell>1938</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>FM radio</cell><cell>1940</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>11/1947</cell><cell>5/1948</cell><cell>26.4</cell><cell>0.0871</cell><cell>3/1949</cell></row><row><cell>Ballpoint pen</cell><cell>1945</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>1/1955</cell><cell>3/1956</cell><cell>47.7</cell><cell>0.0001</cell><cell>9/1957</cell></row><row><cell>Magnetic tape player</cell><cell>1947</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>2/1960</cell><cell>6/1960</cell><cell>62.9</cell><cell>0.0001</cell><cell>8/1960</cell></row><row><cell>Microwave oven</cell><cell>1947</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>8/1965</cell><cell>2/1966</cell><cell>59.2</cell><cell>0.0002</cell><cell>4/1966</cell></row><row><cell>NTSC color TV</cell><cell>1954</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Electric can opener</cell><cell>1956</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Videocassette recorder</cell><cell>1956</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>12/1965</cell><cell>4/1966</cell><cell>79.1</cell><cell>0.0065</cell><cell>6/1966</cell></row><row><cell>Electronic watch</cell><cell>1957</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Cassette</cell><cell>1964</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>8/1969</cell><cell>11/1969</cell><cell>72.9</cell><cell>0.0001</cell><cell>3/1970</cell></row><row><cell>Electronic desktop calculator</cell><cell>1964</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>12/1971</cell><cell>10/1973</cell><cell>50.3</cell><cell>0.0001</cell><cell>6/1974</cell></row><row><cell>Electronic pocket calculator</cell><cell>1968</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>12/1971</cell><cell>1/1973</cell><cell>46.9</cell><cell>0.0001</cell><cell>11/1973</cell></row><row><cell>Dot-matrix printer</cell><cell>1970</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Single-player video game</cell><cell>1972</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>3/1979</cell><cell>11/1981</cell><cell>171.2</cell><cell>0.0029</cell><cell>1/1984</cell></row><row><cell>Digital LED watch</cell><cell>1975</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Disposable shaver</cell><cell>1975</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>6/1979</cell><cell>8/1979</cell><cell>20.1</cell><cell>0.0001</cell><cell>8/1979</cell></row><row><cell>Personal computer</cell><cell>1975</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>7/1982</cell><cell>5/1983</cell><cell>86.2</cell><cell>0.0031</cell><cell>8/1983</cell></row><row><cell>Laser printer</cell><cell>1976</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Laser disc player</cell><cell>1978</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>9/1983</cell><cell>12/1989</cell><cell>186.1</cell><cell>0.0454</cell><cell>6/1990</cell></row><row><cell>Mobile phone</cell><cell>1979</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>7/1986</cell><cell>12/1989</cell><cell>101.9</cell><cell>0.0001</cell><cell>8/1991</cell></row><row><cell>Camcorder</cell><cell>1983</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>1/1988</cell><cell>7/1988</cell><cell>50.7</cell><cell>0.0001</cell><cell>6/1990</cell></row><row><cell>Compact disc player</cell><cell>1983</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>10/1985</cell><cell>6/1987</cell><cell>93.5</cell><cell>0.0711</cell><cell>6/1987</cell></row><row><cell>Portable computer</cell><cell>1983</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Digital camera</cell><cell>1989</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Internet</cell><cell>1991</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>2/1998</cell><cell>2/2000</cell><cell>54.1</cell><cell>0.0001</cell><cell>3/2000</cell></row><row><cell>Minidisc player</cell><cell>1992</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>4/1992</cell><cell>1/1994</cell><cell>43.6</cell><cell>0.0010</cell><cell>8/1994</cell></row><row><cell>Digital video disc player</cell><cell>1997</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>12/1997</cell><cell>12/1997</cell><cell>58.5</cell><cell>0.0665</cell><cell>7/1998</cell></row><row><cell>Digital high-definition TV</cell><cell>1998</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>3/1999</cell><cell>6/1999</cell><cell>35.7</cell><cell>0.0936</cell><cell>6/1999</cell></row><row><cell>GPS receiver</cell><cell>2000</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>4/2007</cell><cell>9/2007</cell><cell>96.7</cell><cell>0.0001</cell><cell>12/2007</cell></row><row><cell>Smartphone</cell><cell>2000</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>8/2004</cell><cell>9/2005</cell><cell>134.9</cell><cell>0.0275</cell><cell>9/2005</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Buy-and-Hold  Returns for the Beginning to End of the Bubble Period Buy-and-hold returns from beginning to end of bubble (%)</figDesc><table><row><cell>Innovation</cell><cell>Comm. year</cell><cell>Innov. stocks</cell><cell>Market</cell><cell>Difference (BHAR)</cell><cell>p-value</cell></row><row><cell>Steam engine train</cell><cell>1825</cell><cell>45.20</cell><cell>13.20</cell><cell>32.00</cell><cell>0.0135</cell></row><row><cell>Telegraph</cell><cell>1845</cell><cell>54.70</cell><cell>−22.90</cell><cell>77.60</cell><cell>0.0037</cell></row><row><cell>Incandescent vacuum lamp</cell><cell>1880</cell><cell>−4.33</cell><cell>−4.69</cell><cell>0.36</cell><cell>0.4599</cell></row><row><cell>Automobile</cell><cell>1886</cell><cell>38.80</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell>38.80</cell><cell>0.1275</cell></row><row><cell>Portable camera</cell><cell>1888</cell><cell>88.10</cell><cell>−3.70</cell><cell>91.80</cell><cell>0.0144</cell></row><row><cell>Disk phonograph</cell><cell>1894</cell><cell>80.20</cell><cell>2.20</cell><cell>78.00</cell><cell>0.0264</cell></row><row><cell>Motion pictures</cell><cell>1898</cell><cell>35.40</cell><cell>34.50</cell><cell>0.90</cell><cell>0.2734</cell></row><row><cell>Rayon</cell><cell>1910</cell><cell>−14.60</cell><cell>7.90</cell><cell>−22.50</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Refrigerator</cell><cell>1916</cell><cell>54.30</cell><cell>−13.30</cell><cell>67.60</cell><cell>0.0321</cell></row><row><cell>Airplane</cell><cell>1919</cell><cell>128.90</cell><cell>54.30</cell><cell>74.60</cell><cell>0.1757</cell></row><row><cell>Radio</cell><cell>1919</cell><cell>18.50</cell><cell>−18.80</cell><cell>37.30</cell><cell>0.0232</cell></row><row><cell>Electric typewriter</cell><cell>1920</cell><cell>145.00</cell><cell>140.50</cell><cell>4.50</cell><cell>0.4992</cell></row><row><cell>Electric blanket</cell><cell>1930</cell><cell>−14.21</cell><cell>0.78</cell><cell>−14.99</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Electric dishwasher</cell><cell>1930</cell><cell>−14.21</cell><cell>0.78</cell><cell>−14.99</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Electric garbage disposer</cell><cell>1935</cell><cell>12.62</cell><cell>14.66</cell><cell>−2.04</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>TV</cell><cell>1936</cell><cell>18.90</cell><cell>54.00</cell><cell>−35.10</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>FM radio</cell><cell>1940</cell><cell>−0.16</cell><cell>−4.65</cell><cell>4.49</cell><cell>0.3254</cell></row><row><cell>Ballpoint pen</cell><cell>1945</cell><cell>1.80</cell><cell>15.30</cell><cell>−13.50</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Magnetic tape player</cell><cell>1947</cell><cell>34.47</cell><cell>2.94</cell><cell>31.52</cell><cell>0.1003</cell></row><row><cell>Microwave oven</cell><cell>1947</cell><cell>75.60</cell><cell>9.50</cell><cell>66.10</cell><cell>0.0216</cell></row><row><cell>Videocassette recorder</cell><cell>1956</cell><cell>3.02</cell><cell>−5.90</cell><cell>8.92</cell><cell>0.2777</cell></row><row><cell>Cassette</cell><cell>1964</cell><cell>10.10</cell><cell>−1.90</cell><cell>12.00</cell><cell>0.3073</cell></row><row><cell>Electronic desktop calculator</cell><cell>1964</cell><cell>53.04</cell><cell>−15.40</cell><cell>68.44</cell><cell>0.0065</cell></row><row><cell>Electronic pocket calculator</cell><cell>1968</cell><cell>97.21</cell><cell>−2.79</cell><cell>100.00</cell><cell>0.0021</cell></row><row><cell>Single-player video game</cell><cell>1972</cell><cell>36.84</cell><cell>80.74</cell><cell>−43.90</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Disposable shaver</cell><cell>1975</cell><cell>16.04</cell><cell>11.77</cell><cell>4.27</cell><cell>0.1837</cell></row><row><cell>Personal computer</cell><cell>1975</cell><cell>105.20</cell><cell>54.00</cell><cell>51.20</cell><cell>0.0797</cell></row><row><cell>Laser disc player</cell><cell>1978</cell><cell>264.44</cell><cell>92.06</cell><cell>172.38</cell><cell>0.0649</cell></row><row><cell>Mobile phone</cell><cell>1979</cell><cell>55.10</cell><cell>43.80</cell><cell>11.20</cell><cell>0.3858</cell></row><row><cell>Camcorder</cell><cell>1983</cell><cell>24.38</cell><cell>40.27</cell><cell>−15.89</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Compact disc player</cell><cell>1983</cell><cell>97.50</cell><cell>58.70</cell><cell>38.80</cell><cell>0.2398</cell></row><row><cell>Internet</cell><cell>1991</cell><cell>570.60</cell><cell>54.60</cell><cell>516.00</cell><cell>0.0018</cell></row><row><cell>Minidisc player</cell><cell>1992</cell><cell>50.86</cell><cell>18.22</cell><cell>32.65</cell><cell>0.2105</cell></row><row><cell>Digital video disc player</cell><cell>1997</cell><cell>12.75</cell><cell>13.43</cell><cell>−0.68</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Digital high-definition TV</cell><cell>1998</cell><cell>42.63</cell><cell>11.52</cell><cell>31.11</cell><cell>0.1258</cell></row><row><cell>GPS receiver</cell><cell>2000</cell><cell>64.80</cell><cell>3.90</cell><cell>60.90</cell><cell>0.0707</cell></row><row><cell>Smartphone</cell><cell>2000</cell><cell>115.70</cell><cell>15.90</cell><cell>99.70</cell><cell>0.0157</cell></row><row><cell>Average</cell><cell></cell><cell>65.01</cell><cell>20.42</cell><cell>44.58</cell><cell>0.0054</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Factors Related to the Magnitude of Innovation Bubbles Dependent variable: Bubble_Mag (Magnitude of the Innovation Bubble)</figDesc><table><row><cell>Independent variables</cell><cell>Model 1</cell><cell>Model 2</cell><cell>Model 3</cell><cell>Model 4</cell><cell>Model 5</cell><cell>Model 6</cell></row><row><cell>Radical</cell><cell>82.92 2.562  *  *</cell><cell>83.60 2.322  *  *</cell><cell>86.82 2.826  *  *  *</cell><cell>87.43 2.862  *  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Disruptive</cell><cell>−86.92 −2.097  *  *</cell><cell>−119.8 −2.476  *  *</cell><cell>−77.04 −1.954  *</cell><cell>−76.42 −1.951  *</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Indirect Network Effects</cell><cell>55.33 1.800  *</cell><cell>87.93 2.243  *  *</cell><cell>58.96 2.014  *  *</cell><cell>58.20 2.002  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Direct Network Effects</cell><cell>−21.06</cell><cell>−44.14</cell><cell>−37.91</cell><cell>−38.53</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>−0.859</cell><cell>−1.388</cell><cell>−1.533</cell><cell>−1.57</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Ngram_Start</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>3.70 2.057  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell>4.14 2.161  *  *</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Ngram_Peak</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>3.93 2.182  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell>4.37 2.275  *  *</cell></row><row><cell>Intercept</cell><cell>−112.7</cell><cell>−42.79</cell><cell>−140.2</cell><cell>−142.4</cell><cell>20.98</cell><cell>18.74</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>−0.945</cell><cell>−0.316</cell><cell>−1.234</cell><cell>−1.261</cell><cell>1.314</cell><cell>1.152</cell></row><row><cell>AIC</cell><cell>457.02</cell><cell>366.59</cell><cell>454.98</cell><cell>454.49</cell><cell>459.71</cell><cell>459.25</cell></row><row><cell>No. obs.</cell><cell>51</cell><cell>43</cell><cell>51</cell><cell>51</cell><cell>51</cell><cell>51</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Analysis of Net Capital Raised and Postbubble Visibility</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Panel A: Univariate statistics</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Variable</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Name</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Description</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Number of obs.</cell><cell cols="2">Mean value</cell><cell cols="2">t-stat.</cell><cell>p-value</cell></row><row><cell>DCapRaised</cell><cell cols="5">Market-adjusted capital raised during bubble</cell><cell></cell><cell>38</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.1857</cell><cell cols="2">1.65</cell><cell>0.1064 ∆</cell></row><row><cell>DCapRaised</cell><cell cols="5">Market-adjusted capital raised before and during</cell><cell></cell><cell>37</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.2795</cell><cell cols="2">1.94</cell><cell>0.0602  *</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>bubble</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Ngram_Max</cell><cell cols="5">Highest value of Ngram for innovations with</cell><cell></cell><cell>38</cell><cell></cell><cell>2.1622</cell><cell cols="2">2.33</cell><cell>0.0256  *  *</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">bubbles minus that of innovations without</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>bubbles</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Ngram_Inflex</cell><cell cols="4">Time to inflection point for innovations with</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>38</cell><cell></cell><cell>4.5929</cell><cell cols="2">1.11</cell><cell>0.2727</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">bubbles minus that of innovations without</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="5">bubbles; time to inflection point is the difference,</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="5">in years, between the commercialization date</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="5">and the date when variable Ngram reaches its</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">inflection point through time</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Panel B: Cross-sectional analysis</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Dependent</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>variable</cell><cell cols="2">CapRaised DCapRaised</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Ngram_Max</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Ngram_Inflex</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Indep.</cell><cell>Model</cell><cell>Model</cell><cell>Model</cell><cell>Model</cell><cell cols="8">Model Model Model Model Model Model Model Model</cell></row><row><cell>variables</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>12</cell><cell>13</cell><cell>14</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>16</cell><cell>17</cell><cell>18</cell></row><row><cell>Bubble_Mag</cell><cell>0.00523</cell><cell>0.00575</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0224</cell><cell>0.0168</cell><cell>0.0169</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">−0.0399 −0.0212 −0.0210</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>2.48  *  *</cell><cell>2.82  *  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>2.46  *  *</cell><cell>1.91  *</cell><cell>1.80  *</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>−1.28</cell><cell>−0.79</cell><cell>−0.73</cell></row><row><cell>CapRaised</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1.5275</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1.0576</cell><cell cols="2">−4.1631</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>−3.5719</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>5.50  *  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>3.14  *  *  *</cell><cell cols="2">−2.26  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>−2.22  *  *</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>DCapRaised</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1.4806</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.9467</cell><cell></cell><cell>−3.9418</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>−3.2794</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>5.68  *  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>2.89  *  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell>−2.19  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>−2.04  *  *</cell></row><row><cell>Intercept</cell><cell>−0.1240</cell><cell>−0.1237</cell><cell>5.5365</cell><cell>5.5018</cell><cell>4.5729</cell><cell>4.7040</cell><cell cols="6">4.6900 12.9706 13.0479 14.4609 14.0179 14.0552</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>−0.80</cell><cell>−0.82</cell><cell cols="2">13.53  *  *  *  13.09  *  *  *</cell><cell>8.82  *  *  *</cell><cell>9.62  *  *  *</cell><cell>9.47  *  *  *</cell><cell>7.02  *  *  *</cell><cell>6.97  *  *  *</cell><cell>5.52  *  *  *</cell><cell>5.24  *  *  *</cell><cell>5.19  *  *  *</cell></row><row><cell>R-square</cell><cell>0.1458</cell><cell>0.1813</cell><cell>0.1614</cell><cell>0.1475</cell><cell>0.1847</cell><cell>0.2508</cell><cell>0.2341</cell><cell>0.0676</cell><cell>0.0590</cell><cell>0.0331</cell><cell>0.0756</cell><cell>0.0665</cell></row><row><cell>Number of obs.</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>38</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Contemporaneous Market Bubbles For each innovation where a bubble has been detected, the table shows the result of</figDesc><table><row><cell>Bubble magnitude (%)</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank Rajesh Chandy and participants at the Marketing Strategy Meets Wall Street conference at Singapore Management University, the 2013 Strategic Management Society Lake Geneva Special Conference on Big Bang Innovation, and the 2012 INFORMS Marketing Science Conference, as well as participants in research seminars at Bocconi University, Tilburg University, the University of Arizona, and the University of Washington, for their valuable feedback. The authors also thank Gareth Campbell for stock prices and dividend data for all firms listed in the Railway Times.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Endnotes <ref type="bibr">1</ref> As we describe in detail in Section 4, we do not measure diffusion directly; rather, we use a contemporaneous measure of the public visibility of innovations that is based on Google Books Ngram data. For a subsample of innovations, we show in Section 4 that the Ngram visibility data correlate highly with the actual diffusion data based on product adoption. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> The nine innovations mentioned by <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Shiller (2015)</ref> are the phonograph, electricity, trains, the automobile, radio, electrification, motion pictures, TV, and the Internet. However, <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Shiller (2015)</ref> does not conduct formal statistical tests to document the existence of the bubbles associated with these nine innovations. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> We do not focus here on the exact mechanism that might trigger a rational bubble; we only study boundary conditions that are conducive to the emergence of rational bubbles. The literature in financial economics discusses several trigger mechanisms for rational bubbles (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Allen et al. 1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">, Zeira 1999</ref>. Common among these papers is the idea that when the cost of entry into the stock market is low and there is asymmetric information among investors, an excessive number of investors will enter the stock market, driving the price of the stock temporarily above its intrinsic value. We note a very interesting parallel between this mechanism and the one that in the marketing literature has been shown to trigger excessive entry of firms into a new industry. Specifically, <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Shen and Villas-Boas (2010)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Shen (2014)</ref> show that under similar conditions of low entry costs into the product market and information asymmetry among firms, an excessive number of firms will enter a new industry, driving economic rents to become negative. Interestingly, both actions are perfectly rational. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> For example, The Economist <ref type="bibr">(2000)</ref> observed that "technological revolutions and financial bubbles seem to go hand in hand," while <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Gross (2009)</ref> is featured on CNN Money under the title "The bubbles that built America" (see http://money.cnn.com/galleries/2007/ news/0705/gallery.bubbles/index.html.). 5 Even when several firms start commercializing a major innovation around the same time, their stocks are likely to be perceived as having a similar level of risk. Therefore, risk cannot be diversified away by investing in a portfolio of firms that manufacture the same radical innovation. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> We excluded 21 innovations from <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Chandy and Tellis (2000)</ref> for the following reasons: 12 innovations were excluded because none of the parent firms were publicly traded at the time of commercialization. Four additional innovations were excluded because dividend or price data were not available. Three innovations were considered duplicates of innovations already in our sample. One innovation was excluded because none of the parent firms were pure plays. The final innovation (telephone) was excluded because of the lack of data for Bell at the time of commercialization and because Bell's successor (AT&amp;T) became a regulated utility in 1910. Firms in regulated industries typically face a cap on revenues that rules out the bubble solution in the <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Blanchard and Fischer (1989)</ref> model. A full explanation for each of these exclusions is presented in Web Appendix B. 7 All of our bubble tests are performed on single time series, even those that are based on a large portfolio of firms. Specifically, if an innovation portfolio contains two or more firms, we begin by aggregating their prices and dividends into single industry-specific time series and perform the tests on these two aggregate time series as if the entire portfolio were a single firm. Moreover, the theory that underlies the formation of bubbles posits that firms commercializing the same innovation have the same probability of experiencing a bubble, as the bubble arises exogenously to firm characteristics, being driven instead by the characteristics of the innovation that meets the four conditions described in Section 2.1. Consequently, our results should not be affected by the number of firms included in each portfolio.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sorescu et al.: Two Centuries of Innovations and Stock Market Bubbles</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>528</head><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 507-529, © 2018</ref> A multiproduct firm can be viewed as a conglomerate of smaller, pure-play firms. Assuming that only one of the firm's products is innovative-and therefore subject to a potential bubble-the stock price of the multiproduct firm is likely to experience a smaller bubble than the stock of a pure play firm in the same industry. Therefore, the inclusion of multiproduct firms in our test portfolios creates an error in the measurement of the magnitude of innovation bubbles. In some of the tests we perform in Section 4, this measurement error is inconsequential because the bubble magnitude is used as a dependent variable. In other tests, where the bubble magnitude is an independent variable, the consequence of the measurement error is to reduce the coefficients toward zero, resulting in a more conservative test. 9 Moreover, the ratings vary significantly across innovations to allow for a meaningful cross-sectional analysis. For the radical dimension, average ratings vary from 3.00 to 4.80; for the direct network dimension, they vary from 2.04 to 4.94; for the indirect network dimension, they vary from 2.09 to 4.65; and for the disruptive dimension, they vary from 2.63 to 4.35. The list of average ratings for all innovations for each of the four characteristics is presented in Web Appendix C. The correlations between these ratings range from 0.55 (correlation between disruptive and direct network effects) to 0.81 (correlation between direct and indirect network effects). The full correlation matrix is also presented in Web Appendix C. 10 Ngram frequencies vary significantly in terms of order of magnitude from 10 −5 to 10 −9 , and, in some cases the Ngram count is identically zero. Therefore, all Ngram frequencies are adjusted using the natural log of (1 + (RawNgram × 10 +9 )), where RawNgram is the actual, raw Ngram frequency downloaded from Google. We do this to improve interpretability and mitigate the effects of heteroskedasticity. 11 This is the discrete-time equivalent of setting the second derivative equal to zero. 12 Parameter ρ t is related to the discount rate for the stock, k t , as follows: ρ t 1/(1 + k t ). Parameter ϕ t is related to the annual growth rate of dividends, g t , as follows: ϕ t (1 + g t ). This estimation is performed each month, t, over periods of time that start 24 months after the beginning of the time series. Progressively, each period of time is nested within the time period used during the subsequent month. For example, when we attempt to detect a bubble in month t 30, we estimate parameters using data from months t 1 to t 30. The following month, when attempting to detect a bubble in month t 31, we reestimate parameters with data from months t 1 to t 31, so the first time interval is nested within the second. Thus, the test allows for estimates of growth and discount rates to change over time; each month, the test produces an intertemporal average estimate of discount rates and growth rates, which takes into account all information available prior to that month. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> For example, for a bubble that starts in March 1887 and ends in June 1888, we would compute the buy-and-hold return of the test portfolio from March 1887 through June 1888 and subtract from it the buy-and-hold return of the market portfolio during that same period. If the buy-and-hold return of the test portfolio is 20% and the buy-and-hold return of the market is 5%, we would conclude that the focal innovation adds 15% in terms of economic value, even after accounting for the collapse of the bubble. <ref type="bibr">14</ref> The results remain substantively the same if Rayon is excluded from the sample. These results are presented in Web Appendix E. <ref type="bibr">15</ref> The amount of new equity raised is computed as the product of the number of shares issued times the price per share, adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. <ref type="bibr">16</ref> However, not all industries appear to take advantage of overvalued prices to issue stock. Most of the new equity capital was issued by the airplane industry, Internet firms, and smartphone firms. To a lesser extent, firms in the radio, microwave oven, video game, laser disc player, camcorder, and GPS sectors also did issue more stock compared to the market. <ref type="bibr">17</ref> We also restrict this sample to the period from 1925 to 2010 and the results are unchanged. <ref type="bibr">18</ref> We are not able to perform a market bubble test associated with the telegraph bubble because of the lack of marketwide dividend data during the telegraph bubble period (1870-1873). Therefore, market bubble tests are conducted for only 36 of the 37 innovations for which we detect bubbles in Table <ref type="table">3</ref>. <ref type="bibr">19</ref> We also repeat the analysis presented in Table <ref type="table">5</ref> after subtracting the magnitude of the market bubble from the magnitude of the innovation bubble. The results remain substantively similar. 20 For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Piketty (2013)</ref> offers wealth inequality as one of the leading causes of the French Revolution.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The market evolution and sales takeoff of product innovations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bayus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1024" to="1041" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Short interest, returns, and unfavorable fundamental information</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Akbas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Boehmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Erturk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Financial Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="455" to="486" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finite bubbles with short sale constraints and asymmetric information</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Morris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Postlewaite</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="206" to="229" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Blanchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Lectures in Macroeconomics</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bubbles, Rational Expectations and Financial Markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Blanchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Watson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Crises in the Economic and Financial Structure</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Lexington Books, Lexington, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Myopic rationality in a mania</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Campbell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Explorations Econom. Hist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="91" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organizing for radical product innovation: The overlooked role of willingness to cannibalize</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chandy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="474" to="487" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The incumbent&apos;s curse? Incumbency, size, and radical product innovation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chandy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Common stock indexes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cowles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Iii</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1939" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why do option introductions depress stock prices? A study of diminishing short sale constraints</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Danielsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Financial Quant. Anal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="484" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Technological innovation and real investment booms and busts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Demarzo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kaniel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Kremer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Financial Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="735" to="754" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The (2000) A survey of the new economy: All technological innovations carry risks as well as rewards</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.economist.com/node/375561" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economist</title>
		<imprint>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Market efficiency, long-term returns, and behavioral finance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fama</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Financial Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="283" to="306" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Ascent of Money: A Financial History of the World</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>Penguin Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New evidence on the first financial bubble</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rgp</forename><surname>Frehen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Goetzmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rouwenhorst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Financial Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="607" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intrinsic bubbles: The case of stock prices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Froot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Obstfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1189" to="1214" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new historical database for the NYSE 1815 to 1925: Performance and predictability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Goetzmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Ibbotson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Peng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Financial Markets</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Historical method in marketing research with new evidence on long-term market share stability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Golder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="156" to="172" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Will it ever fly? Modeling the takeoff of really new consumer durables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Golder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="256" to="270" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Growing, growing, gone: Cascades, diffusion, and turning points in the product life cycle</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Golder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="218" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Pops! Why Bubbles Are Great for the Economy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Kindle ed (HarperCollins</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Greenspan urges policymakers to focus on banks&apos; capitalization. Financial Times</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Guha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.ft.com/content/c78994f0-2b65-11dd-a7fc-000077b07658" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-05-27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling the evolution of markets with indirect network externalities: An application to digital television</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Jain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Sawhney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="396" to="416" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Innovation and diffusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Oxford Handbook of Innovation</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Fagerberg</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mowery</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Oxford, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="459" to="485" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Financial development and innovation: Cross-country evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Hsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Xuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Financial Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="135" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Technology adoption in the presence of network externalities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="822" to="841" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Kindleberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Aliber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Manias, Panics, and Crashes: A History of Financial Crises</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Hoboken, NJ</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>5th ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Financing innovation during the second industrial revolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lamoreaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Levenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Sokoloff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Financing Innovation in the United States: 1870 to the Present</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lamoreaux</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Sokoloff</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cleveland, Ohio; Cambridge, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="84" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Speculative bubbles and overreaction to technological innovation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lansing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco, San Francisco</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why has IPO underpricing changed over time?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Loughran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ritter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Financial Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="37" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When is it worthwhile targeting the majority instead of the innovators in a new product launch?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="488" to="495" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using stock prices to predict market events: Evidence on sales takeoff and long-term firm survival</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Markovitch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Golder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="717" to="729" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Corporate financing and investment decisions when firms have information that investors do not have</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Majluf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Financial Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="187" to="221" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why did finance capitalism and the second industrial revolution arise in the 1890s?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Neal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Financing Innovation in the United States: 1870 to the Present</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lamoreaux</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Sokoloff</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="161" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hypothesis testing with efficient method of moments estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Newey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>West</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="777" to="787" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does innovation cause stock market runups? Evidence from the great crash</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Nicholas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1370" to="1396" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DotCom mania: The rise and fall of Internet stock prices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ofek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Finance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1113" to="1138" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Growth-enhancing bubbles</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Olivier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="151" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Funding new industries: A historical perspective on the financing role of the U.S. stock market in the 20th century</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>O'sullivan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Financing Innovation in the United States: 1870 to the Present</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lamoreaux</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Sokoloff</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="216" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Technological revolutions and stock prices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Pástor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Veronesi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1451" to="1483" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New products, sales promotions, and firm value: The case of the automobile industry</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Pauwels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Silva-Risso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hanssens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="142" to="156" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Innovation diffusion and new product growth models: A critical review and research directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Peres</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Res. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Technological Revolutions and Financial Capital: The Dynamics of Bubbles and Golden Ages</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Perez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<publisher>Edward Elgar Publishing</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Northampton, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Piketty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<pubPlace>Paris</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Capital au XXI e Siècle (Editions du Seuil</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bubbles, Booms, and Busts: The Rise and Fall of Financial Assets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rapp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Was there a bubble in the 1929 stock market?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rappoport</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Hist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="549" to="574" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Asset price bubbles: A survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Scherbina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Schlusche</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Finance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="589" to="604" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dynamic model of entry and exit in a growing industry</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="712" to="724" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategic entry before demand takes off</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Villas-Boas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1259" to="1271" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Shiller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Irrational Exuberance</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Princeton, NJ</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>3rd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do innovations really pay off? Total stock market returns to innovation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="442" to="456" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Demystifying disruption: A new model for understanding and predicting disruptive technologies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="339" to="354" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Innovation&apos;s effect on firm value and risk: Insights from consumer packaged goods</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Spanjol</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="114" to="132" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Indirect network effects in new product growth</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Stremersch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Franses</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Binken</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="52" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Radical innovation across nations: The preeminence of corporate culture</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Prabhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chandy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interpreting the stock returns to new product announcements: How the past shapes investors&apos; expectations of the future</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Warren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="799" to="815" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A specification test for speculative bubbles</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>West</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quart. J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="553" to="580" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The stock market boom and crash of 1929 revisited</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Perspect</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="83" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A heteroskedasticity-consistent covariance matrix estimator and a direct test for heteroskedasticity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="817" to="838" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Bubble Economy: Japan&apos;s Extraordinary Speculative Boom of the &apos;80s and Dramatic Bust of the &apos;90s</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Wood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<publisher>Solstice Publishing</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Jakarta, Indonesia</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Informational overshooting, booms, and crashes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zeira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Monetary Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="237" to="257" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
