<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Explaining Bundle-Framing Effects with Signaling Theory</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2018-07-18">July 18, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jihwan</forename><surname>Moon</surname></persName>
							<email>jihwan.moon@unsw.edu.au</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Marketing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of New South Wales</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>2052</postCode>
									<settlement>Sydney</settlement>
									<region>NSW</region>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
							<email>steven.shugan@warrington.ufl.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Warrington College of Business Administration</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Florida</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>32611</postCode>
									<settlement>Gainesville</settlement>
									<region>Florida</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Explaining Bundle-Framing Effects with Signaling Theory</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 (print)</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2018-07-18">July 18, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.2018.1097</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: January 5, 2016 Revised: March 28, 2017; September 28, 2017; February 8, 2018 Accepted: February 19, 2018</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:26+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>bundling</term>
					<term>framing</term>
					<term>signaling</term>
					<term>appeal</term>
					<term>add-on</term>
					<term>core</term>
					<term>asymmetric information</term>
					<term>popular</term>
					<term>niche</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Many sellers bundle add-ons (e.g., in-flight entertainment, hotel amenities) with core services (e.g., transportation, lodging). One surprising empirical finding is that consumers often believe bundle frames provide greater value than equivalent unbundle frames ($10 &gt; $9 + $1) despite equal all-inclusive prices. Although these context or framing effects appear irrational in isolation, the bundle-framing effect might reflect market relationships caused by underlying seller motives. We show that bundling can signal information about product appeal, that is, popularity. Specifically, only sellers of wide-appeal (popular) add-ons (e.g., well-liked entertainment, sought-after hotel amenities, standard side salads, popular excursions) have an incentive to bundle their add-ons with their core products (e.g., flights, hotel rooms, restaurant entrées, cruise trips). By contrast, sellers of narrow-appeal (niche) add-ons (e.g., unorthodox entertainment, unpopular amenities, exotic side salads, unusual excursions) find that bundling is undesirable because they lose core revenue. Consequently, bundling can convey information about horizontally differentiated markets even when the total all-inclusive price equals that of unbundling. Perhaps some presumed consumer biases can reveal market relationships. Frames provide information about the framer.</p><p>History: Ganesh Iyer served as the senior editor and David Godes served as associate editor for this article. Funding: The authors would like to thank the McKethan-Matherly Foundation for funding.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction: Logical Equivalence Informational Equivalence</head><p>This paper investigates seemingly irrational consumer decisions involving bundle-framing or bundle-context effects. Substantial empirical evidence suggests the existence of framing effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Kahneman and Tversky 2000)</ref>, where logically equivalent presentations of an offer in a decision problem systematically cause people to make different responses or choices. We study framing effects in a bundling context, that is, "bundleframing effects." Our research objective is to propose a rational reconstruction of the bundle-framing effect by showing that frames convey information.</p><p>We study bundle frames involving add-ons (e.g., free breakfast at hotels, free garage parking at restaurants) because of their special properties. First, consumers are usually less familiar with the value of add-ons than core products because add-ons are more numerous and often changing. Thus, product uncertainty is more prevalent for add-ons. Second, there are fewer reasons to bundle add-ons. For add-ons, unbundling is equivalent to partial mixed bundling because, by definition, the add-on is available only with the core.</p><p>Hence, bundling seldom increases profits under certainty (see Appendix A). Third, rational consumers may realize that bundled add-ons disclose some unknown market information. Finally, <ref type="bibr">Fruchter et al. (2011, p. 72)</ref> suggest "additional benefits" might be required for bundled add-ons (which they call "free") to be uniquely optimal. We suggest bundling can provide the benefit of signaling. That benefit may explain why some consumers prefer bundled add-ons even when they pay higher all-inclusive prices for bundles.</p><p>Given the same all-inclusive prices, unbundled add-ons seem logically superior to bundled add-ons. Bundling requires an add-on purchase, while unbundling gives consumers the option of either buying the core with the add-on (a bundle) or buying the core alone (not buying the add-on). Given the same total all-inclusive prices, consumers should prefer unbundle frames. For example, given an $1,100 cruise and an optional $50 city tour at a port of call, consumers should prefer separate prices to an all-inclusive price of $1,150, because having two prices gives them the option of not buying the excursion. In general, unbundled prices provide consumers greater flexibility.</p><p>However, the psychology literature reveals that consumers often more highly value products in a bundle Moon and Shugan: Explaining Bundle-Framing Effects with Signaling Theory <ref type="bibr">Marketing Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 668-681, © 2018</ref> 669 frame (i.e., sold at a single price) than products sold separately <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Gaeth et al. 1991</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">, Heeler et al. 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">, Palmeira and Srivastava 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">, McQuilken et al. 2015</ref>. More interestingly, considerable empirical evidence shows that some consumers prefer bundle frames to separate products systematically even when the bundle price is higher than the sum of the separate component prices <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Naylor and</ref><ref type="bibr">Frank 2001, Repetti et al. 2015)</ref>. These preferences for bundles are more prevalent for consumers unfamiliar with addons and for less frequently purchased product categories <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Naylor and Frank 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">, Hamilton and Koukova 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">, Reinders et al. 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">, Arora 2011</ref>. We replicate the bundle-framing effects with an experiment showing that only the uninformed consumer group prefers a bundled option given the same monetary outlay (see the online appendix).</p><p>These empirical observations imply that the bundle frame provides some information about bundled products to consumers less familiar with the add-on. Although rationality supposedly implies equivalence of different frames, logical equivalence does not always mean informational equivalence. Presentation formats themselves can convey information. Remember, framing is a linguistics concept that involves the communication of subtle information <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Lakoff and Johnson 1999)</ref>. For example, sentences with the same exact words but slightly different inflections or cadence can convey dramatically different meanings. In real markets, consumers may use market relationships created by seller incentives when comparing otherwise equivalent frames. For example, when consumers believe a pricing format attempts to manipulate their decisions, they will prefer alternative formats <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Kachersky and Kim 2010)</ref>. Even frames that change consumer affect (e.g., lighting, music, other atmospherics) can indirectly influence consumer inferences <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Iyer and Kuksov 2010)</ref>. Therefore, framing can provide information about the framer, and that information can be subtle. In our case, consumers make inferences about seller incentives for bundling, which can influence their decisions. In real markets, the existence of one frame rather than another provides information.</p><p>We argue that the bundle-framing effect, which seems irrational in isolation, reflects learned market relationships regarding seller incentives. In the spirit of <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Wernerfelt (1995)</ref>, consumers infer information from contexts based on experiences with similar contexts largely created by seller incentives. Consumers' ability to infer information may depend on experiences rather than fully understanding the market mechanism. Sellers may also learn the profitability of actions in a context by experimentation rather than understanding the theoretical mechanism creating that relationship. However, at equilibrium, it appears sellers and consumers act as if both understand the underlying market mechanism. Hence, we use standard signaling theory (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Spence 1973, Bagwell and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Riordan 1991)</ref> with full rationality to explain the bundle-framing effect.</p><p>The general argument that framing can convey information is not entirely new. One seminal study adopting a similar argument is that by <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Wernerfelt (1995)</ref>. This study explains compromise effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Simonson 1989)</ref>, where many consumers prefer a middle option in choice sets. Using a fully rational model, <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Wernerfelt (1995)</ref> shows that seemingly irrational compromise effects can reflect learned relationships in real markets. For example, consumers of average size (the most popular size) in the population can rationally prefer the average size in an assortment of sizes without knowing actual physical sizes. In a follow-up study, <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Prelec et al. (1997)</ref> measure the importance of information in context effects. They find the inference effect accounts for two-thirds of the context effect and for one-half of the cross-category context-effect variance. Similarly, <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Kamenica (2008)</ref> considers endogenous compromise context effects as sellers attempt to manipulate consumers' beliefs. <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Kamenica (2008)</ref> finds that the compromise context effect and choice overload might arise as market equilibria when sellers respond to consumers' contextual inference in their product design. We study still another context effect where bundle frames can signal product popularity or appeal.</p><p>One potentially interesting implication of this research strand is that, rather than assuming consumer irrationality, consistent with evolutionary game theory, we can learn about real-world market relationships from so-called consumer biases. Like biological environments, markets can reflect complex interactions of players that result in learnable generalizations. When equivalent frames for consumers are not equivalent for the framer, like linguist frames, seller frames can convey information, and consumers can infer seller information from different frames.</p><p>Like this research strand, we use rational learning to explain when and why consumers may prefer a bundle frame to an equivalent unbundle frame. In theory, rational learning requires the equivalence between what consumers infer and what occurs in real markets. We show that the seemingly irrational bundle-framing effects can reflect market information: bundling can signal information about product popularity or appeal. For example, a bundled city tour at a particular port of call may be attractive to most cruise ship passengers <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Seidl et al. 2007)</ref>. By contrast, an unbundled scuba diving tour can be very attractive to one passenger type, while another type may find scuba terrifying and stressful <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Merchant 2011)</ref>.</p><p>Specifically, only sellers of popular or wide-appeal add-ons (e.g., well-liked entertainment, sought-after hotel amenities, standard side salads, popular excursion tours) have an incentive to bundle add-ons <ref type="bibr">Marketing Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 668-681, © 2018</ref> with their core (e.g., flights, hotel rooms, restaurant entrées, cruise trips). However, sellers of niche or narrow-appeal add-ons (e.g., unorthodox entertainment, unpopular amenities, exotic side salads, unusual excursion tours) find bundling undesirable, because bundling decreases core revenue from informed consumers. Thus, bundle frames reflect seller incentives to include popular products that appeal to most consumers, while unbundle frames reflect seller incentives to target niche markets. Different seller incentives to bundle allow uninformed consumers to use bundle frames to infer add-on popularity and expect bundled add-ons to match their tastes as well. For example, restaurants include the most popular sides and sauces with meals, airlines include the most popular amenities at their airport lounges, document/graphics software packages include the most popular fonts, etc. However, these sellers unbundle sides with narrow appeal, less popular amenities, niche fonts, respectively. Rational consumers can infer this market information and prefer bundle frames to unbundle frames even though the bundle frames provide no obvious logical benefit and are often logically (not informationally) inferior.</p><p>In real markets, interestingly, sellers seem to know that bundling can signal information about product appeal (popularity). Many hotels (e.g., Wynn Resorts, Westin Hotels and Resorts, and Fairmont Hotels and Resorts) announce that they bundle the most soughtafter amenities in required resort fees. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Holdnak and Jewett (1994)</ref> study the effect of bundling popular recreational services into the basic room rate at a large upscale resort and find bundling wide-appeal services increases user participation and resort revenue from these services. This finding suggests that resorts can use bundle frames to expand their add-on markets to include uninformed consumers who are uncertain about which amenities will be useful to them.</p><p>Moreover, David Martin <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Tait (2016)</ref>, a commercial airline executive, observes that although ultra-low-cost airlines offered "à la cart options" (i.e., completely unbundled add-ons), some airlines have now moved to bundling the most popular add-ons, and passengers have reacted positively. All three current U.S. transcontinental legacy carriers (i.e., Delta, American, and United Airlines) claim to bundle the most popular add-ons (e.g., popular onboard wines, full episodes of hit shows, and box sets of the most popular TV shows). BMW, like other automakers, bundles wideappeal add-ons (e.g., Bluetooth, cruise control, and power sources), while it unbundles niche add-ons like matching BMW Louis Vuitton custom-designed luggage that includes a BMW business case, garment bag, and two travel bags. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows 20 products in 11 major categories from Amazon.com where the sellers claim to bundle their most popular add-ons.</p><p>We also contribute to the signaling literature. We find that prices do not reveal the product appeal (popularity) because, whether bundled or unbundled, allinclusive prices can be the same in horizontally differentiated markets. Moreover, bundle signals can be costless to sellers, unlike other signaling mechanisms (e.g., advertising). Last, in our signaling framework, bundling can increase seller profits with popular addons and still improve consumer surplus, while traditional explanations for bundling (e.g., negatively correlated consumer valuations and entry barriers) often imply that sellers use bundling to extract consumer surplus.</p><p>This paper proceeds as follows. Section 2 provides a review of related research: bundling and signaling. Section 3 shows that bundling signals popular addons, while unbundling signals niche add-ons; that is, we explain both seller incentives for bundling and consumer preferences for bundles (bundle-framing effects). Section 4 provides conclusions and suggests implications.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Literature Review</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Bundling Add-Ons</head><p>We show rational consumers can infer information about add-ons from whether they are bundled with the core. We contribute to the growing literature that examines add-ons. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Fruchter et al. (2011)</ref> explore a popular trade press view; bundled addons are free, while unbundled add-ons require fees. Their full-information model shows free add-ons can occur when consumers have similar valuations for addons. However, even then, bundling is no more profitable than unbundling with small fees. Thus, they conclude free add-ons may require bounded rationality such as zero price effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Shampanier et al. 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">, Anderson 2009</ref>. Given bounded rationality (hidden add-on prices), <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Ellison (2005)</ref> finds sellers can use add-on pricing to soften competition. When add-on prices are naturally unobservable, and sellers compete only on core price (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Ellison and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Ellison 2009, Ellison and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wolitzky 2012)</ref>, sellers can suffer from adverse selection-lower core prices can attract more price-sensitive consumers who will pay less for add-ons. Adverse selection lessens the incentive to compete on core prices. Surprisingly, unlike <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Ellison (2005)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Lin (2017)</ref> finds that bundling can intensify competition in rational markets (with no hidden add-on fees). <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Lin (2017)</ref> suggests that low-quality hotels can bundle add-ons to compete with high-quality hotels. When the marginal costs of addons are small, low-quality hotels can bundle add-ons to increase total demand. However, screening is still more profitable for high-quality hotels, so they unbundle add-ons such as Wi-Fi. While <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Ellison (2005)</ref> and Lin (2017) focus on boundedly rational and rational consumers, respectively, Shulman and Geng (2013) consider both consumer types. They find that in rational markets, high-quality sellers unbundle and gain from add-on fees, while low-quality sellers suffer. However, add-on fees can enhance low-quality sellers' profits, as boundedly rational consumers are unaware of add-on fees when purchasing the core.</p><p>Another research stream studies add-on bundling within product lines in rational markets. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Anderson and Dana (2009)</ref> derive conditions on quality provisions when a single quality (bundling) is optimal (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Johnson and Myatt 2003)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Shugan et al. (2017)</ref> find that a product line can increase profits with optimal bundling strategies. Their analytical and empirical findings suggest that lines with low core differentiation (e.g., airlines) bundle at the high-end of their line, while lines with high core differentiation (e.g., hotels) bundle at the low-end of their line. They suggest that sellers should strategically choose the quality of bundled add-ons to minimize line cannibalization.</p><p>Unlike these research streams that assume either rationality or lack thereof, we show rational markets with transparent prices can appear irrational until we recognize that consumers can use market relationships to infer seller types. Our signaling model for this inference provides a rational explanation for seemingly irrational consumer behavior involving bundle frames.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Signaling Product Information</head><p>The signaling literature considers how consumers can infer information from the nature of seller offers. For example, when sellers strengthen their marketing mix, consumers receive a signal of product information such as quality and low price <ref type="bibr">(Milgrom and Marketing Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 668-681, © 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">INFORMS Roberts 1986</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">, Wernerfelt 1988</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">, Bagwell and Riordan 1991</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">, Moorthy and Srinivasan 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">, Milewicz and Herbig 1996</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">, Anderson and Simester 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, Jiang et al. 2014</ref>. Weakening the marketing mix can also serve as a signaling mechanism, for example, refraining from advertising <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Kuksov et al. 2013)</ref>, restricting production <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Stock and Balachander 2005)</ref>, demarketing (Miklós-Thal and Zhang 2013), etc. Franchising can also be a signal <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Dant et al. 2007</ref>). These signals are often costly, unlike our bundle signaling.</p><p>We find that bundling can signal that add-ons have wide appeal. Appeal signaling differs from quality signaling in <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Choi (2003)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Sarin et al. (2003)</ref>, who suggest bundling can signal quality. For example, a specific hunting excursion on African tours may be of higher quality than alternative hunting excursions (i.e., more games, greater variety of wildlife, better trophy potential). However, photographic safaris may be more popular than hunting excursions. Similarly, fast food restaurants bundle their most popular add-ons (e.g., fries, soft drinks) rather than their arguably highestquality add-ons (e.g., garden salads, fresh juices).</p><p>Both <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Choi (2003)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Sarin et al. (2003)</ref> argue that bundling leverages information to aid new product introductions for firms with existing products. In a two-period model, <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Choi (2003)</ref> finds only high-quality sellers can irrevocably bundle high-quality new products with established products. A low first-period bundle price eliminates first-period profits for all sellers. However, after a first-period trial reveals quality, highquality sellers obtain positive profits, but low-quality sellers obtain negative profits. Thus, bundling eliminates low-quality sellers.</p><p>We build on <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Choi's (2003)</ref> idea that bundling can signal, but our findings, private information, and signaling mechanism are very different. Unlike <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Choi's (2003)</ref>, our add-on products differ in appeal (popular or niche) but not cost, which produces different equilibrium outcomes. (1) Add-ons with different appeal can coexist. (2) Either add-on type can be more profitable.</p><p>(3) Whether the add-on is bundled signals appeal type. (4) Prices do not necessarily reveal the appeal type. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Choi (2003)</ref>, low introductory bundle prices eliminate low-quality products; however, consumers still make inferences based on bundle and unbundle frames rather than prices. Our signaling allows market expansion in existing markets, not necessarily at high (or low) prices.</p><p>Next, our private information differs from past research <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Choi 2003)</ref>. We model horizontally differentiated markets where types reflect popularity rather than quality (i.e., seller costs). Niche products can have higher prices and costs than popular add-ons. Consider cruise lines' high-cost add-on scuba tours appealing to a niche market and more popular lowcost city tours that appeal to more passengers (e.g., the elderly, families with children, the less physically fit, and risk-averse passengers). The narrow-appeal scuba tours usually have much higher prices than the wideappeal city tours. Hence, there is no obvious relationship between appeal and quality with respect to both costs and valuations. Our add-ons have the same quality and, perhaps, the same all-inclusive price.</p><p>Last, our signaling mechanism differs from that of <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Choi (2003)</ref> in many respects. First, we do not require <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Choi's (2003)</ref> key cost conditions for a separating equilibrium because our signaling mechanism is not cost driven. Second, <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Choi (2003)</ref> considers irrevocable bundling (common for software products), while we consider costless bundling (common for addon products). Third, given a focus on new product introduction, <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Choi (2003)</ref> employs a repeat purchase mechanism <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Kihlstrom and Riordan 1984)</ref> to enforce credibility. The repeat purchase is unnecessary in our single-period model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Bundling Add-Ons Under Consumer Uncertainty</head><p>We consider bundle-framing effects for add-ons. Shugan el al. ( <ref type="formula">2017</ref>) define an add-on as having three characteristics: (1) most consumers value the add-on less than the core; (2) sellers suffer greater losses from losing core sales than losing add-on sales;</p><p>(3) add-ons can be free (some sellers) or require a fee (other sellers); and (4) add-ons are available only when consumers purchase the core. For example, inflight entertainment is available only with a flight ticket. For add-ons, we find that unbundling is equivalent to partial mixed bundling, so unbundling weakly dominates bundling for all sellers but strictly dominates for some sellers (see Appendix A). That difference between sellers under certainty allows consumers to identify the add-on types under uncertainty. Therefore, favorable consumer responses to bundling over unbundling can be rational despite the same all-inclusive price (i.e., logical equivalence). This section derives conditions when bundling provides valuable information (beyond prices) about the add-on so that choosing the bundled add-on over the equivalent unbundled add-on is rational. Specifically, we show that there exists an equilibrium where bundling provides a separating signal of product popularity or appeal. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> summarizes our notation.</p><p>Consider a monopolist who sells the core and addon. The seller can bundle (B) the core and add-on or unbundle (U) the core and add-on. There exist two types of add-ons: wide appeal (w-type) and narrow appeal (n-type) add-ons. For example, intercontinental flights offer both popular add-ons (e.g., light snacks, preassigned seats) and services with more limited appeal (e.g., blankets, noise-canceling headphones). For bundling and unbundling strategies, respectively e, h</p><p>For easy-to-please and hard-to-please consumer segments, respectively C, a, A For the core, add-on, and "all-inclusive" (i.e., core plus add-on), respectively Exogenous parameters θ The fraction of h-consumers γ</p><p>The fraction of consumers who are unaware of the add-on type q w Uninformed h's prior beliefs of the w-type add-oñ ν</p><p>The valuation for the core α</p><p>The valuation for the add-on F</p><p>The cumulative distribution function ofν f</p><p>The probability density function ofν Endogenous variables q w ( • ) Uninformed h's posterior beliefs of the w-type add-on p WB , p NB Bundle price of w-types and n-types, respectively p WC , p NC Core price of w-types and n-types, respectively p Wa , p Na Add-on price of w-types and n-types, respectively p WA , p NA All-inclusive price for unbundled core and add-on of w-types and n-types, respectively π WB , π NB Bundling profits of w-types and n-types, respectively π WU , π NU Unbundling profits of w-types and n-types, respectively Most passengers will pay for popular (w-type) addons, while only some will pay more for niche (n-type) add-ons. Of course, airlines that target different market segments might find different add-ons have wide appeal. In many other industries (e.g., hotels, restaurants), sellers provide both the w-type add-on (e.g., hotel bath care products, restaurant breadbaskets) and the n-type add-on (e.g., hotel golf courses, restaurant durian desserts).</p><p>For the w-type add-on, all consumers will pay α &gt; 0. For the n-type add-on, consider two consumer segments: easy-to-please (e) and hard-to-please (h). Segment e will pay α for the n-type add-on (add-on seeking). Segment h will pay zero. Let θ denote the fraction of segment h. The marginal costs for the core and both types of add-ons are normalized to zero (i.e., symmetric costs). As is apparent in Section 3.2, we show how bundling can signal w-types even when prices provide no information about add-on types, that is, different types have the same price. Note, we can find cases where sellers offer bundles at the same all-inclusive price; for examples, see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">3</ref>. This appears to be a questionable strategy (without signaling) because consumers, who observe only the bundle offer, might not value the add-on and not purchase at the bundle price.</p><p>Given the two types of add-ons with different appeal, informed consumers know the appeal of add-ons, while uninformed consumers are uncertain. Informed or not, segment e values all add-ons. Thus, the uncertainty exists only for h. Let γ denote the fraction of hconsumers who are unaware of the add-on type. Let q w and q w ( • ) denote uninformed h's prior and posterior beliefs of the w-type add-on. Each fraction of consumer segment has unobserved heterogeneous valuations for the core, denotedν &gt; 0. Let F( • ) denote the cumulative distribution function ofν. We normalize the market size to one.</p><p>Our signaling game begins with nature determining the add-on type. Observing the add-on type, the seller bundles or unbundles the add-on. Given the seller's offer, uninformed consumers update their posterior beliefs about the add-on type. Then, consumers decide whether to accept the seller's offer. To solve this signaling game, we adopt a perfect Bayesian equilibrium concept. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows the time line of the game.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Symmetric Information</head><p>As a benchmark, we consider γ 0 (symmetric information). For B and U, w-types' profits are </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">π WB (p WB ) p WB [1 − F(p WB − α)] and π WU (p WC , p Wa ) (p WC + p Wa ) • [1 − F(p WC + p Wa − α)] for p Wa ≤ α,</formula><formula xml:id="formula_1">p * WB 1 − F(p * WB − α) f (p * WB − α) , p * WA 1 − F(p * WA − α) f (p * WA − α) ,<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where p * WA p * WC + p * Wa , f ∂F/∂ν, and the hazard function ofν, f (ν)/[1 − F(ν)], is strictly increasing, making the optimal bundle price p * WB unique. Similarly, n-types' profits are given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">π NB (p NB ) p NB • [{1 − F(p NB )}θ + {1 − F(p NB − α)}(1 − θ)] for B; for U, π NU (p NC , p Na ) p NC [1 − F(p NC )]θ + p NA [1 − F(p NA − α)] • (1 − θ)</formula><p>, where p NB , p NC , p Na , and p NA p NC + p Na denote the n-types' bundle, core, add-on, and unbundled allinclusive prices, respectively. Then, there exist unique optimal prices, p * NB and (p * NC , p * Na ), such that they satisfy the following first-order conditions:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">p * NB [1 − F(p * NB )]θ + [1 − F(p * NB − α)](1 − θ) f (p * NB )θ + f (p * NB − α)(1 − θ) ,<label>(2)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_4">p * NC 1 − F(p * NC ) f (p * NC ) and p * NA 1 − F(p * NA − α) f (p * NA − α) ,<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">p * NA p * NC + p * Na . Note, 0 &lt; p * NA − p * NC 1 − F(p * NA − α) f (p * NA − α) − 1 − F(p * NC + α − α) f (p * NC + α − α) , p * NA &lt; p * NC + α; that is, ν + α − p * NA &gt; ν − p *</formula><p>NC for any core valuation ν &gt; 0 (i.e., incentive compatibility holds). Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">1</ref>) and (2) lead to Lemma 1. All proofs are in Appendix B.</p><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 668-681, © 2018</ref>  Lemma 1. If both sellers bundle, the w-type charges a higher bundle price than the n-type. Precisely, p * WB &gt; p * NB . Lemma 1 considers the case when both sellers bundle, which is not an equilibrium. In this case, the w-type will charge a higher bundle price because bundling forces all consumers to consider buying both the core and add-on. Hence, w-types, with a higher fraction of consumers who value the add-on (achieve a better fit), have higher optimal bundle prices. When both seller types bundle, bundle prices might reveal the types. However, n-types strictly prefer unbundling that offers a product menu (core and bundle) for consumers with different tastes. From Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">1</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_4">3</ref> For the n-type add-on, unbundling divides consumers into two homogeneous groups based on their valuations: one that does not value the add-on and the other that values the add-on. Thus, n-types find it more profitable to unbundle the core and add-on to induce consumers to self-select. By contrast, w-types will obtain the same profits regardless of whether they bundle or unbundle because all consumers will pay for the popular add-ons. Given that w-type and n-type add-ons have the same quality, sellers charge the same The add-on type is given, and the seller observes it</p><p>The seller determines whether to bundle or unbundle the add-on</p><p>The seller decides prices Consumers make their purchase decisions all-inclusive prices. Hence, prices do not reveal the add-on type. However, given that n-types strictly prefer unbundling under certainty (Lemma 2), we can construct a perfect Bayesian equilibrium where bundling signals w-types.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Asymmetric Information</head><p>In a separating equilibrium, from Lemma 2, n-types unbundle. Then, w-types can signal their type by bundling; uninformed consumers infer that the bundled add-on is of the w-type. For Bayesian consistent posterior beliefs, n-types should have no incentive to mimic w-types. Precisely, π NU (p * NC , p * Na ; q w (U) 0</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">) ≥ π NB (p * WB ; q w (p * WB ) 1) p * WB [{1 − F(p * WB )}(1 − γ)θ + {1 − F(p * WB − α)}{1 − (1 − γ)θ}]</formula><p>, which implies a sufficient number of informed consumers; that is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">γ ≤ p * NC [1 − F(p * NC )] − p * WB [1 − F(p * WB )] p * WB [F(p * WB ) − F(p * WB − α)] .<label>(R1)</label></formula><p>The right-hand side of R1 is between 0 and 1 because</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">p * NC is a unique maximizer of p[1 − F(p)] and p * NC [1 − F(p * NC )] &lt; p * WB [1 − F(p * WB − α)]; p * WB − α &lt; p * NC &lt; p * WB . Proposition 1 follows.</formula><p>Proposition 1. Given R1, there exists a perfect Bayesian separating equilibrium, where the w-type bundles the core and add-on at p * WB , and the n-type unbundles at (p * NC , p * Na ). Although consumers face the same all-inclusive price p * WB p * NC + p * Na , consumers can still identify the n-type because only the n-type sells add-ons at a strictly positive price, p * Na .</p><p>Proposition 1 proves bundling can be a costless signal of wide appeal, unlike, for example, advertising. With a sufficiently large number of informed consumers, n-types will not forsake core profits from them to increase add-on profits from uninformed consumers by mimicking w-types' bundling. Thus, the core is a hostage that makes bundling a credible but costless signal. Given different seller incentives to bundle, uninformed h rationally infer that bundled add-ons have wide appeal (will match their tastes) and unbundled add-ons have narrow appeal (will not match their tastes). These rational inferences about matching information cause only uninformed consumers to perceive an incremental value from bundles. Hence, given the same all-inclusive price (p * WB p * NC + p * Na ), uninformed consumers buy add-ons only when bundled with the core.</p><p>In Proposition 1, the signaling message consists of the bundling strategy and price. To isolate the signal of bundling, let only the bundling strategy serve as a signaling message. Then, at a separating equilibrium, n-types never consider a bundling strategy at any price; π NU (p * NC , p * Na ; q w (U) 0) ≥ π NB (p NB ; q w (B) 1), which requires a much larger fraction of informed consumers, that is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">γ ≤ [g 0 (p * NC )− g 0 (p NB )]+[g α (p * NA )− g α (p NB )]odds(1− θ) p NB [F(p NB )− F(p NB − α)] , (<label>R2</label></formula><p>) wherep NB is the n-type's optimal bundle price given q w (B) 1, g α (x) x[1 − F(x − α)], and odds(θ) θ/ (1 − θ). Proposition 2 follows.</p><p>Proposition 2. Given R2, there exists a perfect Bayesian separating equilibrium where bundling alone is a signal of the w-type add-on.</p><p>Proposition 2 shows a restricted condition when consumers can infer the add-on type by observing only whether add-ons are bundled or unbundled; that is, bundling alone can signal appeal even when consumers do not observe the prices. From Propositions 1 and 2, three claims follow. First, given sufficiently small (large) valuations for add-ons, the profitability of unbundling increases as the line differentiation, α, increases (decreases; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Shugan et al. 2017)</ref>. Then, n-types have less incentive to mimic bundling, and w-types require less informed h to signal (Claim 1). Next, given that only the bundle frame is the w-type's signaling message (regardless of price), for mimicking, n-types can charge their optimal bundle prices rather than w-types' optimal bundle price. Then, n-types have more incentive to mimic bundling because mimicking price is unnecessary. Hence, a separating equilibrium requires more informed h (Claim 2). Last, as θ decreases to 0 (i.e., the fraction of segment e increases to 1), the n-type's optimal bundle price (p NB ) approaches the w-type's optimal bundle price (p * WB ); R2 converges to R1 (Claim 3). See Appendix B for formal statements and formal proofs of these claims.</p><p>We show that bundling can reveal appeal but not necessarily quality. When consumers have homogeneous preferences for add-ons, sellers can signal wide appeal by bundling. The bundling-signal credibly separates add-on markets, because with narrow-appeal add-ons (i.e., consumers having heterogeneous preferences), sellers unbundle add-ons to target their niche. Interestingly, bundling can signal wide appeal even when e consumers are willing to pay more for n-type add-ons than w-type add-ons (i.e., consumers who value all add-ons obtain greater utility from niche addons). Similarly, when segments e and h differ sufficiently in their valuations for n-type add-ons, n-types unbundle their add-ons to target e consumers and, by bundling add-ons, w-types can signal wide appeal (see the online appendix for a formal analysis).</p><p>We can also find a pooling equilibrium, where both types unbundle the add-on. However, in a pooling equilibrium, w-types earn strictly less profits (q w &lt; 1) compared to their bundle profits in a separating equilibrium (q w 1) because w-types lose the add-on sales from uninformed h. Therefore, the intuitive criterion <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Cho and Kreps 1987)</ref> eliminates pooling equilibria as well as dominated separating equilibria (that can occur because we allow all possible out-of-equilibrium beliefs in the previous analysis). Proposition 3 follows. Proposition 3. Given R1, only the equilibrium in Proposition survives the intuitive criterion.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> illustrates the profit advantage and disadvantage of bundling for each seller type necessary to maintain a unique bundle-as-a-signal equilibrium. In Appendix C, we develop an illustrative model to show equilibria in other parameter spaces, comparative statics, and social welfare analysis.</p><p>We established that it is rational for consumers to infer that bundled add-ons have wide appeal, while unbundled add-ons have narrow appeal, despite the same all-inclusive price. These rational inferences cause uninformed consumers to perceive an incremental benefit from bundle frames. We suggest managers can use bundling to signal their add-on appeal without incurring signaling costs. Other signaling strategies, such as advertising, can be more costly to implement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Conclusions</head><p>We provide a rational explanation for the seemingly irrational bundle-framing effect; namely, given the same all-inclusive price for a core and add-on, uninformed consumers prefer a bundle frame to an unbundle frame, while informed consumers do not. Previous empirical studies replicate the bundle-framing effect in different settings and contexts. It seems irrational that <ref type="bibr">Marketing Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 668-681, © 2018</ref>  some consumers prefer bundled add-ons to unbundled add-ons given the same all-inclusive price, because only unbundle frames provide an alternative of not buying the add-on. We develop a signaling model to show that these seemingly irrational preferences could be a rational response to inferred seller incentives to employ different frames; that is, the frame provides information about the framer. The existence of one frame rather than another in a real market can convey information.</p><p>Although two frames (bundle and unbundle) seem logically equivalent to rational consumers who want bundled components, these frames are not equivalent for sellers of different types of add-ons. We show that consumers unaware of the add-on types can infer those types from the incentives of sellers to use different frames. Specifically, consumers can infer the appeal of add-ons from sellers' incentive to bundle or unbundle the add-ons. For example, hotels include well-liked amenities, restaurants include their most favored side dishes, auto manufacturers include their most soughtafter accessories, software makers include their most popular fonts, etc. Sellers unbundle unusual amenities, exotic sides, auto accessories with narrow appeal, niche fonts, etc.</p><p>Remember that with unbundling, consumers who buy the core can either buy the add-on or not. With bundling, consumers who buy the core must buy the add-on. Hence, sellers can bundle popular add-ons that appeal to the entire market because the wideappeal add-ons match most consumers' tastes. However, the opportunity costs of bundling are high for add-ons that appeal to niche markets or fewer consumers, even though some consumers will pay high prices. Bundling the niche add-ons reduces core revenues from informed consumers who do not value those add-ons. Therefore, sellers have little incentive to bundle the narrow-appeal add-ons. Understanding different seller incentives to bundle, uninformed consumers can rationally infer that bundled add-ons have a wide appeal and would likely match their tastes, that is, provide a greater value than unbundled ones. However, informed consumers do not find this signaling information valuable. Thus, only uninformed consumers prefer bundles. Our findings complement those of <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Wernerfelt (1995)</ref>, in which signaling the average (most popular) products explains, in part, the compromise effect, where we may interpret providing the product size as "cheap talk."</p><p>The signaling effects of bundling can also explain why sellers provide free add-ons. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Fruchter et al. (2011)</ref> find free add-ons are equivalent to small fees that target all consumers. They suggest that we might require psychological benefits from zero prices or something "free" to obtain a unique "free" add-on equilibrium. However, preserving rationality in consumer choice, we provide a rational reason for bundling (offering free add-ons): sellers can expand add-on markets to include uninformed consumers by signaling add-on popularity.</p><p>Moreover, we show that, given the same quality (i.e., horizontal differentiation), prices do not necessarily reveal seller types because sellers of all types adopt the same prices. However, bundling, even alone, can signal wide appeal and is costless to sellers, unlike other signaling devices (e.g., advertising). Because our signal is appeal or popularity rather than quality, our signaling mechanism is not driven by cost differences associated with differences in quality. Last, traditional explanations suggest that sellers extract consumer surplus by bundling. However, we find that bundling helps consumers make better choices by revealing the add-on popularity. Thus, bundling can increase the profits of sellers with popular add-ons and still improve consumer surplus (see Appendix C).</p><p>In sum, we show that framing reveals information about the framer. Uninformed consumers may prefer bundle frames because bundling signals the incentives of sellers with popular add-ons. Thus, signaling can help these sellers improve their profits, providing another profitable benefit from bundling. Our findings are particularly important in product categories where, in each period, new uninformed consumers enter the market and sellers offer many different add-ons.</p><p>Lemma A.1 implies that, under certainty, the profits from unbundling are weakly greater than the bundle profits, because, unlike bundling, unbundling facilitates screening (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Soberman 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">, Banciu et al. 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">, Lin 2017</ref>. Moreover, unlike independent components, consumers should always buy add-ons with the core regardless of whether they are bundled or not, diminishing the advantage of pure bundling that inhibits consumers from buying individual products separately. Proposition A.1 follows.</p><p>Proposition A.1. Without signaling, when consumers have positive valuations for both the core and add-on, bundling produces no greater profits than unbundling precisely, there are p C and p a such that π U (p C , p a ) ≥ π B (p * B ), where p * B denotes an optimal bundle price. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>678</head><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">Science, , vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 668-681, © 2018</ref>  </p><formula xml:id="formula_10">&lt; ξ &lt; p * B /2. Then, π U (p o C , p o a ) ≥ p o C ∫ K B (p o C +p o a ) f + p o a [∫ K B (p o C +p o a ) f − ∫ K c a (p o a ) f ] ≥ p * B ∫ K B (p * B ) f − p o a f ∞ ∫ K c a (p o a ) 1 ≥ π B (p * B ) − f ∞ ξ 2ν , whereν sup{ν: (ν, α) ∈ K}. Given ε &gt; 0, choose any ξ &lt; [ε/(2ν f ∞ )] 1/2 . Then, π B (p * B ) − π U (p o C , p o a ) ≤ f ∞ ξ 2ν &lt; ε/2 &lt; ε. Q.E.D.</formula><p>Our results highlight that the bundling of add-ons differs from the bundling of independent products. This difference can be dramatic. For example, bundling can be strictly more profitable than unbundling given negatively correlated valuations or other distributions of valuations where bundling decreases heterogeneity (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Adams and Yellen 1976)</ref>. However, the following example shows that a strong negative correlation can lead to the opposite for add-ons.</p><p>Example. When consumer valuations for the core and addon exhibit a strong negative correlation, unbundling can be more profitable than bundling. Consider uniformly distributed add-on valuations, that is,α ∼ U(ᾱ,ᾱ), and core valuations negatively correlated with the add-on valuations, that is,ν V + βα and −1 &lt; β &lt; 0, whereᾱ &gt; 2ᾱ &gt; 0 and −βᾱ &lt;   is unique. Given R1, consumers know that n-types never bundle at p * WB . Thus, w-types have an incentive to deviate to charge p * WB . Next, consider pooling equilibria. No bundling pooling equilibrium exists, because for any 0 &lt; q w &lt; 1, w-types have higher bundle prices than n-types, so given any bundle price, either of the sellers will deviate to charge the optimal bundle price. For unbundling pooling equilibria, we have π WU (p WC , p Wa ; q w &lt; 1)</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">V &lt; (1 + β)(ᾱ − 2ᾱ). Proof. Givenα ∼ U(ᾱ,ᾱ),ν V + βα ∼ U(ν,ν), where ν V + βᾱ andν V + βᾱ. Letb ν +α. Then, we haveb V + (1 + β)α ∼ U(V + (1 + β)ᾱ, V + (1 + β)ᾱ). For B, π B (p B ) p B [V + (1 + β)ᾱ − p B ]r B ,</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix B. Proofs</head><formula xml:id="formula_12">Proof of Lemma 1. Let H (1 − F)/ f . Suppose p * NB ≥ p * WB . Then, p * NB ≥ H(p * WB − α) ≥ H(p * NB − α) &gt; ([1 − F(p * NB )]θ + [1 − F(p * NB − α)](1 − θ))/( f (p * NB )θ + f (p * NB − α)(1 − θ)) because H is strictly decreasing. From Equation (2), it is a contradiction. Consequently, p * WB &gt; p * NB . Q.E.D. Proof of Lemma 2. From Equation (1), π WB (p * WB ) p * WB [1 − F(p * WB − α)] p * WA [1 − F(p * WA − α)] (p * WC + p * Wa )[1 − F(p * WC + p * Wa − α)] π</formula><formula xml:id="formula_13">) p * NC [1 − F(p * NC )]θ + p * NA [1 − F(p * NA − α)](1 − θ) ≥ p * NB [1 − F(p * NB )]θ + p * WB [1 − F(p * WB − α)](1 − θ) &gt; p * NB [{1 −F(p * NB )}θ + {1 − F(p * NB − α)}(1 − θ)] π</formula><formula xml:id="formula_14">p WC [1 − F(p WC )]γθ + (p WC + p Wa ) • [1 − F(p WC + p Wa − α)](1 − γθ) &lt; p WA [1 − F(p WA − α)] ≤ p * WA [1 − F(p *</formula><p>WA − α)] π WB (p * WB ; q w (p * WB ) 1). Q.E.D. Claim 1. Given sufficiently small α, R1 becomes less restricted as α increases. Similarly, given sufficiently large α, R1 becomes less restricted as α decreases.</p><p>Proof. Let RHS 1 denote the right-hand side of R1. Differentiating RHS 1 with respect to α, </p><formula xml:id="formula_15">∂RHS 1 ∂α f (p * WB )[p * WB − H(p * WB )](1 − RHS 1 ) ∂p * WB ∂α − RHS 1 • p * WB f (p * WB − α) • (p * WB [F(p * WB ) − F(p * WB − α)]) −1 . (B.</formula><formula xml:id="formula_16">(B) 1) p NB [{1 − F(p NB )}(1 − γ)θ + {1 − F(p NB − α)}{1 − (1 − γ)θ}].</formula><p>Thus,p NB satisfies the following first-order condition:</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">p NB [1 − F(p NB )](1 − γ)θ + [1 − F(p NB − α)][1 − (1 − γ)θ] f (p NB )(1 − γ)θ + f (p NB − α)[1 − (1 − γ)θ] . (B.2) Let L lim θ→0pNB . From (B.2), L H(L − α). Thus, L p * WB .</formula><p>Then, as θ → 0, the right-hand side of R2 (RHS 2 ) converges to RHS 1 , that is, lim θ→0 RHS 2 RHS 1 . Q.E.D.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix C. An Illustrative Model</head><p>We develop a simple model with closed-form solutions for other equilibria, comparative statics, and social welfare analysis. We consider a certain fraction of uninformed h who believe that the add-on is of the w-type, denoted by q. More precisely, uninformed consumers' prior beliefs of w-type are either 1 − ε or ε for an arbitrary small ε &gt; 0. Thus, uninformed consumers still update their posterior beliefs, while we can eliminate the complexity of pooling equilibria that depend on consumers' prior beliefs.</p><p>We consider a uniform distribution of consumer valuations. For consumers who consider the add-on, let their bundle valuations be uniformly distributed on [0, 1/β]. For consumers who do not consider (or do not value) the add-on, let their core (or bundle) valuations be uniformly distributed on [0, 1/β ], where β &gt; β. In other words, there is a positive linear correlation between add-on and core valuations for consumers who value the add-on.</p><p>Given 0 ≤ q ≤ 1, for w-types and n-types, bundle and unbundle profits are</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">π WB (p WB ; q) p WB (1 − β p WB )γθ(1 − q) + p WB (1 − βp WB )[1 − γθ(1 − q)], π NB (p NB ; q) p NB (1 − β p NB )θ(1 − γq) + p NB (1 − βp NB )[1 − θ(1 − γq)], (C.1) π WU (p WC , p WA ; q) p WC (1 − β p WC )γθ(1 − q) + p WA (1 − βp WA )[1 − γθ(1 − q)], π NU (p NC , p NA ; q) p NC (1 − β p NC )θ(1 − γq) + p NA (1 − βp NA )[1 − θ(1 − γq)], (C.2)</formula><p>respectively. From Equation (C.1), the optimal bundle prices of w-types and n-types are </p><formula xml:id="formula_19">p * WB 1/[2{γθ(1 − q)(β − β) + β}], p * NB 1/[2{θ(1 − γq)(β − β) + β}]. (C.</formula><formula xml:id="formula_20">π * WB (q) 1/[4{γθ(1 − q)(β − β) + β}], π * NB (q) 1/[4{θ(1 − γq)(β − β) + β}], π * WU (q) [β − γθ(1 − q)(β − β)]/(4β β), π * NU (q) [β − θ(1 − γq)(β − β)]/(4β β). (C.5)</formula><p>Comparing profits reveals the optimal strategies</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">∆π * WUB (q) π * WU (q) − π * WB (q) (β − β) 2 γθ(1 − q)[1 − γθ(1 − q)] 4β β[γθ(1 − q)(β − β) + β] ≥ 0, ∆π * NUB (q) π * NU (q) − π * NB (q) (β − β) 2 θ(1 − γq)[1 − θ(1 − γq)] 4β β[θ(1 − γq)(β − β) + β] ≥ 0. (C.6)</formula><p>From Equation (C.6), ∆π * WUB (1) 0 and ∆π * NUB (0) &gt; 0; that is, at a separating equilibrium, n-types unbundle the core and add-on, and w-types bundle to differentiate their strategy. Then, w-types will not deviate to unbundle because π * WB (1) ≥ π WU (p * NC , p * NA ; q 0). For a separating equilibrium, n-types should have no incentive to mimic w-types; π * NU (0) ≥ π NB (p * WB ; q 1), that is, γ ≤ 1 − β/β , where w-types charge the first-best bundle price. With fewer informed consumers (γ &gt; 1 − β/β ), however, bundling alone cannot signal w-types. To signal, w-types increase the bundle price p WB from the firstbest price p * WB 1/(2β) such that π * NU (0) π NB (p WB ; q 1); that is, the price of the bundle option is a part of the signal. Solving the equation, we have p WB p * WB &gt; p * WB , wherē</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">p * WB β + [β − β (1 − γ) + (β − β)θ(1 − γ)](1 − β/β )βθ 2β[β + (β − β)θ(1 − γ)] .</formula><p>(C.7) Differentiating Equation (C.7) with respect to γ and θ, we have From Equation (C.8), with a larger γ (i.e., more uncertainty), n-types have more incentive to mimic w-types, so the signaling distortion increases. From Equation (C.9), when the number of h increases, n-types have more incentive to attract h by mimicking w-types, causing larger signaling distortion.</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">∂p * WB ∂γ β(β − β)θ(p * WB ) 2 [β − β (1 − γ) + (β − β)θ(1 − γ)](1 − β/β )βθ ≥ 0, (C.8) ∂p * WB ∂θ (1 − β/β )[1 − 4β β(1 − γ)(p * WB ) 2 ] 4 [β − β (1 − γ) + (β − β)θ(1 − γ)](1 − β/β )</formula><p>Last, a separating equilibrium requires w-types to have no incentive to unbundle. Therefore, </p><formula xml:id="formula_24">2 −1 + γ 1 − J + θ(1 − γ) Jθ + (θγ + 1)[1 − θ(1 − γ)]J − (1 − γθ)θ(1 − γ) ≥ 0, (C.10)</formula><p>where J β/β . Figure C.1 shows separating and pooling equilibria with three different θ's from Equation (C.10).</p><p>For γ ≤ 1 − β/β (i.e., a sufficient number of informed), bundling signals w-types without signaling distortion. However, for γ &gt; 1 − β/β , w-types should increase their bundle price to signal because n-types' benefits of mimicking increases. Then, with a large number of h who do not value n-type add-ons, n-types still find bundling (mimicking) less profitable than unbundling (targeting). Thus, there is no pooling equilibrium; see Figure C.1 for θ 0.8. With a small number of h, however, n-types become similar to w-types, making it difficult for w-types to signal. Thus, pooling equilibria exist; see Figure C.1 for θ 0.4 and θ 0.1. In this case, when β/β ≈ 1 or β ≈ β , that is, add-on margins are sufficiently small, n-types can gain only small add-on profits from mimicking; hence, w-types can signal their type by bundling.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>/ '</head><p>/ ' / '</p><p>Note. SE and PE denote separating equilibria and pooling equilibria, respectively, and p * W B</p><p>1/2β.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Social Welfare Analysis</head><p>Given γ ≤ 1 − β/β , for w-types, consumer surplus is given by At a pooling equilibrium, uninformed h who believe the addon is of the w-type lose their surplus when those consumers buy n-type add-ons they will not value. The loss in consumer surplus increases when consumers are less price sensitive to w-type bundles (a smaller β); that is, uninformed h with a bias in their beliefs pay more for n-type bundles. Therefore, with signaling, consumer surplus increases for n-types. Given a bundle signal, w-types gain profits from uninformed h who believe the add-on is n-type while n-types lose profits from uninformed h who believe the add-on is w-type. Finally, Equation (C.16) shows that the bundle signal increases social welfare for w-types because both consumers and sellers benefit. However, for n-types, signaling may not influence social welfare because n-types lose their profits from uninformed h with a bias, while those consumers correctly infer add-on types from the bundle/unbundle signal, increasing their surplus <ref type="bibr">.16)</ref> </p><formula xml:id="formula_25">CS WB (1) ∫ 1/β 1/(</formula><formula xml:id="formula_26">SW W (q) CS WB (1) − CS WU (q) + π * WB (1) − π * WU (q) 3(β − β)γθ(1 − q) 8β β ≥ 0, SW N (q) CS NU (0) − CS NU (q) + π * NU (0) − π * NU (q) 0. (<label>C</label></formula></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. Time Line of the Signaling Game</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>that p * B exists because π B is continuous on a compact set. Given p * B , thereexists (ν 1 , α 1 ) ∈ K such that p * B ν 1 + α 1 ; p o C ν 1 + α 1 − p o a ≥ ν +ᾱ − p o a ν&gt; 0. Then, we consider unbundling the core and add-on at (po C &gt; 0, p o a &gt; 0); π U (p o C , p o a ) ≥ p o C ∫ K B (p o C +p o a ) f + p o a ∫ K B (p o C +p o a )∩K a (ᾱ) f (p o C + p o a ) ∫ K B (p o C +p o a ) f π B (p * B ). Q.E.D. Without the positive-value condition in Proposition A.1, Corollary A.1 proves that the profit improvement of B is arbitrarily small; in theory, the seller is at best indifferent between U and B.Moon and Shugan: Explaining Bundle-Framing Effects with Signaling Theory</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>INFORMSCorollary A.1. Givenᾱ ≥ 0, for any ε &gt; 0, there are p C and p a such that π B (p * B ) − π U (p C , p a ) &lt; ε. Proof. We only need to considerᾱ 0. Let p</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>where r B [(1 + β)(ᾱ −ᾱ)] −1 . Therefore, the optimal bundle price and profits are p *B [V + (1 + β)ᾱ]/2 and π B (p * B ) (p * B ) 2 r B . Let p o C [β(1 + β)ᾱ + (2 + β)V]/[2(1 + β)] and p o a [(1 + β)ᾱ − V]/[2(1 + β)]. Checkν &lt; p o C &lt;ν,ᾱ &lt; p o a &lt;ᾱ, and p o C + p o a p * B . Forν ≤ p o C ,ν +α [(1 + β)ν − V]/β ≥ [(1 + β) • p o C − V]/β p * B andα (ν − V)/β ≥ (p o C − V)/β p o a . For ν &gt; p o C ,α &lt; p o a . Thus, π U (p o C , p o a ) p o C + p o a (p o C − V − βᾱ)/ [β(ᾱ −ᾱ)] p o C +p o a p * B r B p o C (1 − p * B r B ) + (p * B ) 2 r B &gt; π B (p * B ) because p * B r B &lt; 1. Q.E.D.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>C.4), we can show that buyers of the bundle get greater utility compared to when they buy the core (i.e., incentive compatibility holds); given a bundle valua-tion b ≥ 1/(2β), [b − 1/(2β)] − [bβ/β − 1/(2β )] (β − β)[b − 1/(2β)]/β ≥ 0.Substituting the equilibrium prices in Equations (C.3) and (C.4), we can derive the equilibrium profits in Equation(C.5)    </figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Given γ &gt; 1 − β/β , 4β β(1 − γ)(p * WB ) 2 &lt; 1. Proof. Let g(γ) 4β β(1 − γ)(p * WB ) 2 . Clearly, g(1) 0 &lt; 1, and g(γ 1 − β/β ) 1. Note that g (γ) 4β βp * WB [−p * WB + 2(1 − γ) • (∂p * WB /∂γ)]. For γ ≥ 1 − β/β , g (γ) 0 has two unique solutions: γ 1 1− β/β and γ 2 1+ β/[(β − β)θ] &gt; 1. Thus, g(γ) &lt; 1 for any γ ∈ (1 − β/β , 1]. Q.E.D.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>2β) β[ν − 1/(2β)] dν 1/(8β), (C.11) CS WU (q) γθ(1 − q)/(8β ) + [1 − γθ(1 − q)]/(8β), (C.12)for a separating and pooling equilibrium, respectively. From Equations (C.11) and (C.12),∆CS W CS WB (1) − CS WU (q) (β − β)γθ(1 − q)/(8β β) ≥ 0.(C.13) From Equation (C.13), consumer surplus is higher at the separating equilibrium because bundle signals help consumers make better choices.For n-types, Equation (C.14) shows consumer surplus in a pooling equilibriumCS NU (q)θ(1 − γq) .15) reveals that the difference in consumer surplus between signaling (q 0) and pooling is positive for n-types∆CS N CS NU (0) − CS NU (q</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Bundling Popular Add-Ons (Amazon.com)    </figDesc><table><row><cell>Core</cell></row></table><note>A song book: "songbook includes many hit songs from the past and present including hits from country, bluegrass . . . " Patio, lawn, and garden Bird basket feeder Bird suet cake: "popular suet blend attracts these [14] colorful songbirds: cardinals, chickadees, goldfinches . . A transmitter: "contains the popular TGY-i6 2.4 Ghz transmitter"Note.ASIN, Amazon Standard Identification Numbers (accessed November 20, 2016).</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Notations For the w-type and n-type, respectively B, U</figDesc><table><row><cell>Variables</cell><cell>Description</cell></row><row><cell>Subscripts</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>W, N</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>respectively, where p WB , p WC , and p Wa denote the w-types' bundle, core, and add-on prices, respectively. Given homogeneous add-on valuations, w-types are indifferent between B and U; π WU (p WC , p Wa p WA − p WC ) π WB (p WB p WA ), where p WA &gt; p WC denotes the w-types' unbundled allinclusive price. The w-types' optimal prices, p * WB and (p</figDesc><table /><note>* WC , p * Wa ), should satisfy the following first-order conditions:</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Bundle Price Core Price + Add-On Price (Amazon.com)</figDesc><table><row><cell>Core and list price</cell><cell>Add-on and list price</cell><cell>Total price when</cell></row><row><cell>when sold alone</cell><cell>when sold alone</cell><cell>sold as bundle</cell></row><row><cell>Sea Eagle: Inflatable Explorer Kayak</cell><cell>Sea Eagle: QuikRow Kit</cell><cell>Price: $1,399.00</cell></row><row><cell>Price: $999.00</cell><cell>Price: $399.00</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Canon: ImageCLASS Laser Printer</cell><cell>Canon: 125 Toner Cartridge-Black</cell><cell>Price: $136.53</cell></row><row><cell>Price: $77.54</cell><cell>Price: $58.99</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>DEWALT: Circular Saw</cell><cell>DEWALT: Lithium Ion Battery 2-Pack</cell><cell>Price: $248.00</cell></row><row><cell>Price: $99.00</cell><cell>Price: $149.00</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Epiphone: Les Paul Tribute Plus Electric Guitar</cell><cell>Marshall: Amp/Hosa: Guitar Cable</cell><cell>Price: $836.94</cell></row><row><cell>Price: $749.00</cell><cell>Price: $79.99 + $7.95 $87.94</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>DJI: Mavic Pro (Drone)</cell><cell>DJI: Mavic Battery</cell><cell>Price: $1,084.02</cell></row><row><cell>Price: $999.00</cell><cell>Price: $85.02</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Garmin: Vívoactive (Smartwatch)</cell><cell>Garmin: Heart Rate Monitor/Strap</cell><cell>Price: $159.99</cell></row><row><cell>Price: $134.00</cell><cell>Price: $24.78</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>PowerBridge: Single Outlet (In-wall)</cell><cell>PowerBridge: HDMI Cables</cell><cell>Price: $68.95</cell></row><row><cell>Price: $59.95</cell><cell>Price: $9.00</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>AmazonBasics: Paper and Credit Card Shredder</cell><cell>AmazonBasics: Lubricant Sheets</cell><cell>Price: $37.48</cell></row><row><cell>Price: $29.99</cell><cell>Price: $7.49</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>Note. This table reports Amazon's prices on July 21, 2017.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>.</head><label></label><figDesc>We can similarly prove for the case of a sufficiently large α. Q.E.D. R2 is a more restricted condition than R1. R2 converges to R1 as θ goes to . Note that the valuep NB maximizes π NB (p NB ; q w</figDesc><table><row><cell>1)</cell></row><row><cell>Differentiating Equation (1) with respect to α, ∂p  *  WB /∂α H (p  *  WB − α)(∂p  *  WB /∂α − 1). Thus, ∂p  *  WB /∂α −H (p  *  WB − α)/ [1 − H (p  *  WB − α)] &gt; 0 (∵ H &lt; 0). Check lim α→0 RHS 1 0. We need to show only lim α→0 ∂RHS 1 /∂α &gt; 0. From (B.1), lim α→0 ∂RHS 1 /∂α [H (p  *  NC )] 2 /[2p  *  NC {1 − H (p  *  NC )}] &gt; 0 be-cause lim α→0 p  *  WB p  *  NC and lim α→0 ∂p  *  WB /∂α −H (p  *  NC )/ [1 − H (p  *  NC )]. Claim 2. Proof. Suppose R2 holds. Then, π NU (p  *  NC , p  *  Na ; q w (U) 0) ≥ π NB (p NB ; q w (B) 1) ≥ π NB (p  *  WB ; q w (p  *  WB ) 1). Thus, R1 also</cell></row><row><cell>holds. Q.E.D.</cell></row><row><cell>Claim 3. Proof</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors would like to thank the senior editor, the associate editor, and the anonymous reviewers for their constructive suggestions. The authors benefited from the insightful comments from seminar participants at Emory University and the University of New South Wales.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix A. Without Uncertainty: Bundling, Unbundling, and Mixed Bundling</head><p>We show that unbundling add-ons is equivalent to the partial mixed bundling of add-ons. It might appear that sellers have three pricing strategies in a one-period game: bundling (selling the core and add-on at one price), unbundling (selling the core and add-on at separate prices), and mixed bundling (selling the core at one price and the bundle at another price). However, unbundling and partial mixed bundling provide consumers with the same options: buying only the core and buying the add-on with the core (the bundle). Thus, unbundling creates a product line, which weakly dominates having a single bundle product, or bundling at best provides infinitesimally greater profits under very specific conditions. Unless we introduce other factors (e.g., signaling), having multiple products seems best. Consider a monopolist selling a core and an add-on in one period. A unit mass of consumers each buy at most one unit. Consumers have unobserved heterogeneous valuations for the core and add-on, denoted byν andα, respectively. Let f (ν, α) denote the joint density for (ν,α). We assume (ν,α) is a continuous random vector on a compact set, K, where given any (ν, α) ∈ K, ν ≥ν and α ≥ᾱ for some constantsν,ᾱ &gt; 0. Without loss of generality, consumers' reservation utility and marginal costs are zero.</p><p>For bundling (B), let p B denote the bundle price. Equation (A.1) shows the bundling profits</p><p>where</p><p>For unbundling (U), let p C and p a denote the core and add-on prices, respectively. Consumers buy the core if and only if p C + p a ≤ ν + α or p C ≤ ν. Given a core purchase, consumers buy the add-on if and only if p a ≤ α. Thus, the unbundling profits are</p><p>f dνdα,</p><p>where K C (p C ) {(ν, α) ∈ K | p C ≤ ν} and K a (p a ) {(ν, α) ∈ K | p a ≤ α}. For mixed bundling (M), given the core and bundle prices (p C and p B ), consumers buy the core if and only if p C ≤ ν and ν − p C &gt; (ν + α) − p B . Consumers buy the bundle if and only if p B ≤ ν + α and (ν + α) − p B ≥ ν − p C . Thus, the mixed bundling profits are</p><p>where </p><p>, that is, p a ≤ α. Then, p C + p a ≤ ν + α. Hence, (ν, α) ∈ K B (p C + p a ) ∩ K a (p a ) ⊂ G. Q.E.D.</p><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">Science, , vol. 37, no. 4, pp. 668-681, © 2018</ref>   </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Commodity bundling and the burden of monopoly. Quart</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Adams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Yellen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="475" to="498" />
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Free: The Future of a Radical Price</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>Hyperion</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When is price discrimination profitable?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Dana</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="980" to="989" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of sale signs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Simester</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="155" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bundling or unbundling frequently purchased products: A mixed method approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="75" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High and declining prices signal product quality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Bagwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Riordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="224" to="239" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bundling strategies when products are vertically differentiated and capacities are limited</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Banciu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gal-Or</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mirchandani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2207" to="2223" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Signaling games and stable equilibria</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kreps</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quart. J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="221" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bundling new products with old to signal quality, with application to the sequencing of new products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Indust. Organ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1179" to="1200" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A cointegration analysis of the correlates of performance in franchised channels</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kacker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Coughlan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Emerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cliquet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tuunanen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hendrikse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Windsperger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Economics and Management of Networks</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Heidelberg, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Physica-Verlag HD</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="189" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model of add-on pricing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ellison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quart. J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="637" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Search, obfuscation, and price elasticities on the Internet</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ellison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Ellison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="427" to="452" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A search cost model of obfuscation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ellison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wolitzky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="417" to="441" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fee or free? How much to add on for an add-on</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Fruchter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Dobson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consumer evaluation of multi-product bundles: An information integration analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gaeth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Chakraborty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choosing options for products: The effects of mixed bundling on consumers&apos; inferences and choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Koukova</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Acad. Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="423" to="433" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bundles discount? Revisiting complex theories of bundle effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Heeler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Buff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Product Brand Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="492" to="500" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impacts of &quot;all inclusive pricing&quot; on selected resort recreation participation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Holdnak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Jewett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Visions Leisure Bus</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="18" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consumer feelings and equilibrium product quality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Iyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kuksov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Management Strategy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="168" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Signaling through pricing by service providers with social preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="641" to="654" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiproduct quality competition: Fighting brands and product line pruning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Myatt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="748" to="774" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of price bundling on consumer evaluations of product offerings</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Herrmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Res. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="142" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When consumers cope with pricepersuasion knowledge: The role of topic knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kachersky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="28" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Values, and Frames</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contextual inference in markets: On the informational content of product lines</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kamenica</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2127" to="2149" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advertising as a signal</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kihlstrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Riordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="427" to="450" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advertising and consumers&apos; communications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kuksov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Shachar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="294" to="309" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Philosophy in the Flesh: The Embodied Mind and Its Challenge to Western Thought</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Lakoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<pubPlace>Basic Books; New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Add-on policies under vertical differentiation: Why do luxury hotels charge for Internet whereas economy hotels do not?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="610" to="625" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consumer perceptions of bundles and time-limited promotion deals: Do contracts matter?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mcquilken</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Polonsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="157" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Negotiating underwater space: The sensorium, the body and the practice of scuba-diving</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Merchant</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Tourist Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="234" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">De)marketing to manage consumer quality inferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Miklós-Thal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="69" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Differences in market signaling behavior between manufacturers and service firms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Milewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Herbig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Professional Services Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Price and advertising signals of product quality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Milgrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="796" to="821" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Signaling quality with a money-back guarantee: The role of transaction costs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Moorthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="442" to="466" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of price bundling on consumer perceptions of value</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Naylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Services Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="270" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Free offer cheap product: A selective accessibility account on the valuation of free offers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Palmeira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="644" to="656" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of inference in context effects: Inferring what you want from what is available</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Prelec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Wernerfelt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Zettelmeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="118" to="125" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using product bundling to facilitate the adoption process of radical innovations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Reinders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Frambach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Schoormans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Product Innovation Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1127" to="1140" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pricing strategies for resort fees: Consumer preferences favor simplicity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Repetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Roe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gregory</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Contemporary Hospitality Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="790" to="809" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategic use of bundling for reducing consumers&apos; perceived risk associated with the purchase of new high-tech products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sarin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sego</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Chanvarasuth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Theory Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="83" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cruising for colones: Cruise tourism economics in Costa Rica</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Seidl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Guiliano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Pratt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Tourism Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="85" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Zero as a special price: The true value of free products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Shampanier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Mazar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ariely</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="742" to="757" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Product line bundling: Why airlines bundle high-end while hotels bundle low-end?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Moon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124" to="139" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Add-on pricing by asymmetric firms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Shulman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Geng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="899" to="917" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choice based on reasons: The case of attraction and compromise effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Simonson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="158" to="174" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simultaneous signaling and screening with warranties</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Soberman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="176" to="192" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Job market signaling</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Spence</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quart. J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="374" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The making of a &quot;hot product&quot;: A signaling explanation of marketers&apos; scarcity strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Stock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Balachander</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1181" to="1192" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When free is not easy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Tait</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>http://travelindustrytoday.com/2016-05-05-when-free -is-not-easy::23879</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Travel Industry Today</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-05-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Umbrella branding as a signal of new product quality: An example of signalling by posting a bond</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Wernerfelt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="458" to="466" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A rational reconstruction of the compromise effect: Using market data to infer utilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Wernerfelt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="627" to="633" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
