<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Managing User-Generated Content: A Dynamic Rational Expectations Equilibrium Approach</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-11-23">November 23, 2015.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Dae-Yong</forename><surname>Ahn</surname></persName>
							<email>daeyongahn@cau.ac.kr</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jason</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Duan</surname></persName>
							<email>duanj@mccombs.utexas.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Carl</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Mela</surname></persName>
							<email>mela@duke.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">College of Business and Economics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chung-Ang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>156-776</postCode>
									<settlement>Seoul</settlement>
									<country key="KR">Korea</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">McCombs School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>78712</postCode>
									<settlement>Austin</settlement>
									<region>Texas</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Fuqua School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Duke University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>27708</postCode>
									<settlement>Durham</settlement>
									<region>North Carolina</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Managing User-Generated Content: A Dynamic Rational Expectations Equilibrium Approach</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 (print)</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2015-11-23">November 23, 2015.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.2015.0937</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: June 28, 2013; accepted: March 8, 2015; Sanjog Misra served as the guest editor-in-chief and Avi Goldfarb served as associate editor for this article.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:24+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>user-generated content</term>
					<term>marketing strategy</term>
					<term>rational expectations</term>
					<term>approximate aggregation</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>1. Introduction 1.1. Overview By dramatically lowering the cost of content dissemination and consumption, online communication platforms have engendered a rapid proliferation in global user engagement in contexts as diverse as chat rooms, video sharing sites, and Internet forums (e.g., tv.com/forums/ and espn.go.com/nfl/forums). Evidence is afforded by a Google's Ad Planner ranking listing several user sites with substantial user-generated content among the top 20 most trafficked websites <ref type="bibr">(YouTube.com, Wikipedia.com, Mozilla.com, Wordpress.com, Ask.com, Amazon.com, and Taobao.com)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Coincident with this increase, advertisers are spending 37% more on social media and user-generated content (UGC) sites, exceeding $4 billion annually, or more than 10% of firms' online advertising expenditures (eMarketer 2013). Because of their rapid growth, content platforms have seen increasing attention in the literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Albuquerque et al. 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">, Chevalier and Mayzlin 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">, Dellarocas 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">, Duan et al. 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">, Shriver et al. 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">, Ghose and Han 2011</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">, Huang et al. 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">, Moe and Schweidel 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">, Zhang et al. 2012</ref>.</p><p>UGC platforms bridge two behaviors, consuming content (e.g., listening or reading) and generating content 1 See http://www.google.com/adplanner/static/top1000/.</p><p>(e.g., discussing or writing). On the content consumption side of the platform, users generate utility via the pleasure of reading or the utility of information. As more content is generated by others, the likelihood of finding content of interest grows. On the content generation side of the platform, such as posting video game "cheats" and TV show reviews, users obtain utility from the reputation effect of being influential, knowledgeable, or popular, suggesting utility increases as more content is consumed <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bughin 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">, Hennig-Thurau et al. 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">, Moe and Schweidel 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">, Nardi et al. 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">, Nov 2007</ref>). As such, users' beliefs about others' current and future participation on the platform are central to the problem of one's own participation, content generation, and consumption. Yet few, if any, papers explicitly consider the potential role of these beliefs on the growth of UGC networks.</p><p>Hence, we build on the UGC literature along two key dimensions. First, we allow users' beliefs about others' participation to vary with the state of the network; to this end, we consider a rational expectations equilibrium framework regarding the network's current and future usage. This is material because changes in agents' expectations of the number of users contributing to the site affects whether agents visit the site and consume or create content. Second, we consider dynamic decision making. UGC, like advertising, decays in efficacy over time, analogous to the advertiser problem outlined  <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Dubé et al. (2005)</ref>. Because content is somewhat durable (i.e., viewers can find older content to be relevant), there is a trade-off between the marginal cost of investing time in content creation intended for future consumption and creating that content later. Intuitively, one might expect that lower future costs will encourage users to shift content generation to later periods (e.g., when in the office), but this shift must also be weighed against the loss of current period readership. Another source of dynamics arises from the future beliefs about the site's use. If users expect more site participation in the future, they are more likely to participate in the current period. This dynamic regarding future beliefs can accelerate the growth of the network. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> These two dimensions lead to a rational expectations dynamic equilibrium wherein each user forms beliefs about many thousands of other users, a task that is cognitively unwieldy for the network's users and computationally infeasible for the researcher. To address these two concerns, we apply and extend the approximate aggregation approach of <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Lee and Wolpin (2006)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Krusell and Smith (1998)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> In this approach, users reason that the aggregate evolution of the network should be consistent with the sum of decisions made by all of the members of the network, thereby enabling users to form beliefs about aggregate state transitions in lieu of every other user's actions and state. As a result, the aggregate state transitions across all of the users can vary with changes in the primitives of the system, yielding a structural interpretation of the social engagement problem.</p><p>In sum, our contribution is to develop a dynamic, rational expectations equilibrium model of site participation, content generation, and content consumption in the context of a large number of heterogeneous users to shed insight into the management of these networks. We discuss some of these implications next.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2.">UGC Policy Implications</head><p>Enabling users' beliefs to dynamically adapt to changes in market states allows for consideration of policy questions pertaining to the management of UGC platforms. Specifically, we consider how the amount and 2 A more formal characterization of dynamics in our model is presented in §3.7. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> Our work builds on the approximate aggregation approach as follows. First, a single unit of supply (e.g., a post) can be consumed (read) by many users at the same time. In past research on labor or capital, a single unit of supply is consumed by a single agent. As such, we have no market clearing condition. Rather, equilibrium arises from a balance of different network effects, such as competition for readers (direct network effects) and the attraction of readers (indirect network effects). Second, because content is generated and consumed by the same agent, our problem differs considerably from previous markets wherein producers and suppliers differ. Third, we adapt the concept to an entirely new context, UGC networks. quality of aggregate content affects users' content generation, content consumption, and likelihood of site participation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2.1.">Network Expansion.</head><p>To increase users' utility of consumption, platforms can provide more sitesponsored content (SSC); for example, an online forum site could invite experts to create additional content to supplement that of users. On one hand, increased sponsored content attracts more users who can generate more content. In this instance, sponsored content is a strategic complement to user content. On the other hand, sponsored content can dissuade users from generating content, because sponsored and user content are substitutes from the readers' points of view. The optimal amount of sponsored content, therefore, becomes a question of the relative magnitude of these various effects. In our context, we find that sponsored and user content are strategic complements at low levels of sponsored content, but become substitutes when the sponsored content crowds out user content.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>1.2.2.</head><p>Network Contraction. Of central interest to network formation is the concept of a tipping point, wherein the platform has a sufficient amount of content to attract readers and a sufficient number of readers to attract content in a self-sustaining manner (that is, the critical mass to become self-sustaining). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Without sufficient reading mass, content generators might believe that there is little value in creating content or participating on the site, thereby causing the network to become ensnared in an undesirable equilibrium with very low levels of activity for the hosting platform, often referred to as coordination failure in the economics literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Liebowitz and Margolis 1994)</ref>. We consider two means by which to influence the tipping point of the network.</p><p>User-Generated Content. We consider the threshold at which the network contracts from its self-sustaining level or, alternatively, tips from its low activity level. First, we find that 10.7% of the content level of the self-sustaining UGC network is sufficient to tip the network-if the network focuses on its most active participants. Marketing strategies such as advertising or incentives and rewards for creating content are not uncommon approaches to attract and retain such users. Second, some network members actively create and consume content, whereas others primarily consume content but rarely, if ever, generate it, a behavior often called "lurking" <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Preece et al. 2004)</ref>. We find that it is not possible to tip a network with just lurkers, although they play an important indirect role in tipping the network. The content threshold for active participants needed to tip the network increases to 16% when the number of lurkers halves. This outcome is obtained because lurkers increase overall reading and thus lead to higher content generation utility.</p><p>Site-Sponsored Content. An alternative option to tip the network is to substitute SSC for UGC; that is, a firm can sponsor content in an effort to attract content creation and consumption. Two strategies exist to achieve this outcome. First, a firm can seek to jumpstart the network by sponsoring content early on and then cease to do so once the network self-sustains. Such an approach can minimize expenses in the long run, because the cost of creating content is only borne by the firm early in the life of the network. We find that this strategy requires an initial amount of SSC at 9.3% of the content level of the self-sustaining network for tipping to occur. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Alternatively, a firm can sponsor content creation at a steady level and thus change users' beliefs about the steady-state content. We find that this strategy requires a regular amount of SSC at 8% of the content level of the self-sustaining network for tipping to occur. The tipping point is lower than in the first case, because user expectations about increased amount of future content affect current participation decisions. Overall, our results suggest that tipping is feasible with a relatively small amount of high quality sponsored content at the network's inception. This strategy may be quite cost effective, because the expense in creating content manifests only in the early stages of the network. Examples of websites that have pursued this strategy include Soulrider.com <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Shriver et al. 2013)</ref>, a wind-surfing site that jump-started the network by inviting experienced surfers to generate high quality content in its infancy.</p><p>1.2.3. Content Quality. In addition to exploring the amount of content, it is also possible to assess the effects of the quality of content users read. We consider two such potential manipulations on the part of the platform: changing the quality of SSC and UGC.</p><p>Changing Sponsored Content Quality. For both mature and nascent networks, SSC can have higher average quality than UGC. In our counterfactual analysis, we consider the implications of higher quality content generation strategies by the firm and find that tipping points can be substantially lowered. For the strategy of sponsoring content early on, higher quality can lower the amount of SSC required for tipping from 9.3% to 1%; for the steady SSC strategy, the amount of SSC required for tipping can be lowered from 8% to 1%.</p><p>Higher quality content can also be especially effective at growing mature networks.</p><p>Changing User Content Quality. Sites can also filter user content by eliminating low quality content. We find it is optimal to filter a small amount of low quality content, on the order of 1% to 1.25% for this particular site.</p><p>1.2.4. Summary. As noted in §1.1, a key innovation in our model is its equilibrium concept that enables user aggregate beliefs about participation to change dynamically with the states of the system. We find the amount of UGC to tip the network increases from 10.7% to 19.0% of the self-sustaining equilibrium content when updating of beliefs is ignored-an error of nearly 80%. The amount of content needed to tip the network is overestimated in the absence of modeling dynamic expectations because users are not allowed to update their beliefs about potential increases in content in the future. Hence, rational expectations and dynamics play a key role in assessing the effects of policy interventions.</p><p>In the balance of this paper, we discuss our data and context and use this information to construct our model. Then we discuss identification and estimation, detail our results, and conduct policy simulations. We conclude with a discussion of key implications and future directions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Data</head><p>The data comes from a large Internet site devoted to a common interest, which includes a forum where users can discuss various topics much like fans would discuss a sports team, its players, or various games. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> However, our model is not restricted to these data; it can be applied more generally to a number of UGC contexts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Data Context</head><p>Decisions observed in the considered data context include content consumption, content generation, and site participation.</p><p>Users consume content (such as reading others' posts about a video game) generated by others for their interest in information. An increase in content generation can lead to an increase in content consumption, because users are more likely to find information of interest <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Stigler 1961)</ref>.</p><p>Similarly, an increase in content consumption can also lead to an increase in content generation; those who post content presumably do so because they are motivated to have their posts read by others <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bughin 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">, Hennig-Thurau et al. 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">, Moe and Schweidel 2012</ref>   <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Nov 2007)</ref>. There is also a potential negative network externality of content generation on content generation; as more content appears, competition for readers increases. Rational users base their own participation decisions (whether they visit the site) on the actions of others (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Katz and Shapiro 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">, Ryan and Tucker 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">, Dubé et al. 2010</ref>. More participation in aggregate leads to more content and higher reading rates, thus leading to greater individual participation utility. When the mass of participation becomes sufficiently high, there is a threshold beyond which a network can become self-sustaining and below which the network implodes. Our paper extends prior research by modeling both the network participation decisions and the content generation/consumption decisions.</p><p>Below, we provide some descriptive statistics to characterize the three decisions captured in our data as well as the potential for strategic content management by users.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Descriptive Statistics</head><p>We collect two months of forum participation data in user log files from October through November 2009 and use this as our basis of exploration for social engagement. User log files include the complete visit, read and post history for each registrant. We consider total reads and posts by each user on a daily basis. This yields 19,461,572 user-day observations. Table <ref type="table">1</ref> reports the descriptive statistics for the key variables (excluding 0.05% of outliers) used in our analysis. The table indicates participation is frequent, with 42% of users visiting the site on any given day. Forum reading is far more prevalent than forum posting, and there is a significant variation in forum reading and posting across individuals as indicated by large standard deviations of these variables. The average individual post stock (defined by Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_13">12</ref>)) of 1.19 is quite low, but some users are heavily invested in the site with larger post stocks.</p><p>Further considering the differences across users, we present the distribution of site engagement, defined as participation rate, reading rate, and posting rate per user. From Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>(a), we note that the observed rates of reading and posting are remarkably close to the endemic "80/20" rule observed in many marketing contexts: 20% of the users are responsible for 76% of posting and 73% of reading. This observation again suggests the need to accommodate unobserved heterogeneity in reading and posting.</p><p>Finally, Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>(b) plots the joint distribution (using two-dimensional kernel smoothing) of content generation and consumption conditional on site participation. The figure shows that reading is more common than posting, as there is a substantial percentage of users who read more than 100 posts a day, but very few users create more than five posts a day. Users' reading and posting rates are highly correlated, as users with higher posting rates tend to have higher reading rates. These observations further underscore the need to accommodate unobserved heterogeneity jointly in reading and posting. Given site participation, all users read posts, but some do not create posts. Therefore, the reading model should accommodate an interior solution for the utility optimization problem, whereas one can characterize content generation via a discrete choice model with the option of choosing zero content.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Exploratory Analysis</head><p>To explore the potential for indirect network effects and dynamics characterized in §2.1, we conduct a regression analyses using a random data sample of daily activities of 600 users over 61 days.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.1.">Individual Reading and Aggregate Post</head><p>Stock. We regress daily individual reading against aggregate UGC stock (in the unit of 10,000 postings), individual post stock, and an indicator for an end-ofweek effect. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">2</ref> reports that aggregate UGC stock correlates positively with daily individual reading, whereas individual post stock does not correlate with daily reading. The findings suggest the existence of an indirect network effect wherein users tend to read more content when the total amount of content on the site increases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.2.">Individual Posting and Aggregate Reading</head><p>Rates. Next, we explore the effects of the population's average rate of reading per post on individuals' posting.</p><p>If users obtain utility from others who read their posts, higher reading rates should increase individuals' utility of posting. Although readers do not directly observe readership counts for every post, we postulate that they can extrapolate their own behaviors to others to develop an expectation of the average reading rate per post. Therefore, we expect individual posting to increase with the average reading rate per post. Moreover, lagged individual posting stock increases the  current period's entering content, thereby decreasing the marginal utility of content generation. Accordingly, we expect to see a negative correlation between lagged individual post stock and current postings.</p><p>As daily individual posts are small integers, we fit a generalized linear model (GLM) using the Poisson family where the daily number of posts is the dependent variable, and the independent variables are listed in Table <ref type="table">3</ref>. Table <ref type="table">3</ref> reports the results of this analysis. The results suggest a significant positive effect of the average rate of reading per post and a significant negative effect of the lagged individual post stock on the likelihood of posting. The aggregate UGC stock does not have a direct significant effect on individual posting conditional on the average reading per post, consistent with a process wherein posting utility is mediated by reading.  <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Chintagunta et al. (2012)</ref>, we conduct exploratory analyses of dynamic behavior. <ref type="bibr">Chintagunta et al.'s (2012)</ref> approach relies on the autocorrelation between future states and current behaviors, implying that users consider future states in current decisions. In our context, content generation costs appear higher at the end of the week, as evidenced by the large decrease in posts observed then (perhaps because of the increased opportunity costs of leisure time such as evenings out on Thursday, Friday, and Saturday). Hence, increased content generation prior to the end of the week suggests users strategically manage posts to avoid higher future posting costs. Likewise, because users can create costly content today or tomorrow for consumption tomorrow, there may be an incentive to delay content creation to when its consumption will be higher.</p><p>We analyze these timing decisions by fitting the GLM with the Poisson family for the daily number of postings. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> The results in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">4</ref> indicate a negative effect (p-value &lt; 0 05) of the reading rate per post of the next period on current period postings, suggesting that users delay content generation until there is an audience available to read it. A similar effect is evidenced for the impending end of the week; the indicator of the day before the end of the week is positive (p-value &lt; 0 01), implying that users move content generation before the end of the week when posting costs are higher. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> Collectively, Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">2 through 4</ref> suggest the potential for indirect network effects and dynamics to affect network formation and growth in the context of UGC. We consider these possibilities more formally in §3, discussed next.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Model</head><p>This section formalizes the model for the decisions outlined in §2.1. First, we consider content consumption in the face of heterogeneous quality of UGC in §3.1. Second, we outline the role of consumption on content generation in §3.2. Third, we discuss site participation conditional on these two decisions in §3.4. Finally, we discuss users' strategic behaviors in content generation implied by the dynamic model in §3.7.</p><p>In sum, we consider (i) a population of M users' decisions (indexed by i = 1 M) to participate on a content sharing website, n it = 0 1 , at period t (t = 1 T ) and, (ii) conditional on participation (n it = 1), how much content to consume (read), r it , and (iii) how much content to generate, a it . Users choose these three actions n it r it a it to maximize their utility, conditional on their expectations regarding overall participation of others in the network. Though the decision to participate on the site is made first, it is contingent on expectations on the utility of reading and posting obtained after visiting. Hence, we solve this problem via backward induction, first solving for the content consumption and generation decisions, and then solving for the participation decision.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Content Consumption</head><p>3.1.1. Reading Utility. Readers consume content when the benefit exceeds costs. The utility of reading is dependent on the total content available, because an increase in the number of others' posts enhances the likelihood that a user finds items of interest. To formalize this notion, our model uses order statistics for post quality, which is analogous to what <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Stigler (1961)</ref> shows in the derivation of minimal price given the number of price searches. Let readers face a distribution of the entire stock of posts, denoted by K t , whose qualities, denoted as Q 1 Q K t , are independent and identically distributed (i.i.d.) Uniform L U . <ref type="bibr">10</ref> Individuals read the posts of the highest quality. Let the qualities be ranked as their order statistics</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Q 1 ≤ Q 2 ≤ • • • ≤ Q K t . Each order statistic, Q k , has the distribution Q k ∼ K t ! k − 1 ! K t − k ! Q k − L U − L k−1 • U − Q k U − L K t −k 1 U − L (1)</formula><p>which is a linear transformation of the Beta distribution</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">(i.e., Q k − L / U − L has a Beta k K t + 1 − k distribu- tion).</formula><p>So the expected quality can be expressed as If individual i reads the r it highest quality postings, the expected utility is</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">E Q k K t = U − L k K t + 1 + L (2)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_3">u R r it = E K t k=K t −r it +1 Q k = U − L K t + 1 K t + 1 2 r it − r 2 it 2 + Lr i<label>(3)</label></formula><p>Reparametrizing 1 = U and 2 = U − L, one can define</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">u R r it = 1 K t + 1 − 2 + 1/2 2 K t + 1 r it − 2 K t + 1 r 2 it 2 (4)</formula><p>The utility of reading can be further simplified when K t is a large number using the approximation K t + 1 ≈ K t and</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">K t + 1 − 2 / 1 + 2 / 2 1 / K t + 1 ≈ 1.</formula><p>Thus, reader i's utility of reading becomes</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">u R r it = 1 r it − 2 r 2 it 2K t (5)</formula><p>The reading utility is higher when 1 = U , which represents the upper limit on perceived content quality, is higher and lower when 2 = U − L, which represents the uncertainty of the content quality, is higher. Given 1 and 2 , the marginal utility of reading a post is increasing with posts K t . The result follows intuitively from a greater likelihood of finding content of interest when there are more posts. It also provides a microeconomic foundation for empirical regularities detailed in recent research <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Ransbotham et al. 2012)</ref>. Note that this utility evidences diminishing marginal returns from reading at a decreasing rate in the total number of posts and higher quality.</p><p>It is not necessary that all of the users have the same ordering of post quality nor the same quality distribution itself. We can introduce individual heterogeneity parameter, i , in the reading utility</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">u R r it = 1 − i r it − 2 r 2 it 2K t (6)</formula><p>which implies that the perceived average content quality, 1 − 2 /2 − i , is heterogeneous.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.2.">Reading Costs.</head><p>Next we consider the cost of reading. We assume the cost has a quadratic form that reflects an increasing scarcity of time or attention as more items are read, so that</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">c R r it = 1it r it + 2i r 2 it 2 (7)</formula><p>where the cost function is convex when 1it and 2i are both positive. Cyclicality, such as the effect of the end of the week, is accommodated by allowing 1it in Equation ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>) to vary over time, i.e., 1it = 1i w t , where w t is an indicator for the end of the week. The cost parameters 1i and 2i are heterogeneous across users.</p><p>The users' total payoff from reading is therefore expressed as utility less cost, or</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">u R r it − c R r it = 1 − i − 1it r it − 2 K t + 2i r 2 it 2 (8)</formula><p>Given this utility, the expected optimal amount of reading, r * it , is solved from the first order condition,</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">r * it = 1 − i − 1it 2 /K t + 2i (9)</formula><p>Because of heterogeneity in reading costs across segments, r * it differs across segments. After user i decides to visit the website, she realizes a contextual shock, it , which is not observed by the econometrician. We assume that the observed amount of reading by i is r * it multiplied by individual specific random shock ( it ) so that r it = r * it it . 11 Therefore, ex post amount of reading will also differ across users in the same segment. Because it is realized after the user's site participation decision, the user's ex ante decision to visit the site at time t depends only on the ex ante expected optimal amount of reading defined by Equation ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>). In sum, a reader's optimal level of consumption increases with the overall level of content on the site and the quality of the posts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Content Generation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1.">The Per-Period Utility of UGC Generation.</head><p>Site users derive utility from others reading their posts. The average rate of reading per post based on rational expectations is used to model the reading likelihood, because a user on our site cannot observe the exact amount of reading for each of her posts (there is no counter for the "number of views" in our data). 12 This expected rate of reading per post, y t , is defined by</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">y t = R t K t = M i=1 E n it r * it K t i K t<label>(10)</label></formula><p>Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_11">10</ref>) shows two competing effects of the aggregate UGC stock K t on y t . First, there is a primary demand effect of K t in the numerator as the expected total amount of reading increases with the supply of content. This constitutes an indirect network effect on posting from reading. Second, there is a competitive effect of K t in the denominator because more postings will dilute the reading rate per post. This constitutes a direct network effect of posting on posting. Therefore, the net effect K t on y t can be positive or negative. Following the advertising literature, we assume that posted information follows a geometric decay over time with a parameter <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Clarke 1976</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">, Mela et al. 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">, Dubé et al. 2005</ref>). In our case, the decay rate is exogenous and relates to obsolescence. For example, posts about basketball games from preceding weeks are less relevant than similar posts from preceding days. The aggregate stock of posts therefore has the following form:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">K t = t =0 t− A = K t−1 + A t (11)</formula><p>where &lt; 1 is the discount rate, and A t is the number of new posts in period t. Likewise, let the individual stock of posts and new posts at t by user i be k it and a it , respectively, where</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">k it = t =0 t− a i = k i t−1 + a it<label>(12)</label></formula><p>Given that users form rational expectations for the reading rate y t , the per-period utility from generating content using the constant relative risk aversion utility function with diminishing marginal return is</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">u P a it = u P k i t−1 + a it y t = k i t−1 + a it y t 1− 1 − (13)</formula><p>3.2.2. Costs of UGC Generation. Content is not costless to create <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Ghosh and McAfee 2011)</ref>. These costs include the time to draft and post the content, weighed against the opportunity costs of other activities. For a sample of our data, the mean number of words per post is 72.2, with a standard deviation of 108.8. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Karat et al. (1999)</ref> report that the average typing rate for composition is 19 words per minute, meaning that creating content takes about four minutes on average, and can range up to 15 minutes. With multiple posts evident in our data, content generation can take upwards of an hour. Given that opportunity costs of time differ during a week and that Internet access may as well, it is likely that these costs vary exogenously with the day of the week.</p><p>The cost of posting is specified as</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">c P it a it = it + i a it − it a it (<label>14</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_16">)</formula><p>where the random error in the cost function, it a it , has a generalized extreme value distribution. The timeinvariant component of the linear marginal cost i , which is heterogeneous across users, is assumed to follow a latent segment structure. In addition, it models a cyclical effect such as letting it = i w t , where w t is an end-of-week indicator. We also assume the cyclical effect i to be idiosyncratic for different latent segments. The heterogeneity in the cost of posting captures the potential unobserved individual-level differences in posting.</p><p>3.2.3. Optimal UGC Generation. We presume a user chooses the optimal number of postings a * it (amount of content to generate) to maximize the expected discounted sum of per-period utilities minus per-period costs</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">u P a it − c P it a it + E h=t+1 h−t u P a ih − c P ih a ih (<label>15</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_18">)</formula><p>This summed utility can be formulated as a dynamic programming problem with the Bellman equation</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">V i s it it = max a it ∈A u P a it −c P it a it + it a it + E V i s i t+1 i t+1 s it a it (<label>16</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_20">)</formula><p>where thec P it a it = it + i a it represents the nonrandom component of the posting costs. The value function V i s it it depends on s it = k i t−1 K t w t and it , which are the state variables. The number of per-period postings a it is the control variable, which is discretized because over 99% of users create fewer than 10 posts a day. Hence, we let a it ∈ A = 0 1 2 ā , whereā represents the maximum number of daily postings. Define the integrated value function EV i s it a it as</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">EV i s it a it = s i t+1 i t+1 V i s i t+1 i t+1 • p s i t+1 i t+1 s it it a it ds i t+1 d i t+1</formula><p>We can derive the probability of writing a it content postings conditional on site participation as</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">P a it s it n it = 1 = exp u P a it −c P it a it + Ẽ V i s it a it a it ∈A exp u P a it −c P it a it + Ẽ V i s it a it<label>(17)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Modeling Heterogeneity in UGC Consumption and Generation</head><p>We jointly model the heterogeneity parameters in the reading and posting models with J latent segments</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">i 1i 2i i i ∼ J j=1 p j I i =¯ j 1i =¯ 1j 2i =¯ 2j =¯ j i =¯ j<label>(18)</label></formula><p>In Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_23">18</ref>),¯ j ,¯ 1j ,¯ 2j ,¯ j , and¯ j are the segmentspecific values for the parameters in the content consumption and generation models. Because reading and posting costs follow a distribution that is jointly estimated, our model captures a wide array of interdependent behaviors for reading and posting. If, for example, one segment has a low posting cost and a low reading cost and another segment has a high posting cost and a high reading cost (reflective of the tendency of some individuals to read and post more than others), then reading and posting will be positively correlated across users.</p><p>In the reading model represented by Equation ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>), it is obvious that the data cannot separately identify 1 and¯ j , j = 1 J . Hence, we constrain¯ j such that J j=1¯ j = 0.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.">Site Participation</head><p>Prior to posting and reading, a user must decide whether to visit the UGC website, and this decision is predicated on the net expected utility from consuming and generating content should the user decide to visit. Hence, the utility from visiting the site (n it = 1) includes utilities from expected posting and expected reading</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">u V n it = 1 = 1 E max r it u R r it − c R it r it + E max a it u P a it − c P it a it + Ẽ V i s it a it + it n it = 1 (<label>19</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_25">)</formula><p>where 1 and are scale parameters that rescale the utility of reading and the contextual shock relative to the utility of posting, respectively. The contextual shock it n it = 1 represents the exogenous cost for a user to visit the site at period t, and it is assumed to be known to the user but not the econometrician. The corresponding utility from not visiting the site (n it = 0) contains three components: First, users continue to obtain utility from others' reading their previous posting stock, given by u P k i t−1 y t + Ẽ V i s it a it = 0 . Second, 0j is a segment-specific intercept and captures the utility from time spent on alternative pursuits when one does not visit the site. Third, there is a random shock it n it = 0 . Therefore, the utility from not visiting the site is obtained by summing these three components</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">u V n it = 0 = 0j + u P k i t−1 y t + Ẽ V i s it a it = 0 + it n it = 0 (20)</formula><p>A user chooses to visit the website if u V n it = 1 &gt; u V n it = 0 and vice versa.</p><p>We assume it a it , it n it = 0 , and it n it = 1 have i.i.d. Type 1 extreme value (Gumbel) distributions, resulting in a nested logit model of site participation and content generation given site participation.</p><p>Let the inclusive value of posting content be</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">IV it = ln a it ∈A exp u P a it −c P it a it + Ẽ V i s it a it (<label>21</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_28">)</formula><p>Then the choice probability of visiting the site can be written as</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">P n it = 1 s it = exp 1 E max r it u R r it − c R it r it + IV it • exp 0j + u P k i t−1 y t + Ẽ V i s it a it = 0 + exp 1 E max r it u R r it − c R it r it + IV it −1 (<label>22</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_30">)</formula><p>and P n it = 0 s it = 1 − P n it = 1 s it .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5.">State Transitions</head><p>The state transitions are as follows. First, the random shocks, it , are assumed to be i.i.d. over time and across individuals and independent of the other state variables in s it . Second, the individual stock, k it , evolves deterministically, k it = k i t−1 + a it . Third, the day of week effects, w t , evolve deterministically over time. Last, the aggregate UGC stock, K t , is defined as K t = M i=1 k it , and hence it evolves deterministically given K t−1 and a it ; i = 1 M. However, we assume that from the perspective of any individual user, K t evolves stochastically given K t−1 , but independent of the individual's own action a it . When the site has a very large number of users, every user i will neither perfectly observe the actions, a i t , and stocks, k i t , of the other users, nor believe her own action a it has any influence on the aggregate UGC stock, K t . If we impose the rational expectations constraint, then user i's belief about the state transition for K t must coincide with the actual behaviors of all users on the site, as discussed next.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.6.">Rational Expectations and Approximate</head><p>Aggregation Rational expectations require that users' beliefs about the evolution of K t be consistent with the actual transition, which is the sum of all individuals' posting decisions. This observation becomes germane in policy simulations, because the evolution of K t is neither exogenous nor invariant to a change in policy that might affect users' participation levels. Accordingly, users' beliefs can change in response to a change in the strategy of the site.</p><p>3.6.1. Approximate Aggregation. Extending an approximate aggregation approach to the rational expectations equilibrium pioneered by <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Krusell and Smith (1998)</ref>, we first formulate an individual's beliefs on how the aggregate state variable K t evolves over time as follows: where w t is the end-of-week indicator, and K 2 represents the cyclical effect. The parameters K 0 , K 1 , K 2 for the stock of the aggregate content are determined by the rational expectations equilibrium.</p><formula xml:id="formula_31">K t = K 0 + K 1 K t−1 + K 2 w t + K t (<label>23</label></formula><p>We posit a first degree order of the lag in the state transitions to be consistent with the primitives in the consumer model to ensure that the approximate beliefs regarding the aggregate state transitions are consistent with the Markovian structure in the underlying individual posting model. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> From an individual's perspective, there is a degree of uncertainty about the evolution of K t ; we express this uncertainty using K t , which is a zero-mean random error given K t−1 .</p><p>Our model also assumes that individual users approximate the expected average reading rate per post as a function of K t as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_32">y t = y 0 + y 1 K t + y 2 w t (<label>24</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_33">)</formula><p>where y 2 is again for the effect for the end of the week. Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">24</ref>) approximates Equation (10), which does not have a closed form for the function y t of K t . When the number of users is very large, the observed quantity of average reading per post can closely approximate the expected one. 14 See Web Appendix A for details. The parameters y 0 , y 1 , and y 2 are also determined by the rational expectations equilibrium.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.6.2.">Consistency of Approximate Aggregation.</head><p>In reality, K t is deterministic given the actions of all individuals</p><formula xml:id="formula_34">K t = K t−1 + M i=1 a * it (25)</formula><p>Using Equation (25) directly to calculate users' rational expectations requires us to assume that every user knows how each and every other user chooses their optimal action a * it given their respective policy functions and states. Complete knowledge of the optimal behavior of thousands of other users is an unrealistic assumption that imposes a large informational <ref type="bibr">13</ref> Note that the order of the state transition equations cannot be higher than the order of the individual-level model, or else the individual level model would fail to account for a users' beliefs about these higher order states. Here we assume that individuals only use one lagged K t−1 to predict K t , and hence it implies an AR(1) model for K t . Conceivably, individuals may use more than one lagged stock to predict K t . Were they to use an AR(q) model, then K t−2 K t−q would also have to be in the set of state variables in the dynamic optimization problem. Because a surfeit of state variables can induce computational dimensionality constraints, the most parsimonious state transition model possible for K t is desirable from a computational perspective. In §2.3, we test and find the AR(1) model is the best model for our data. <ref type="bibr">14</ref> We also approximate R t in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_11">10</ref>) with R t = R 0 + R 1 K t + R 2 K 2 t + R 3 w t • K t , from which we derive the approximation for y t = R t /K t in estimation. We find that the estimation results remain unchanged, so the approximation by Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">24</ref>) is robust.</p><p>burden on individual users. On the other hand, approximate aggregation (assuming bounded rationality) only requires that K t and y t predicted by Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">24</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula">25</ref>) coincide with the real K t and y t . This implies that agents need only be able to form rational beliefs regarding the transitions of the aggregate states. Using an initial guess for the parameters K 0 , K 1 , K 2 and y 0 , y 1 , y 2 , we compute individual optimal behaviors n * it , a * it , and r * it . Aggregating across users, we recompute K t and y t and recompute individual behaviors, iterating back and forth between the individual-level and aggregate models until convergence. Web Appendix B details the algorithm used to simulate a rational expectations equilibrium. The parameters K 0 , K 1 , K 2 and</p><formula xml:id="formula_35">y 0 , y 1 , y 2</formula><p>are reestimated in every step of the iterations to find the fixed point of the rational expectations equilibrium. <ref type="bibr">15</ref> In sum, the use of approximate aggregation enables us to accommodate heterogeneity in a rational expectations equilibrium model. We explore some theoretical properties of our rational expectations equilibrium with approximate aggregation by simulation in Web Appendix D.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.7.">Dynamic Strategic Behavior</head><p>In this final subsection, we afford some intuition regarding the nature of dynamics implied by our model. The dynamics in our model rests on two integrated foundations: (i) the individual intertemporal substitution of content creation and (ii) the expected indirect network effects.</p><p>We begin by discussing the individual's intertemporal substitution of content. Considering a simplified and stylized version of the UGC generation problem where we treat the discrete posting decision, a t , as a continuous variable, the cost function as linear, and abstract away from the error (we suppress individual index i for clarity), we obtain</p><formula xml:id="formula_36">V s t = max a t ∈A k t−1 + a t 1− / 1 − − t a t + V s t+1 (26)</formula><p>The Euler equation from this simplified problem can be derived as follows: from the next period to the current period, they gain (i) the utility from those that read that content this current period y t k t−1 + a t − and (ii) the cost difference of creating that accelerated content this current period ( t ) rather than the next period ( t+1 ), but (iii) lose some utility from others reading tomorrow because of the decay in content and the discounted utility . Overall, this expression implies dynamics involve shifting content creation to align with periods with higher reading rate y t and lower posting cost t . Finally, we note that, all else equal, an increase in entering posting stock, k t−1 , implies an attendant reduction in a t to maintain the equality, k t . The rationale behind this relationship is that there is an optimal level of current and past content that can be obtained either by having a larger stock of old content or an increase in current content.</p><formula xml:id="formula_37">k t−1 + a t − y 1− t − t k t + a t+1 − y 1− t+1 − t+1 =<label>(</label></formula><p>Next, we consider the role of expected network effects in dynamics as discussed in §3.6. Although the Euler equation in the simplified model outlines the ratio of content across periods, it is not informative about the absolute level of content. Yet beliefs about future content availability also affects the overall level of content. In this regard, the individual decision to maintain stock k t depends not only on the current period network effects (represented by y t and K t ) but also the expected future network effects as implied by the aggregate state transition equations. This is analogous to a firm that makes investment choices given their expectations on future profitability and interest rates. For example, if a user believes the site manager will continuously sponsor content, as opposed to only once, then the user expects more readers in the future which will affect the generation of current postings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Estimation and Identification</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Estimation</head><p>Within each iteration of the likelihood optimization algorithm, an efficient estimation approach using maximum likelihood (MLE) requires solving both (i) the nonlinear dynamic optimization problem for every individual user and (ii) the rational expectations equilibrium for the aggregate reading and posting. The computational cost of this approach is therefore considerable as it involves (i) iterations for rational expectations within (ii) iterations for the fixed point solutions for the dynamic program within (iii) iterations for the likelihood routine.</p><p>To facilitate the second set of iterations, we design a two-step estimation approach as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Rust (1994)</ref>, first estimating the state transition equation for the aggregate UGC in ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_31">23</ref>) and the reading per posting as a function of the UGC in (24), and second estimating the parameters in reading, posting, and site-participation models.</p><p>In the first step of this approach, we estimate the state transition equation for the aggregate UGC in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_31">23</ref>) and the reading per posting as a function of the UGC in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">24</ref>). We obtain the MLE estimates of the regression coefficients K 0 , K 1 , K 2 and y 0 , y 1 , y 2 , which capture the evolution of the aggregate states in the data under the current equilibrium. Because the observed K t and y t reflect the current equilibrium, no iteration is needed to reestimate K 0 , K 1 , K 2 and</p><formula xml:id="formula_38">y 0 , y 1 , y 2</formula><p>. This equilibrium assumption is not likely to hold in our counterfactuals, wherein we do need to recompute the expectations.</p><p>In the second step, we estimate the structural parameters in the individual reading, posting, and siteparticipation models. In this step, we use the first-step results to estimate the structural parameters. The reading and posting models are estimated by MLE, using the joint likelihood function of reading and posting for each individual user i</p><formula xml:id="formula_39">J j=1 p j T t=1 Exponential r it 1 −¯ j −¯ 1j w t 2 /K t +¯ 2j • exp u P a it −c P a it +Ẽ V j s it a it a it ∈A exp u P a it −c P a it +Ẽ V j s it a it (<label>28</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_40">)</formula><p>The site-participation model in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_29">22</ref>) is estimated as a binary choice model with the likelihood function</p><formula xml:id="formula_41">J j=1 p j T t=1 P n it = 1 s it n it P n it = 0 s it 1−n it (<label>29</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_42">)</formula><p>given the estimated parameters in the reading and posting models. The derivation of these likelihood functions is detailed in Web Appendix C. To facilitate the first set of iterations pertaining to solving the dynamic programming problem during the second step of the estimation, the estimation algorithm parallels <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Dubé et al. (2012)</ref>, which is a maximum likelihood estimator using mathematical programming with equilibrium constraints. <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Su and Judd (2010)</ref> show that the two-step pseudo-maximum likelihood estimator discussed above is consistent. We bootstrap to compute the standard errors. See Web Appendix C.2 for details.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Identification</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.1.">Post Stock Decay Parameter .</head><p>As indicated in §3.2, the information contained in a posting gradually becomes obsolete. We model this phenomenon by imputing an exogenous decay parameter to the post stock in our model. The decay rate is identified and estimated using a secondary data set, which records a sample of posts and their respective histories of how many times they are read over time. In this data set, we observe (i) that there is a decline over time in the number of times that a particular posting is accessed by forum users after it is posted and (ii) the average reading rate per post, the aggregate UGC stock, and the average participation rate are stationary over time. The data are consistent with our modeling assumption that a post has a finite lifetime with a decay parameter . When the average reading rate per post is stationary over time, as observed in our data, the decay parameter is identified by the ratio of the times that a post is read in periods t − 1 and t. Under the exponential decay assumption, this ratio equals the decay rate in the amount of reading per post. 16 4.2.2. Other Parameters. In the aggregate state transition (Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_31">23</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">24</ref>)), the coefficients are identified from the time series structure of the aggregate level data-specifically, from the autocorrelation for the K t and correlation between the y t and K t . Next, we consider the identification of the parameters in the reading and posting models from the second stage estimation. Note that the optimal individuallevel reading r * it for person i at time t is equal to 1 −¯ j −¯ 1j w t / 2 /K t +¯ 2j if person i belongs to segment j per Equations ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_23">18</ref>). This expression suggests that 1 is not identified, because one can divide the numerator and denominator by any constant and obtain the same ratio. For this reason, we normalize 1 to 1, which also achieves scale normalization. Heterogeneity in the reading (¯ j ,¯ 2j ) and posting (¯ j ) models can be inferred from differences in individuals' mean reading and posting levels over time from the panel structure of the data. To identify the cyclical effect in reading and posting,¯ 1j and¯ j , we use an indicator variable that is set to 1 for the end of the week and 0 otherwise. Hence, these parameters are identified by differences in the mean amount of reading and number of postings between the end of the week and the other days in the week. The parameter that captures the diminishing marginal returns for the utility in posting, , is identified by the observed difference in mean posting levels at different levels of individual post stock. In general, the discount factor is not identified in dynamic discrete choice models (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Manski 1993, Magnac and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Thesmar 2002)</ref>. Hence we set = 0 99. 17 Finally, there are scale parameters in the site participation model, 0 1 , and . Conditional on the parameters estimated above for the reading and posting model, these parameter estimates follow from standard identification arguments for the logit with panel data on site participation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Decay Parameter and Initialization of</head><p>Post Stock As indicated in §3.2, the decay rate quantifies the rate of diminution in posting stock over time. This decay rate is estimated using an auxiliary data set collected by the Internet site regarding when a sample of users' posts were visited by other users. The decay in the number of users clicking on these posts over time is informative about their durability. We consider a random sample of 473 forum postings in the first week of the sampling period. The data set records the daily number of times that these posts are read over 20 days. The average number of times that a post is read on the first day is 7 59 sd = 13 9 ; the second day, 4 90 sd = 5 4 ; and the third day, 3 49 sd = 3 1 , etc.</p><p>The decay parameter is identified by the ratio of the times that a posting is read in periods t − 1 and t. Let z kt be the number of times post k is read in the t-th period after it is posted. We estimate using the model z kt ∼ Poisson t−1 k , where k captures the heterogeneity in the amount of reading among posts. The MLE using generalized linear models yields log = −0 30 0 0036 , so the decay parameter estimate is 0.74.</p><p>Because there is no history of posts prior to the initial week, individuals' initial post stocks in the first week of the data are unobserved. Hence, the individual post stock is computed by setting the initial stock at zero and recursively applying Equation (12) using the 61-day posting data until the individual post stock reaches a steady state. The individual's steady state is then reused as the initial post stock to calculate the individual post stock for the 61-day data. Most of the users in our sample have been using the forum for a long time prior to the sampling period, so their post stocks are likely to have reached the steady state at the starting period of our data. The aggregate stock, K t , is computed by aggregating individual stocks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Aggregate Variables Under Rational</head><p>Expectations Section 3.6 outlines the aggregate state transition model that captures the rational expectations process. The estimation results for the AR(1) model in ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_31">23</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">24</ref>) are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">5</ref>. The results provide evidence of strong autocorrelation ( K 1 = 0 93) for the aggregate UGC stock. The average reading rate per post is an increasing function of aggregate UGC stock ( y 1 = 0 054 for UGC in unit of 10,000 postings), which implies a  positive network effect of posting. The effect of the end of a week in model ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">24</ref>) is significantly negative, which means lower reading activity at the end of the week. We also test an AR(2) model</p><formula xml:id="formula_43">K t = K 0 + K 1 K t−1 + K 2 K t−2 + K 3 w t + K</formula><p>t using the second order lag K t−2 . We find the second lag coefficient K 2 to be not significant (p-value = 0 73). The Durbin-Watson test for the residuals of the AR(1) model</p><formula xml:id="formula_44">K t = K 0 + K 1 K t−1 + K 2 w t + K t</formula><p>has the p-value equal to 0.63, not rejecting the null hypothesis that the autocorrelation of the residuals is 0. Therefore, our data support the assumption that users can use approximate aggregation and AR(1) to predict K t on the basis of rational expectations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.">Content Consumption, Generation, and Site Participation</head><p>We randomly selected a sample of 600 users to estimate the individual-level model. The amount of reading and number of postings for each individual in the sample are recorded for 61 days from October 1 to November 30, 2009. If both reading and posting are zero for a user in a certain day, we conclude that the user did not visit the site that day. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_11">6</ref> reports the parameter estimates for the model for two segments of users. <ref type="bibr">18</ref> We begin by discussing the results for the content generation and consumption models. The two segments of the content generation model are specified to share a common posting utility parameter, , in Equation ( <ref type="formula">13</ref>), but differ with respect to their posting costs,¯ j , in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_15">14</ref>), as heterogeneity in both costs and utilities are not separately identified. The two segments of the content consumption model share a common utility parameter, 2 , but differ with respect to utility parameter,¯ j , and cost parameters,¯ 1j and¯ 2j . Note that the estimated segment specific effect (¯ j ) is equal and opposite in magnitude across two segments, which reflects the normalization needed for identification, as we discuss in §3.3.</p><p>Comparing the two groups, the second segment is larger in size and evidences higher reading and posting costs; hence, this group of users reads less often and rarely posts content. Thus, we denote them "light users." Also of note, the effect¯ j in the posting cost function is positive, so the users tend to post less at the end of the week.</p><p>Next we consider the parameter estimates in the site participation model. As indicated in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_11">6</ref>, the first segment participates more often because of their higher expected reading and posting utilities. This implies that reading and posting behaviors are correlated across users. Of note, conditional on reading and posting utilities, no parameters differ significantly between segments in the site participation model. This suggests that heterogeneity in site participation decisions are largely predicated on reading and posting utilities.</p><p>To quantify model fit, we simulate user reading, posting, and visiting data given the estimated parameter values in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_11">6</ref>. We then calculate the mean absolute percentage error (MAPE) between the simulated aggregate UGC, the average reading rate per post, and the number of visitors across 61 observed days and the corresponding observed values. These values are, respectively, 7.59%, 4.47%, and 7.04%, which shows that the model fits the data well. 19 <ref type="bibr">19</ref> We also fit two static models to the data. In the first model, we let users realize the flow utility from the net present value of their posts, but without the intertemporal ability to choose when to post. We find this static model fits the data much more poorly (log-likelihood = −1 50774 × 10 5 ) than our dynamic model (loglikelihood = −9 9972 × 10 −4 ). In the second model, we aggregate data to the weekly level to filter out daily variation and estimate a static model. Because the likelihoods are not comparable between daily and weekly models, we compute MAPE for the weekly average UGC and reading rate and find our model has better predictive performance than the weekly aggregate data model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Managing Content Quality and Quantity</head><p>In this section, we investigate how the site can manage its content to improve its traffic. We explore two types of content management strategies: influencing UGC and creating SSC. We consider SSC that looks identical to UGC from the perspective of the reader except in their quality (e.g., the sponsorship is not revealed in essence disguising SSC as UGC). We focus on disguised content to ensure that the parameters in our UGC reading model are valid for inferring how SSC affects user behavior. When a site sponsors content, readers choose the best content available across the entire set of UGC and SSC; if SSC is of better average quality than UGC, then it attracts more readers from UGC. To be more precise, define SSC quality distribution parameters S 1 = U S , S 2 = U S − L S analogous to the definition of the UGC quality distribution. By allowing U 1 , U 2 and S 1 , S 2 to differ, we can assess the role of user and sponsored content quality on site traffic, content consumption, and generation.</p><p>The optimal levels of reading for user and sponsored content, r S it and r U it , are the solutions to the optimization problem of the total reading payoff. In Web Appendix E, we derive the optimal total amount of reading and how it is allocated between UGC and SSC given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_45">r * S it r * U it = S 2 /K S t + 2i 2i 2i U 2 /K U t + 2i −1 • S 1 − i − 1it U 1 − i − 1it (<label>30</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_46">)</formula><p>Using this approach, we consider several content management strategies. First, we consider how the addition of SSC will affect current traffic. Second, we explore the role of SSC and UGC quality and quantity in tipping the network. We then conclude by considering how filtering posts can affect network traffic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.">Increasing Site Traffic by SSC</head><p>In the context of the site's current state of user engagement, the issue of how sponsored content affects site traffic and user engagement is germane. Increased site traffic is material because revenue typically arises from advertising, and advertising revenue increases with visits.</p><p>We simulate the effect of quality and quantity of SSC on UGC. Without loss of generality, we manipulate the quality of SSC by altering the lower bound of quality, S 2 . The upper bound of SSC quality is represented by S 1 , which we set to equal U 1 . This approach presumes that the site does not create relatively "bad" content. Note that higher S 2 also means that SSC has higher mean quality ( S 1 − S 2 /2) and less quality variation ( S 2 2 /12) than UGC. We set the quality of SSC to one of two levels: (i) equal to the quality of UGC (by letting S 2 / U 2 = 100%) or (ii) substantially higher than that of UGC ( S 2 / U 2 = 10%). The resulting aggregate UGC, number of visitors, and reading rate per post (normalized to the percentages of the corresponding values in the currently observed data) in equilibrium over a 70-day simulated sequence versus the levels of SSC are plotted in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref> demonstrates that SSC increases the number of visitors only slightly when the quality of SSC is equal to that of UGC (by 5% for a 10% increase in overall content). If the site can generate a sufficiently large quantity of much higher quality SSC ( S 2 / U 2 = 10%), the site can increase the participation rate by as much as 25%. Hence, the sponsored content arc elasticity is about 0.5 and 2.5 for these respective cases.</p><p>The increase in UGC is much less pronounced than the increase in participation owing to the competition between UGC and SSC. For a 10% increase in high quality SSC, there is a 6% increase in aggregate UGC (i.e., an arc elasticity equal to 0.6). For a 10% increase in equal quality SSC, there is a 1% increase in UGC (i.e., an arc elasticity equal to 0.1). An increase in high quality SSC from 7% to 10% actually dampens UGC, presumably because user posts are affected by the shift of readers to higher quality site-sponsored posts.</p><p>Similarly, the reading rate per post decreases to about 96% in the case when UGC and SSC have equal quality because of the competition effect. In the high quality SSC case, the increase in reading rate per post is moderate at about 9%.</p><p>Overall, we conclude that there is potential to grow the network primarily with very high quality SSC, but UGC will be adversely affected if the level of SSC exceeds about 7%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.">Network Tipping</head><p>In the preceding subsection, we considered a counterfactual analysis predicated on the current equilibrium state observed in the data, wherein the network has already become self-sustaining in terms of high user participation. Another potential equilibrium for the UGC platform is a state of extremely low user participation, where individual postings, reading, and site visiting are all close to zero. This also constitutes a stable equilibrium, because low UGC stock attracts very few readers, which will further attenuate posting activity. The site converges to an equilibrium of extremely low activity, which can be interpreted as the implosion of the network. This kind of network contraction has often been reported in the online community. For example, the UGC site TVTome.com, which used to have a large network of users, has since declined, and the domain name has been sold to TV.com.  To prevent network contraction, one way to tip the network to a self-sustaining high-activity equilibrium is to attract user content to the site (e.g., via marketing or advertising). A second approach, such as the strategy employed by Soulrider.com, is to sponsor a sufficiently high level of content to tip the network-either with a large initial amount or a regular but smaller stream of posts, or both. If it takes a large amount of user posts to tip the network, it might be sensible to "jump-start" the network by sponsoring posts rather than relying solely on user posts. It may be better for the site to sponsor posts early on than at a constant rate, because once the network tips, the site will no longer need to bear the expense of sponsoring. Although a definitive answer to these three strategies (incentivizing initial UGC, creating initial sponsored content only or regular sponsored content) depends on actual costs, one must first understand how these strategies affect network growth and exactly how much content is necessary to tip the network. Quantifying this amount is our aim in this section. 6.2.1. UGC on Tipping. We first consider the role of UGC stock on network tipping. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3</ref> demonstrates the relationship between the initial UGC, defined as the stock at the start of the network, and the subsequent steady-state equilibrium level of forum activities the network will ultimately attain (normalized to the percentages of aggregate UGC, the number of visitors, and the reading per post in the self-sustaining highactivity equilibrium). The critical UGC stock needed to tip the network is 10.7%; that is, when the initial UGC is below the 10.7% of the UGC in the highactivity equilibrium, the forum will collapse into the low-activity equilibrium wherein site participation rate reduces to only about 3%, UGC to only about 0.5%, and reading per post to about 8%. By contrast, when the initial UGC stock is 10.7% or greater, the site will reach 100% of the high activity.</p><p>It is worth noting that modeling rational expectations profoundly affects the tipping point of the network. Stated differently, the dynamics in the system, coupled with rational expectations, play a major role in the tipping point. When beliefs about the participation of others is not allowed to evolve with changes in the system, we find that 19% of the current observed levels of UGC is needed to tip the network. The rationale behind the 78% increase in the tipping point value when rational expectations are ignored is provided in §3.7; the updated beliefs about higher future reading rates and content increases the incentives to participate in it in the current period, thereby lowering the tipping point.</p><p>Next we consider the role of user heterogeneity in tipping. The heavy user segment, comprised of 43% of users, tends to both consume and generate content frequently. The light user segment tends predominantly to read. This light user segment is sometimes characterized as the lurking segment <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Preece et al. 2004)</ref>. Because they generate no content, lurkers alone cannot easily tip the network. However, they can have a considerable indirect effect on tipping, because those in the heavy user segment obtain more utility from content generation because of reading by lurkers. Our simulations find that the critical UGC stock needed for tipping is raised from 10.7% to 16% if the lurker segment is cut in half (though there is little effect if this segment is reduced by only 20%). To our knowledge, this is the first study to quantify the effect of a lurking segment on tipping rates. A key implication is that, if lurkers are cheap to attract, it can be more efficient to grow this segment to increase the marginal impact of heavy users on tipping. Because heavy users generate more content, one might surmise that targeting this group would tip the network the fastest. Indeed, for the frequent user segment, an initial endowment of the user post stock at 11% of the high-activity equilibrium level can tip the network even if we set the initial stock of light users to zero. By contrast, for light users, an initial endowment of user post stock at 80% of the highactivity equilibrium level can tip the network when we set the initial stock of frequent users to zero. Hence, the frequent user segment's role in network tipping is far more substantial, but a large population of lurkers can also tip a network.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.2.">SSC on Tipping.</head><p>Next we consider the role of SSC on tipping; that is, the site may invite sponsored content to "jump-start" user activity. We consider two approaches to jump-start the network, In the first, the site increases the initial SSC only. This strategy is analogous to sponsoring posts when the network is in the low-activity equilibrium and then stopping this practice after it tips. The impetus for this strategy is that the network will quickly become self-sustaining, such that the site no longer needs to bear the costs of sponsoring posts. Next we contrast these results to a case wherein, instead of initial SSC only, the site continues sponsoring posts on a regular basis and thus changes users' rational expectations regarding future SSC. We also consider the cases where the quality of SSC is either (i) equal to the quality of UGC (by letting S 2 / U 2 = 100%) or (ii) substantially higher than that of UGC ( S 2 / U 2 = 10%). The results of these analyses are reported in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4</ref>.</p><p>Results shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4</ref>(a) suggest that the initial SSC of 9.3% of the UGC in the high-activity equilibrium is sufficient to tip the network when the quality of SSC is equal to that of UGC, and that 1% is sufficient when the quality of SSC is much higher.</p><p>As evidenced in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4</ref>(b), the effect of sponsoring content on a regular basis tips the network at a level equivalent to 8% of the UGC in the high-activity equilibrium when site and user contents are equal in quality. The tipping point decreases further to 1% when the quality of SSC is much higher. The low tipping point arises because users perceive a regular stream of high quality content availability. Hence, we find it possible for the site to tip the network with a relatively small number of high quality posts, so long as the site is committed to sponsoring content for an indefinite period of time.</p><p>In summary, we contrast three strategies: (i) enlisting heavy users to post perhaps through marketing via targeted advertising or incentives, (ii) the site sponsoring initial posts only, and (iii) the site taking a more regular route to sponsoring posts. The first option takes the most posts to tip the network, and the last strategy the least. The key reason it takes more user than site posts to tip the network pertains to the diminishing marginal returns to user posting. When users' initial stock increases, the marginal effect of their next posting decreases. If the site sponsors posts instead, the value of SSC remains high enough to attract readers, but the individual user stock is sufficiently low, enhancing their incentive to post. Because of this, the site tips more quickly.</p><p>The preferred strategy would be incumbent on the relative cost of each. It is more effective for the site to jump-start with just initial posts (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4</ref>(a)) than with a constant stream of posts (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4</ref>(b)). However, the cost of the latter strategy is borne each period rather than once. Were the site able to sponsor high quality posts at a reasonable cost in a short period of time, this would favor the strategy of such posts at the network's start and then withdrawing completely after the network tips to the favorable equilibrium. Collectively, our counterfactual analyses indicate that site strategies have a profound effect on networks taking off, but a rather limited effect on the current steady-state level of user engagement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3.">Managing UGC Quality</head><p>Finally, we consider the possibility of filtering user content by removing low quality posts such as profanity or trolling. The results of this counterfactual are presented in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">5</ref>.</p><p>Predictably, reading rates increase as average quality increases. However, knowing that content is subject to removal, users tend to generate less content on Managing UGC Quality average. Stated differently, content remains as costly to produce, but it generates less expected utility. Given users create less content in response to having it filtered, the total drop in UGC will be greater than the amount of content removed by the site. The two forces (better quality, but less content available and less utility from posting) trade off in terms of overall participation. In terms of improving overall traffic (number of visitors), it appears optimal to only filter a small amount of content, on the order of 1% to 1.25%.</p><p>With a static utility model, the improvement in site use is overestimated by one percentage point when 1% of content is filtered, and the decrease in site use is underestimated by six percentage points when 5% of content is filtered. In other words, visitation is consistently overestimated. We conjecture this bias arises because the posting utility loss from not having future content not read is ignored; hence, site participation utility increases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">Conclusions</head><p>Recent advances in technology and media have enabled UGC sites to become an increasingly prevalent source of information for consumers as well as a more relevant channel for advertisers to reach users of these sites. Hence, the factors driving the use of these networks is of topical concern to marketers. In this paper, we consider how content, readership, and site policy drive the evolution of content and readership on these sites.</p><p>Since our goal is to develop prescriptive and theoretical insights regarding user engagement on UGC platforms, we build on the existing literature on social participation by developing a dynamic structural model to explore these effects. Individual reading behavior is developed from a model of information search that relates reading to the overall level of content on the site. Individual content generation is assumed to reflect the utility that users receive from others' reading the posts. Underpinning these two behaviors are users' beliefs regarding how the aggregate amounts of content and readership on the platform evolve. These beliefs stem from the rational expectations equilibrium model, whereby the evolution of aggregate reading and content states is assumed to be consistent with the aggregation of individual-level reading and contribution decisions across the population.</p><p>Our paper makes several contributions. On a methodological front, we develop a dynamic structural model of UGC. Of future interest, this approach can be applied to assess the formation or dissolution of similar networks, such as academic journals (readers and authors), social media sites, blogs, and so forth. Moreover, we extend the approximate aggregation approach along multiple dimensions, including (i) enabling a single unit of supply to be consumed concurrently by many, (ii) accommodating both continuous and discrete behaviors, and (iii) applying computational advances to enhance the scale of the problem solved. As a result, our approach facilitates the computation of a rational expectations equilibrium in the face of a large number of heterogeneous agents. Our advances could prove useful in other contexts in marketing and economics wherein firms face heterogeneous consumers.</p><p>On a theoretical dimension, we explore the tipping effects. We find that the potential exists for multiple equilibria depending on whether initial usage can cross a sufficient threshold to attract participation. Another theoretical insight is that UGC and SSC can serve as Marketing Science 35(2), pp. 284-303, © 2016 INFORMS strategic complements or substitutes depending on whether the primary demand effect of content (attracting more users) dominates the secondary demand effect (splitting readers). An analogous argument can be constructed for past and current posts as their durability increases. Finally, we note that dynamics play a role in determining the tipping. Ignoring future value of site participation leads to a lower utility of engagement and, therefore, higher tipping thresholds.</p><p>In a substantive domain, we consider a number of policy prescriptions to advise the site. First, we consider the role of sponsored content on user participation in a mature network. On one hand, sponsored posts attract more readers, thereby growing the network. On the other hand, these posts are competitive with other users' posts. Overall, we conclude that the former effect predominates and the site can increase participation if sponsored posts are of sufficiently higher quality. Second, we consider the effect of sponsored and user content in jump-starting a network. We find that the site can tip its network to a self-sustaining state by either incentivizing users to post or using sponsored content. When sponsored post quality is sufficiently high, it only takes about 1% of the observed posting levels in the mature network for tipping to occur. Our study offers evidence of the efficacy of this strategy. Finally, we consider the impact of filtering low quality user content. While filtering a small amount of very low quality content can increase site traffic, filtering a large amount of moderately poor quality content has an unambiguously deleterious effect on traffic.</p><p>Several opportunities for extensions are present. First, the potential for competition exists for forum sites and extending our work to competing platforms would be of interest. Our analysis focuses on the user side and abstracts from modeling the payoffs of UGC websites. This might be reasonable in many UGC contexts because studying dynamics and network effects on one site is important, but the competition between platforms is an area of interest. Second, it would be useful to extend our model to capture heterogeneity in content information to explore what information is most relevant in increasing site engagement. Relevantly, certain leading content creators generate large followings and measuring the effect of lead users is of practical interest. Of note, these extensions potentially involve a considerable expansion of the requirement for numerical computation to become feasible. Third, thanks to the institutional details characterizing our problem, it is not amenable to a closed form solution. An analytic approach might yield more generalized insights. Finally, our analysis considers a site where posts are not rated. The ratings of posts provide another incentive to post and would likely enter a joint postingrating utility function. Owing to the prevalence of sites with rated content, this is an interesting future direction.</p><p>In sum, we hope that our research will lead to additional innovations in both UGC and the application of the rational expectations equilibrium with approximate aggregation in marketing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplemental Material</head><p>Supplemental material to this paper is available at http://dx .doi.org/10.1287/mksc.2015.0937.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Summary Plots of Reading and Posting</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2Effect of SSC Strategies on Increasing Site Traffic</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3The Critical Point of Initial UGC</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4Effect of Sponsored Content Strategies</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5Managing UGC Quality</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Ahn, Duan, and Mela: Managing UGC: A Dynamic Equilibrium Approach Marketing Science 35(2), pp. 284-303, © 2016 INFORMS 285 in</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">The Effect of Aggregate UGC Stock on Individual Reading</cell></row><row><cell>Variable</cell><cell>Coefficient (std. error)</cell><cell>p-value</cell></row><row><cell>Aggregate UGC Stock</cell><cell>0 79 (0.21)</cell><cell>&lt;0 01</cell></row><row><cell>Individual Post Stock</cell><cell>0 11 (0.08)</cell><cell>0 19</cell></row><row><cell>End-of-Week Effect</cell><cell>−1 03 (0.51)</cell><cell>0 04</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>The Effects of Future Average Reading Rate per Post and End of Week on Individual Posting</figDesc><table><row><cell>Variables</cell><cell>Coefficient (std. error)</cell><cell>p-value</cell></row><row><cell>Average Reading Rate</cell><cell>0 14 (0.035)</cell><cell>&lt;0 01</cell></row><row><cell>per Post (current period)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Average Reading Rate</cell><cell>−0 053 (0.024)</cell><cell>0 03</cell></row><row><cell>per Post (next period)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Aggregate UGC Stock</cell><cell>0 0048 (0.0071)</cell><cell>0 50</cell></row><row><cell>Lagged Individual Post Stock</cell><cell>−0 013 (0.0031)</cell><cell>&lt;0 01</cell></row><row><cell>End-of-Week</cell><cell>−0 051 (0.0024)</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>Day Before End-of-Week</cell><cell>0 11 (0.026)</cell><cell>&lt;0 01</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">2.3.3. Exploratory Evidence of Dynamic Behavior.</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Following the approach outlined in</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>)</head><label></label><figDesc>Ahn, Duan, and Mela: Managing UGC: A Dynamic Equilibrium Approach</figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science 35(2), pp. 284-303, © 2016 INFORMS</cell><cell>293</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Estimation Results for the Aggregate UGC Stock Transition Equation and Average Reading Rate per Post Equation</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>AR(1) for UGC</cell><cell>Reading rate</cell></row><row><cell>Model parameter</cell><cell>stock</cell><cell>per post</cell></row><row><cell>Intercept K 0 or y 0</cell><cell>2 89 (1.35)</cell><cell>6 02 (0.94)</cell></row><row><cell>Lagged aggregate UGC stock K 1 Current aggregate UGC stock y 1 End-of-week effect K 2 or y 2</cell><cell>0 93 (0.33) -−0 69 (0.094)</cell><cell>-0 054 (0.0052) −0 55 (0.035)</cell></row><row><cell>Residual R 2</cell><cell>0.89</cell><cell>0.51</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Notes. Standard errors are in parentheses. All parameters are significant at</cell></row><row><cell>p-value &lt; 0 05.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>Table 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Estimation Results for the Parameters in Content Generation, Consumption, and Site Participation Models</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>First segment;</cell><cell>Second segment;</cell></row><row><cell>Parameters</cell><cell>frequent users</cell><cell>light users</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Content generation model</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Utility coefficient</cell><cell cols="2">0.79 (0.015)</cell></row><row><cell>Cost coefficient¯ j</cell><cell>1 29 (0.087)</cell><cell>6 83 (0.33)</cell></row><row><cell>End-of-week effect¯ j</cell><cell>8 99 (3.93)</cell><cell>9 60 (4.31)</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Content consumption model</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Utility coefficient 2</cell><cell cols="2">0.60 (0.092)</cell></row><row><cell>Utility heterogeneity coefficient¯ j</cell><cell>−0 70 (0.082)</cell><cell>0 70 (0.082)</cell></row><row><cell>End-of-week cost effect¯ 1j</cell><cell>−0 049 (0.040)</cell><cell>0 0052 (0.014)</cell></row><row><cell>Quadratic cost coefficient¯ 2j</cell><cell>0 026 (0.0023)</cell><cell>0 011 (0.0021)</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Site participation model</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Intercept, 0j</cell><cell>27.12 (13.23)</cell><cell>4.46 (2.11)</cell></row><row><cell>Reading scale parameter 1</cell><cell cols="2">0.51 (0.23)</cell></row><row><cell>Gumbel scale parameter</cell><cell cols="2">0.97 (0.014)</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Heterogeneity</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Segment size</cell><cell>43% (3.1%)</cell><cell>57% (3.1%)</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Note. Bootstrapped standard errors are in parentheses.</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4"><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Dubé et al. (2010)</ref> and<ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Katz and Shapiro (1994)</ref> define tipping as "the degree of market share concentration due to indirect network effects"(Dubé et al. 2010, p. 216). In our context, the indirect network effects for the platform arise from generation and consumption rather than software and hardware; tipping is defined as achieving the critical mass for the network to become self-sustaining.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">Note the sponsored content required to tip the network is lower than the user content needed to tip the network. As we discuss shortly, the difference arises when there are diminishing marginal returns to the utility of user content creation.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">Because of the context, in the remainder of the text we use content generation and posting interchangeably, in which case posting implies the posting of UGC.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">End of the week is defined as Thursday, Friday, and Saturday, as site usage is lower then. Because site activity is predominantly in the evening (over 50% of reading and posting appears from 4:00 p.m. to 11:59 p.m. Pacific Standard Time) and users tend to be young, we conjecture that the Thursday through Saturday end-of-week drop in site activity is due to the opportunity costs of other types of social activity such as heading out for the evening.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8">We note the following analyses are exploratory because there are no formal statistical tests of dynamics(Manski 1993, Magnac and<ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Thesmar 2002)</ref>. The relationship to the dynamics in our model is motivated in Web Appendix D.3 (available as supplemental material at http://dx .doi.org/10.1287/mksc.2015.0937).9  For a robustness check, we also test three additional models by eliminating the effects of day before the end of the week (Model 2) and the end of week (Model 3), and by adding the reading per post of the second next period (Model 4). The results show the same pattern of correlations. Overall, this exploratory regression analysis is consistent with the content generation model.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="10">In §6 we generalize our analysis to allow for SSC to differ in its quality from UGC.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="11">Because it is realized after a user visits the site, it is independent of the participation decision and uncorrelated with K t . It is not imperative to impose any parametric distribution on it , although we assume it to be exponential in Web Appendix C.1 to facilitate the maximum likelihood estimation.12  In Web Appendix A, we show that the users' expected reading rate per post, y t , can be closely approximated by the observed amount of reading per post under the assumption of rational expectations when the number of users and the UGC stock, K t , are both very large-so actual reading rates can be used in estimation. However, it is necessary to recompute this rational expectation equilibrium in our counterfactual analyses. (See §3.6 for more details.)</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">is necessary. In the counterfactual analyses, states need to be computed.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="16">We test the exogeneity of the decay parameter by regressing the log ratio of the times that a posting is read between periods t − 1 and t on the aggregate UGC and the average reading rate per post at period t. For our data (see the results in §5.1), we find neither factor to be statistically significant. This suggests that the decay parameter is independent of the aggregate activities of the forum and therefore exogenous.17  We also estimate the model with = 0 98, 0.95, and 0.90, and our insights remain unchanged.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="18">We also test three segments of users. However, the Bayesian information criterion for the three-segment model is higher than that for the two-segment model.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors would like to thank Joel Huber, Wagner Kamakura, Vineet Kumar, Oded Netzer, and seminar participants at Carnegie Mellon University, Erasmus University, Indiana University, King Carlos III University, Tilburg University, University of Chicago, University of Texas, and the 2011 Quantitative Marketing and Economics Conference for their comments. The authors also thank the Networks, Electronic Commerce and Telecommunications (NET) Institute (www.netinst.org) for partial financial support of this project.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating promotional activities in an online two-sided market of user-generated content</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Albuquerque</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pavlidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Chatow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Jamal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="406" to="432" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How companies can make the most of usergenerated content</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bughin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">McKinsey Quart</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="4" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of word of mouth on sales: Online book reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Chevalier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mayzlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="345" to="354" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New drug diffusion when forward-looking physicians learn from patient feedback and detailing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Goettler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="807" to="821" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Econometric measurement of the duration of advertising effect on sales</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="345" to="357" />
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategic manipulation of Internet opinion forums: Implications for consumers and firms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dellarocas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1577" to="1593" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do online reviews matter?-An empirical investigation of panel data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Duan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Gu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Whinston</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decision Support Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1007" to="1016" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving the numerical performance of static and dynamic aggregate discrete choice random coefficients demand estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dubé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2231" to="2267" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tipping and concentration in markets with indirect network effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dubé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hitsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="216" to="249" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical model of advertising dynamics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dubé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hitsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Manchanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="144" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://www.emarketer.com/newsroom/index.php/emarketer-review-key-2013-trends-coverage-areas-platform-growth/" />
		<title level="m">eMarketer in review-Key 2013 trends, coverage areas and platform growth</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A dynamic structural model of user learning on the mobile Internet. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ghose</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<pubPlace>New York University; New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incentivizing high-quality user-generated content</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ghosh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mcafee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 20th Internat. Conf. World Wide Web</title>
				<meeting>20th Internat. Conf. World Wide Web<address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="146" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electronic word-of-mouth via consumer-opinion platforms: What motivates consumers to articulate themselves on the Internet?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hennig-Thurau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Gwinner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Walsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Gremler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Interactive Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="38" to="52" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A structural model of employee behavioral dynamics in enterprise social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ghose</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2825" to="2844" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Duan</forename><surname>Ahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mela</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>© 2016 INFORMS 303</idno>
		<title level="m">Managing UGC: A Dynamic Equilibrium Approach Marketing Science</title>
				<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="284" to="303" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Patterns of entry and correction in large vocabulary continuous speech recognition systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Karat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Halverson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Horn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Karat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. SIGCHI Conf. Human Factors Comput. Systems</title>
				<meeting>SIGCHI Conf. Human Factors Comput. Systems<address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="568" to="575" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Systems competition and network effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Perspectives</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="115" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Antitrust in software markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Competition, Innovation and the Microsoft Monopoly Antitrust in the Digital Marketplace</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Eisenbach</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lenard</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="81" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Income and wealth heterogeneity in the macroeconomy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Krusell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="867" to="896" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intersectoral labor mobility and the growth of the service sector</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Wolpin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Network externality: An uncommon tragedy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Liebowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Margolis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Perspectives</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="150" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying dynamic discrete decision processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Magnac</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Thesmar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="801" to="816" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic choice in social settings: Learning from the experiences of others</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Manski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="136" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The long-term impact of promotion and advertising on consumer brand choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Mela</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="248" to="261" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online product opinions: Incidence, evaluation, and evolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Moe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Schweidel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="372" to="386" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why we blog</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nardi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Schiano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gumbrecht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Swartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What motivates Wikipedians?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Nov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="64" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The top five reasons for lurking: Improving community experiences for everyone</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Preece</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Nonnecke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Andrews</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Human Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Network characteristics and the value of collaborative user-generated content</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ransbotham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Kane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Lurie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="387" to="405" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structural estimation of Markov decision processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rust</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Econometrics</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Engle</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mcfadden</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>North-Holland, Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3081" to="3143" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heterogeneity and the dynamics of technology adoption</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Ryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="109" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social ties and user generated content: Evidence from an online social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Shriver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Nair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hofstetter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1425" to="1443" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The economics of information</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Stigler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="225" />
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structural estimation of discrete-choice games of incomplete information with multiple equilibria</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Judd</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Behavioral Quant. Game Theory: Conf. Future Directions, BQGT &apos;10</title>
				<meeting>Behavioral Quant. Game Theory: Conf. Future Directions, BQGT &apos;10<address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page">39</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Content contributor management and network effects in a UGC environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Evgeniou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Padmanabhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="433" to="447" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
