<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Modeling Choice Interdependence in a Social Network</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2013-10-08">October 8, 2013.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jing</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>jingwang16@gmail.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Anocha</forename><surname>Aribarg</surname></persName>
							<email>anocha@umich.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yves</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Atchadé</surname></persName>
							<email>yvesa@umich.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Gary</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">McKinsey &amp; Company</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>200020</postCode>
									<settlement>Shanghai</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>48109</postCode>
									<settlement>Ann Arbor</settlement>
									<region>Michigan</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Statistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>48109</postCode>
									<settlement>Ann Arbor</settlement>
									<region>Michigan</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Modeling Choice Interdependence in a Social Network</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 (print)</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2013-10-08">October 8, 2013.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.2013.0811</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: October 31, 2010; accepted: July 27, 2013</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:26+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>social interactions</term>
					<term>social network</term>
					<term>social influence</term>
					<term>homophily</term>
					<term>conjoint experiment</term>
					<term>Markov random field</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Researchers have long recognized that social interactions among individuals in a social network have an impact on their preference evolution and product adoptions. The rapid growth of social networking websites has facilitated social interactions to an unprecedented level. In addition to encouraging users to maintain current connections and build new ones on its site, Facebook automatically passes along information about users' site activities to their friends. For instance, when users become a fan of a brand page or respond to an interactive ad on the site, their friends receive a notification. These notifications are sent with the expectation that they may influence other users. Social interaction effects are also undoubtedly prevalent in off-line contexts. Individuals' decisions to purchase a hybrid vehicle, for example, may be influenced by recommendations from their neighbors. Teenagers' decisions to purchase certain brands of jeans can be influenced by observing their peers' choices. In this paper, we examine social interactions in a multiattribute choice context where we conceptualize choice interdependence in a social network as being driven by individuals' preference shifts induced by social interactions after controlling for their initial preferences.</p><p>Although extant research has attempted to measure social interaction effects (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Nair et al. 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">, Nam et al. 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b87">, Tucker 2008</ref>, it does not recognize that such effects may arise from different types of social influence. Prior behavioral research <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Bearden and Etzel 1982</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">, Burnkrant and Cousineau 1975</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">, Deutsch and Gerard 1955</ref> distinguishes a value-expressive influence from an informational social influence. Whereas an informational influence is driven by an individual's goal to gain more knowledge, a valueexpressive influence is driven by an individual's goal to maintain and enhance his or her self-perception or identity in relation to his or her peers. Given different goal orientations, consumers rely more on the credibility of the source of influence when it comes to an informational influence and more on <ref type="bibr">Wang, Aribarg, and Atchadé:</ref> Modeling Choice Interdependence in a Social Network</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>978</head><p>Marketing Science 32(6), pp. 977-997, © 2013 INFORMS desirable characteristics of the source when it comes to a value-expressive influence <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(McGuire 1969)</ref>. Given that we expect an informational influence to play a more important role for a technology-related product and a value-expressive influence for a fashionrelated product, we examine how experts (i.e., with more credibility) versus popular individuals (i.e., with a more desirable social characteristic) are asymmetrically more influential for technology-related versus fashion-related products. In addition, previous research suggests that two distinct groups of influentials and imitators may play different roles in the diffusion of innovations (Van den Bulte and Joshi 2007). That is, influentials tend to be opinion leaders <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Katz and Lazarsfeld 1955)</ref> and early adopters who influence, but are not or to a lesser degree influenced by, imitators. Provided with information about the sequence of choices, we also assess whether individuals are more influenced by the choices made by early decision makers than they are by choices made later.</p><p>Prior research has attempted to identify the causal effects of social interactions <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Hartmann et al. 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Manski 1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Manski , 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Moffitt 2001</ref>). With observational data, social interactions are likely confounded with homophily or endogenous group formation, correlated unobservables, and simultaneity. We propose a novel conjoint experiment for studying social interactions that helps alleviate these endogeneity concerns. Specifically, we examine choice interdependence in a social network and conceptualize consumer choices to be driven by multiattribute utilities. We conduct a two-stage choice experiment with a preinfluence stage and a postinfluence stage. The experiment also involves two product categories: one that is fashionrelated and another that is technology-related. In the preinfluence stage, we use a conjoint choice experiment to measure each participant's initial preferences for different product attributes that govern the utilities of the product choices. We also collect information about each participant's social connections within a closed social network. In the postinfluence stage, we conduct an incentive-aligned choice experiment to induce and observe choice interdependence within the network. This experimental design helps us identify preference shifts as a result of social interactions separately from initial preferences.</p><p>To study choice interdependence and identify the social interaction effects, researchers should be able to observe both individual choices and the sequence of choices (complete data). We fit a discrete-time Markov chain (DMC) model to the complete data. However, researchers often do not keep records of the sequence because of a capacity constraint, or in offline contexts, it may not even be feasible to observe the choice sequence. In these situations, researchers have to work with cross-sectional data, where realized choices are recorded only at a particular time point (snapshot data). We demonstrate how researchers can use a Markov random field (MRF) model as an alternative to a DMC model when only snapshot data are available. Given their theoretical connection, both DMC and MRF models are appropriate for modeling choice interdependence in a social network because both models properly account for the dependence structure in the data (i.e., the joint probability of individual choices).</p><p>Controlling for individuals' heterogeneous initial preferences, we find significant social interaction effects based on both the DMC and MRF models. Our findings suggest that, on the one hand, popular individuals (i.e., those with more connections) exert greater influence for a fashion-related product where value-expressive influence is more prominent. On the other hand, experts exert greater influence for a technology-related product where informational influence dominates. We also find that individuals who make choices earlier are more influential in the technology-related product category. This result alludes to the opinion leadership of early decision makers for this product category. Finally, our model comparison shows good out-of-sample predictive performance of the MRF model for the technologyrelated product.</p><p>The contribution of our paper is threefold. First, we assess how different types of influences, informational versus value-expressive, lead experts versus popular individuals to asymmetrically exert greater influence, respectively, for technology-related versus fashion-related products. We also examine the potential disproportionate influence of early decision makers. Second, coupled with network information, we demonstrate how researchers can use a two-stage conjoint choice experiment, which we conceptualize based on the multiattribute utility framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Keeney and Raiffa 1993)</ref>, to identify individual preference shifts induced by social interactions after controlling for their initial preferences. Our approach helps mitigate the endogeneity concern. Finally, given that we use the DMC to model choice interdependence when the information on both choices and their sequence is available, we examine how the theoretically connected MRF model can be used as an alternative when the sequence information is missing-a common occurrence in most online and off-line situations.</p><p>The rest of this paper is structured as follows. We begin with the literature review in relation to our conceptual framework and then present our modeling framework. This is followed by a description of our experimental design and data collection procedure. Our empirical analysis section includes (i) descriptive statistics of the participants and their social network, (ii) the analysis of individual-specific initial</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Literature Review and Conceptual Framework</head><p>There is a sizable body of literature on social interaction effects (also referred to as peer, neighborhood, and social contagion effects) in the fields of economics, sociology, and marketing. In economics, the primary focus is on identifying an "active" social interaction that gives rise to a social multiplier using observational data <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Brock and Durlauf 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Manski 1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Manski , 2000</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Hartmann et al. (2008)</ref> distinguish active from passive social interactions; the former involves two individuals' actions being simultaneously affected by the actions of the other and resolved as an equilibrium outcome (e.g., Hartmann 2010), whereas the latter treats the impact of an individual's action on the other's action as being sequential in nature. Although the concept of active social interactions originates in sociology <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Granovetter 1978</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b78">, Schelling 1971</ref>, the majority of work in this discipline does not hinge on an equilibrium assumption (i.e., focus on passive social interactions), and the emphasis is placed on how the structure of individuals' social network affects how social interactions propagate information diffusion in the network <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Granovetter 1973</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">, Katz and Lazarsfeld 1955</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b94">, Watts and Dodds 2007</ref>. Compared with sociology, not much attention has been paid to the structure of a social network in the economic literature. Early research in economics and sociology mainly proposes theoretical frameworks to characterize the mechanism of social interactions without corroborating empirical evidence.</p><p>Despite no explicit attempt to model social interactions, the marketing literature has long recognized their role (i.e., influentials versus imitators) in the diffusion of innovations <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Bass 1969</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b89">, Van den Bulte and Stremersch 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b90">, Van den Bulte and Wuyts 2007</ref>. With the availability of observational data especially in online contexts, research in marketing explicitly links social interactions to firm performance and product adoptions <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Godes et al. 2005</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">, Hartmann et al. 2008</ref>). On the one hand, some researchers have examined the effects aggregate word of mouth <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Chen et al. 2011</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">, Chevalier and Mayzlin 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">, Godes and Mayzlin 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b98">, Zhu and Zhang 2010</ref>, online viral marketing activities <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(De Bruyn and</ref><ref type="bibr">Lilien 2008, Toubia et al. 2011)</ref>, and online community participation <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Algesheimer et al. 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">, Manchanda et al. 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">, Stephen and Toubia 2010</ref>) have on aggregate sales. On the other hand, others attempt to establish the causal effects of social interactions on adoption decisions at the individual level <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">(Nair et al. 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">, Nam et al. 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b87">, Tucker 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b97">, Zhang 2010</ref>. A few researchers examine social interactions in a multiattribute utility framework 1 <ref type="bibr">(Narayan et al. 2011, Yang and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b95">Allenby 2003)</ref> or explicitly collect network information <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">(Nair et al. 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">, Narayan et al. 2011</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">, Reingen et al. 1984</ref>. In studying choice interdependence, we conceptualize individual choices to be driven by multiattribute utilities and focus on the passive form of social interactions. We incorporate explicit information on a network of individuals that is not endogenously determined by choice behavior.</p><p>None of the aforementioned research considers that social interaction effects may arise from different types of social influence. Behavioral research <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Bearden and Etzel 1982</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">, Bearden et al. 1989</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">, Burnkrant and Cousineau 1975</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">, Deutsch and Gerard 1955</ref> distinguishes a value-expressive influence from an informational social influence. According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Kelman (1958</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Kelman ( , 1961</ref>, whereas an informational influence operates through the internalization process, a valueexpressive influence operates through the identification process. An informational influence is driven by an individual's goal to gain more knowledge to make informed decisions. Faced with uncertainty, individuals seek information from sources that are viewed as credible <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(DeBono and Harnish 1988</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">, Kelman 1958</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">, McGuire 1969</ref>. In contrast, a value-expressive influence 2 is driven by someone's goal to maintain and enhance their self-perception or identity by associating with a reference group <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Belk 1988</ref>). These individuals would associate (disassociate) themselves with a reference group they perceive as being positive (negative) <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">(Miller et al. 1993)</ref>. As a result, they rely on desirable characteristics of the information source, such as attractiveness <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(DeBono and</ref><ref type="bibr">Harnish 1988, Kelman 1958)</ref>, as criteria to judge the value of the information. <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Park and Lessig (1977)</ref> suggest that the extent to which different types of social influence affect an individual's brand selection varies by product category. Informational influence plays a more important role for a technology-related product; therefore, 1 Some research relies on the random utility framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Brock and</ref><ref type="bibr">Durlauf 2001, Hartmann 2010)</ref> but not the multiattribute utility framework.</p><p>2 Previous research distinguishes two types of normative influence: (i) a value-expressive influence, which is motivated by selfmaintenance or enrichment, and (ii) a utilitarian influence, which is motivated by external rewards. We focus only on a subtype of normative influence, the value-expressive influence, because it simplifies the connection between the type of social influence and technology-related versus fashion-related products. Note, however, despite their conceptual differences, researchers have had difficulty in empirically distinguishing value-expressive and utilitarian influences <ref type="bibr">(Bearden et al. 1989, Burnkrant and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Cousineau 1975)</ref>.</p><p>Marketing Science 32(6), pp. 977-997, © 2013 INFORMS we expect that individuals pay more attention to the source credibility, and experts exert an asymmetrically larger influence in this product category. In contrast, value-expressive influence dominates in a fashion-related product; therefore, we expect that individuals focus more on the desirable characteristics of the source, and popular individuals exert an asymmetrically larger influence in this product category. The asymmetric effects of social interactions have been documented in the prescription drug <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">(Nair et al. 2010</ref>) and video messaging <ref type="bibr" target="#b87">(Tucker 2008</ref>) categories. However, the study contexts primarily involve informational influences. In addition, <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Nair et al. (2010)</ref> examine asymmetric social interaction effects for prescription decisions-decisions for others, not for one's self. <ref type="bibr" target="#b87">Tucker (2008)</ref> studies social interactions in the presence of network externalities-a larger number of adopters enhance product performance and benefits. We study choice interdependence in the absence of network externalities.</p><p>In the context of diffusion of innovations, influentials may have a greater influence than imitators (Van den Bulte and Joshi 2007, Van den Bulte and Wuyts 2007). Influentials are early adopters of innovations, who are likely to be opinion leaders <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Katz and Lazarsfeld 1955</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">, Myers and Robertson 1972</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">, Rogers and Cartano 1962</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Czepiel (1974)</ref> reports early adopters to exhibit great opinion leadership in the diffusion of technological innovation among competing firms. <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Nair et al. (2010)</ref> find that research-active specialists who are supposed to be early decision makers exert asymmetrically higher influence. Although not in the context of innovation adoptions, <ref type="bibr" target="#b86">Trusov et al. (2010)</ref> also document that users who have been a member of a social networking site for a longer period of time (measured by the months a user has been a member) are more influential than others in stimulating activities on the site. Given the information about the choice sequence, we also assess whether early decision makers (i.e., influentials) have a greater influence than later decision makers (i.e., imitators). In studying choice interdependence, we examine how experts versus popular individuals exert asymmetrically greater influence for technology-related versus fashion-related products, respectively, and how the choices made by early decision makers may be disproportionately more influential.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Modeling Framework</head><p>To examine choice interdependence in a social network, it is desirable to have complete longitudinal choice data where both choices and their sequence are observed. With the choice sequence information, we can examine how observed choices in a particular order may be more influential than others. It also allows us to model not only which choice is made but also who is likely to make a choice at a particular time. Snapshot data, on the other hand, are cross-sectional choice data collected at a fixed time point. This type of data is easier and less expensive to obtain. However, a lack of information on the choice sequence makes it difficult to understand the dynamic process because different processes can give rise to the same snapshot data. No matter what type of data is available, we need to model all consumers' choices jointly rather than independently to properly preserve the dependence structure in the data. In modeling choice interdependence, we treat the social network as being exogenous and fixed instead of modeling its formation or properties <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Ansari et al. 2011</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">, Iacobucci and Hopkins 1992</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">, Reingen and Kernan 1986</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b94">, Watts and Dodds 2007</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discrete-Time Markov Chain for Complete Data</head><p>Besides sociology, social networks and their influences on individuals' behavior have also sparked interests of researchers in other fields, such as statistics and computer science. Some researchers <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Hoff et al. 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">, Hunter 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">, Robins et al. 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b93">, Wasserman and Pattison 1996</ref> primarily focus on modeling the structure (i.e., connections among nodes) and properties of a social network, whereas others <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Hill et al. 2006)</ref>, like us, attempt to model the behavior of the network nodes, e.g., choice decisions such as in our study. For instance, <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Koskinen and Snijders (2007)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">Snijders et al. (2007)</ref> model the dynamics of network formation and behavioral evolution simultaneously by collecting the snapshot data of network structure and behavioral outcomes at more than one time point (e.g., every three months). However, the authors collect data at a few time points. As such, between two consecutive time points there are multiple processes that can lead to the same observed behavioral outcomes. They hence use a continuoustime Markov process to fit the data and treat the possible processes between consecutive time points as latent variables to be augmented. With complete data, we do not need to rely on augmented variables and adopt a simpler DMC model <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">(Ross 1996)</ref>.</p><p>Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Koskinen and Snijders (2007)</ref>, we assume that at most one individual may make a choice decision at a given time (i.e., no multiple decisions are allowed simultaneously). This assumption is reasonable in the context of sequential choice such as ours because it is unlikely that two individuals will make choice decisions at the exact same time. The assumption simplifies our model specification because we do not need to handle the possible dependence of the transitions made at the same time. The state of the Markov chain hence has two parts: (i) who is likely to make a choice and (ii) the choices made by all n individuals in a network at a particular time. Again, we emphasize that the state of the Markov chain involves all individuals' choices rather than a single person's as a result of the interdependence. We denote "who is likely to make a choice" at time t by c t , which takes values from 1 to n, and individual i's choice at time t by Y t i , which takes nominal values 0 K. The state at time point t is S t = c t Y t 1 Y t n . The first-order Markovian property dictates that p s t+1 s 1 s t = p s t+1 s t (1)</p><p>Under the assumption that only one transition is allowed, only one person's choice Y t+1 c t+1 can be different from Y t c t+1 , while all other choices remain the same, Y t+1 j = Y t j for j = c t+1 . Then we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">p s t+1 s t = p c t+1 = i y t+1 i c t y t I y t+1 −i = y t −i = p c t+1 = i c t y t p y t+1 i c t+1 = i c t y t •I y t+1 −i = y t −i (2)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">y −i = y 1 y i−1 y i+1 y n . The likelihood is p s 1 s T s 0 = T −1 t=0 p s t+1 s t</formula><p>, where y 0 and c 0 are to be specified later. Researchers can postulate any probability form of interest for P c t+1 = i c t y t</p><p>. Conditional on c t , there is great flexibility in specifying the multinomial choice probability p y t+1 i c t+1 = i c t y t (e.g., a multinomial logit). We include I y t+1 −i = y t −i for completion to ensure that only one choice can be made at a time. Note that a transition is determined by an individual attempting to make his or her choice. Given that DMC models everyone's choices together, it preserves the interdependence within the system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Markov Random Field for Snapshot Data</head><p>Recognizing that many times researchers may not have information on the choice sequence, we examine the use of an MRF model with snapshot data. Despite the differences in the formulation and type of data they handle, DMC and MRF are closely connected. We provide a proof in Online Appendix A (available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/ mksc.2013.0811) that under certain conditions, the DMC converges to the MRF, or, in other words, the MRF is an equilibrium model for the DMC.</p><p>The MRF is the general generating function for a multivariate logistic (MVL) choice model. (A detailed description of the MRF structure is provided in Online Appendix B.) MVL models have been used in marketing for studying consumer market baskets <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">(Russell and Peterson 2000)</ref>, multiple-category price competition <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">(Song and Chintagunta 2006)</ref>, multiplecategory incidence and quantity <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">(Niraj et al. 2008)</ref>, product recommendations <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Moon and Russell 2008)</ref>, and coordinated choice decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b96">(Yang et al. 2010</ref>). An MVL that involves binary choices is referred to as an autologistic model and one that involves multinomial choices as an auto-model.</p><p>An auto-model <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Besag 1974</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Besag , 1975</ref> is essentially a special case of the MRF. We denote individual i's choice by y i ; i = 1 n. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b96">Yang et al. (2010)</ref>, each choice is dummy coded as a vector of 0 and 1; e.g., y i = 0 1 0 indicates that among the three choice options, individual i chooses option 2. The joint distribution of the auto-model takes the form of p y 1 y n = exp 1≤i≤n y i U y i + 1≤i&lt;j≤n ij y i y j /z , where U y i is a function capturing individual i's own preferences, ij y i y j captures choice interdependence, and z is the normalizing constant that sums over all possible values of y = y 1 y n . The parameter ij = 0 when choice decisions of individuals i and j are independent. Given the restrictive specification of ij y i y j , the automodel can only accommodate symmetric social influence effects ij = ji . The MRF allows for any functional form to capture choice interdependence and thus can accommodate asymmetric effects of social interactions. (A technical discussion appears in Online Appendix B.)</p><p>To incorporate influence asymmetry, some necessary conditions need to be met for both DMC and MRF. The first condition involves a clearly defined identity of each node at either the individual or role level (e.g., some people are experts on high-tech products whereas others are novices). The second condition is that statistics corresponding to the parameters for asymmetry must have different values, which most of the time are satisfied in a directed network. To identify asymmetric influence at the individual level, researchers also need to observe more than one choice for each individual. If node identities are defined at the role level, one decision per individual will be sufficient as long as aggregate statistics associated with each role differ.</p><p>As the group size grows, the MRF, as well as the auto model, suffers from the intractable normalizing constant problem. Specifically, because z involves summing over all possible values of y, its computation can become intractable. Given that our paper involves a large social network, we demonstrate the use of an efficient approximate sampling algorithm <ref type="bibr">(Murray et al. 2006, Wang and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b91">Atchadé 2014</ref>; see also Online Appendix C) to circumvent the intractable normalizing constant problem in estimating an MRF model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experimental Design and Data Collection Experimental Design</head><p>Overview. We conduct a two-stage conjoint choice experiment: a preinfluence stage and a postinfluence Marketing Science 32(6), pp. 977-997, © 2013 INFORMS stage. The experiment also involves two products: a bundle of university sports paraphernalia and a Bluetooth ® headset. Our multistage conjoint design is in line with previous research examining reference group influence 3 <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Aribarg et al. 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">, Arora and Allenby 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">, Narayan et al. 2011</ref>) using conjoint experiments. In the preinfluence stage, for each product we use a standard conjoint choice experiment <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Haaijer and Wedel 2003)</ref> to measure each participant's initial preferences (i.e., part-worths) for different product attributes that govern the utilities of the product choices he or she makes. We then collect information about the participants' connections within a relatively well-connected and closed social network. Our network involves undergraduate students who took an introduction to marketing class in the fall of 2009 at a Midwest university. The majority of participants knew each other. We expect this network to be denser than that of a randomly selected group of students.</p><p>In the postinfluence stage, we conduct a field conjoint experiment where we ask participants to enter two raffles as a token of appreciation-in addition to class credits-for their participation in the preinfluence stage. Each participant may opt out of the raffles. Our design is consistent with the incentivealigned design discussed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Ding (2007)</ref>. We notify the participants that they will receive an email with a Web page link from which they can make a prize choice (from four possible options) should they win one of the raffles. Each of these prize options is described by product attributes for which we measure individualspecific part-worths of the participants in the preinfluence stage. Participants make a series of choices in the preinfluence stage but only make one prize choice for each product in the postinfluence stage. The choice set in the postinfluence stage also does not overlap with any choice set in the preinfluence stage. To induce choice interdependence, we show the participants on the Web page the choices made by their friends (including "no choice"). We let the choice interdependence process evolve organically and collect longitudinal data of choices sequentially made. All choices are recorded in real time (complete data). As a result, we also obtain cross-sectional data that are the realization of the complete data at the end of the study (snapshot data).</p><p>Fashion-Related vs. Technology-Related Products. We regard university sports paraphernalia as a fashion-related product and a Bluetooth headset as a technology-related product. Choice decisions for both products are likely affected by reference group influences because they can be easily "seen or identified by others" <ref type="bibr">Etzel 1982, Bourne 1957)</ref>. The products are also of interest to the student population. <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Park and Lessig (1977)</ref> develop a series of Likert scale questions to measure the extent to which informational and value-expressive influences are relevant to a consumer's brand selection for a product. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> We use these questions to validate our product selection.</p><p>We recruit 78 participants from the undergraduate student population at the same university. Each participant rates both products on this scale. We randomize the order of products being rated across participants. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> The findings show that for sports paraphernalia, the mean value-expressive influence (4.139, SD = 0 549) is significantly higher than the mean informational influence (2.994, SD = 0 980; t = 9 177), whereas for the Bluetooth headset, the mean informational influence (4.034, SD = 0 655) is significantly higher than the mean value-expressive influence (3.709, SD = 0 791; t = 2 884). The mean informational influence is also significantly higher for the Bluetooth headset than for sports paraphernalia (4.034 versus 2.994; t = 7 745). In contrast, the mean valueexpressive influence is significantly higher for sports paraphernalia than for the Bluetooth headset (4.139 versus 3.709; t = 4 509). These results validate the use of university sports paraphernalia as a product that involves a value-expressive influence and a Bluetooth headset as a product that involves an informational influence.</p><p>Identification of Social Interaction Effects. Observed correlation in the behavior of individuals who belong to the same reference group may not indicate that someone's action has a causal effect on the actions of the others in the group. Previous research has extensively discussed the identification (i.e., the causal inference) of social interaction effects from potential confounds, including homophily or <ref type="bibr">4</ref> We include all 14 items that are supposed to measure three types of influence, informational, utilitarian, and value-expressive, although we only report the results for the two types of influence that are relevant to our research. The complete analysis is available from the authors upon request. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> A factor analysis shows that for the value-expressive influence, all five items form a single factor. However, for the informational influence in the Bluetooth category, two out of five items appear to capture a different underlying factor from the other three that capture the majority of the explained variance. Upon further investigation, we decide to use only these three statements because they are also more relevant to the product categories in our study. We drop two statements: (i) the brand that the individual selects is influenced by observing a seal of approval of an independent testing agency and (ii) the individual's observation of what experts do influences his choice of a brand (such as observing the type of car the police drive or the brand of television TV repairmen buy). endogenous group formation, correlated unobservables, and simultaneity <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(Manski 1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Manski , 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Moffitt 2001)</ref>. Homophily describes the reverse causality effect of social interactions where the correlated behavior of individuals within a reference group results from the individuals' tendencies to form social connections with others who share similar tastes and preferences, and not a causal effect of someone's behavior on another.</p><p>In economics, the collection of exogenous social network information is rare. Social connections are sometimes inferred from the observed behavior with a sensitivity to social interactions that researchers aim to study <ref type="bibr" target="#b87">(Tucker 2008)</ref> or the geographic and/or demographic proximities of individuals <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Bell and Song 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">, Nam et al. 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b95">, Yang and Allenby 2003</ref>. Such procedures have the potential to interject a homophily problem into a study. Different methods are proposed as remedies. With the availability of panel data, one can specify a model with individual fixed <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">(Nair et al. 2010)</ref> or random effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Hartmann 2010)</ref> to control for individual preferences for a behavior or an action. Alternatively, researchers can simultaneously model the group formation process, which requires exclusion restrictions <ref type="bibr" target="#b81">(Steglich et al. 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b87">, Tucker 2008</ref>, or use other exogenous variables to help separate social interaction effects from homophily <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">(Nam et al. 2010)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Aral et al. (2009)</ref> propose a dynamic matched sample estimation framework to tease out correlated product adoption that can be explained by observable individuals' characteristics and behavior. <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Bramoullé et al. (2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">), Hartmann et al. (2008</ref>, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Manski (1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Manski ( , 2000</ref> advocate more research to collect network information that is exogenous to the focal behavior to circumvent homophily. The social network in our study is determined by the frequency with which participants interact, not their choice behavior. However, one may expect individuals who interact frequently to have similar preferences for certain product attributes, such as a particular brand <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Reingen et al. 1984)</ref>. We control for potential homophily by accounting for each participant's utility (i.e., overall preference) for each prize option presented to him or her in the postinfluence stage. Each option's utility is derived from each participant's partworths-capturing his or her initial preferences for different product attributes-estimated from the preinfluence stage. In addition to network information, <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Manski (2000)</ref> encourages more research to explicitly elicit preferences using an experimental approach. Our design employs both elements.</p><p>Shalizi and Thomas (2011) distinguish latent homophily from homophily. The authors argue that even when researchers tease out homophily by conditioning on previous behavior or action (e.g., jumping off a bridge) and observable individual traits including preference (e.g., fondness of jumping of a bridge), the presence of unobservable individual traits that drive the preference for the action (e.g., a thrill-seeking propensity trait) and engender the social tie (e.g., a bond formed by a common thrillseeking propensity) still confounds the social interaction effects with latent homophily. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Most research studying social interactions cannot easily measure the latent preference driving the action under investigation (e.g., technology adoption, school performance) and controls for preference only at the action level (e.g., adding fixed effects to a model intercept). In contrast, conjoint experiments allow us to precisely measure individuals' intrinsic preferences at the characteristic of the action level (i.e., preferences for attributes of a choice). In a way, we measure the latent attribute preferences (e.g., the element of thrillseeking in jumping off a bridge) that drive the utility (i.e., overall preference) of each choice option. Our multiple choice tasks in the preinfluence stage are created based on an optimal design, which aims to maximize the efficiency of part-worth estimates. As a result, each choice option, including those in the postinfluence stage, is hypothetically created and entirely determined by the attributes that characterize the option. As such, the possibility that a prize choice is influenced by latent factors other than a participant's latent initial attribute preferences and induced social interactions is minimal.</p><p>Correlated unobservables can be explained by individuals behaving similarly because of their likely exposure to the same external stimuli (e.g., individuals in the same zip code receive the same promotion from a car dealership). The use of geographic and demographic proximities to infer social relations can further exacerbate this type of endogeneity. The inclusion of individual fixed effects helps mitigate both homophily and correlated unobservables concerns. However, with observational data, researchers may need to also include time fixed effects and additional variables that help control for time-varying changes that are specific to each individual <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">(Nair et al. 2010</ref>). In our study, all participants make their prize choices on an identical Web page within a short time frame. There are no promotions on the sports paraphernalia items we use during the raffle period, and the Bluetooth headset options are hypothetical. In fact, outside marketing activities should not concern us; our focal behavior is prize choice, which is costless to the participants, and everyone has an equal probability of winning. The only difference across the participants is the information about prize choices made by Marketing Science 32(6), pp. 977-997, © 2013 INFORMS their friends. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> We thus expect the impact of correlated unobservables to be minimal.</p><p>Finally, the simultaneity issue may arise if individuals make choices at the same time. Given our emphasis on studying passive social interactions in a sequential choice context, our experimental design separates preinfluence from postinfluence choices and exploits the choice sequence information. The imposition of temporal ordering makes simultaneity not relevant in our research <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Hartmann et al. 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">, Manski 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">, Narayan et al. 2011</ref>.</p><p>More recent research advocates the use of randomized experiments to identify social interaction effects. Several experimental procedures have been proposed: (i) a random assignment of group membership <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Moffitt 2001</ref>); (ii) with mutually exclusive reference groups, a random assignment of members in each group to a treatment (e.g., a policy intervention) or a control condition <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Moffitt 2001</ref>); (iii) a random assignment of individuals either to one of the treatment conditions where different types of social cues are present or to a control condition where the social cue is absent <ref type="bibr">Walker 2011, Bakshy et al. 2012)</ref>; and (iv) for each adopter, a random assignment in which some of his or her peers receive information about the adoption and the rest receive no information <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Aral and Walker 2012)</ref>. Despite the merits of these approaches <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">(Rubin 1974)</ref>, a few caveats exist. The random assignment of group membership can change the structural nature of social interactions; hence, the less obtrusive nature of the last three approaches makes them more appealing. Nonetheless, the last three approaches are more appropriate for a social network wherein reference groups do not overlap. Overlapping connections across members can create leakage <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Aral and Walker 2011)</ref> or incompatibility across conditions. In our social network, friendships are intertwined across participants. Therefore, it is not plausible to create nonoverlapping treatment and control conditions that allow us to conduct simple mean comparison analyses. Obtaining good data from a randomization approach also requires having an adequate sample size in each experimental condition. As a result, our research uses a statistical modeling approach where we control for initial preferences directly as an alternative to using a randomized controlled experiment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Collection Procedure</head><p>As mentioned earlier, our data collection procedure consists of pre-and postinfluence stages. The preinfluence stage involves measuring initial preferences for different attributes of a university sports paraphernalia bundle and a Bluetooth headset and collecting their network information. For sports paraphernalia, we created product bundles based on four attributes: jacket style (four levels: blue style 1, grey style 1, blue style 2, and grey style 2), T-shirt color (two levels: blue and white), hat style (two levels: 1 and 2), and price (four levels: $39, $49, $59, and $69). We included six attributes for the Bluetooth headset: brand (two levels: Motorola and Plantronics), color (two levels: black and silver), weight (two levels: 8 and 13 grams), talk time per battery charge (two levels: five and eight hours), noise cancellation (two levels: yes and no), and price (four levels: $49, $59, $69, and $79). For each product, a blocked design involving 10 sets of 12 quadruples was created using an optimal design generated by SAS OPTEX <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Kuhfeld et al. 1994)</ref>. Participants were randomly assigned to 1 of the 10 sets and complete 12 choice tasks (each with four options). We also included a fifth baseline option of "an earplugged wired headset at $29" for the Bluetooth headset category.</p><p>To collect social network information, we first asked the participants to nominate 10 students in the class with whom they had interacted most frequently. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> To ensure privacy, <ref type="bibr">9</ref> we later provided the participants with an option to indicate to which nominees they were unwilling to disclose their choice information. We then invited the participants to enter the two raffles. We finally collected demographic information including gender, time spent on email daily, confidence in apparel taste, knowledge about cell phone headsets, and interest in winning the products.</p><p>In the postinfluence stage, we first launched the online raffle for sports paraphernalia. All participants received an email that included the URL that directed them to a Web page. On the page, they could select one of four sports paraphernalia bundles they wished to receive should they win the raffle. The four prize options were described by the same attributes as those used in the preinfluence stage (see Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>). <ref type="bibr">10</ref> The four options were relatively close to one another with regard to their overall utilities (computed from the part-worth estimates obtained from the preinfluence stage) and were pretested with a similar pool of participants to ensure similar choice shares. To facilitate choice interdependence, we showed the participants the choices that were previously made by their "friends." 11 One's friends are other participants who specified him or her as someone they had interacted with frequently and agreed to share choice information with in the preinfluence stage. For sports paraphernalia, we expected that the participants' product decisions may also be influenced by a larger-scale social interaction based on gender (i.e., gender norm) <ref type="bibr">(Brock and Durlauf 2001, Miller and 11</ref> To further induce social interactions, the experiment featured the real-time delivery of friends' choices during the raffle period. The procedure works as follows: The first time a participant makes a choice, or every time he or she changes a choice, emails are sent out to his or her friends. The email informs each participant's friends about his or her most recent activity and urges the friends to visit the raffle page. The Web page URL is included in the email.</p><p>Prentice 1996). To examine whether the influence of gender norm can coexist with the social influence at the reference group level (i.e., global versus local social interactions), we showed each participant the aggregate proportions of other participants choosing each option. The aggregate proportions were computed based on (1) all participants who had already chosen each option, (2) only female participants who had already chosen each option, and (3) only male participants who had already chosen each option at a particular time point. The participants could change their prize choice as often as they wished before the end of the raffle. We informed them that if they did not make a choice, one of the four bundles would be drawn randomly as their prize should they win the raffle. Our database was updated in real time to ensure that the Web page offered up-to-date information about friends' activities. To increase the response rate, we sent an email reminder in the middle of the raffle.</p><p>A week later we launched the second raffle for the Bluetooth headset. The setup was similar to the paraphernalia raffle except that participants did not see the aggregate proportions of male and females who chose each Bluetooth option. We did not expect a gender norm to be relevant for this product category. In addition, the default option for the participants who did not make a prize choice was a wired headset priced at $29 (the outside option we used in the conjoint experiment in the preinfluence stage). The raffle was closed after a week. Two email reminders were sent out during this period. A winner was drawn for each raffle at the conclusion of the study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Empirical Analysis</head><p>Descriptive Statistics of Participants and Their Social Network Participant Profile. There were 292 participants in the preinfluence stage, 215 of which agreed to participate in the raffles in the postinfluence stage. The general demographic profiles of the participants who agreed to enter the raffles and those who did not were not significantly different, except that those in the raffles were more interested in the products they could win (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>). All the analysis discussed below is based on these 215 participants.</p><p>Among the 215 raffle participants, 21.4% rated their confidence in apparel taste greater than 6 on a 1 to 7 scale, with 1 being least confident, and 18.6% rated their level of knowledge about cellphone headsets greater than 5 on a scale from 1 to 7, with 1 being not knowledgeable. More than half of the participants were "very interested" in winning a sports paraphernalia bundle, giving this a rating of 7 on a 1 to 7 scale, with 1 being "not interested all at"; the mean rating was 5.99. For the Bluetooth headset, interests were more evenly distributed, although one-third of the ratings were 7 (on a 1-7 scale), and the mean rating was 4.51.</p><p>Social Network Profile. Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> depicts the directed social network among the raffle participants. Each node represents a participant. Recall that in our experiment one's friends are defined as participants who nominate him or her as one of those with whom they have frequently interacted and agree to share choice information. In other words, a participant cannot choose his or her friends. It is other participants who nominate themselves to be his or her friends. An arrow indicates the direction of the nomination. For instance, an arrow from node 110 to 2 means participant 110 nominates participant 2 and becomes one of participant 2's friend. A doubleheaded arrow between 185 and 196 means both participants nominate each other. Among the 628 pairs of connected participants (the same two individuals are only counted as one pair), 26.6% of them have double-headed arrows in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> (i.e., have reciprocal connections).</p><p>It is not surprising that a small group of participants in the network are substantially more popular (i.e., many other students nominate each of them as one of their friends) than the rest. We use the size of each node to represent the number of friends each participant has. The bigger the node is, the larger the number of friends he or she has (i.e., the more arrows pointing inward in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>). Participants 9, 110, and 140 are examples of the popular participants. On the flip side, we use color to denote the number of others each participant nominates. Each of the three orange nodes, 24, 50, and 121, nominates nine students (nine arrows pointing outward) although they themselves do not get as many nominations from others (i.e., fewer arrows pointing inward). From this plot, we do not see a strong correlation between popularity (being nominated) and the number of nominations. Nodes of the same size can thus have a variety of colors.</p><p>The network solicitation procedure leads to participants having 3.7 friends on average. The most popular participants have 12 friends, whereas 14 participants have no friends. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> provides some network structure statistics. As expected, the density, reciprocity, and transitivity are low because we worked with a relatively large network. Two characteristics of our experimental setup also contribute to the network's sparse nature. First, we asked each participant to select up to 10 friends with whom they interacted most frequently for a practical reason. <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Narayan et al. (2011)</ref> allow participants to nominate up to N − 1 (the N sample size = 70) others as their influencers. This would have been a timely prohibited task for us with 292 participants-and we propose a design that is applicable for a large network.</p><p>Other researchers take a similar approach in restricting the number of nominations per participant <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Leider et al. 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">, Nair et al. 2010</ref>. Second, because participants' choices were shared along with their names, to protect privacy, participants were given the right to opt out from sharing choice information with the friends they nominated, which makes our network even sparser. Unlike in <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Centola (2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Centola ( , 2011</ref> where people do not know each other before the experiment and their information is shared with the screen names they choose-which eliminates the privacy issue-our experiment hinges on actual friendship and cannot get around the privacy issue. Privacy is also not a concern in a field experiment, where focal behavior is naturally expected to be observed among peers <ref type="bibr">Walker 2011, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>As noted in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref>, 4.2% of the participants receive no nomination from other students, although they nominate at least one other student as their friend (i.e., arrow pointing outward only). We observe that 85.1% of the participants share choices with at least one friend, and 93.5% of the participants can observe at least one other participant's choice. At the same time, 14.9% (the percentage with arrows pointing inward only + the percentage that are isolated) are not willing to nominate anybody with whom they will eventually share their choice information.</p><p>The major difference between them and those sharing choice information is that they are more socially peripheral; i.e., they have fewer friends sharing choice information with them (on average, 2.4 versus 3.9  e ij e j i e ii /n n − 1 n − 2 0 007%</p><p>Note. e ij = 1 if i nominates j, 0 otherwise.</p><p>Wang, Aribarg, and Atchadé: Modeling Choice Interdependence in a Social Network</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>988</head><p>Marketing Science 32(6), pp. 977-997, © 2013 INFORMS friends). There is no significant difference in other demographic profiles except that participants not sharing are on average less knowledgeable about a cell phone headset (3.1 versus 3.7 on a 1-7 point scale).</p><p>Raffle Choice Summary. For sports paraphernalia, 167 participants visited the Web page, and 62.3% of them were male, which is similar to the proportion of males among the 215 raffle participants. Among the 25 participants who visited the page multiple times, 17 did not change their choices in all the visits, whereas the remaining 8 first did not choose any option but then picked one later. The percentages of people choosing options 1 to 4 and not choosing any of the options are 30.5%, 38.9%, 9.0%, 16.8%, and 4.8%, respectively.</p><p>For the Bluetooth headset, 97 participants visited the Web page, and 25.8% claimed to be knowledgeable (rating their knowledge greater than 5 on a 1-7 scale), which is higher than the percentage among the 215 enrolled (18.6%). The main reason could be that the participants who consider themselves knowledgeable are more interested in winning a Bluetooth headset than those who are less knowledgeable, as the mean winning interests are 5.9 and 4.2 for the more knowledgeable and less knowledgeable groups, respectively. Among the 97 participants, 92 also logged on to the paraphernalia raffle page. Thirty-four participants visited the page multiple times, and 28 of them maintained the same choices in all the visits. The remaining six first did not choose an option but later chose one. The percentages of people choosing options 1 to 4 and not choosing any of the options are 14.4%, 3.1%, 74.2%, 2.1%, and 6.2%, respectively. 12</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analysis of Participants' Initial Preferences</head><p>We use the hierarchical Bayes logit model <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Allenby and Rossi 1999)</ref>  ik is an error term following Type I extreme value distribution, and the superscript I denotes initial preference. All the attributes are dummy-coded, including price. The model specifications for the sports paraphernalia and the Bluetooth headset are the same except that for the headset, the participants also have an option to choose an earplug version at <ref type="bibr">12</ref>   (3)</p><p>We follow the conventional prior setting of a hierarchical Bayes model: b 0 ∼ N 0 100I P ×P , V 0 ∼ IW P + 2 I P ×P , and I i ∼ N b V , where I P ×P is a P × P identity matrix.</p><p>We estimate the model using the standard Metropolis-within-Gibbs algorithm with 10,000 iterations. According to the trace plots and autocorrelation plots, the Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) chain converges and has good mixing. We keep every 10th draw from the last 8,000 of the MCMC chain for model estimation and inference. We obtain the posterior means of the hyperparameters for the partworths. To perform a hypothesis test, we calculate the probability of a parameter being greater or less than 0 based on the kept draws. The posterior means of almost all of the part-worths are significant, indicating that the participants have preferences for actual attributes of these products, not focusing only on price when making their choices. We calculate the posterior means of the individual-specific part-worths to represent the initial preferences for each participant, and we examine the extent to which they share their preferences with their friends (i.e., evidence for homophily). <ref type="bibr">13</ref> We first compute the correlation between the initial preferences of each participant and his or her friend for each attribute (795 pairs 14 ). Then, to maintain the same sample size, for each participant, we randomly select the same number of other participants who are not identified as one of his or her friends as the number of friends he or she has. Then we compute the correlation between the initial preferences of each participant and his or her randomly selected "nonfriend" for each attribute. In the presence of homophily, we  should expect the correlations of the preferences from the former calculation to be large and much higher than those in the latter. Our findings are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">3</ref>, and we do not observe high correlations for either case. Finally, given that prior research <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Aral et al. 2009</ref>) suggests that homophily may be more prevalent among early adopters, we also compute the correlations of initial preferences between early adopters, defined as the first 16% of participants who made choices in each product category, 15 and their friends. The results show relatively higher correlations for a few attributes including hat style (0.107) for sports paraphernalia and the outside option (0.241) for the Bluetooth headset. Nonetheless, we do not consider these correlations to be alarming high. To summarize, we do not find strong evidence that our social network is endogenously determined by the <ref type="bibr">15</ref> We classify 27 (16% of 167) and 16 (16% of 97) participants who made prize choices earlier as early decision makers for sports paraphernalia and the Bluetooth headset, respectively. According to the adoption of innovation curve, 16% of consumers who first adopt a new innovation are regarded as innovators (2.5) or early adopters (13.5%).</p><p>participants' preferences, which drive the observed choices. <ref type="bibr">16</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model Specification and Estimation</head><p>For each product, we fit two models: (i) the baseline model (Equation ( <ref type="formula">3</ref>)) to the preinfluence stage conjoint data and a DMC model to the postinfluence stage raffle choice data and (ii) the same as (i) except that we fit an MRF model to the raffle data instead of the DMC model. In both cases, we estimate the baseline model and the model for the raffle data simultaneously in the MCMC chain.</p><p>Discrete-Time Markov Chain. We fit a DMC model to the complete raffle data. We only model the choices of participants who at least logged on to the raffle website and treat the rest as if they declined participating in the raffle in the preinfluence stage. However, the information from participants who did not choose any option still enters the model in the calculation of social interaction statistics for the participants who logged on. Let m be the number of participants in each raffle. To model who is likely to make a choice at time point t + 1, c t+1 , we use a logit model with the deterministic part of the utility for participant i, u t+1 i = v i , where v i is a vector that includes interest in winning the raffle (rated on a scale from 1 to 7, with 1 being the least interested) and proportions of friends making any prize choice before participant i does, and is the corresponding parameter vector. The intuition is that the participants who are more interested in winning the raffle are more likely to make their choice, and they may be prompted to make their choice if they observe that many of their friends have already made choices. The corresponding likelihood is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">p c t+1 = i c t y t v = exp u t+1 c t+1 m i=1 exp u t+1 i (4)</formula><p>Conditional on c t+1 = i, we next specify the component of the model that captures which choice a participant makes. We specify the participants' choices to be influenced by their initial preferences as well as the preference shifts induced by social interactions. The initial preferences are identified by observed choices from both stages, whereas the shifts are identified only by the prize choice from the postinfluence stage. We further decompose the impact of social interactions into five parts: (i) influence from their connected friends (i.e., the reference group effect),</p><p>Marketing Science 32(6), pp. 977-997, © 2013 INFORMS (ii) incremental influence from friends who are more popular, (iii) incremental influence from friends with more expertise, (iv) incremental influence from early decision makers, and (v) gender norm influence (only for sports paraphernalia).</p><p>To capture the reference group effect for each participant, we use the summation of observed choices made by his or her friends normalized by the number of friends (i.e., the proportion of friends choosing each prize option). This normalization ensures that we control for different numbers of friends across different participants. This statistic is consistent with a measure called normalized degree centrality <ref type="bibr" target="#b92">(Wasserman and Faust 1994)</ref>. The statistics to capture asymmetry based on popularity and expertise are computed in an analogous manner, except that they are based only on friends who are considered popular or experts relative to participant i. Specifically, we take a relative approach instead of an absolute approach in identifying experts and popular individuals associated with participant i to avoid subjectivity from imposing certain cutoffs. Based on the self-reported ratings on confidence in apparel taste and knowledge about cell phone headsets, we define an expert as a friend who provides a higher rating on each of these two questions than a target participant i. For popularity, we define a popular friend as someone who has more friends than a target participant i. To capture the disproportionate influence of early decision makers, we include a term to allow for the incremental impact of the first choice each participant i observes. For sports paraphernalia, we also include the proportions of choices made by those with the same gender as participant i to capture the gender norm effect. Finally, we include an intercept to account for the case where the participants log on but do not choose either product. For sports paraphernalia, we inform the participants that if they do not make a prize choice, they will receive a randomly chosen option if they win. We hence include the average utility of the four prize options in the model.</p><p>Let m be the number of participants making choices in each raffle and let n be the number of participants agreeing to participate in the raffles (215); let y t+1 i be participant i's choice at time t +1; let u t+1 iy t+1 i be the utility associated with participant i choosing option y t+1 i ; let x = x 1 x 4 , where x k is the vector of attributes of option k in the raffle; letx = 4 k=1 x k /4 be the vector of mean attribute values across options, let be a vector of parameters associated with the social interaction effects, let W = w ji be the matrix of a binary directed network with w ji = 1 if participant j is a friend of i and 0 otherwise; and let g i be i's gender in the paraphernalia raffle, E = e ji , where e ji = 1 if j is a relative expert compared with i. We define H in a way similar to E, but it is associated with popularity. Participant i's opinion leader (the friend who first made a non-zero choice before i first logged on) is denoted as O i , and t O i is the first time O i makes a choice. The probability of a choice made at time t + 1, p y t+1 i c t+1 = i c t y t x I g W H E , has a logit form, with u t+1</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">iy t+1 i = I y t+1 i = 0 0 + 1 I ix + I y t+1 i &gt; 0 1 I i x y i + 2 m j=1 w ji I y t+1 i = y t j n j =1 w j i + 3 I y t+1 i &gt; 0 m j=1 h ji w ji I y t+1 i = y t j m j =1 h j i w j i + 4 I y t+1 i &gt; 0 m j=1 e ji w ji I y t+1 i = y t j m j =1 e j i w j i + 5 I y t+1 i &gt; 0 I y t+1 i = y t O i O i + 6 I y t+1 i &gt; 0 m j=1 =i I y t+1 i = y t j g i = g j m j=1 =i I y t j &gt; 0 g i = g j (<label>5</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_4">)</formula><p>where 0 is the intercept for the no-choice option,</p><p>1 is a scaling factor that adjusts the magnitude of the initial preferences, 2 is the baseline reference group influence, 3 is the asymmetric popularity influence, 4 is the asymmetric expert influence, 5 is the early decision maker influence, and 6 is the gender norm influence. We also define 0 0 = 0 for all the ratios. In the Bluetooth headset raffle, because we have the information about the initial preference − i0 for a wired headset from the preinfluence data, we use − 0 i0 instead of 0 . The term 1 I ix is also not relevant. Observing the choice sequence and assuming that only one choice can be made at a particular time point allows us to use a simple logit specification to model the choice made at each time point. The full likelihood function is thus specified as</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">p s 1 s T s 0 x I g W H E = T −1 t=0 exp u t+1 c t+1 m i=1 exp u t+1 i exp u t+1 c t+1 y t+1 c t+1 4 k=I y t c t+1 =0 exp u t+1 c t+1 k • I y t+1 −c t+1 = y t −c t+1<label>(6)</label></formula><p>We specify c 0 = 0, meaning no one is likely to make a choice before the raffle starts, and y 0 is a vector of 0, indicating that everyone starts without any selection. We include data from all 215 participants who agreed to participant in the raffles to get more efficient estimates of individual-specific initial preferences (i.e., better shrinkage), although the number of participants in each raffle is smaller.</p><p>The full likelihood contains both preinfluence and postinfluence raffle choices, p s 1 s T s 0 x I g W H E p y I x I I , where p y I x I is defined in Equation ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>). The prior for the social interaction parameters is 0 ∼ N 0 100I 4×4 . Although we estimate initial preferences at the individual level, we can only estimate the social interaction effects at the aggregate level, because we only observe one final choice from the raffle (participants do not change their choices after the first selection) for each participant and each product.</p><p>Markov Random Field. We fit the MRF to the snapshot data. The model specification for the MRF is similar to that of the DMC. (The detailed specification of the MRF model is in Online Appendix B.) However, the statistics corresponding to the social interaction effects are quite different. Take the baseline reference group influence 2 as an example. In the DMC model, when participant c t+1 makes a choice decision at time t + 1, we compute the statistic as the proportion of friends who made the same choice as c t+1 up to time t, m j=1 w ji I y t+1 i = y t j / n j =1 w j i (recall that is a vector of everyone's choices at time t). The computation of this statistic takes the time stamp of participant c t+1 's decision into account. In contrast, for MRF for each individual i, we calculate the proportion of friends who make the same choice as i observed at the end of the raffle (i.e., time T ), m j=1 w ji I y T j = y T i / n i =1 w j i . This means that the MRF statistics associated with individual i also include individual i's friends who make choices after individual i. The statistics for each individual i can therefore take different values in the DMC and MRF models. Also, we may calculate the statistic for individual i multiple times if he or she makes decisions more than once, and the statistic each time might be different depending on his or her friends' choices up to that time point. All other statistics to capture asymmetry and gender norm are computed analogously.</p><p>Similar to the hierarchical Bayes logit model, we carry out the Metropolis-within-Gibbs algorithm for 10,000 iterations for both models (see Online Appendix D for the estimation procedure), and we use every 10th draw from the last 8,000 for parameter estimation and inference. For the MRF model, we use the approximate sampling to circumvent the intractable normalizing constant problem. Online Appendix C describes our approximate sampling procedure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model Comparison</head><p>In this section, we compare the DMC and MRF models using in-sample and out-of-sample hit rates. To quantify the impact of social interactions on preference shifts, we also fit a simple logit choice model instead of the DMC and MRF model to the raffle data as a baseline model. Superior fits of the DMC and MRF models, which account for social interaction effects, to those of the baseline model indicate the significant role of the social interactions in the prize choice decisions made in the social network. An in-sample hit rate is computed as the mean percentage of correctly predicted choices for all participants and an out-of-sample hit rate as the mean percentage of correctly predicted choices for out-ofsample participants. We opt to use a hit rate instead of traditional fit measures such as log marginal density and deviance information criterion because these traditional measures require the calculation of the normalizing constant for the MRF model, which is computationally expensive. To make the results more comparable across models, in the DMC model the two hit rates are computed only for the final choices, and in prediction we condition on who is likely to make a choice. To compute out-of-sample hit rates, we first fit the models to the participants who make choices earlier to predict choices of the last 20 holdout participants. The model prediction procedure is further described in Online Appendix E.</p><p>Based on both in-sample and out-of-sample hit rates, the MRF and DMC models perform better than the baseline model, especially for the Bluetooth headset category (see Table <ref type="table">4</ref>). These findings suggest the significance of social interaction effects particularly for a technology-related product. The participants appear to rely less on their friends' choices in making their prize selections for sports paraphernalia compared with a technology-related product, such as Bluetooth headset. For sports paraphernalia, although the in-sample hit rate of the MRF is higher than that of the DMC, the superior out-of-sample hit rate suggests better predictive performance of the DMC in the fashion-related category. Surprisingly, although we observe that the DMC and MRF provide similar in-sample hit rates, the out-of-sample hit rate of the MRF is higher than that of the DMC in the Bluetooth headset category. Given that the DMC takes advantage of additional information on the choice sequence, Notes. Within parentheses is the standard error of the hit rate, computed from the kept draws of the posterior predictive distribution. We use two independent sample t-tests (assuming that the central limit theorem holds) to determine whether one model gives a significantly better hit rate than the other. * * Significantly greater than hit rate of baseline model at the significance level of 0.05.</p><p>Marketing Science 32(6), pp. 977-997, © 2013 INFORMS we expect the DMC to provide better predictive performance than the MRF.</p><p>One possible explanation could lie in the relationship between the DMC and the MRF. That is, the MRF can be regarded as an equilibrium model for the DMC, as also shown by our proof in Online Appendix A. <ref type="bibr" target="#b96">Yang et al. (2010)</ref> propose an automodel, a special case of the MRF, to model coordinated choice. They refer to their model as an equivalent conditional approach to <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Hartmann's (2010)</ref> unconditional or equilibrium approach to modeling coordinated choice. It is possible that for a technology-related product, individuals may make choices based on how they have anticipated choices to be realized at the equilibrium (e.g., an option with the most sophisticated technology will be the one their relatively more high-tech friends adopt). Therefore, we may not lose much from the prediction standpoint using the MRF with snapshot data as opposed to the DMC with complete data. Given these results, for the Bluetooth headset we draw conclusions from the DMC model with some caution. Despite its inferior out-of-sample prediction, the exploitation of the choice sequence information using the DMC model alleviates the simultaneity concern. The findings from the DMC model are also more insightful. That is, we can explore the potential disproportionate influence of early decision makers in the social interaction process. We can also examine who is likely to make a choice. This information can be useful for firms to target influential consumers. Neither of these insights can be drawn from the MRF model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Estimation Results</head><p>Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">5 and 6</ref> report the posterior means of the model parameters for sports paraphernalia and the Note. Baseline levels are defined in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">3</ref>. * Probability of parameter estimates being greater or less than 0 is 0.9; * * probability of parameter estimates being greater or less than 0 is 0.95.</p><p>Bluetooth headset, respectively. We omit the estimates for the initial preferences based on the preinfluence and postinfluence data in all the models, because they lead to the same inferences as to the estimates based only on the preinfluence data (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">3</ref>). We present results from the DMC model with different specifications (Models 1-4) and the MRF model (Model 5). Model 1 is our proposed model (Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">5</ref>)). In Model 2, the numbers, instead of the proportion, of friends are used to as statistics to capture social interactions.</p><p>Using the proportion of friends (i.e., average friends' behavior) to capture social interactions is consistent with the majority of prior research (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Brock and Durlauf 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">, Nair et al. 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b87">, Tucker 2008</ref>. However, some research that allows participants to discuss preferences between the preinfluence and postinfluence stages uses the average initial preference, instead of behavior, of a reference group <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Aribarg et al. 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Aribarg et al. , 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Arora and Allenby 1999</ref>) as a statistic. The decision to use the average behavior is driven by our primary mechanism to induce choice interdependencethat is, the observation of friends' choices on a Web page. However, the participants may have discussed their preferences off-line. We add the average preference of a participant's friends who have made prize choices before him or her in Model 3. We assume that the participants only rely on information from their friends who have made choice commitments. Finally, we further examine the potential impact of homophily on our results by estimating Model 4, where we do not control for the participants' initial preferences in the estimation of social interaction effects.</p><p>For sports paraphernalia, the results from the MRF (Model 5) and DMC (Model 1) are quite similar. Note. Baseline levels are defined in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">3</ref>. * Probability of parameter estimates being greater or less that 0 is 0.9; * * probability of parameter estimates being greater or less that 0 is 0.95.</p><p>Given its superior out-of-sample fit, the DMC model becomes our focus. The participants' initial preference ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>) is found to be significant in determining participants' prize choices, suggesting that they make prize choices based on their own evaluations of options' utilities. Interestingly, the baseline reference group effect ( 2 ) is not significant. Nonetheless, as expected for a fashion-related product where value-expressive influence is more prominent, we find the asymmetric popularity effect ( 3 ) to be significant and the asymmetric expertise effect to be insignificant ( 4 ). These results suggest that participants are affected by only friends in their reference group who are more popular than them (i.e., have more friends) in this product category. We also do not find early decision makers ( 6 ) to be disproportionately more influential but did find gender norm ( 5 ) to also play a significant role. Finally, the results from the who is likely to make a choice part indicates that observing their friends making prize choices prompts participants to also make their prize choices.</p><p>The results from the model based on the number of friends (Model 2) and that controlling for the initial preference of the reference group (Model 3) lead to similar conclusions as Model 1. The significant effect of the initial preference of the reference group suggests possible off-line communication among the participants. Interestingly, the MRF model (Model 5), which is fit to the incomplete snapshot data, cannot detect the significant effect of asymmetric popularity.</p><p>Looking at the proposed model (Model 1) for the Bluetooth headset, similar to sports paraphernalia, the initial preference plays a significant role ( 1 ); the baseline reference group effect does not ( 2 ). As expected for a technology-related product where informational influence dominates, the asymmetric expertise effect is significant ( 4 ), whereas the asymmetric popularity effect is not ( 3 ). Nonetheless, the MRF model (Model 5), which provides a better out-of-sample fit, leads to a slightly different conclusion. That is, the MRF suggests significance of both the asymmetric expertise and popularity effects (the parameters related to the two types of asymmetry are also not significantly different from each other). Despite the better out-of-sample fit, the results based on the DMC better represent the actual social interaction process because it exploits the complete data. To be conservative, we urge future research to reinvestigate the presence of the asymmetric popularity effect in the technology-related category.</p><p>Unlike sports paraphernalia, we find the disproportionate influence of early decision makers ( 6 ) for the Bluetooth headset. That is, the participants are more significantly influenced by the first choice they observe compared with choices observed later. We also find that the participants who are more interested in the raffle are also more likely to make the prize choice early. Taken together, these results suggest that for a technology-related product, individuals who are more interested in a technology product are likely to adopt the product earlier than others. These early adopters also exert a disproportionate influence on later adopters (i.e., taking an opinion leadership role). These conclusions are consistent with previous theoretical and meta-analysis work (Van den Bulte and Joshi 2007) that touts the important role of opinion leaders in the area of diffusion of innovations. Our results complement prior research, as we provide empirical evidence for these effects at the individual level.</p><p>Compared with other specifications of the DMC model, we do not find a significant effect of the initial preference of the reference group in this category (Model 3). Using the number of friends (Model 2) also leads to a different conclusion that there exists only the baseline reference group effect, but not the asymmetric popularity or expertise effect. We draw our conclusions based on our proposed DMC model (Model 1) instead of Model 3, because the statistics in Model 1 are more consistent with the normalized degree centrality measure widely used in the sociology literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b92">(Wasserman and Faust 1994)</ref> to capture social network effects.</p><p>For both products, we find controlling for the participants' initial preferences is more important for sports paraphernalia than for Bluetooth headset. Despite the difference in the magnitude of parameter estimates, the estimates from the model that does not control for the initial preference (Model 4) for Bluetooth headset suggest a similar pattern of social interaction effects as that from Model 1. For sports paraphernalia, however, Model 4 does not detect the asymmetric popularity effect. These findings indicate that even with low correlations in the initial preferences within a reference group (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">3</ref>), researchers can benefit from controlling for heterogeneous initial preferences across individuals in the estimation of social interaction effects. It is noteworthy that the observed low correlations and absence of discernible differences in the correlations between the participants and their friends' initial preferences and those between the participants and randomly selected nonfriends' initial preferences may also be masked by the uncertainty in the part-worth estimates at the individual level.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Our paper delineates an experimental and modeling framework to examine social interaction effects. Relying on the multiattribute utility framework and two-stage conjoint experiment where we measure individuals' initial attribute preferences and collect exogenous social network information, we can separately identify choice interdependence-shifts in choice preferences as a result of social interactionsin a social network. Our conjoint experiment coupled with statistical modeling is an alternative approach to a controlled randomized experiment, particularly when reference groups largely overlap in a social network. Our findings prompt the importance of controlling for individual initial preferences when examining social interaction effects, even with the incorporation of exogenous network information.</p><p>Previous behavioral research has recognized the differences between informational and valueexpressive influences <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Burnkrant and Cousineau 1975</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">, Deutsch and Gerard 1955</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">, Kelman 1958</ref>) and extensively examined different factors that moderate the impact of these two types of influence. These factors can be categorized as those related to the characteristics of the influenced individuals, such as the extent of self-monitoring and susceptibility to social influence <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Batra et al. 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">, Bearden and Rose 1990</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">, Bearden et al. 1989</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">, DeBono and Harnish 1988</ref>; the characteristics of the influencers, such as their credibility and attractiveness <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Kelman 1958)</ref>; and the characteristics of information or decision contexts, such as the transparency of decisions to others, the uniformity of opinions, and product necessity and conspicuousness <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Bearden and Etzel 1982</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">, Burnkrant and Cousineau 1975</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">, Childers and Rao 1992</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">, Cohen and Golden 1972</ref>. Extending previous research, we explore how the interaction between the type of product and the characteristics of influencers moderates the two types of social influence. Specifically, we examine differential asymmetric influences based on popularity and expertise for fashion-related versus technology-related products. We find popular individuals exert greater influence for a fashion-related product, but experts exert greater influence for a technology-related product. Nonetheless, we urge future research to reexamine whether the asymmetric popularity effect can also exist in the technologyrelated product category given our results from the MRF model, which provides good predictive performance.</p><p>Given the choice sequence information, our findings show that choices made by early decision makers are more influential than choices made by later decision makers, and early decision makers are those who are more interested in owning the product in the technology-related category. Previous research views a combination of expertise or knowledge, high category involvement, and influence as characterizing opinion leaders <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Jacoby and Hoyer 1981</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">, Midgley 1976</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b72">, Robertson et al. 1984</ref>. Our result is in line with the previous research and suggests the important role of early decision makers as highly involved and knowledgeable opinion leaders for technologyrelated products. Finally, in the absence of the choice sequence information, we demonstrate that the MRF model can be used as an alternative to the DMC model. In fact, the MRF model provides good predictive performance for the technology-related product.</p><p>As avenues for future research, our design can be further benefited by a technique to solicit social network information that forces individuals to be more accurate in their friend nominations <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Leider et al. 2009</ref>). Our research also does not account for potential nonlinear social interaction dynamics, where the marginal effect of observing behavior of one more friend may not be constant across different numbers of friends <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Aral and Walker 2011</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">, Aral et al. 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">, Bakshy et al. 2012</ref>). In the context of nonoverlapping reference groups, future research may combine a statistical modeling approach with a two-stage conjoint experiment such as ours with a randomized experimental approach. For example, for each person who makes a choice, researchers can randomly send the choice information to only a subset of his or her friends. One benefit of a modeling approach is its ability to facilitate researchers in performing predictive and counterfactual exercises. Finally, in this paper we propose a DMC to model the sequences of choices (i.e., who is likely to make a choice). However, additional information on the time between two consecutive choices will allow us to also model how long it takes for someone to make a choice. It is generally difficult to track the time between two consecutive choices. Even with social media technology, it can become cumbersome to record large amounts of data. However, if such data are available, a continuoustime, instead of a discrete-time, Markov chain model can be applied to study the factors that influence the time it takes for someone to make a choice. Modeling this type of data is beyond the scope of our paper, but it could be a fruitful avenue for future research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplemental Material</head><p>Supplemental material to this paper is available at http://dx .doi.org/10.1287/mksc.2013.0811.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Web Page for Sports Paraphernalia Raffle</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2Social Network Plot</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>1≤i j i ≤n i =j =i</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>to fit the conjoint choice data from the preinfluence stage. Participant i's utility of option k is P p=1 I ip x I ipq k + I ik , where I ip captures individual i's initial preference for the pth product attribute, x I ipq k indicates the pth attribute's value for option k in task q, I</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>$</head><label></label><figDesc>29. Hence, we estimate the preference ( I i0 ) for this outside option for the headset. Let n be the number of participants; let I i be a vector of i's choices in 12 conjoint choice tasks, taking values of 1 to 4 (as well as 0 for a no-choice option for the headset); let the corresponding attributes for option k in qth task be x I iq k</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The baseline levels for the paraphernalia bundle are as follows: (a) style 2 grey jacket, (b) white T-shirt, (c) style 2 hat, and (d) $69. The baseline levels for the headset are as follows: (e) Plantronics, (f) silver, (g) 13 grams, (h) 5 hours, and (i) $79.* * Probability of parameter estimates being greater or less than 0 is 0.95.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Descriptive Statistics</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Participants'</cell><cell>Nonparticipants'</cell><cell>Test statistic a</cell></row><row><cell>Variable</cell><cell>mean (SD)</cell><cell>mean (SD)</cell><cell>(df)</cell></row><row><cell>Gender</cell><cell>60.9% male</cell><cell>63.6% male</cell><cell>0 08 (1)</cell></row><row><cell>Apparel confidence</cell><cell>5 52 (1.18)</cell><cell>5 51 (1.30)</cell><cell>0 09 (123)</cell></row><row><cell>Headset knowledge</cell><cell>3 59 (1.75)</cell><cell>3 27 (1.70)</cell><cell>1 38 (138)</cell></row><row><cell>Time spent on email</cell><cell>38.6% b</cell><cell>28.6%</cell><cell>5 43 (3)</cell></row><row><cell>Interest in sports</cell><cell>5 99 (1.34)</cell><cell>3 22 (2.06)</cell><cell>10 05 (78)  *  *</cell></row><row><cell>paraphernalia</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Interest in Bluetooth</cell><cell>4 51 (2.12)</cell><cell>2 35 (1.77)</cell><cell>8 11 (119)  *  *</cell></row><row><cell>headset</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>a A chi-square test is used for gender and time spent on email; an independent-sample t-test is used for the remaining variables.b Percentage of participants spending more than an hour on email every day.* * p &lt; 0 05 (two-tailed).</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Network Structure Statistics</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Effects</cell><cell cols="2">Network statistics</cell><cell>Values</cell></row><row><cell>Mean in-/out-degree</cell><cell cols="2">e ij /n</cell><cell>3 7</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>1≤i j≤n</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Variance of in-degree</cell><cell>var</cell><cell>e j i</cell><cell>7 0</cell></row><row><cell>(prestige)</cell><cell>1≤j≤n</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Variance of out-degree</cell><cell>var</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Patterns of Participants' Initial Preferences</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Correlation in initial preferences</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Preference between</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Preference between</cell><cell>participant and</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Posterior</cell><cell>participant and</cell><cell>a randomly</cell></row><row><cell>Attribute</cell><cell>mean</cell><cell>each friend</cell><cell>selected nonfriend</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Parameter Estimates: Sports Paraphernalia</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>DMC</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Proposed model</cell><cell>Statistics based on</cell><cell cols="2">Controlling for avg. friends' Not controlling for initial</cell><cell>MRF</cell></row><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell>(Model 1)</cell><cell>no. of friends (Model 2)</cell><cell>preference (Model 3)</cell><cell>preference (Model 4)</cell><cell>(Model 5)</cell></row><row><cell>Social interaction effects</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Outside good</cell><cell>0 524  *  *</cell><cell>0 528  *  *</cell><cell>0 510  *  *</cell><cell>n/a</cell><cell>0 301  *  *</cell></row><row><cell>Scale parameter for initial</cell><cell>0 517  *  *</cell><cell>0 516  *  *</cell><cell>0 501  *  *</cell><cell>n/a</cell><cell>0 418  *  *</cell></row><row><cell>preference ( 1 )</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Overall reference group influence ( 2)</cell><cell>−0 009</cell><cell>−0 020</cell><cell>−0 184</cell><cell>−0 174</cell><cell>0 354</cell></row><row><cell>Asymmetric popularity influence ( 3)</cell><cell>0 766  *  *</cell><cell>0 492  *  *</cell><cell>0 839  *  *</cell><cell>0 416</cell><cell>0 604</cell></row><row><cell>Asymmetric expertise influence ( 4)</cell><cell>−0 103</cell><cell>0 024</cell><cell>−0 229</cell><cell>0 242</cell><cell>−0 526</cell></row><row><cell>Early decision maker influence ( 5 )</cell><cell>0 053</cell><cell>0 056</cell><cell>0 008</cell><cell>0 268</cell><cell>n/a</cell></row><row><cell>Gender norm ( 6 )</cell><cell>1 892  *  *</cell><cell>1 899  *  *</cell><cell>1 730  *  *</cell><cell>2 211  *  *</cell><cell>1 510  *  *</cell></row><row><cell>Intrinsic preference of the reference</cell><cell>n/a</cell><cell>n/a</cell><cell>0 194  *  *</cell><cell>n/a</cell><cell>n/a</cell></row><row><cell>group ( 7</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Factors determining who is likely</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>to make a choice decision</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>% friends made a choice</cell><cell>0 377  *</cell><cell>0 029</cell><cell>0 349  *</cell><cell>0 363  *</cell><cell>n/a</cell></row><row><cell>Interest in winning the raffle</cell><cell>0 010</cell><cell>0 004</cell><cell>0 010</cell><cell>0 012</cell><cell>n/a</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Parameter Estimates: Bluetooth Headset</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>DMC</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Proposed model</cell><cell>Statistics based on</cell><cell cols="2">Controlling for avg. friends' Not controlling for initial</cell><cell>MRF</cell></row><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell>(Model 1)</cell><cell>no. of friends (Model 2)</cell><cell>preference (Model 3)</cell><cell>preference (Model 4)</cell><cell>(Model 5)</cell></row><row><cell>Social interaction effects</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Outside good</cell><cell>0 075  *</cell><cell>0 090  *</cell><cell>0 106  *</cell><cell>n/a</cell><cell>−0 038</cell></row><row><cell>Scale parameter for initial</cell><cell>0 394  *  *</cell><cell>0 430  *  *</cell><cell>*  *</cell><cell>n/a</cell><cell>0 316  *  *</cell></row><row><cell>preference ( 1 )</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Overall reference group influence ( 2)</cell><cell>0 576</cell><cell>0 285  *  *</cell><cell>0 664</cell><cell>−0 429</cell><cell>0 127</cell></row><row><cell>Asymmetric popularity influence ( 3)</cell><cell>0 390</cell><cell>−0 248</cell><cell>0 069</cell><cell>0 149</cell><cell>1 598  *  *</cell></row><row><cell>Asymmetric expertise influence ( 4)</cell><cell>1 034  *  *</cell><cell>0 255</cell><cell>0 822  *  *</cell><cell>1 071  *  *</cell><cell>1 235  *  *</cell></row><row><cell>Early decision maker influence ( 5 )</cell><cell>0 805  *  *</cell><cell>1 270  *  *</cell><cell>1 216  *  *</cell><cell>1 646  *  *</cell><cell>n/a</cell></row><row><cell>Initial preference of the reference</cell><cell>n/a</cell><cell>n/a</cell><cell>−0 165</cell><cell>n/a</cell><cell>n/a</cell></row><row><cell>group ( 7 )</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Factors determining who is likely</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>to make a choice decision</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>% friends made a choice</cell><cell>0 011</cell><cell>0 036</cell><cell>0 035</cell><cell>0 034</cell><cell>n/a</cell></row><row><cell>Interest in winning the raffle</cell><cell>0 055  *</cell><cell>0 056  *</cell><cell>0 057  *  *</cell><cell>0 054</cell><cell>n/a</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">We study individual choice decisions, not joint<ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Aribarg et al. 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Aribarg et al. , 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Arora and Allenby 1999)</ref> or coordinated choice<ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Hartmann 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b96">, Yang et al. 2010</ref> decisions.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">The authors provide the empirical support for their arguments via simulation studies.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">The participants also see the names of their friends who have not made their choices by the time they log on to the site.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8">To facilitate the nomination process, our Java program has a builtin search tool. Participants can easily locate the nominees' names by typing part of their first or last names. The search tool helps us avoid typos and solves the problem that participants may not necessarily remember the full name of all the nominees.9  This procedure was included on the request from the Institutional Review Boards of Health Sciences and Behavioral Sciences.10  We omitted price because including it may have prompted students to choose the most expensive bundle.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="13">To be more rigorous, one is expected to conduct the analysis using the actual draws from the MCMC chain to account for the uncertainty in the parameter estimates. We use the posterior means of individuals' draws to simplify our analysis.14  We decided to use double-counted pairs, 167 of 628 pairs, for the participant-friend pairs so as to make a comparison with the randomly selected participant pairs.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="16">We also conducted a similar analysis with the utilities of the prize options in the raffles. That is, we used individual-specific partworths to compute these utilities before performing the correlation analysis. The results exhibit similar patterns and are available from the authors upon request.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The paper is based on the first author's dissertation. The authors thank Stefan Witwicki for his assistance in Java and Flash programming to facilitate their data collection process. They thank Natasha Zhang Foutz for great comments on this paper. Finally, they thank the review team for providing them with valuable comments and directions for the paper.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of customer community participation on customer behaviors: An empirical investigation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Algesheimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Borle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dholakia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="756" to="769" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Marketing models of consumer heterogeneity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rossi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling multiple relationships in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ansari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Koenigsberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Stahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="713" to="728" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Creating social contagion through viral product design: A randomized trial of peer influence in networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Aral</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1623" to="1639" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying influential and susceptible members of social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Aral</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">337</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6092</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="341" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinguishing influencebased contagion from homophily-driven diffusion in dynamic networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Aral</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Muchnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sundararajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21544" to="21549" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the role of preference revision and concession in group decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Aribarg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Bodur</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="336" to="349" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting joint choice using individual data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Aribarg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="157" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring the influence of individual preference structure in group decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="476" to="478" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social influence in social advertising: Evidence from field experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bakshy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Eckles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Rosenn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 13th ACM Conf. Electronic Commerce</title>
				<meeting>13th ACM Conf. Electronic Commerce<address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="161" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new product growth model for consumer durables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="227" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Values, susceptibility to normative influence, and attribute importance weights: A nomological analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Batra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Homer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Kahle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Psych</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="115" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reference group influence on product and brand purchase decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Bearden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Etzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="183" to="194" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attention to social comparison information: An individual difference factor affecting consumer conformity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Bearden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Rose</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="461" to="471" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measurement of consumer susceptibility to interpersonal influence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Bearden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Netemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Teel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="473" to="481" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Possession and the extended self</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Belk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="168" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neighborhood effects and trail on the Internet: Evidence from online grocery retailing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="361" to="400" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spatial interaction and the statistical analysis of lattice systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Besag</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Roy. Statist. Soc. Ser. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="192" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical analysis of non-lattice data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Besag</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Roy. Statist. Soc. Ser. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="195" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Group influence in marketing and public relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bourne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Some Applications of Behavioral Research</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Likert</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Hayes</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Basel, Switzerland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>UNESCO</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1957" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="255" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identification of peer effects through social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Bramoullé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Djebbari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Fortin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">150</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discrete choice with social interactions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Brock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Durlauf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="235" to="260" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Informational and normative social influence in buyer behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Burnkrant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cousineau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="206" to="215" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The spread of behavior in an online social network experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Centola</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">329</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5996</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1194" to="1197" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An experimental study of homophily in the adoption of health behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Centola</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">334</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6060</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1269" to="1272" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online social interactions: A natural experiment on word of mouth versus observational learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="238" to="254" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of word of mouth on sales: Online book reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Chevalier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mayzlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="345" to="354" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The influence of familial and peerbased reference groups on consumer decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Childers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="198" to="211" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Informational social influence and product evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Golden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Psych</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="54" to="59" />
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word-of-mouth processes in the diffusion of a major technological innovation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Czepiel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="172" to="180" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A multi-stage model of word-ofmouth influence through viral marketing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>De Bruyn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lilien</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Res. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="163" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Source expertise, source attractiveness, and the processing of persuasive information: A functional approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Debono</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Harnish</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Personality Soc. Psych</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="541" to="546" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A study of normative and informational social influences upon individual judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Deutsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Gerard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Abnormal Soc. Psych</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="626" to="636" />
			<date type="published" when="1955" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="977" to="997" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An incentive-aligned mechanism for conjoint analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="214" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="2007-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using online conversations to study word-of-mouth communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Godes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mayzlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="545" to="560" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The firm&apos;s management of social interactions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Godes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mayzlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dellarocas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Pfeiffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Libai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Verlegh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3-4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="415" to="428" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The strength of weak ties</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Granovetter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. J. Sociol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1360" to="1380" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Threshold models of collective behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Granovetter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. J. Sociol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1420" to="1443" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conjoint choice experiments: General characteristics and alternative model specifications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Haaijer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conjoint Measurement Methods and Applications</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gustafsson</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Herrmann</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="371" to="412" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>3rd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling social interactions: Identification, empirical methods and policy implication</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hartmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Nair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Manchanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bothner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dodds</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Godes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hosanagar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="287" to="304" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Demand estimation with social interactions and the implications for targeted marketing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hartmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="601" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Network-based marketing: Identifying likely adopters via consumer networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Provost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Volinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statist. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="256" to="276" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Latent space approaches to social network analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Raftery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Handcock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">97</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">460</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1090" to="1098" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Curved exponential family models for social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hunter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc. Networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="216" to="230" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling dyadic interactions and networks in marketing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Iacobucci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Hopkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What is opinion leaders didn&apos;t know more? A question of nomological validity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jacoby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advance in Consumer Research</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Monroe</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Ann Arbor, MI</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Consumer Research</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="299" to="303" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Lazarsfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Personal Influence: The Part Played by People in the Flow of Mass Communications</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Free Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1955" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Decision with Multiple Objectives</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Keeney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Raiffa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compliance, identification, and internalization: Three processes of attitude change</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Kelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Conflict Resolution</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="1958" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Process of opinion change</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Kelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Public Opinion Quart</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian inference for dynamic social network data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Koskinen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tab</forename><surname>Snijders</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Statist. Plan. Inference</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">137</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3930" to="3938" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient experimental design with marketing research applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Kuhfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Tobias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Garratt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="545" to="557" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Directed altruism and enforced reciprocity in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Leider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mobius</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Rosenblat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q-A</forename><surname>Do</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quart. J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1815" to="1851" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Social dollars: The economic impact of customer participation in a firmsponsored online community. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Manchanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Packard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pattbhiramaiah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<pubPlace>Ann Arbor</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Michigan</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identification of endogenous social effects: The reflection problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Manski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="531" to="542" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Economic analysis of social interactions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Manski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Perspect</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="115" to="136" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The nature of attitudes and attitude change</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mcguire</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Handbook of Social Psychology</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Lindzey</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Reading, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="136" to="314" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A simple mathematical theory of innovation behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Midgley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward formalizing fashion theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Mcintyre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Mantrala</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="142" to="157" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The construction of social norms and standards</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Prentice</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Social Psychology: Handbook of Basic Principles</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Higgins</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kruglanski</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Guilford Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="799" to="829" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Policy interventions, low-level equilibria, and social interactions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Moffitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Social Dynamics</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Durlauf</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Washington, DC</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Brookings Institution Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="82" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting product purchase from inferred customer similarity: An autologistic model approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Moon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="82" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Murray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Ghahramani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Djc</forename><surname>Mackay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">MCMC for doublyintractable distributions. 22nd Conf. Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence UAI 2006</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-07-13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dimensions of opinion leadership</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Asymmetric social interactions in physician prescription behavior: The role of opinion leaders</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Nair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Manchanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="883" to="895" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of signal quality and contiguous word of mouth on customer acquisition for a video-on-demand service</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Manchanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="690" to="700" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How peer influence affects attribute preferences: A Bayesian updating mechanism. Marketing Sci</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Narayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Saunders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="368" to="384" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Niraj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Padmanabhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Seetharaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Cross-category model of households&apos; incidence and quantity decisions. Marketing Sci</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="235" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Students and housewives: Differences in susceptibility to reference group influence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Lessig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="102" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analysis of referral networks in marketing: Methods and illustration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Reingen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kernan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="370" to="378" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Brand congruence in interpersonal relations: A social network analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Reingen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Seidman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="771" to="783" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Consumer Behavior (Scott, Foresman and Company</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zielinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
			<pubPlace>Glenview, IL</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An introduction to exponential random graph (p * ) models for social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Robins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pattison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kalish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lusher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc. Networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="173" to="191" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Methods of measuring opinion leadership</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Cartano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Public Opinion Quart</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="435" to="441" />
			<date type="published" when="1962" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Stochastic Processes</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating causal effects of treatments in randomized and nonrandomized studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Ed. Psych</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="688" to="701" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analysis of cross category dependence in market basket selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Peterson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Retailing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="367" to="392" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic models of segregation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Schelling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Math. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="186" />
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Homophily and contagion are generically confounded in observational social network studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Shalizi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc. Methods Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="239" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling the coevolution of networks and behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tab</forename><surname>Snijders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Steglich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schweinberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Longitudinal Models in the Behavioral and Related Sciences</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Van Montfort</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Oud</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Satorra</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Mahwah, NJ</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="71" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic networks and behavior: Separating selection from influence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Steglich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Tom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Snijders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Pearson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc. Methodol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="329" to="393" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling Choice Interdependence in a</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aribarg</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Atchadé</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>© 2013 INFORMS 997</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Network Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="977" to="997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deriving value from social commerce networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Stephen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Toubia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="228" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring cross-category price effects with aggregate store data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1594" to="1609" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Viral marketing: A largescale field experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Toubia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Stephen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Freud</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management, Financial Markets</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="65" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determining influential users in Internet social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Trusov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Bodapati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Bucklin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="643" to="658" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying formal and informal influence in technology adoption with network externalities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2024" to="2038" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New product diffusion with influentials and imitators</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Van Den Bulte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="400" to="421" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social contagion and income heterogeneity in new product diffusion: A meta-analytic test</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Van Den Bulte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Stremersch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="530" to="544" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b90">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social Network and Marketing. Marketing Science Institute Relevant Knowledge Series</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Van Den Bulte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wuyts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science Institute</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b91">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Approximate Bayesian computation for exponential random graph models for large social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Atchadé</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. Statist. Simulat</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Forthcoming</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b92">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wasserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Faust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Social Network Analysis: Methods and Applications</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b93">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Logit models and logistic regressions for social networks: An introduction to Markov random graph and p *</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wasserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pattison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychometrika</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="401" to="425" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b94">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influentials, networks, and public opinion formation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Watts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Dodds</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="441" to="458" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b95">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling interdependent consumer preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="282" to="294" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b96">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling the intrahousehold behavioral interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Erdem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="470" to="484" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b97">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The sound of silence: Observational learning in the U.S. kidney market</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="315" to="335" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b98">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impact of online consumer reviews on sales: The moderating role of product and consumer characteristics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="148" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
