<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Product Differentiation and Collusion Sustainability When Collusion Is Costly</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2012-10-12">October 12, 2012.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Stefano</forename><surname>Colombo</surname></persName>
							<email>stefano.colombo@unicatt.it</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Università Cattolica del Sacro Cuore</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>I-20123</postCode>
									<settlement>Milan</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Università Cattolica del Sacro Cuore</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>I-20123</postCode>
									<settlement>Milan</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Product Differentiation and Collusion Sustainability When Collusion Is Costly</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 (print)</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2012-10-12">October 12, 2012.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1120.0750</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: January 9, 2012; accepted: September 13, 2012; Preyas Desai served as the editor-in-chief and Duncan Simester served as associate editor for this article.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:25+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>product differentiation</term>
					<term>competition</term>
					<term>collusion</term>
					<term>collusion costs</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Product differentiation is a widely explored issue by both marketing and industrial organization theorists. It has been discussed with regard to the positioning choices of firms in the product space and with regard to the effects that various positioning configurations have on, for example, the firms' equilibrium profits. Particularly relevant is the role that different market structures play in firms' ability to reduce the strength of competition. Reducing fierceness of competition is a key issue for competitors in the real world. Therefore, identifying those market configurations where a tacit collusive agreement is easier to enforce (i.e., where competition is less fierce, such as in a cartel) is a relevant theoretical and practical concern for strategy researchers as well as for antitrust authorities. Along these lines, the Horizontal Merger Guidelines (U.S. Department of Justice/Federal Trade Commission 1992) claim that a high level of product differentiation is anticollusive, as homogeneity increases "both the ability to reach terms of coordination and to detect or punish deviations from those terms" ( §2.1). However, and in contrast to the clear-cut conclusion of those guidelines, the discussion among scholars about the impact of product differentiation on collusion sustainability is still open, and such a clear-cut assessment has not yet been reached. The reason for such theoretical ambiguity is that when firms producing differentiated goods compete, a high degree of substitutability determines a low equilibrium price and low equilibrium profits. In response, the firms may be willing to jointly raise the price above the competitive level. However, not only does the opportunity for collusion increase when product differentiation is low but the incentive to deviate from a cartel increases as well; as with scarcely differentiated products, any cheating firm captures a large share of the market when it lowers the price unilaterally (i.e., when it deviates). Therefore, because the degree of sustainability in equilibrium of a collusive agreement is determined by the level of collusive, deviation, and punishment profits, it is not surprising that, depending on the specific model adopted, the impact of product differentiation over collusion sustainability may have a different sign. The findings in the theoretical literature seem to confirm such ambiguity. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Chang (1991)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Häckner (1995)</ref>, in a model with uniform pricing firms, find that the more the firms' products are similar, the more collusion is difficult to sustain in equilibrium, whereas the opposite occurs in the case of price-discriminating firms <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Gupta and Venkatu 2002)</ref> or partial collusion <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Friedman and Thisse 1993</ref> All the above-mentioned articles are based on the assumption that collusion is costless-that is, there are no monitoring or implementation costs linked to the creation and the maintenance of a cartel. However, these costs are likely to exist, and they are often relevant. Indeed, setting up a collusive agreement entails the costs of negotiation, maintaining collusion requires the continuous monitoring of the other members of the cartel to avoid secret defections, and-given the illegal nature of cartelsavoiding prosecution from antitrust authorities generates additional costs. Several examples exist that demonstrate how setting up and maintaining a collusive agreement may be costly for the participating firms. For example, firms participating in a food flavor enhancers' cartel met several times a year to coordinate their actions. 2 These meetings required time, effort, and money. Sometimes, direct contacts may not be sufficient to maintain a collusive agreement, and a formal infrastructure has to be created to support collusion. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> In other cases, colluding firms have used joint sales agency to enhance their collusive agreement. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> In this article, we introduce collusion costs in a highly general model of collusion encompassing previous specific models. The aim of this paper is to provide a general theory about the "product differentiation-collusion sustainability" relationship in the presence of (sufficiently high) collusion costs. We shall show that the impact of product differentiation on the degree of collusion sustainability can be easily characterized and that the introduction of sufficiently high collusion costs might dramatically modify the impact of product differentiation on collusion sustainability with respect to the case where collusion costs are absent or low. That is, the way the market structure (product differentiation) influences the ability of firms to reduce competition depends in a nonobvious way on the costs for firms to set up and maintain an agreement.</p><p>To the best of our knowledge, the only article considering this issue is <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Thomadsen and Rhee (2007)</ref>. The authors show that when collusion costs are high enough, the relationship between product differentiation and collusion sustainability is always negative. However, this result is based on some specific assumptions on the sign of the derivative of the collusive, the deviation, and the punishment profits functions with respect to the level of product differentiation. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Our contribution is broader and provides a general theory about the impact of product differentiation on collusion sustainability without recourse to specific modelling assumptions: we shall show that the impact of product differentiation over the sustainability of collusion may also be positive and nonmonotonic with sufficiently high collusion costs, and we shall provide simple necessary and sufficient conditions for this to occur.</p><p>The rest of this paper proceeds as follows. In §2, we characterize the impact of collusion costs on the relationship between product differentiation and collusion sustainability in a general model of costly collusion. In §3, we illustrate our results by analyzing a Hotelling-style model with quantity-setting firms and a price discrimination model. Section 4 concludes with some final remarks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">A General Model of Costly Collusion</head><p>We consider a general model of collusion sustainability. The analysis is conducted here in the case of Nash reversion when a deviation from a cartel occurs <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Friedman 1971</ref>). <ref type="bibr">6</ref> We define d ∈ d d as the degree of differentiation between firms, where d ∈ R + ∪ 0 andd ∈ R + indicate the minimum and the maximum levels of product differentiation, respectively. We denote by N d , C d , and D d the static Nash equilibrium profits, the perperiod collusive profits, and the per-period deviation profits, respectively. The profit functions are continuous and once differentiable. To avoid trivial cases where collusion is never sustainable in equilibrium or always sustainable in equilibrium, it must be D d ≥ C d ≥ N d . <ref type="bibr">7</ref> To save on notation, the argument of the profits functions shall be omitted in the rest of the article when not necessary.</p><p>Let us denote by the market discount factor, which indicates the weight attached by firms to the future. Collusion is sustainable as a subgameperfect Nash equilibrium if and only if the discounted value of the profits that each firm obtains under collusion exceeds the discounted value of the profits that each firm obtains deviating from the cartel agreement. Formally stated, the following incentive-compatibility constraint must be satisfied in equilibrium for each firm participating in the cartel:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">t=0 t C d ≥ D d + t=1 t N d .</formula><p>After rearranging, the constraint can be rewritten as</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">≥ * ≡ D d − C d / D d − N d .</formula><p>We shall refer to * as the critical discount factor. The incentivecompatibility condition says that when the market discount factor is greater than the critical discount factor, collusion is sustainable in equilibrium; otherwise, it is not sustainable. Therefore, the critical discount factor represents a natural measure of the sustainability of the collusive agreement: the greater the * , the smaller the set of market discount factors that support collusion (i.e., collusion is more difficult to sustain); conversely, the lower the * , the larger the set of market discount factors that support collusion (i.e., collusion is less difficult to sustain).</p><p>We introduce a per-period cost of sustaining collusion, which is denoted by C. Therefore, the collusion profits in each period become C * = C − C. In this general context, we ask what the impact of a sufficiently high cost of sustaining collusion is on the relationship between product differentiation and collusion sustainability-that is, we investigate the sign of * / d. Our goal is to derive a simple and general characterization of the sign of * / d.</p><p>First, note that for collusion to be sustainable in equilibrium-at least for a nonempty subset of parameters-the costs of sustaining collusion cannot be too high. In particular, the following constraint must be satisfied at least for a subset of parameters: C ≤C d ≡ C − N . If the constraint is not satisfied, collusion (once the collusion costs are taken into account) is less profitable than competition; therefore, it cannot be sustainable. We assume thatC d is monotonically increasing, monotonically decreasing, or inverted U-shaped. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> Let us define ≡ arg max dC d , which is unique by assumption. Because we are looking for the impact of high collusion costs, we focus on the neighborhood ofd: by the definition ofd, if collusion costs satisfy the constraint C ≤C d outside the neighborhood ofd, they must also satisfy the constraint neard, although the reverse is not necessarily true. That is, if the constraint C ≤ C d is satisfied for some d, 9 it is always possible to find a sufficiently high C such that the constraint C ≤ C d holds in the neighborhood ofd. Consider the derivative of the critical discount factor with respect to d. We have *</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">d = D − C d D − N − D − N d D − C + C • D − N 2 −1 (1) If D − N / d ≤ 0, by (1) we have that * / d ≥ ≤ 0 ⇔ C ≥ ≤ C * , where C * ≡ D − N • D − C / d / D − N / d − D − C . On the other hand, if D − N / d ≥ 0, we have that * / d ≥ ≤ 0 ⇔ C ≤ ≥ C * .</formula><p>Proposition 1 provides the central result of this article. (c) Ifd =d, there always exists a level of C such that the critical discount factor decreases with the level of differentiation.</p><p>Proof. See the appendix. Proposition 1 has relevant implications. Even when the gain from colluding is not maximal at the minimum degree of differentiation, the impact of high costs of collusion over the relationship between product differentiation and collusion sustainability can still be easily characterized. Indeed, Proposition 1 shows that, if the gain from colluding has an interior maximum, there always exists a sufficiently high collusion cost such that the relationship between product differentiation and the critical discount factor is U-shaped, whereas if the gain from colluding is maximum when the degree of differentiation is maximum, there always exists a sufficiently high collusion cost such that the relationship between product differentiation and the critical discount factor is negative. In other Marketing Science 32(4), pp. 669-674, © 2013 INFORMS words, the shape of the gain from collusion function determines the impact of collusion costs on the relationship between product differentiation and collusion sustainability.</p><p>The intuition behind Proposition 1 is as follows (in the following discussion, we consider only the case where D − N / d ≤ 0; the other case can be treated by symmetry). With positive collusion costs, the critical discount factor becomes</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">* = D − C / D − N + C/ D − N . It fol- lows that * / d = D − C / D − N / d + C 1/ D − N / d.</formula><p>The latter equation shows that if C is sufficiently high, the impact of the differentiation degree over the critical discount factor is positive. We already indicated the critical threshold for the sign of the critical discount factor derivative by C * d . Let us denote the condition C ≥ C * d as the positivity constraint, because when it is satisfied, the relation between the differentiation degree and the critical discount factor is positive; otherwise, it is negative. However, recall that for collusion to be possible, the collusion costs must also satisfy the constraint regarding participation in the cartel-that is, C ≤C d . Therefore, for the impact of product differentiation over the critical discount factor to be positive, there must exist a level of C that simultaneously satisfies the participation constraint C ≤C d and the positivity constraint C ≥ C * d . The existence of such a level of collusion costs depends on the relative value of C * d andC d . In particular, for the relation between product differentiation and the critical discount factor to be positive for sufficiently high collusion costs, the necessary condition is that C * d must always be lower thanC d . In this case, it is always possible to find a level of costs that satisfies both constraints. On the other hand, under general shapes of the profits functions, it may be that C * d ≥C d : in this case, the participation constraint becomes binding at levels of collusion costs that do not satisfy the positivity constraint. Therefore, it is not possible to find collusion costs satisfying the positivity constraint while simultaneously maintaining the profitability of collusion, and the relation between product differentiation and the critical discount factor is negative or nonmonotonic. In sum, the impact of product differentiation on collusion sustainability under sufficiently high collusion costs is driven by both the participation and the positivity constraints. This opens the way for nonmonotonic relations between product differentiation and collusion sustainability.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Two Examples</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">First Example</head><p>In the first example, we consider the differentiated Hotelling model with quantity-setting competitors. This class of models was introduced by  <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Hamilton et al. (1989)</ref> and has received consistent attention by scholars. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> The following analysis is based on <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Hamilton et al. (1989)</ref>, Arevalo Tomé and Chamorro-Rivas ( <ref type="formula">2007</ref>), and <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Colombo (2012)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> Different from these articles, we introduce the positive costs of collusion. The profits functions are</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">N d = 12 − 6t 1 + d 2 + t 2 1 + 27d 2 − 16d 3 108 C d = 12 − 6t 1 − 2d + 2d 2 + t 2 1 − 3d + 3d 2 96 and D d = 60−6t 5−2d +6d 2 +t 2 5−3d +39d 2 −16d 3 384</formula><p>where d ∈ 0 1 measures the product differentiation degree, and t ∈ 0 1/2 indicates the disutility costs. Note that the function C − N is globally maximized atd = 20 + 63t − √ 400 − 2 088t + 5 121t 2 / 128t . Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> illustrates what happens to the critical discount factor when positive costs of sustaining collusion are introduced. <ref type="bibr">12</ref> Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> should be compared with Figures 1-3 in <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Thomadsen and Rhee (2007)</ref>. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Thomadsen and Rhee (2007)</ref>, one observes that when the collusion costs become sufficiently high, the critical discount factor for collusion sustainability increases in the level of product differentiation. In contrast, Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows that, for sufficiently high collusion costs, the critical discount factor becomes U-shaped for all levels of differentiation such that the critical discount factor is 10 See <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Colombo (2012)</ref> for an extensive review of this class of models. 11 Examples of cartels where firms collude by sharing the market and fixing the quantity to deliver are Amino Acids cartel-Archer Daniels Midland Co. and others (case 36545, D.Comm. June 7, 2000), Food Flavour Enhancers (case 37671, D.Comm. December 17, 2002), and Methylglucamine (case 37978, D.Comm. November 27, 2002). The last antitrust case states, for example, "According to this agreement, [customer 2]'s yearly needs of meglumine would be supplied by RPB up to a minimum of 25 tonnes. If requested by [customer 2], Merck could supply [customer 2] with its remaining needs" (see paragraph 91, http://eur-lex.europa.eu/ LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32004D0104:EN:HTML, accessed April 2, 2012). 12 Figures <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1 and 2</ref> have been drawn for t = 1/4. lower than 1 at least for some values of d. Interestingly, no level of the collusion costs satisfying the participation constraint can be found such that the critical discount factor is a monotonically increasing function of the degree of product differentiation between the firms. This occurs because, in contrast to the examples in <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Thomadsen and Rhee (2007)</ref>, the gain of collusion does not monotonically decrease for the whole range of product differentiation degrees. In particular, the gain of collusion has an interior maximum: we are in case (b) of Proposition 1, where we show that for sufficiently high collusion costs the relation between product differentiation and the critical discount factor must be U-shaped.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Second Example</head><p>In the second example, we consider the following collusive agreement between price-discriminating firms: firms coordinate on a uniform price but deviate and punish by adopting discriminatory prices. This kind of collusive agreement has been studied by <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Liu and Serfes (2007)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Colombo (2011)</ref>. Price discrimination implies that the firms are able to set price schedules instead of a uniform price: price schedules mean that the price is a function of the location of consumers, where the location of consumers can be intended both in a geographical sense <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Thisse and Vives 1988)</ref> and in a product-characteristic-space sense <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Shaffer and Zhang 1995)</ref>. Sufficient conditions for price discrimination to be possible are that the firms are able to recognize the consumers' location and that the consumers cannot arbitrate. The type of collusive agreement considered here assumes that the firms collude on a uniform price, even if they are individually able to set discriminatory prices. This type of collusive scheme can be rationalized as follows. Colluding on discriminatory prices is difficult to implement because it requires negotiating on a huge number of prices (one for each consumer/market). A less extreme collusive agreement is when firms try to coordinate on a uniform price. This scheme is less profitable, but it is easier to implement because it requires the firms to agree only on one price. On the other hand, during the deviation stage and during the punishment stage, there is no agreement between firms; thus each firm can use discriminatory prices. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> From <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Liu and Serfes (2007)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Colombo (2011)</ref>, we derive the relevant profits functions: C d = 4 − t 1 − 2d + 2d 2 /8 and D d = 4 − t 1 + 2d 2 /4, with d ∈ 0 1 and t ∈ 0 1/2 . We suppose here that firms adopt optimal punishment in the case of a deviation from the agreement. In the case of price <ref type="bibr">13</ref> Examples of this collusive scheme can be found in Austrian Banks (D.Comm. June 12, 2002) and Specialty Graphite (D.Comm. December 17, 2002). Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> is similar to Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> and contrasts with Figures 1-3 in <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Thomadsen and Rhee (2007)</ref>. It shows that when the costs of collusion are low, the relationship between product differentiation and the critical discount factor is negative. On the other hand, when the collusion costs increase, the critical discount factor becomes U-shaped with the differentiation level.</p><p>No admissible collusion costs level exists such that the critical discount factor strictly increases with the degree of differentiation between firms. As indicated in Proposition 2, the U-shaped relation between the degree of product differentiation and the critical discount factor for high levels of collusion costs depends on whether the gain of collusion has an interior maximum. 16</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Conclusions</head><p>Setting up and maintaining a collusive agreement is often costly for firms. Collusion costs include, for <ref type="bibr">14</ref> It follows that the collusive profits (including also the collusion costs) must be higher than the average profits in the case of punishment, which are zero in this case. <ref type="bibr">15</ref> Proposition 1 is still valid once the Nash profits are substituted by the average profits in case of punishment. <ref type="bibr">16</ref> The same result emerges when firms engage in imperfect price discrimination; that is, they are able to price discriminate across different groups of consumers but not across consumers belonging to the same group, and they adopt Nash reversion in the case of a deviation (see <ref type="bibr">Serfes 2004, Colombo 2010)</ref>. In this case, when the collusion costs are low, the critical discount factor increases with the level of product differentiation, but when the collusion costs become sufficiently high, the relationship between the critical discount factor and product differentiation becomes U-shaped. Details are available from the author upon request.</p><p>Marketing Science 32(4), pp. 669-674, © 2013 INFORMS example, the costs of negotiation and monitoring. This article considers collusion costs as regards a heavily debated question: What is the impact of product differentiation on the sustainability of a collusive agreement? It is shown that for sufficiently high collusion costs, the impact of product differentiation on the sustainability of a collusive agreement can be easily characterized through simple necessary and sufficient conditions. In particular, if the gain of collusion is maximized at a nonextreme degree of differentiation, for sufficiently high collusion costs, the relationship between product differentiation and the critical discount factor is U-shaped. For example, a U-shaped relationship between product differentiation and the critical discount factor for collusion sustainability is shown to exist for the case of a differentiated demand à la Hotelling, with firms competing with quantities, and for the case of firms being able to price discriminate across consumers having different tastes. Therefore, we have shown that the introduction of sufficiently high collusion costs might dramatically modify the impact of product differentiation on collusion sustainability with respect to the case where collusion costs are absent. For this reason, the existence of costs of collusion-which there surely are-is a key factor when assessing the impact of product differentiation over the likelihood that a collusive agreement arises in equilibrium.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Proposition 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>(a) Ifd = d, there always exists a level of C such that the critical discount factor increases with the level of differentiation. (b) Ifd ∈ d d , there always exists a level of C such that the critical discount factor is a U -shaped function of the level of differentiation.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1The Impact of Collusion Costs (First Example)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2The Impact of Collusion Costs (Second Example)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Colombo: Product Differentiation and Collusion Sustainability When Collusion Is Costly</figDesc><table><row><cell>670</cell><cell>Marketing Science 32(4), pp. 669-674, © 2013 INFORMS</cell></row></table><note>).1   </note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">See also<ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Tyagi (1999)</ref>, who analyzes the implications of demand specifications for the relationship between product differentiation and collusion sustainability. See<ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Colombo (2010)</ref> for more references on this issue.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2"> Food Flavour Enhancers (case 37671, D.Comm. December 17, 2002).3  In the Cast Iron and Steel Rolls case(D.Comm. October 17, 1983)   the firms involved in the cartel created a central office in charge of collecting and sharing relevant information (such as prices and outputs) across the cartel's members.4  <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Levenstein and Suslow (2006)</ref> contain a comprehensive discussion of the different types of costs emerging when a collusive agreement is constituted and participants act to preserve it from defection of members. Evidence of these costs is provided in numerous antitrust cases. Apart from the two previously cited cases, existence of collusion costs can also be found, for example, in Imperial Chemical Industries Ltd. v. Commission of the European Communities (ECJ July 14, 1972), PVC II (D.Comm. July 27, 1994), British Sugar plc et al.(D.Comm. October 14, 1998), Industrial and Medical Gases (case 36700, D.Comm. July 24, 2002), Methylglucamine (case 37978, D.Comm. November 27, 2002), and Organic Peroxide (case 37857, D.Comm. December 10, 2003).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">Namely,<ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Thomadsen and Rhee (2007)</ref> assume that the gains from colluding with and from deviating from the agreement strictly decrease with product differentiation. Although these assumptions hold in some models discussed in literature, they do not hold in other common models, such as those discussed in §3.6  It can be easily shown that our main result applies identically also to the case of optimal punishment<ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abreu 1988</ref>) once the Nash profits in the presented formulae are substituted by the average profits during the punishment stage, provided that the collusive profits (including the collusion costs) are higher than the average punishment profits. Details are available from the author upon request. The second example in §3 refers to a case of optimal punishment in the case of a deviation from the cartel.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">Clearly, if N d ≥ C d , collusion is never profitable. If C d ≥ D d ,collusion is always sustainable (provided that it is also profitable) because no firm has an incentive to deviate from the collusive agreement.8  This guarantees the existence of no more than one stationary point forC d . It should be noted that Proposition 1 holds also for more general shapes of functionC d , provided thatd is unique. I thank a reviewer for this clarification.d</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">Clearly, if C ≥C d for every d, the analysis is meaningless because collusion is never sustainable, as it is never profitable for the firms to participate in the cartel.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="17">A straightforward implication is that C * must intersectC in all the stationary points (if they exist) ofC.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The author thanks editor-in-chief Preyas Desai, the associate editor, and three anonymous reviewers for their great suggestions on previous versions of this work.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the theory of infinitely repeated games with discounting</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Abreu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="383" to="396" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Credible collusion in a model of spatial competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Arevalo Tomé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chamorro-Rivas J-M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Papers Regional Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="633" to="642" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of product differentiation on collusive pricing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M-H</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Indust. Organ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="453" to="470" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Product differentiation, price discrimination and collusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Colombo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Res. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spatially asymmetric firms and the sustainability of a price agreement</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Colombo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2414" to="2421" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collusion in two models of spatial competition with quantity-setting firms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Colombo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. Regional Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="69" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A non-cooperative equilibrium for supergames</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Partial collusion fosters minimum product differentiation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J-F</forename><surname>Thisse</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">RAND J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="631" to="645" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tacit collusion in a spatial model with delivered pricing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Venkatu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="64" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Endogenous product design in an infinitely repeated game</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Häckner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Indust. Organ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="277" to="299" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cournot in a model of location choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J-F</forename><surname>Thisse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Weskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Regional Sci. Urban Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="102" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Spatial discrimination: Bertrand vs</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What determines cartel success?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Levenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Suslow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Literature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="95" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quality of information and oligopolistic price discrimination</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Serfes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Management Strategy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="671" to="702" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Market segmentation and collusive behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Serfes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Indust. Organ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="378" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Delivered pricing and the impact of spatial differentiation on cartel stability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Miklós-Thal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Indust. Organ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1365" to="1380" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competitive coupon targeting</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Shaffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="395" to="416" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the strategic choice of spatial price policy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J-F</forename><surname>Thisse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Vives</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="122" to="137" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Costly collusion in differentiated industries</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thomadsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K-E</forename><surname>Rhee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="660" to="665" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the relationship between product substitutability and tacit collusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Tyagi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Managerial Decision Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="293" to="298" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Horizontal Merger Guidelines</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.justice.gov/atr/public/guidelines/horiz_book/hmg1.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<pubPlace>Washington, DC</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>U.S. Department of Justice/Federal Trade Commission ; U.S. Department of Justice</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
