<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org A Direct Utility Model for Asymmetric Complements</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2013-04-08">April 8, 2013.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sanghak</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
							<email>sanghak-lee@uiowa.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jaehwan</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Greg</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
							<email>allenby.1@osu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Tippie College of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Iowa</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>52242</postCode>
									<settlement>Iowa City, Iowa</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Business School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Korea University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Korea University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>136-701</postCode>
									<settlement>Seoul</settlement>
									<country key="KR">Korea</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Fisher College of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ohio State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>43210</postCode>
									<settlement>Columbus</settlement>
									<region>Ohio</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org A Direct Utility Model for Asymmetric Complements</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 (print)</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2013-04-08">April 8, 2013.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.2013.0782</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: November 21, 2011; accepted: January 19, 2013</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:24+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>utility theory</term>
					<term>choice modeling</term>
					<term>Bayesian estimation</term>
					<term>indivisible demand</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>The simultaneous demand for goods in multiple categories can be attributed to many factors. Demand can be simultaneously high because goods are complements, from cross-category timing of promotions and price discounts, from relaxed budgets corresponding to large shopping trips, and from the presence of joint demand shocks reflecting unobserved spikes in demand. Until recently, multicategory demand models have relied extensively on modified versions of the same models used to study substitute goods. Modifications include the introduction of correlated error terms <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Li et al. 2005</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">, Manchanda et al. 1999</ref>, correlated coefficients <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Duvvuri et al. 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">, Hansen et al. 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">, Erdem 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">, Ainslie and Rossi 1998</ref>, the presence of common covariates <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Nair et al. 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">, Basu et al. 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">, Manchanda et al. 1999</ref>, and the distinction between consumption and purchase <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Dubé 2004</ref>) that helps account for the likelihood of simultaneous purchases. Although these modifications have the capability of representing patterns of correlated demand, they are limited in their ability to explain its origin. Correlated errors and correlated coefficients do not distinguish between inherently complementary products, defined in terms of superadditive utility, versus the presence of other reasons for simultaneous purchase and negative cross-price effects.</p><p>An interesting aspect of modeling cross-category demand lies in detecting the presence of demand asymmetries. One category might be more dependent on the other while the other less dependent on the first, which is not reflected by introducing simple interaction terms into a consumer's utility function. In models of quadratic utility where U x 1 x 2 = x + 1/2 x Bx, for example, off-diagonal elements of the coefficient matrix, B, are constrained to be symmetric (e.g., ij = ji ), because utility is scalar and depends on the sum of coefficients in the term ij + ji x i x j , not each coefficient separately. The symmetry constraint is present in all models employing quadratic forms-e.g., translog utility functions <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Christensen et al. 1975)</ref>.</p><p>The marketing literature has recently begun to move to more formal models of cross-category demand. <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Song and Chintagunta (2007)</ref> propose a model structure for cross-category analysis based on economic theory that relies on a Taylor series approximation to an underlying indirect utility function. Their model captures households' multicategory purchase incidence, brand choice, and purchase quantity Lee, Kim, and Allenby: Direct Utility Model for Asymmetric Complements Marketing Science 32(3), pp. <ref type="bibr">454-470, © 2013 INFORMS 455</ref> decisions by considering a joint utility function of multicategory purchases. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Mehta's (2007)</ref> model is similar to that of <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Song and Chintagunta (2007)</ref> in that the basic translog indirect utility function is employed and the logit choice probability forms the basis of the model. However, the model is restricted to account for the purchase incidence only, ignoring the possibly confounding effect of satiation on market basket demand. We note that both models rely on an indirect translog utility function <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Pollak and</ref><ref type="bibr">Wales 1992, Christensen et al. 1975)</ref>, which in turn relies on a Taylor series approximation of an arbitrary utility or indirect utility function. One of the advantages of this approach is that it does not rely on any specific form of a utility function. However, although offering some flexibility, it is limited in describing crosscategory relationships that result from the symmetry restriction.</p><p>We propose a direct utility model in which a consumer makes a sequence of purchase decisions across multiple categories. Asymmetric cross-category dependences are identified from the differential responsiveness of the demand of one category to the changes in cross-category purchases and inventory. Temporal variations in purchase quantities, together with interpurchase times, allow us to infer the latent inventories that might have a differential impact on its cross-category demand. A latent sequence of a consumer's purchases allows for a direct interaction among the multicategory decisions within the same shopping trip such that purchases in one category are affected by earlier purchases in other categories. We posit a latent model for the purchase sequence, allowing the probability of a particular sequence to be influenced by product inventory and observed merchandising variables. Our data likelihood is obtained by integrating over the latent sequences.</p><p>We contribute to the literature on complementary demand by developing a direct utility model that identifies asymmetric interdependencies among goods. Our model has the following properties: (i) an order of sequential purchase decisions is estimated;</p><p>(ii) the model allows for asymmetric interdependencies among categories including complementarity as well as substitutability; (iii) the model provides a unified framework to handle brand-level purchase quantities, accommodating both corner and interior solutions; and (iv) the model explicitly deals with the indivisibility of data, not assuming a continuous decision space for a consumer. The model is applied to scanner panel data of milk and cereal purchases. The parameter estimates provide evidence of asymmetric complementarity between milk and cereal such that the impact of milk on the utility of cereal is greater than the impact of cereal on the utility of milk. The presence of asymmetric spillover effects has implications for marketing practice, particularly for the sequencing of category investment decisions and the cross-category coordination of promotional campaigns. We show that asymmetric interdependency in utility leads to asymmetric spillover effects of promotions and that assuming symmetric effects will bias the parameter estimates and distorts policy implications.</p><p>In the next section, we develop our direct utility model that is assumed to be maximized subject to budgetary and packaging restrictions. In §3, our model is applied to scanner panel data, and the estimation results are summarized. Section 4 discusses the implications of our model, and concluding remarks are offered in §5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Model Development</head><p>Complementary products are defined in our model in terms of a superadditive utility structure that favors joint as opposed to separate purchase. Our definition is different from the standard economic definition of complementarity (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Pashigian 1998)</ref>, where negative cross-price effects are used to identify complementary products. That is, if a price decrease in one good leads to increased demand for another, then the goods are traditionally considered as complements. Such an effect, however, can be due to many factors such as a person's attention to prices being more acute during a weekly, large budgeted shopping trip versus a filler trip for specific basket items. Our goal here is to derive insight into how utility is formed, which we believe to be more informative than studying how consumers react to prices.</p><p>We begin our model development with the utility specification, and then we introduce a latent decision sequence into a model. We then present the specification of the model likelihood and discuss the identification of the asymmetric complementarity. The model is developed in terms of two product categories for exposition and then generalized to an arbitrary number of categories.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Direct Utility Model for Sequential Decisions</head><p>Our model assumes that a consumer makes a series of decisions over multiple categories within a shopping trip. Only one category is considered at a time, and the decisions made earlier have an impact on the later decisions based on their cross-category relationships. The purchase quantities of all the brands within a category, however, are determined simultaneously. A model of sequential decisions might reflect a physical path of a consumer's trip at a store, or it might represent the order of decisions made in a consumer's mind that may be different from the temporal sequence of actual purchases.</p><p>Marketing Science 32(3), pp. <ref type="bibr">454-470, © 2013 INFORMS</ref> The assumption of sequential decisions has an intuitive appeal in that necessary information for decision making is provided in a sequential manner in a marketplace. For example, a consumer is exposed to the prices and promotions of the items under one category as the consumer walks in the aisle of that category. In addition, the model of sequential decisions better represents how consumers deal with the inherently high dimensionality of multicategory decisions. In cases where there are n categories and m brands under each category, a consumer makes purchase decisions about total n × m items in a given shopping trip. We believe that consumers make a series of smaller and feasible decisions, each of which considers only m brands under the same category rather than solving a constrained utility maximization of the n × m items simultaneously.</p><p>Suppose there are two product categories (i.e., X and Y ), and two brands are available for each category (i.e., x 1 , x 2 and y 1 , y 2 ), with their unit prices being (p x 1 , p x 2 p y 1 p y 2 ) and unit volumes being (s</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">x 1 s x 2 s y 1 s y 2</formula><p>). In a shopping trip at time t, a consumer has a fixed budget E that implies the maximum willingness to pay for the two categories, and the consumer is aware of the levels of the inventories of the two categories (i.e., x t , y t ). We assume that consumer purchases reflect a sequential process of constrained utility maximization across product categories. If category X is considered first and the decision on category Y is made conditional on the decision on X, then the purchase decision can be described as two-step procedure.</p><p>First, a consumer makes a purchase decision on X to maximize the joint utility of X and an outside good Z x under a set of constraints: (i) a budget constraint defined by E and the unit prices p x it , (ii) the discreteness imposed by package sizes, and (iii) nonnegativity of purchase quantities. Here, the outside good is defined as the remaining dollars that are saved rather than spent on the inside goods (X), and the linear subutility for the outside good is assumed:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">max x 1t x 2t z xt U x 1t x 2t z xt x t y t = 2 i=1 x it log s x i x it + x t + z z xt s.t. 2 i=1 p x it x it + z xt ≤ E x it ∈ 0 1 2 ∀ i ∈ 1 2 z xt ≥ 0 (1)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">x it = exp x i + yx y t + x i m x it + x it , with m x it</formula><p>denoting a marketing activity on x it . The parameter x i represents the time-invariant baseline utility of x it , and x i measures the impact of a marketing activity m it ; 1 yx captures the impact of category Y on the utility of category X, with positive yx implying complementarity and negative yx implying substitutability; x it implies a demand shock that is known to a decision maker but not revealed to a researcher, and it is assumed to follow an independent and identically distributed (i.i.d.) probability distribution. Because of the concavity of logarithm, the marginal utility of x it is a decreasing function of its own purchase quantity and the inventory of X. The utility specification in (1) allows for horizontal variety-seeking behavior of a consumer, which is manifested by the shopping basket where multiple brands of a category are purchased simultaneously.</p><p>Once the purchase decision is made for the first category, the second category is considered in the same manner. However, its purchase utility is influenced by the previous purchase decision on the first category, and the unspent money from the first decision becomes the total budget for the second decision. Conditional on the purchase decision on X (i.e., x * 1t , x * 2t ), the consumer makes a purchase decision on Y such that the joint utility of Y and the outside good Z y is maximized under the remaining budget (i.e.,</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">E = E − 2 i=1 p x it x * it ): max y 1t y 2t z yt U y 1t y 2t z yt x * 1t x * 2t x t y t = 2 j=1 y jt log s y j y jt + y t + z z yt s.t. 2 j=1 p y jt y jt + z yt ≤ E y jt ∈ 0 1 2 ∀ j ∈ 1 2 z yt ≥ 0 (2)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">y jt = exp y j + xy x t + 2 i=1 s x i x * it + y j m y jt + y jt ;</formula><p>xy captures the impact of category X on the utility of category Y and is associated with the sum of the inventory and the newly purchased amount of X (i.e.,</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">x t + 2 i=1 s x i x * it )</formula><p>. Linear subutility of an outside good implies that the value of unspent money does not satiate and leads to the constant marginal utility of the outside good (i.e., U z t = U / z t = z ), which is independent of the budgetary allotment, E. Therefore, our model is agnostic not only to the level of the budgetary allotment but also to whether consumers have separate budgets for different categories. The unspent money from the first decision can either be allocated for the second category or be saved again in the second decision.</p><p>When the sequence of purchase decisions is reversed, everything remains the same except for two things: (i) the budgetary allotment is now E for the purchase of Y , and E = E − 2 j=1 p y jt y * jt for X; and (ii) x it is dependent on</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">y t + 2 i=1 s y j y * jt , whereas y jt</formula><p>is only influenced by the current inventory of Y and not by the purchase amount of X at time t. Note that the optimality conditions under the two sequences are indifferent if the observed purchases are all zero. Positive purchase quantities differentiate the optimality conditions under the two different sequences, informing which sequence is more likely than the other.</p><p>We introduce a latent level of category interest, t , by which the order of the purchase sequence is determined:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">x t = x 0 + 1 x t + 2 2 i=1 m x it + x t y t = y 0 + 1 y t + 2 2 j=1 m y jt + y t<label>(3)</label></formula><p>The parameter 0 implies the category-specific baseline of interest, and 1 and 2 capture the influence of inventory and marketing activities, respectively. We expect the interest of a category increases when the inventory is low or when marketing activities draw more attention from a consumer. 2 t is a stochastic component of latent interest and is assumed to follow an i.i.d. Type I extreme-value distribution, 3 which produces a closed-form expression for the sequence probability. Category X is considered first if its interest level is greater than that of Y (i.e., x t ≥ y t ); the reverse is true otherwise.</p><p>Because household inventory is not observed by an analyst, a model for consumption is required to approximate the inventory of goods. We employ an exponential decay model for inventory depletion, in which a fixed proportion of goods is consumed in each period <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Ailawadi et al. 2007</ref>). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> The inventory y 1 ). However, the difference was found to be insignificant in our empirical analysis, which might not be the case when dealing with other categories. The choice of the base unit for each category as the most frequently chosen package size alleviates the concern of incomparability of the inventories of different categories. 3 F x = exp − exp −x . <ref type="bibr">4</ref> We also tried a linear decay model, in which a constant amount of goods is consumed in a unit period. However, the exponential decay pattern is chosen based on the model fit.</p><p>of category X at time t is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">x t = t−1 t x x t−1 + 2 i=1 s x i x i t−1 (4)</formula><p>where t − 1 t denotes the time interval between the two shopping trips, and x indicates the rate of inventory for category X, which lies between 0 and 1. Because of the recursive structure of the inventory decay model in (4), an initial inventory level is required. We set it to be equal to the average inventory level that can be calculated from the data in a model-free manner.</p><p>There are two sources of inventory updates in our model. First, the consumption of a good is the major source of inventory updates. The time-series observation of past purchase quantities and interpurchase time provide the information for estimating the rate of consumption. Second, a latent decision sequence allows for the immediate update of the inventory of the previously purchased good when the decision of the second good is made. This allows for a direct interaction between the purchase decisions that are made during the same shopping trip.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Model Likelihood</head><p>The model likelihood comprises two stochastic components: (i) the probability of each sequence and (ii) the conditional probability of purchase quantities given a sequence. Because we only observe the purchase quantities without knowing the sequence of decisions, we first derive the conditional likelihood for the purchase quantities and then integrate over the probabilities of the sequences to obtain the marginal likelihood of the purchase quantities. There are two possible sequences with two categories: (i) first X, then Y (i.e., x t ≥ y t ); or (ii) first Y , then X (i.e.,</p><p>x t &lt; y t ). The probability of each sequence can be derived in closed form as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">Pr x t ≥ y t = 1 1+exp y 0 − x 0 + 1 y t − x t + 2 2 j=1 m y jt − 2 i=1 m x it Pr x t &lt; y t = 1−Pr x t ≥ y t<label>(5)</label></formula><p>The conditional likelihood of purchase quantities given a specific sequence is derived by associating the observed data with the optimality conditions for the sequential decision problems formulated in (1) and (2). The indivisibility of purchase data is incorporated into the model as a constraint on a consumer's decision space with the observed purchase quantities not necessarily indicating the exact point of utility maximization, but rather the grid point at which feasible and constrained utility is maximized (see <ref type="bibr">Lee</ref>  <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">and Allenby 2013</ref>). If a consumer makes Marketing Science 32(3), pp. 454-470, © 2013 INFORMS a decision on X first and then considers the purchase of Y , the likelihood of the data (x * 1t x * 2t y * 1t y * 2t ) can be factored into the likelihood of (x * 1t x * 2t ) and the likelihood of (y * 1t y * 2t x * 1t x * 2t ). Because the budget constraint is binding at the optimal solution (i.e., 2 i=1 p x it x * it + z *</p><p>xt = E), we can simplify the decision problem in (1) by substituting the budget constraint for z xt in the utility specification:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">max x 1t x 2t U * x 1t x 2t x t y t = 2 i=1 x it log s x i x it + x t + z E − 2 i=1 p x it x it s.t. x it ∈ 0 1 2 ∀ i ∈ 1 2 E − 2 i=1</formula><p>p x it x it ≥ 0 (6) U * is the constrained utility function of the inside goods only, where the budget constraint is always satisfied. The nonnegativity constraint for the outside good in (1) places an upper boundary for the decision space of the inside goods such that the total spending for the inside goods does not exceed the budgetary allotment (i.e., E − 2 i=1 p x it x it ≥ 0). When the unconstrained utility function U is additively separable with the linear subutility for the outside good, the sufficient conditions for an observed quantity (x * 1t x * 2t ) to be optimal can be simplified as follows: <ref type="formula">7</ref>) Substituting the constrained utility in (6) into the optimality conditions in (7) yields the bounds on error realizations (</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">U * x * 1t x * 2t ≥ max U * x * 1t + 1 x * 2t + 2 i ∈ −1 0 1 (</formula><formula xml:id="formula_12">x 1t x 2t ) that rationalize the observed demand (x * 1t x * 2t ): lb x it &lt; x it &lt; ub x it ∀ i ∈ 1 2 where lb x it = log 0 p x it − log log s x i x * it + x t s x i x * it − 1 + x t − x i − yx y t − x i m x it ub x it = log 0 p x it − log log s x i x * it + 1 + x t s x i x * it + x t − x i − yx y t − x i m x it (8)</formula><p>In the case x * it = 0, no comparison is required with the point where i = −1 because of the nonnegativity constraint for x it . Therefore, there is no lower boundary for x it (i.e., lb x it = − ). Theoretically, a similar logic can be applied to the case where additional purchase of brand i is not feasible because of the restriction of the budgetary allotment. 5 However, we preclude this case by setting E that can afford additional purchase of any inside good. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> It is assumed that purchasing an additional unit of any inside good is always feasible, but it does not occur for optimality (i.e., it is better off to save that money). Because the budget constraint is always binding at the optimal solution (i.e., 2 i=1 p x it x * it + z *</p><p>xt = E), this assumption implies that there is always some saved money that is no less than the maximum price of the inside goods (i.e., z *</p><p>xt ≥ max p x 1t p x 2t ). Assuming x it follows an i.i.d. probability distribution f , we can compute the likelihood of (x * 1t x * 2t ) by integrating over the joint density of the errors over the region specified in (8):</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">L x * 1t x * 2t x t ≥ y t = ub x 1t lb x 1t f x 1t d x 1t ub x 2t lb x 2t f x 2t d x 2t (9)</formula><p>The likelihood of (y</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">* 1t y * 2t x * 1t x * 2t ) can be computed in a similar way. The budget is now E (=E − 2 i=1 p x it x * it )</formula><p>, and the utility of y jt y jt is influenced not only by the inventory ( x t ) but also by the purchase quantities of </p><formula xml:id="formula_15">X 2 i=1 s x i x * it : max y 1t y 2t U * y 1t y 2t x * 1t x * 2t x t y t = 2 j=1 y jt log s y j y jt + y t + z E − 2 j=1 p y jt y jt s.t. y jt ∈ 0 1 2 ∀j ∈ 1 2 E −</formula><p>6 Because our model is agnostic to the level of the budgetary allotment as a result of the linear subutility for the outside good, the estimation results are not influenced by the choice of E. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>459</head><p>Integrating the joint density of ( y 1t y 2t ) over the region in (11) produces the likelihood of (y</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">* 1t y * 2t x * 1t x * 2t ): L y * 1t y * 2t x * 1t x * 2t x t ≥ y t = ub y 1t lb y 1t f y 1t d y 1t ub y 2t lb y 2t f y 2t d y 2t<label>(12)</label></formula><p>The conditional likelihood of (x * 1t x * 2t y * 1t y * 2t ) given the specific sequence is equal to the product of the likelihood of</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">x * 1t x * 2t and the likelihood of y * 1t y * 2t x * 1t x * 2t : L x * 1t x * 2t y * 1t y * 2t x t ≥ y t = L x * 1t x * 2t x t ≥ y t L y * 1t y * 2t x * 1t x * 2t x t ≥ y t<label>(13)</label></formula><p>Consequently, the joint likelihood of the sequence and the purchase quantities is given by multiplying the probability of the sequence in ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_9">5</ref>) by the conditional likelihood of the purchase quantities given the sequence in ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_18">13</ref>):</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">L x * 1t x * 2t y * 1t y * 2t x t ≥ y t = Pr x t ≥ y t L x * 1t x * 2t y * 1t y * 2t x t ≥ y t<label>(14)</label></formula><p>Because the joint likelihood of the opposite sequence and the purchase quantities is given in a similar manner, we can compute the marginal likelihood of the purchase quantities by integrating out the purchase orders:</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">L x * 1t x * 2t y * 1t y * 2t = L x * 1t x * 2t y * 1t y * 2t x t ≥ y t +L x * 1t x * 2t y * 1t y * 2t x t &lt; y t<label>(15)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Identification</head><p>Asymmetric complementarity is identified by the differential responsiveness of demand to the latent cross-category inventories. Whereas the demand of a strongly dependent category is sensitive to the temporal changes in the latent inventory of another product category, the demand of an independent category is not affected by the cross-category inventory. The expression for the marginal utility 7 illustrates this property:</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">U x it = U x it = s x i exp x i + yx y t + x i m x it + x it s x i x it + x t (16)</formula><p>Dealing with purchase quantities is crucial for the model identification because they provide information for the temporal variations in latent inventories. The longitudinal variations in purchase quantities <ref type="bibr">7</ref> Although indivisibility prevents us from using the marginal utility for computing the likelihood, this expression is still valid because the discreteness comes from the constraint, not from the utility.</p><p>( x t y t T t=1 ), together with interpurchase time, lead to variation in inventories over time ( x t y t T t=1 ) that enables us to identify asymmetric complementarity ( yx xy ). The extent to which the demand of X is responsive to the inventory of Y determines the sign and the magnitude of yx , which might be different from xy .</p><p>For the purpose of illustration, we contrast two sets of hypothetical data where good X is more dependent on good Y in one (i.e., xy &lt; yx ), and the opposite is true in the other (i.e., xy &gt; yx ). All the other model elements are set to be identical to ensure that any difference between the two data sets is attributed to the asymmetry in complementarity. Each data set is simulated such that a hypothetical consumer makes a purchase quantity decision for two goods, X and Y , over a certain period (T = 200). Idiosyncratic errors are drawn from a normal distribution, and prices and feature advertisements are generated from a standard normal and a binomial distribution, respectively.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> illustrates the different patterns in the hypothetical data sets that are driven by the asymmetric complementarity. Each box plot summarizes a distribution of 1,000 sample correlations, each of which is computed from a randomly drawn hypothetical data set.</p><p>When X is more dependent on Y (i.e., xy &lt; yx ), the correlation between the demand of X and the inventory of Y is greater than the correlation between the demand of Y and the inventory of X. We also observe that the magnitude of the positive correlation between the demand of X and the demand shifter of Y , such as price or feature advertisement, is greater than that of the opposite case. Likewise, when Y is more dependent on X, the demand of Y is more responsive to the temporal changes in the inventory of X, which are possibly driven by the demand shifters of Y .</p><p>Note that it is seldom the case that the demonstrated patterns in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> are observed in actual data in a model-free manner. Because the observed demand is influenced by many factors other than complementarity, any asymmetry between the two goods can create differences in correlations. In addition, the proliferation of zeros in actual data masks or at least weakens the relationship among variables unless it is systematically controlled for.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.">Extensions to N Categories</head><p>Although the model likelihood in ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_20">15</ref>) is derived for the simplest case with two categories, it can be extended to a more general case where N categories are related to one another. A consumer has a latent level of interest for category i, which is affected by the  level of inventory and the sum of marketing activities conducted on the n i brands under the category:</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">i t = i 0 + 1 i t + 2 n i k=1 m i kt + i t i ∈ 1 N (<label>17</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_23">)</formula><p>If i t is assumed to follow an i.i.d. Type I extremevalue distribution, the probability of a complete sequence is given by an exploded logit form as follows <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Chapman and Staelin 1982)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">Pr 1 t &gt; 2 t &gt; • • • &gt; N t = N −1 i=1 exp i 0 + 1 i t + 2 m i kt N j=i exp j 0 + 1 j t + 2 m j kt (18)</formula><p>Conditional on a specific sequence S i (e.g.,</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">1 t &gt; 2 t &gt; • • • &gt; N t )</formula><p>, it is straightforward to compute the conditional likelihood of purchase quantities. Let x i * denote the observed purchase quantities for brands in category i. The conditional likelihood of the purchase quantities across N categories (x 1 *</p><p>x N * ) is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">L x 1 * x N * S i = L x 1 * S i L x 2 * x 1 * S i ×••• ×L x N * x 1 * x N −1 * S i (19)</formula><p>Consequently, the likelihood of purchase quantities is computed by summing over all the joint probabilities of the purchase quantities and sequence as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">L x 1 * x N * = N ! i=1 Pr S i L x 1 * x N * S i (20)</formula><p>We acknowledge that the proposed model of sequential decisions is limited to accommodate a relatively small number of categories because the number of latent sequences increases exponentially as the number of categories increases; N categories give rise to N ! different latent sequences in total. However, if we can predefine independent categories, the number of latent sequences to be explored is dramatically reduced, which enables us to expand the number of categories in analysis. The development of a more general framework for asymmetric complements is left as a further study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5.">Heterogeneity</head><p>Consumer heterogeneity is incorporated by introducing a random-effect specification for household parameters:</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">h = h h * h h * h ∼ N ¯ + z h V (<label>21</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_29">)</formula><p>where h = 1 H indexes the households, and = exp * = 1/ 1 + exp − * . <ref type="bibr">8</ref> We examine household size and household income as covariates z h , and we center these variables so that¯ reflects the population mean.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.6.">Simulation Study</head><p>A simulation study is conducted to illustrate the performance of our model. Data are generated according to the model likelihood with randomly generated prices and feature advertising variables for 150 respondents and 150 observations per respondent. These choices were made so that the simulated prices and data are of similar length to our empirical study reported below. We illustrate the model using three product categories and two brands under each category, and various cross-category relationships are imposed among the three categories: X and Y are asymmetric complements, Y and Z are substitutes, and X and Z are assumed to be independent. A random-effect distribution was employed without covariates with covariance equal to 0 5I. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">1</ref> reports the estimated mean of the random-effect distribution, along with the true values.</p><p>All the parameters are well recovered, having the true values within 95% credible intervals. The simulation study confirms that we can estimate models of various cross-category relationships including independence, substitutes, and asymmetric complementarity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Empirical Analysis</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Data</head><p>We applied our model to the IRI panel data set described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bronnenberg et al. (2008)</ref>. Milk and cereal categories are chosen to illustrate the asymmetric cross-category inferences afforded by our <ref type="bibr">8</ref> The reparameterization guarantees 0 &lt; , 0 &lt; &lt; 1. 1 000 1 000 0 040 −0 209 0 041 Impact of marketing activity on utilitȳ</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">¯</formula><formula xml:id="formula_31">x * 1 −1 204 −1 292 0 085 ¯ x * 2 −1 204 −1 292 0 098 ¯ y * 1 −1 204 −1 319 0 106 ¯ y * 2 −1 204 −1 285 0 098 ¯ z * 1 −1 204 −1 239 0 121 ¯ z * 2 −1 204 −1 230 0 109 Inventory ratē * x 0 0000 −0 021 0 074 ¯ * y 0 000 −0 047 0 084 ¯ * z 0 000 −0 101 0 082 Decision sequencē y 0 0 000 −0 027 0 148 ¯ z 0 0 000 −0 295 0 245 ¯ 1 −1 000 −0 849 0 291 ¯ 2</formula><p>1 000 0 823 0 136</p><p>Notes. Posterior standard deviations are given in parentheses. = exp * and = 1/ 1 + exp − * model specification. The data contain each household's grocery shopping history, in which purchase quantities, prices, and marketing activities (e.g., feature and display) are available. We include all purchase occasions in our analysis, including those when no purchases are made in either category. Although our model is general enough to be applied to a brandlevel analysis, the cereal category contains many brands with relatively small volume, with the top 40 brands accounting for 70% of total demand and the share of the leading brand being just 8.8%. We therefore engage in an aggregation of stock-keeping units to keep the number of model parameters to a reasonable level. We retain the two leading manufacturers in each product category for analysis and aggregate the products to form three package-size groups within each manufacturer. This allows us to move from an analysis of 157 universal product codes (UPCs) to 12 aggregates-6 in milk and 6 in cereal. Therefore, the subscript i in (1) corresponds to each aggregate  </p><formula xml:id="formula_32">x i = x 1 D1 x i + x 2 D2 x i + x l DL x i + x s DS x i (<label>22</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_33">)</formula><p>where D1 x i , D2 x i , DL x i , and DS x i are the indicators of manufacturer 1, manufacturer 2, large package size, and small package size, respectively. The top two manufacturers are Guida's and private label for milk and General Mills and Kellogg's for cereal, and they account for approximately 60%-80% of the total sales with each category. 9 A share-weighted average of the UPC-level store variables (e.g., unit price, unit volume, feature, and display) is computed to represent those of each package-size group. We select households who have at least 20 purchases of milk and cereal during the two-year data period, resulting in 140 households. The unit volume of the most frequently purchased item is used as the base unit of volume for each category (128 oz. for milk, 15 oz. for cereal). A basic description of the data is provided in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">2</ref>.</p><p>Households make an average of 151 shopping trips during the two-year data period, with 42% of the trips involving the purchase of milk and 27% of the trips involving cereal; 47% of the trips contain purchases in neither category, and 16% of the trips contain both. We find that large-sized and mediumsized packages of milk are more frequently promoted (e.g., feature advertisement) than other package sizes and that the data show variety-seeking behavior of consumers in both milk and cereal categories. Of the cereal purchases, 13% come from multiple manufacturers, which is rarely observed in milk. Joint purchases of multiple pack sizes (within the same manufacturer) are observed 5% of the time for milk and 16% for cereal. We use 90% of the data for the model calibration, leaving 10% for prediction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Estimation Results</head><p>We assume that consumers maximize utility subject to budget and packaging constraints, and we employ Lee and Allenby's (2013) estimation strategy for indivisible demand. Demand discreteness is caused by transactions constrained to lie on a grid of support defined by the available package sizes, resulting in a model likelihood with interior points defined in terms of point masses instead of the usual density contribution to the likelihood. As discussed earlier, there are many error realizations associated with any observed purchase when demand is indivisible.</p><p>A standard normal distribution with mean zero and unit variance is employed for the distribution of errors. We found that the variance of the errors is weakly identified in our empirical study, which might be due to the lack of variations in purchase quantities. Because zeros and ones are the most frequently observed quantities in our data, fixing the variance at one helps identifying the model parameters. The correlation among the errors within a category is not allowed for alleviating the computational burden in the likelihood computation. However, our model allows for positive correlation among the utilities of the brands within the same category because the category-level inventories affect all the brands within the same category to the same direction. For example, a high inventory of category A decreases the utilities of all the brands within category A because of satiation while it increases the utilities of all the brands within category B because of complementarity.  We estimate the model using Bayesian Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) methods with proper but relatively diffuse priors. 10 Seventy thousand iterations of the chain were used to generate parameter estimates, with the first 20,000 draws discarded as burn-in. Because sequential draws from the joint posterior are autocorrelated, we thinned the chain by keeping every 10th draw of the remaining 50,000 draws <ref type="bibr">Lewis 1992, Geyer 1992)</ref>. The detailed sampling procedure is provided in Appendix A. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref> reports posterior means and standard deviations of the hyperparameters,¯ .</p><p>There is ordinal agreement between the estimates of baseline preferences for manufacturers reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref> and the market shares reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">2</ref>. Consumers prefer the one-gallon package size in milk and disfavor milk packaged in quart containers. In cereal, the larger package size (20 oz.) is less preferred to medium (15 oz.) or small (11 oz.) package sizes. More</p><formula xml:id="formula_34">10 h ≡ h h * h h * h ∼ N ¯ V , where¯ ∼ N 0 100I and V ∼ IW 25 25I .</formula><p>interesting are the estimates of complementary parameters that reflect cross-category effects. The two categories show a complementary relationship in which the marginal utility of one good is enhanced by the presence of the other. The impact of milk on the utility of cereal is greater than the impact of cereal on the utility of milk (i.e.,¯ mc &gt;¯ cm ), indicating the presence of asymmetric complementarity. Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> illustrates the asymmetric effect, where the subutility of cereal is heightened with the presence of milk whereas the subutility of milk is weakly enhanced by cereal. These results have face validity because milk is often consumed independently whereas cereal is more likely to be consumed with milk.</p><p>Marketing activities of the retailer (e.g., feature advertisement, merchandising display) enhance the marginal utility of the promoted item, which in turn increases the likelihood of purchase. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref> shows differences in the effectiveness of various marketing activities. Feature advertisement is effective for Guida's milk and Kellogg's cereal, whereas its influence is small for private label milk and General Mills cereal. The merchandising display of cereal has a greater impact in increasing the marginal utility than the feature advertisement.</p><p>The inventory rate is greater for cereal than for milk, implying that consumers tend to stockpile cereal, whereas milk is more frequently depleted. The baseline interest of cereal is higher than that of milk, which is set to be zero for identification. However, when a consumer stockpiles cereal, the purchase decision for milk is made first as the latent interest of cereal is lowered because of the inventory. The marketing activities such as feature and display do not make a significant impact on the latent interests of the categories.</p><p>Finally, we find that household size is significantly related to the individual-level parameters as summarized in Table <ref type="table">4</ref>. Larger households prefer larger packages of milk, but not cereal. We do not find any significant relationship between household income and individual-level parameters.</p><p>Although not reported, for the sake of brevity, the estimate of the variance-covariance matrix of the random effects show that consumers are more heterogeneous in the impact of milk on the utility of cereal than in the impact of cereal on the utility of milk (i.e., var mc = 0 59 &gt; var cm = 0 27). The positive correlation among the two complementarity parameters (i.e., cov mc cm = 0 09) suggests that the two goods tend to be jointly complementary.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Model Comparison</head><p>The proposed model is compared with six benchmark models. The first model is identical to the proposed model except for the symmetric restriction in complementarity (i.e., ij = ji ). The second model assumes that there is no interdependency between the two categories (i.e., ij = ji = 0). When categories are independent, the conditional likelihood of purchase quantities given a sequence stays the same across different sequences. Therefore, the parameters for capturing the latent level of category interest (i.e., ) are not identified in benchmark model 2. In the third and fourth benchmark models, consumers' purchase sequence is assumed to be fixed and thus preimposed by the analyst. Benchmark model 3 assumes that milk is determined independently, and then the decision on cereal is made conditionally. The opposite sequence is true in benchmark model 4.</p><p>We also develop a model of simultaneous decisions, benchmark model 5, in which consumers are assumed to maximize the joint utility of milk and cereal together with an outside good. This model does not allow for the direct interaction between the purchase quantities of milk and cereal in the same shopping basket. The last benchmark model employs a linear consumption pattern for latent inventory, assuming that a fixed amount of a good is consumed during a unit period. This model allows us to check the robustness of our results with regard to the choice of a consumption pattern of latent inventory. Detailed descriptions of the six benchmark models are provided in Appendix B. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">5</ref> compares the proposed model with the benchmark models in terms of model fit, and the parameter estimates of the six benchmark models are presented in Table <ref type="table">6</ref>.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">5</ref> shows that the proposed model outperforms all the benchmark models in both in-sample and predictive fits. In Table <ref type="table">6</ref>, imposing symmetric restrictions on the nature of complementarity as in the first benchmark model leads to a systematic bias such that the impact of milk on the utility of cereal is underestimated whereas the impact of cereal on the utility of milk is overestimated. Accordingly, the baseline parameters of the more dependent category (i.e., cereal) are inflated, whereas those of the independent category (i.e., milk) are reduced. Benchmark model 2, in which no complementarity is assumed, shows the worst performance in fitting the data. This indicates that allowing for some complementarity is important, and we also find that ignoring complementarity results in the overestimation of the baseline parameters, especially for the more dependent category (i.e., cereal). Comparison to the third and fourth benchmark models indicates that the sequence of purchase decisions varies over time and across households. </p><formula xml:id="formula_35">0 084 0 088 ¯ 1 m 2 * 0 204 0 110 ¯ 1 c 1 * 0 192 0 089 ¯ 1 c 2 * 0 106 0 079 Impact of merchandising displaȳ 2 m 1 * nā 2 m 2 * nā 2 c 1 * −0 005 0 065 ¯ 2 c 2 * 0 150 0 090 Inventory ratē * m 0 204 0 166 ¯ * c −0 139 0 081 Decision sequencē c 0 −0 319 0 195 ¯ i −0 305 0 393 ¯ f −0 226 0 130 ¯ d 0 148 0 221</formula><p>Notes. Posterior standard deviations are given in parentheses. = exp * , and = 1/ 1 + exp − * . na, not available.</p><p>The simultaneous decision model (i.e., benchmark model 5) does not fit the data as well, supporting the view that consumer decisions across categories are sequential, not simultaneous. Finally, when we employ a linear form of inventory decay, the asymmetric complementarity between milk and cereal  is preserved, showing the robustness of our results regardless of the choice of consumption pattern. There are some parameters whose estimates are sensitive to the choice of a consumption pattern such as the baseline parameters. Because the linear decay model is susceptible to a spike in demand, while it is more smoothly accommodated in the proposed model due to the exponential decay pattern, it is not surprising to see the decrease of the model fit as well as the differences in the parameter estimates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Discussion</head><p>Asymmetric complements are products that drive utility in other categories at differential rates, and their presence is potentially important for product design, pricing, distribution, and advertising decisions. In the extreme case of tied goods such as a computer printer and ink, it is often profitable to enhance, advertise, and price discount the dominant good (e.g., the printer) with the goal of inducing sales in the dependent good.</p><p>Our model informs such decisions through the estimated model parameters. In our analysis of scanner panel data, we observe varying prices and merchandising variables, and in this section we explore the implications of asymmetric complements on these variables.</p><p>We use our sequential model of asymmetric complements to investigate two issues. First, we compute model-based cross-price elasticity estimates by aggregating individual-level demand estimates under various price discounts, and we show that the estimates are influenced by the presence of asymmetric effects. We then investigate the cross-category effect of merchandising variables.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Cross-Price Elasticity</head><p>Complementarity produces a positive interaction in the demand for products, resulting in negative crossprice effects where the decrease in the price of one category leads to an increase in the demand of another. To estimate the cross-price elasticity between milk and cereal, we calculate the expected demand of each category for various prices. The expected demand is computed by integrating over the posterior distributions of parameters as well as the distribution of error terms for each of the actual (observed) prices versus prices that are increased or decreased by the indicated amount. The budgetary allotment for each household is set to be equal to the maximum spending for the inside goods plus the maximum unit price among the inside goods, which guarantees the feasibility of the additional purchase. Feature and display variables are set to be their average values in the data to reflect an average level of promotion in the product category. The level of inventory is similarly set to be the average value of the inventory trajectory that is computed from the household-specific estimate of the Notes. Posterior standard deviations are given in parentheses. = exp * . = 1/ 1 + exp − * for benchmarks 1-5 and = exp * for benchmark 6. na, not available.</p><formula xml:id="formula_36">Model¯ 1 m * 1¯ 1 m 2 * ¯ 1 c 1 * ¯ 1 c 2 * ¯ 2 c 1 * ¯ 2 c 2 * ¯ * m¯ * c¯ c 0¯ i¯ f¯ d</formula><p>inventory rate parameter and the time-series data of purchase history. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">7</ref> reports changes in expected demand when prices are changed by 10%. Also reported, in parentheses, is the expected change in demand for the first two benchmark models. The first benchmark model assumes that complementary effects are symmetric (i.e., ij = ji ), and the second benchmark model assumes no complementary relationships (i.e., ij = ji = 0). Note. Price elasticities based on benchmark models 1 and 2 are provided in parentheses for comparison. a % Change implies the ratio of increased demand compared with the demand under a reference condition, where neither price is changed.</p><p>As the price of a product decreases, its own demand increases (i.e., negative own-price elasticity), and the demand of the complementary product increases while the demand of the outside good decreases. The own-price elasticity of cereal (i.e., −1.689) is greater in its magnitude than that of milk (i.e., −1.326). The demand for cereal is sensitive to the price change of milk (i.e., −0.678), and the impact of cereal prices on the demand of milk is smaller (i.e., −0.339), showing that the asymmetric effects in utility leads to asymmetric effects in price. The comparison to the benchmark models indicates that the restriction of symmetric or no interdependency distorts the ownprice as well as cross-price elasticities. The model of symmetric complementarity underestimates the spillover effect of price change in milk and overestimates the spillover effect of price change in cereal.</p><p>One might argue that the complementarity between the two goods is not the only source of the negative cross-price elasticity of aggregate demand. When there is a price discount in one category, it not only changes the rate of exchange among goods (i.e., the substitution effect) but also enhances the purchasing power (i.e., the income effect) of a consumer's budget. The Slutsky equation addresses this issue by decomposing the impact of a price change into two effects, a substitution effect and an income effect:</p><formula xml:id="formula_37">x i p E p j = h i p u p j − x i p E E x j p E (23)</formula><p>where h p u is the Hicksian demand and x p E is the Marshallian demand, at price p, budget E, and utility level u. Whereas the substitution effect results from the change of relative prices, the income effect captures an increase or decrease in the consumers purchasing powers as a result of the price change.</p><p>The results of Slutsky decomposition 11 are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">8</ref>. Whereas the income effects are small for the inside goods, it is relatively greater for the outside good, implying that the increased purchase power by a price discount tends to be saved rather than increasing the purchase quantities of the inside goods. The positive substitution effect of a price discount on the crosscategory demand reflects that the positive impact of complementarity overrides the negative impact of changes in the relative prices. Consequently, the observed positive cross effects are mainly driven by complementarity, not by an income effect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Spillover Effect of Marketing Activity</head><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">9</ref> reports estimates of the effect of changes in the feature advertisement. Reported is the percentage <ref type="bibr">11</ref> Because of the uncertainties in the estimated utility and the demand indivisibility, the Slutsky decomposition was conducted by using simulated demand. The total change in demand (i.e., x p E − x p E ) is decomposed by introducing the hypothetical demand that would be realized under the new price with the maintained purchase power (i.e., x p E , where E = x p E × p ). That is, the substitution effect implies the change in demand due only to the change in price ratio when the income is adjusted so that the consumer can exactly afford the original bundle (i.e., x p E − x p E ), whereas the income effect is measured by the remaining change in demand (i.e., x p E − x p E ). change in demand when the feature advertisement is enhanced by 20% in each category. We find, as with the price elasticity estimates, that the spillover effect is greater when the independent category is promoted. Enhanced feature advertisement in milk increases the demand of cereal by 0.57%, and the demand of milk increases by 0.24% with the feature advertisement in cereal.</p><p>In summary, we find that allowing for asymmetric parameters in a direct utility model is important for measuring cross-category spillover effects. Demand of the more dependent category is influenced to a greater extent by the marketing activities on its complement, and the spillover effect is small for the opposite case. Not accounting for asymmetric parameters in the utility structure, as is in benchmark models 1 and 2, leads to systematic biases in the effects of prices and merchandising variables: (i) the underestimation (overestimation) of the cross-category effects of marketing activities of a less (more) dependent category and (ii) the distortion of the effects of marketing activities on its own demand.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Concluding Remarks</head><p>A model of asymmetric complements is developed within a formal model of direct utility maximization. Complementary effects occur when the marginal utility of one good is enhanced by the presence of a second good. A challenge in developing models of such asymmetry is due to it being equal to the second derivative of the utility function 2 U / x 1 x 2 , which is symmetric because the order of differentiation does not matter. Additional information is therefore needed to identify asymmetric utility effects, and this paper uses the longitudinal variation of marginal utility in response to the variation in the cross-category inventory as revealed in observed purchases across product categories.</p><p>A latent decision sequence is hypothesized and used to identify a sequential purchase decision where the purchase of goods early in the sequence is not affected by goods later in the sequence. We allow the order Marketing Science 32(3), pp. 454-470, © 2013 INFORMS of the purchase sequence to be partially dependent on current product inventory and merchandising variables that change over time. The model likelihood is obtained by integrating over all possible decision sequences, and it is shown to fit our data better than models that restrict effects to be either symmetric or nonexistent. We find evidence of asymmetric spillover effects between milk and cereal, where milk influences the consumption of cereal but cereal has little effect on milk consumption.</p><p>Identifying the presence of asymmetric complements is important whenever decisions have multiple components and the decision sequence is not fixed. Cross-selling activities is one example where the order of product purchase may impact the likelihood of purchasing other items. This occurs in financial services where it is believed that some initial exposure to a firm through a simple product (e.g., a checking account) aids in the successful sale of more complicated products (e.g., insurance products). The same rationale is used to offer introductory items at a discount to encourage additional purchases in the future. The identification of which introductory items have larger spillover effects is an important consideration in this strategy. We therefore believe the model has potentially wide application.</p><p>We acknowledge the following limitations of our model and empirical findings. First, we selected the households that purchase both milk and cereal on a regular basis because enough variations in data help us to better identify the model parameters. The variations in purchase quantities lead to the variations in latent inventories, which enable us to identify asymmetric complementarity. 12 Second, our model is restricted to accommodate a relatively small number of categories because the number of possible sequences increases exponentially as more categories are included. Third, the proposed model is limited in its ability to allow for bidirectional influence between the purchase quantities of two complementary goods because the later decision of a latent sequence does not have an impact on earlier decisions. The development of a simultaneous decision model where bidirectional influence is captured is left for future research. Finally, additional research is needed to identify the attributes and attribute levels that give rise to asymmetric effects. Our analysis based on observed demand data did not include information on product attributes, and <ref type="bibr">12</ref> We confirmed that the asymmetric complementarity found in our empirical study is preserved with a larger data set where less frequent shoppers (i.e., at least five purchases of milk and cereal during the two-year data period) are also included. The randomeffects distribution in the Bayesian hierarchical model plays an important role in identifying the individual-level parameters for households with sparse purchase occasions. The estimation results with an extended data set are provided in Appendix C.</p><p>we view the ability to identify the origin of asymmetric effects as a potentially profitable area of marketing research. The development of asymmetric models of stated preference data is therefore also needed.</p><p>A Fixed Decision Sequence Model (Milk First). The model assumes that the purchase decision of milk (x * t ) is always made first. The utility of milk is enhanced only by the inventory of cereal, but not by the new purchase (y * t ):</p><formula xml:id="formula_38">x it = exp x i + yx y t + x i m x it + x it</formula><p>Because the purchase of cereal (y * t ) is considered after the decision on milk (x * t ), the utility of cereal is influenced by the sum of the inventory and the newly purchased amount of milk: . The model does not allow for direct interaction between the purchase quantities of milk and cereal in the same shopping basket, implying that the utility enhancement is driven by the cross inventory only. Because it brings a new set of challenges <ref type="bibr">13</ref> to develop a simultaneous decision model in which the direct interaction between the purchase quantities of the complementary goods is incorporated, we leave it for future research. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> For example, a joint decision model for complementary goods requires a utility specification that is not additively separable A Model with a Linear Inventory Decay. The model assumes that a constant amount of goods is consumed in a unit period. Because a linear decay pattern does not preclude negative values, inventories are truncated at zero, which implies depletion:</p><formula xml:id="formula_39">x t = max 0 x t−1 + 2 i=1 s x i x i t−1 − x t − 1 t</formula><p>Appendix C. Estimation Results with an Extended Data Set</p><p>The extended data set contains 303 households who have at least five purchases of milk and cereal during the two-year data period. The estimation results reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">C</ref>.1 show a consistent pattern with the main results in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref>.  because of the synergetic effect of a joint purchase. In this case, accommodating the discreteness of demand is challenging because a complicated integration is required for the likelihood computation <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Lee and Allenby 2013)</ref>. Second, a joint utility maximization model for complementary goods is limited in its flexibility for accommodating the multifaceted nature of multicategory demand. In particular, the chance of a variety-seeking behavior, where multiple brands of one category are chosen together, has been largely ignored in previous literature to reduce the dimensionality of the problem. <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Song and Chintagunta (2007)</ref> employ a linear subutility for brands within a category, implying that only one brand can be purchased under each category. Finally, a joint utility maximization model for complementary goods assumes that a decision maker is aware of all the market information (e.g., prices, promotions) for all the brands in multiple categories. Given that a consumer is exposed to marketing information in a sequential manner, the inconsistency between the model assumption and the reality should be carefully handled.   Notes. Posterior standard deviations are given in parentheses. = exp * , and = 1/ 1 + exp − * . na, not available.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Identification of Asymmetric Complementarity</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Posterior standard deviations are given in parentheses. = exp * , and = 1/ 1 + exp − * . For milk, subscripts 1 and 2 indicate Guida's and private label, respectively. For cereal, subscripts 1 and 2 indicate General Mills and Kellogg's, respectively. na, not available.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2Asymmetric Interdependency in Utility</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>91 (linear inventory decay)Note. LMD, log marginal density<ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Newton and Raftery 1994)</ref>.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Because the sequence is fixed such that milk is always considered first (i.e., Pr x t ≥ y t = 1 , the likelihood of the observed purchase quantities is given by Sequence Model (Cereal First). The model assumes that the purchase decision of cereal is always made prior to the purchase decision of milk.A Simultaneous Decision Model with Asymmetric Complementarity. The model assumes that a consumer maximizes the joint utility of milk and cereal together with an outside good</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Lee, Kim, and Allenby: Direct Utility Model for Asymmetric Complements</figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science 32(3), pp. 454-470, © 2013 INFORMS</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Lee, Kim, and Allenby: Direct Utility Model for Asymmetric Complements</figDesc><table><row><cell>460</cell><cell>Marketing Science 32(3), pp. 454-470, © 2013 INFORMS</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Parameter Estimates of the Simulation Study</figDesc><table><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell>True value</cell><cell>Posterior mean</cell></row><row><cell>Baselinē</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>x</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Lee, Kim, and Allenby: Direct Utility Model for Asymmetric Complements</figDesc><table><row><cell>462</cell><cell>Marketing Science 32(3), pp. 454-470, © 2013 INFORMS</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Data Description</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">(a) Purchase frequency</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Milk and cereal</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Milk only</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Cereal only</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>None</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Number of trips (%)</cell><cell></cell><cell>3,312 (15.7%)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>5,625 (26.6%)</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">2,323 (11.0%)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>9,882 (46.7%)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">(b) Descriptive statistics</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Milk</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Cereal</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Guida's</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Private label</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">General Mills</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Kellogg's</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Package size</cell><cell>Large</cell><cell>Medium</cell><cell>Small</cell><cell>Large</cell><cell>Medium</cell><cell>Small</cell><cell>Large</cell><cell>Medium</cell><cell>Small</cell><cell>Large</cell><cell>Medium</cell><cell>Small</cell></row><row><cell>Number of UPCs</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>20</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>14</cell><cell>23</cell><cell>22</cell><cell>23</cell></row><row><cell>Unit volume (16 oz.)</cell><cell>8.00</cell><cell>4.00</cell><cell>2.00</cell><cell>8.00</cell><cell>4.00</cell><cell>2.00</cell><cell>1.27</cell><cell>0.93</cell><cell>0.70</cell><cell>1.25</cell><cell>0.91</cell><cell>0.68</cell></row><row><cell>Unit price (USD)</cell><cell>3.38</cell><cell>1.92</cell><cell>1.07</cell><cell>3.27</cell><cell>1.80</cell><cell>1.05</cell><cell>4.30</cell><cell>3.58</cell><cell>3.51</cell><cell>3.82</cell><cell>3.46</cell><cell>3.27</cell></row><row><cell>Price per volume</cell><cell>0.42</cell><cell>0.48</cell><cell>0.54</cell><cell>0.41</cell><cell>0.45</cell><cell>0.53</cell><cell>3.38</cell><cell>3.84</cell><cell>4.99</cell><cell>3.07</cell><cell>3.81</cell><cell>4.79</cell></row><row><cell>Feature</cell><cell>0.15</cell><cell>0.04</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell>0.11</cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell>0.03</cell><cell>0.13</cell><cell>0.17</cell><cell>0.12</cell><cell>0.10</cell><cell>0.12</cell><cell>0.10</cell></row><row><cell>Display</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell>0.06</cell><cell>0.05</cell></row><row><cell>Purchase incidence (%)</cell><cell>7.15</cell><cell>2.57</cell><cell>0.09</cell><cell>20.23</cell><cell>13.16</cell><cell>1.50</cell><cell>4.38</cell><cell>8.53</cell><cell>4.58</cell><cell>5.54</cell><cell>5.69</cell><cell>5.86</cell></row><row><cell>Purchase quantity</cell><cell>1.35</cell><cell>1.28</cell><cell>1.11</cell><cell>1.26</cell><cell>1.35</cell><cell>1.06</cell><cell>1.49</cell><cell>1.60</cell><cell>1.29</cell><cell>1.32</cell><cell>1.34</cell><cell>1.35</cell></row><row><cell cols="6">offering, and x i is determined by the following four</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>indicators:</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Parameter Estimates of the Proposed Model</figDesc><table><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell>Posterior mean</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Baseline preference for manufacturer</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Model-Fit Comparison</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>In-sample fit</cell><cell>Prediction</cell></row><row><cell>Model</cell><cell>(LMD)</cell><cell>likelihood</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 7</head><label>7</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Estimates of Price Elasticity</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">% Change in demand a</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Milk</cell><cell>Cereal</cell><cell>Outside good</cell></row><row><cell>10% decrease in</cell><cell>13.26</cell><cell>6.78</cell><cell>−0.34</cell></row><row><cell>milk price</cell><cell>(13 85 11 41)</cell><cell>(5 08 0 00)</cell><cell>(−0 30 −0 01)</cell></row><row><cell>10% decrease in</cell><cell>3.39</cell><cell>16.89</cell><cell>−0.34</cell></row><row><cell>cereal price</cell><cell>(5 24 0 00)</cell><cell>(15 78 13 13)</cell><cell>(−0 37 −0 06)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 8</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Slutsky Decomposition of the Price Effects</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">% Change in demand a</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Milk</cell><cell>Cereal</cell><cell>Outside good</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">(a) 10% decrease in milk prices</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Substitution effect</cell><cell>12 71</cell><cell>5 93</cell><cell>−0 48</cell></row><row><cell>Income effect</cell><cell>0 55</cell><cell>0 85</cell><cell>0 14</cell></row><row><cell>Total effect</cell><cell>13 26</cell><cell>6 78</cell><cell>−0 34</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">(b) 10% decrease in cereal prices</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Substitution effect</cell><cell>2 75</cell><cell>14 74</cell><cell>−0 52</cell></row><row><cell>Income effect</cell><cell>0 64</cell><cell>2 14</cell><cell>0 18</cell></row><row><cell>Total effect</cell><cell>3 39</cell><cell>16 89</cell><cell>−0 34</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">a % Change implies the ratio of increased demand compared with the</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">demand under a reference condition, where neither price is changed.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table 9</head><label>9</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Spillover Effect of Merchandising Activity</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">% Change in demand a</cell></row><row><cell>Merchandising activity</cell><cell>Milk</cell><cell>Cereal</cell><cell>Outside good</cell></row><row><cell>Feature advertisement</cell><cell>2.23</cell><cell>0.56</cell><cell>−0.11</cell></row><row><cell>of milk</cell><cell>(2 00 1 51)</cell><cell>(1 00 0 00)</cell><cell>(−0 12 −0 05)</cell></row><row><cell>Feature advertisement</cell><cell>0.24</cell><cell>1.83</cell><cell>−0.08</cell></row><row><cell>of cereal</cell><cell>(0 81 0 00)</cell><cell>(2 28 1 72)</cell><cell>(−0 12 −0 06)</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Note. Spillover effects based on benchmark models 1 and 2 are provided</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">in parenthesis for comparison.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="4">a % Change of demand is the percentage increase in demand when mer-</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">chandising is enhanced by 20% a compared with existing merchandising</cell></row><row><cell>activity.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table C</head><label>C</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>.1</cell><cell>Parameter Extimates of the Proposed</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Model with an Extended Data Set</cell></row><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell>Posterior mean</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Baseline preference for manufacturer</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Lee, Kim, and  Allenby: Direct Utility Model for Asymmetric Complements 470 Marketing Science 32(3), pp. 454-470, © 2013 INFORMS</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12"><head>Table C</head><label>C</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>.1</cell><cell>(Cont'd.)</cell></row><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell>Posterior mean</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Impact of merchandising displaȳ</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">We acknowledge that marketing activities such as feature advertisement do not directly affect consumer's utility, but rather they influence the level of attention or the consideration set formation<ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Terui et al. 2011</ref>), which will lead to the increased probability of purchase. Because neither a level of attention nor a consideration set formation is formally modeled, the impact of marketing actions on the purchase likelihood is captured by introducing them in utility formulation.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">The impact of inventory (or marketing activities) might differ across categories (e.g., x</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">If adding one more unit of brand i makes the total spending exceed the budget (i.e., p x it x * it +1 + 2 j=1 j =i p x jt x * jt &gt; E), x it is bounded only from below (i.e., ub x it = ).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">The market share for each manufacturer is as follows: Guida's, 21.02%; private label, 54.12%; General Mills, 33.48%; and Kellogg's, 32.68%.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">* k−1 h ¯ k−1 V k−1 . (ii) Draw * k h k h k h k−1 h * k−1 h ¯ k−1 V k−1 (iii) Draw k h * k h k h k h * k h ¯ k−1 V k−1 (iv) Repeat (i)-(iii) for each household (h = 1 H ). Step 4. Draw¯ . k ∼ N B HV k−1 −1 + 100I −1 −1 where B = HV k−1 −1 +100I −1 −1 HV k−1 −1 H h=1 k h +100I −1 0Step 5. Draw V .V k ∼ IW 0 + H I + H h=1 k h −¯ k k h −¯ kStep 6. Repeat Steps 3-5 at each iteration of the MCMC. (The draws at the previous iteration become the new initial values.)Lee, Kim, and Allenby: Direct Utility Model for Asymmetric Complements Marketing Science 32(3), pp. 454-470, © 2013 INFORMS</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Appendix A. Estimation Procedure</p><p>The proposed model of asymmetric complementarity is estimated by Bayesian MCMC methods. The joint posterior is derived by multiplying the model likelihood, derived in §2.2, to the prior distributions specified as follows:</p><p>The estimation algorithm starts by setting the initial values for the coefficients of the random-effect distribution (i.e.,¯ and V ). Conditional on these initial values, the individuallevel parameters (i.e., h ) can be drawn by a Metropolis-Hastings algorithm with a random walk chain. The spirit of a blocked Gibbs sampler can be employed for efficiency such that two or more parameters are grouped and sampled together using a Metropolis-Hastings algorithm conditional on the rest of the parameters. In our empirical study, the individual-level parameters were grouped into three: (i) h h , (ii) * h , and (iii) h * h , and the parameters in the same group were jointly drawn the Metropolis-Hastings algorithm with a random walk chain. Once all the individual-level parameters are drawn, the coefficients for the random-effects distribution can be easily drawn by using a Gibbs sampling method that is widely used for a Bayesian multivariate regression.</p><p>Step 1. Set initial values for¯ and V (¯</p><p>Step 3. Draw h h=1 H . At the kth iteration, k h is drawn from a Metropolis-Hastings algorithm with a random walk chain</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix B. Benchmark Models</head><p>A Sequential Decision Model with Symmetric Complementarity. The model is identical to the proposed model except for the symmetry restriction in complementarity (i.e., ij = ji ). A Sequential Decision Model with No Complementarity. The model is identical to the proposed model except for the restriction of no complementarity (i.e., ij = ji = 0).</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decomposition of the sales impact of promotion-induced stockpiling</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Ailawadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Gedenk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lutzky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Neslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="450" to="467" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Similarities in choice behavior across product categories</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ainslie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rossi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Indirect network externality effects on product attributes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Basu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mazumdar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Raj</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="221" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Database paper: The IRI marketing data set</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bronnenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kruger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Mela</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="745" to="748" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting rank ordered choice set data within the stochastic utility model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Staelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="288" to="301" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transcendental logarithmic utility functions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Jorgenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="367" to="383" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiple discreteness and product differentiation: Demand for carbonated soft drinks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J-P</forename><surname>Dubé</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="81" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consumers&apos; price sensitivities across complementary categories</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Duvvuri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ansari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1933" to="1945" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical analysis of umbrella branding</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Erdem</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="339" to="351" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Practical Markov chain Monte Carlo</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Geyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statist. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="473" to="483" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding storebrand purchase behavior across categories</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hansen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="90" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Modeling indivisible demand. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<pubPlace>Iowa City</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Iowa</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-selling sequentially ordered products: An application to consumer banking services</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wilcox</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="233" to="239" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The &quot;shopping basket</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Manchanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ansari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">A model for multicategory purchase incidence decisions. Marketing Sci</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="114" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating consumers&apos; purchase incidence and brand choice decisions across multiple product categories: A theoretical and empirical analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Mehta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="196" to="217" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empirical analysis of indirect network effects in the market for personal digital assistants</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Nair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J-P</forename><surname>Dubé</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="58" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Approximate Bayesian inference by the weighted likelihood bootstrap</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Newton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Raftery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Roy. Statist. Soc. Ser. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="48" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Pashigian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Price Theory and Applications</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Irwin/McGraw-Hill</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Demand System Specification and Estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pollak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wales</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Oxford, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Practical Markov chain Monte Carlo]: Comment: One long run with diagnostics: Implementation strategies for Markov Chain Monte Carlo</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Raftery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statist. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="493" to="497" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A discrete-continuous model for multicategory purchase behavior of households</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="595" to="612" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of media advertising on brand consideration and choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Terui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ban</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="74" to="91" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
