<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org User-Generated Open Source Products: Founder&apos;s Social Capital and Time to Product Release</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2012-02-16">February 16, 2012.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Girish</forename><surname>Mallapragada</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Rajdeep</forename><surname>Grewal</surname></persName>
							<email>rgrewal@psu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Gary</forename><surname>Lilien</surname></persName>
							<email>glilien@psu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Kelley School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Indiana University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>47405</postCode>
									<settlement>Bloomington</settlement>
									<region>Indiana</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Smeal College of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Pennsylvania State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>16802</postCode>
									<settlement>University Park</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org User-Generated Open Source Products: Founder&apos;s Social Capital and Time to Product Release</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 (print)</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2012-02-16">February 16, 2012.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1110.0690</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: January 24, 2010; accepted: October 3, 2011; Russell Winer served as the special issue editor and Kannan Srinivasan served as associate editor for this article.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:29+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>user-generated products</term>
					<term>product development</term>
					<term>social networks</term>
					<term>open source</term>
					<term>innovation</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Blogs, Twitter feeds, social network profiles, user videos, and other forms of digital products have the common feature that the associated content's consumers are also its producers; hence such content is known as user-generated content. In the open source software (OSS) domain, where the user-generated content is a software product <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Raymond 1999)</ref>, users are developers of software code as well as consumers of the resulting software products. Because the intellectual property or source code is available in the public domain, these products are referred to as open source products. The Android mobile operating system, Firefox browser, Apache Web server, and Linux operating system are a few examples of some successful open source products <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(O'Mahony and Ferraro 2007)</ref>.</p><p>The OSS paradigm provides an alternative to traditional, top-down, firm-driven software new product development (NPD) processes (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lakhani and von Hippel 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">, Shah 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">, von Krogh and von Hippel 2006</ref>. In OSS development, NPD pro-cess success depends on the contributions of volunteer users who both produce and use the products (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">O'Hern et al. 2011)</ref>; various NPD projects thus compete for the community's attention and resources (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Subramaniam et al. 2009)</ref>. When project teams release working product versions quickly, they earn an early mover advantage that offers them the ability to appeal to the community earlier than their competitors and thereby benefit from the community's contributions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lakhani and</ref><ref type="bibr">von Hippel 2002, Raymond 1999)</ref>. Therefore, the time to product release is a critical metric for NPD process success in the OSS domain and the focus of our research.</p><p>The user community for an OSS project consists of two subcommunities: developer users, who include OSS project members and developers, and end users, who just download and use the product, though they might develop other projects. Drawing on the NPD literature in both traditional firm settings (for a metaanalysis, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Henard and Szymanski 2001)</ref> and the OSS domain <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Grewal et al. 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">, Lee et al. 2009</ref>), Mallapragada, Grewal, and Lilien: Open Source Products: Founder's Social Capital and Time to Product Release Marketing Science 31(3), pp. <ref type="bibr">474-492, © 2012 INFORMS 475</ref> and recognizing the critical roles both subcommunities play, we propose three factors that influence OSS NPD process success: (1) the information and resources available to the project, which depend on the location of the project founders in the social network of developer users <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Burt 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">, Lin 2001</ref>; (2) the interplay of the project's developer user and end user communities; and (3) the characteristics of OSS projects and the resulting products.</p><p>Project founders' social capital in the network of developer users is the basis for the first factor; we thus draw on literature from sociology pertaining to social networks and social capital <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Lin 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">, Obstfeld 2005</ref> and measure social capital through the embeddedness and brokerage activities of founders. Embeddedness measures the volume of information and resource input founders receive from the network; brokerage measures the novelty of such information and resources <ref type="bibr">Waguespack 2007, Nerkar and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Paruchuri 2005)</ref>. For the second factor, we measure both user engagement, which reflects how the end user community participates in the projects <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Stewart et al. 2006)</ref>, and the product's audience focus, which determines which community the products target, i.e., the developer users or end users <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Subramaniam et al. 2009)</ref>. For the third factor, we consider several OSS project and product characteristics, including the project founders' experience, type of open source license, and team size <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Stewart et al. 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">, Subramaniam et al. 2009</ref>). We model time to product release with a split hazard model to account for projects that never release a product. We collect data over 42 months and include 817 projects that began in January 2003 on SourceForge.net.</p><p>Results from a simulated maximum likelihood estimation of the split hazard model show that increases in both embeddedness and brokerage shorten the time to product release of new open source projects. In addition, the engagement of end users and product's audience focus significantly affect the influence of embeddedness on this time. Beyond their statistical significance, our results have managerial implications; for example, time to product release declines by an average of 31% when project founders have both high embeddedness and high brokerage.</p><p>In the next section, we discuss the OSS context, develop the central position that time to product release plays in that context, and introduce our conceptual framework. We next develop theoretical arguments for the main effects in our model. Then we outline our timing process model and describe our data source, data collection procedure, and measures. Next we discuss our findings and model validation approach, followed by the implications of our work for theory and practice, its limitations, and opportunities for further research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Conceptual Background</head><p>The fundamental principle of the OSS model is simple: OSS community members who develop new digital products (developer users) post the source code on Internet forums (e.g., SourceForge, RForge) under an open source license, and other OSS community members test and use the product (end users), submit feedback, and may modify the code and create their own versions as long as they adhere to the open source licensing restrictions. The term "cocreation" describes such collaboration because content is created and used by the same set of members <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(O'Hern et al. 2011)</ref>. In this model, the users' decision to participate in a particular project often depends on the project's visibility, uniqueness, and popularity <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Lakhani and</ref><ref type="bibr">von Hippel 2002, Subramaniam et al. 2009</ref>). Developer users contribute by writing and modifying code, resolving bugs, maintaining documentation, and addressing support requests; end users contribute by reporting bugs, downloading products, and participating in forums, which generate product visibility. Thus, the creation and maintenance of user-generated content involves the active and iterative interplay of the developer user and end user communities. <ref type="bibr">Raymond's (1999, p. 29)</ref> call to "release early, release often" is a central tenet of the OSS model. A product version that performs only core functions but lacks secondary features or final aesthetics can be released to generate rapid feedback and engagement from the user community. Releasing a product early may provide initial traction and attract dedicated users who offer vital early, critical feedback <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Lakhani and</ref><ref type="bibr">von Hippel 2002, Raymond 1999)</ref>. Furthermore, the first file release is a credible signal that the project team is serious about the project, which fosters interest and engagement from both the developer and user communities. Therefore, time to product release is a critical measure of success for OSS development. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Evidence from meta-analytic studies regarding the drivers of traditional NPD suggest that success depends on the product characteristics, organizational processes and strategies, and marketplace characteristics <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Henard and Szymanski 2001)</ref>. Similar OSS research suggests that OSS project and product characteristics, such as type of license, availability of prior code, user and developer interest (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Subramaniam et al. 2009)</ref>, and network locations of project managers <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Grewal et al. 2006)</ref>, affect open source project Marketing Science 31(3), pp. 474-492, © 2012 INFORMS success too. Thus, the success of an OSS NPD process likely depends on the information and resources available and the characteristics of the product <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Barczak et al. 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">, Lee et al. 2009</ref>. Furthermore, because the OSS community consists of two distinct subcommunities-developer users and end userstheir interplay should also affect OSS NPD success.</p><p>In particular, the availability of information and resources for a project depends on the social capital of developer users working on the project, as reflected in their location in the social network of other developer users <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Lin 2001)</ref> and their interactions with end users <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Shah 2006</ref>). As in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>, the drivers of success thus should include (1) the founders' social capital, (2) the interplay of developer users and end users, and (3) control variables related to OSS project and product characteristics. Because developer users drive the NPD process, the effect of their social capital should be moderated by variables concerning the interplay of the developer user and end user subcommunities.</p><p>Literature on social capital and social networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Lin 2001)</ref> shows that sufficient embeddedness and brokerage <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Burt 2005</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">, Granovetter 1985</ref>) provide the necessary resources for NPD projects <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">, Obstfeld 2005</ref>. When a new project begins, the founders' social network represents the primary connection to the OSS community and a critical determinant of information and resource availability. Research in organizational ecology <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Romanelli 1989</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">, Stinchcombe 1965</ref>) also shows that initial resource environments have lasting effects on subsequent organizational structures, processes, strategies, and survival likelihood. In the OSS context, the social network of the founders therefore should be the primary  source of information and resources at founding, and its characteristics should influence the success of OSS projects (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Waguespack 2007, Grewal et al. 2006</ref>). The interplay of developer user and end user communities can be characterized by two variables. First, the degree of user engagement captures the level of interest in the user community and indicates the level of information transfer between communities, forming a channel by which feedback from the end user community reaches the developer user community <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Stewart et al. 2006)</ref>. Second, the product's audience focus represents whether the developer user community presents products to the end user community as "developer-focused" (i.e., technical products) or "end user-focused" (i.e., nontechnical) <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Subramaniam et al. 2009)</ref>. We theorize that the degree of user engagement and product's audience focus both moderate the influence of the developer user social network on time to product release.</p><p>Finally, following research on firm-centric NPD processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Henard and Szymanski 2001)</ref>, we incorporate the following project and product characteristics as control variables: the type of OSS license, the size of the first release file, the size of the project team, and the availability of prior project code (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Stewart et al. 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">, Subramaniam et al. 2009</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Founders' Social Capital</head><p>Collaboration in goal-oriented groups occurs either through direct, natural collaboration between individual actors who interact <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Coleman 1988</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">, Granovetter 1985</ref> or through brokerage <ref type="bibr">(Burt 2005, Fleming and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Waguespack 2007)</ref>. In either case, collaboration signals trust and entails information and knowledge (resource) sharing <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Uzzi 1997)</ref>. The resource benefits from direct collaboration are higher when the actor is more deeply embedded in the network; higher embeddedness implies greater access to "finegrained information" that tends to be "tacit, complex, or proprietary" <ref type="bibr">(Fleming et al. 2007, p. 444)</ref>. Resource benefits from brokered collaboration instead reflect the strength of weak ties <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Granovetter 1973)</ref>, which connect distant parts of a network, so actors that broker weak ties gain access to diverse information and control information sharing <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Burt 1997)</ref>.</p><p>To capture both forms of collaboration, we characterize founders' social capital as incorporating both embeddedness and brokerage (see <ref type="bibr">Grewal et al. 2006, Nerkar and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Paruchuri 2005)</ref>. For example, executing innovation requires the mobilization of available resources, which vary directly with embeddedness, but creativity often stems from integrating diverse information, obtained from social capital such as brokerage <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Obstfeld 2005)</ref>.</p><p>In Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> we illustrate embeddedness and brokerage in a social network. Seven users work on common projects, and two users are connected if they work on a common project (i.e., a two-mode or affiliation network; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Wasserman and Faust 1999</ref>). An actor's embeddedness increases as it connects to more actors <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Swaminathan and Moorman 2009</ref>) and becomes more central to the social network <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Ronchetto et al. 1989)</ref>. For example, in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>, user 4 works on two projects, and user 3 works on three, so user 3 is more embedded than user 4. Brokerage instead increases with actors' ability to connect disconnected parts of the network <ref type="bibr">(Burt 2005, Fleming and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Waguespack 2007)</ref>. User 4 brokers the relationship between two groups (left and right of user 4), (1) User 1 shares a project with users 2 and 3; user 2 shares a project with users 1 and 3; user 3 shares a project with users 1, 2, and 4; user 4 shares a projects with users 3 and 5; user 5 shares a project with users 4, 6, and 7; user 6 shares a project with users 5 and 7; and user 7 shares a project with users 5 and 6. (2) User 4 works on two projects, whereas user 3 works on three projects, so user 3 is more embedded than user 4 (degree centrality; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Ronchetto et al. 1989</ref>). (3) User 4 brokers the relationship between the two groups, one comprising users 1, 2, and 3 and the other users 5, 6, and 7. As the sole link between these otherwise disconnected groups, user 4 scores higher on brokerage than the other users.</p><p>and as the sole link between them, it earns a high brokerage score by spanning gaps <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Burt 2004)</ref>.</p><p>2.1.1. Embeddedness. Embeddedness provides efficient access to other parts of the network <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Grewal et al. 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">, Ronchetto et al. 1989</ref>, so greater founders' embeddedness signals greater and often-required redundancy in connections. By serving as the access point for redundant connections, highly embedded founders enjoy the benefit of being the centers of action and can coordinate activities <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Swaminathan and Moorman 2009)</ref>. That is, high embeddedness provides the resources, information, and feedback necessary to ensure coordination in the OSS domain <ref type="bibr">(Fleming et al. 2007, Kogut and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Zander 1992)</ref>, and it thereby reduces the time to product release <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Barczak et al. 2009)</ref>.</p><p>In our research context, newly founded projects compete in a crowded virtual community with strict resource constraints, with high rates of failure <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">(von Krogh and von Hippel 2006)</ref>. Projects initiated by highly embedded founders gain access to diverse member skills, enjoy the benefits of improved coordination <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Uzzi 1997)</ref>, and experience quicker product development. However, greater founder embeddedness means that they can devote less attention to any given project <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Rosa et al. 1999)</ref>. Therefore, embeddedness should decrease time to market, with diminishing returns, and we hypothesize the following.</p><p>Hypothesis 1 (H 1 ). As the project founders' embeddedness at the time of founding increases across projects, the time to product release decreases at a decreasing rate.</p><p>2.1.2. Brokerage. Developer users that broker relationships by linking sparsely connected parts of a social network have access to and control over information, which gives the broker power and fosters creativity <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Burt 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Burt , 2005</ref>. The combination of power and creativity should result in timely completion of high-quality NPD projects <ref type="bibr">(Fleming et al. 2007, Nerkar and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Paruchuri 2005)</ref>. The existing NPD literature supports this assertion for the general NPD process (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Sethi et al. 2001, Song and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Parry 1997)</ref>.</p><p>For OSS, such improvements should result in shorter mean times to product release with diminishing returns to social capital <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">(Zucker et al. 1995)</ref>. Thus, we hypothesize the following.</p><p>Hypothesis 2 (H 2 ). As the project founders' brokerage at the time of founding increases across projects, the time to product release decreases at a decreasing rate.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.3.">Interaction of Embeddedness and Brokerage.</head><p>Several studies predict trade-offs in the extent to which social network members benefit from various types of social capital <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Burt 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">, Obstfeld 2005</ref>. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Burt (2004)</ref> shows Marketing Science 31(3), pp. 474-492, © 2012 INFORMS that decreased brokerage might reflect greater connection density for a member, a larger network, or changes in the network hierarchy. Therefore, members in a network structure may have to shift their location to gain the benefits of one type of social capital relative to another. For our study context, this trade-off refers to the project founder's desire to achieve efficiency by improving embeddedness over the desire to foster creativity or increase brokerage by occupying a unique network location ). It parallels the exploration versus exploitation dichotomy that <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">March (1991)</ref> proposes for organizational learning processes.</p><p>Because founders' connections facilitate information and resource dissemination, greater embeddedness should directly benefit their new projects. When brokerage increases, founders also should obtain more indirect value from being able to combine disconnected sets of resources through greater embeddedness, which facilitates information dissemination ). Then projects benefit from founders' ability to create an environment marked by both explorative and exploitative processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Obstfeld 2005)</ref>. We predict that embeddedness has a greater impact on time to product release when brokerage increases.</p><p>Hypothesis 3 (H 3 ). As the project founders' brokerage at the time of founding increases across projects, the magnitude of the reduction in time to product release as a result of embeddedness increases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Interplay of Developer Users and End Users</head><p>The exchange of information between developer user and end user communities is the primary basis for the creation and maintenance of user-generated content; we characterize this exchange using the degree of user engagement and the product's audience focus.</p><p>As user engagement (i.e., number of bugs reported) increases, the benefits that the project team receives from the community's feedback also increase <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Grewal et al. 2006)</ref>. Products that garner many bug reports benefit from elevated user activity, which reveals problems in functionality and suggests fixes. Overall, the degree of user engagement should reduce time to product release. However, when the project founder's social capital is greater, the beneficial effects of degree of user engagement should be stronger: More social capital enables founders to understand and take advantage of user engagement and feedback to speed up the NPD process <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Grewal et al. 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">, Hahn et al. 2008</ref>. Therefore, Hypothesis 4 (H 4 ). As the degree of user engagement increases across projects, the magnitude of the reduction in time to product release as a result of the founders' (a) embeddedness and (b) brokerage increases.</p><p>The product's audience focus is critical in the OSS context <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Subramaniam et al. 2009</ref>). The project administrator decides whether to target developer users (technical) or end users (nontechnical), although it seems logical that development teams prioritize products with the broadest community appeal <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Lakhani and</ref><ref type="bibr">von Hippel 2002, Shah 2006</ref>). Therefore, user-focused, nontechnical products should exhibit a shorter time to product release than developer-focused, technical products. The effect of the founder's social capital also should vary by the product's audience focus. User-focused projects may generate less technical feedback, resulting in faster development <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Lakhani and von Hippel 2002)</ref>. That is, the reduction in time to product release as a result of social capital should be greater for user-focused compared with developer-focused projects.</p><p>Hypothesis 5 (H 5 ). The magnitude of the reduction in time to product release across projects as a result of the founders' (a) embeddedness and (b) brokerage is greater for user-focused projects than for developer-focused products.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Model Development</head><p>To model the effect of the three theorized factors on the time to product release of user-generated products, we denote the founding point as time 0 and seek a model that accounts for (1) censored observations, (2) projects that never release a product, (3) the influence of covariates (some of which vary over time) and control variables, (4) unobserved heterogeneity, and (5) an appropriate specification of the underlying timing distribution. In our base model, the random variable T represents the time to the first product release when the hazard rate-or the probability of product release at time T , given that the first release has not occurred-is h T = f T /S T , with T as the time to product release, f • as a probability density, and S • as a survival function, where S • = 1 − F • and f • = F • , with F • as a cumulative distribution function.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Censored Observations</head><p>Some covariates that affect the hazard vary over time, so for each project i in the sample, the interval 0 t i is divided into k exhaustive, nonoverlapping subintervals, such that t 0 &lt; t 1 &lt; • • • &lt; t k−1 &lt; t k , with t 0 = 0 and t k = t i . Then C i indicates the release event for project i; so C i = 1 if a release occurs and 0 otherwise. The covariate vector is</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">X i = X DU i X EU i X C</formula><p>i , where X DU i represents the project founders' social capital variables derived from the developer user network, X EU i represents variables that characterize the interplay between developer users and end users, and X C i is the OSS project and product characteristics, i.e., control variables. For simplicity, we drop the subscript i. Covariates may change from one interval to the next but stay constant within an interval. The 479 hazard function from time t j−1 to t j can be written as h t X j , and because h t = −d log S t /dt, Pr T &lt; t j T ≥ t j−1 = exp − t j t j−1 h s X j ds</p><p>(1) Therefore, the survival function for a duration of t k or longer can be written as</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">S t k X k = k j=1 Pr T ≥ t j T ≥ t j−1 = k j=1 exp − t j t j−1 h s X j ds (2)</formula><p>If we take the logs of both sides of Equation ( <ref type="formula">2</ref>), we derive</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">ln S t k = k j=1 t j t j−1 h s X j ds (3)</formula><p>The log-likelihood for a single observation can be written as the sum of the contributions to the hazard and survival functions; that is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">LL i = C i • ln h t k X k − k j=1 t j t j−1 h s X j ds (4)</formula><p>Finally, projects that do not get released during the observation window (0, T c ], such that C i = 0 at the end of the observation window, contribute only to the survival function. Projects released during one of the k intervals during the observation window (0, T c ], such that C i = 1, contribute to both survival and hazard functions. If we substitute Equation (3) into Equation (4), we can simplify the log-likelihood as</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">LL i = C i • ln h t k X k + ln S t k (5)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Accounting for Projects That Never Release</head><p>A standard assumption in basic hazard models is that all observations eventually experience the event, which implies an eventual occurrence probability of 1. However, this probability rarely equals 1 for all observations <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Schmidt and Witte 1989)</ref>, because some open source projects may never release a product file. To account for two subpopulations (events that occur and those that do not), we modify the basic hazard specification with a split-hazard formulation (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Dekimpe et al. 1998, Sinha and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Chandrashekaran 1992)</ref>; the probability of eventual product release i is a function of covariate vectors, including founders' social capital variables X DU i , characteristics of the interplay between communities X EU i , and OSS project and product characteristics</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">X C i , as i = X DU i X EU i X C</formula><p>i . The log-likelihood for a single observation can be specified as</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">LL i = C i • ln h t k X k + ln 1 − i + i • S t k (6)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Model Covariates and Controls</head><p>We incorporate the effects of project founders' social capital (X DU i , the characteristics of the interplay between developer users and end users, i.e., the moderators (X EU i ), and OSS project and product characteristics (X C i ) on time to product release. We also incorporate the interaction between the moderators and founder's social capital. Let i be the positive location parameter, and let p be the scale parameter of the duration distribution. We incorporate these effects by modifying the location parameter of the hazard function i as a function of X DU i X EU i , and X C i as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">i = exp 0 + X DU i + X EU i + X DU i X EU i + X C i (<label>7</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_8">)</formula><p>where 0 is the constant term, captures the effect of founders' social capital variables, is the main effect of moderators (i.e., degree of user engagement and product's audience focus), refers to the interaction between social capital variables X DU i and the moderators X EU i , and is the effect of control variables X C</p><p>i . The degree of user engagement is a timevarying covariate in the model.</p><p>In addition, to accommodate the effect of unobserved individual project characteristics, we incorporate the effect of unobserved heterogeneity, using a random effects approach, with a random parameter <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Sastry 1997</ref>). Thus, a standard normal random variable ∼ N 0 2 affects the location parameter as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">i i = exp 0 + X DU i + X EU i + X DU i X EU i + X C i + i (8)</formula><p>Then the modified log-likelihood conditional on i can be specified as</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">LL 1 N = N i=1 C i • ln h t i i i p + ln 1 − i + i • S t k (9)</formula><p>The timing process model in Equation ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) incorporates heterogeneity as a function of project characteristics on both time to product release and the probability of eventual product release <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Dekimpe et al. 1998)</ref>. To obtain the unconditional log-likelihood, we integrate i from Equation ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>), such that LL</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">= N i=1 + − C i • ln i • f t i i i p + ln 1 − i + i • S t k f i d i (10)</formula><p>Because the log-likelihood in Equation ( <ref type="formula">10</ref>) does not have a closed form, the integral can be computed by simulating draws of i , then averaging the Marketing Science 31(3), pp. 474-492, © 2012 INFORMS log-likelihood across draws <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Train 2003)</ref>. The simulated log-likelihood approach has been employed as an effective estimation technique in other studies (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Erdem and Keane 1996</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">, Park and Gupta 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">, Villas-Boas and Winer 1999</ref> with estimation problems similar to ours. The simulated log-likelihood is</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">LL s = N i=1 1 R R r=1 C i • ln i • f t i i ir p + ln 1 − i + i • S t k (<label>11</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_13">)</formula><p>where ir is a simulated random sample of R Halton draws.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.">Timing Distribution Specification</head><p>The timing process model in Equations ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>)-( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_12">11</ref>) can accommodate a range of timing distributions, such as exponential with a constant hazard, Weibull with a monotonic hazard, and log-normal with a nonmonotonic hazard. We have no a priori theoretical reason to support one of these distributions over others and use model fit to select among them. We gathered data on the network structure of OSS projects at their founding and the projects' characteristics from a sample of open source projects registered on SourceForge. Our access to these data proceeded through the SourceForge data warehouse, which records and organizes all activities on the site <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Madey 2005)</ref>. The data warehouse is a separate entity from the website and provides a repository of activities taking place on SourceForge, maintained by researchers at the University of Notre Dame.</p><p>To avoid inconsistencies or confounds from different start times and obtain the longest observation possible, we only selected new projects initiated during the first 10 days of January 2003, the earliest available data. We identified 817 new projects, which we tracked for 42 months. The first file release by the project, recorded in the data warehouse, is our primary interest. We tabulated such events for our sample and calculated the time to first release (registration to release) in hours. We found 468 projects that resulted in product releases; 349 projects did not report a product release during the 42-month observation window.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">The Network of User-Generated Products</head><p>and Founders Because data on the network structure of the projects are not directly available on SourceForge, we constructed the network structure at founding from userproject membership information. The data warehouse stores monthly snapshots of all activity on the Source-Forge website, so we accessed database tables for January 2003, which represent the cumulative history from 1999 to 2003. Subsequent monthly data dumps are available beginning November 2004 and are updated every month. These data about user-project memberships provided details about the founding users for 817 focal projects in the user-project membership table for January 2003. We then transformed the relational data (i.e., who founded which project) into network structure data, represented by an affiliation network matrix <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">(Wasserman and Faust 1999)</ref> with the network analysis software UCINET 6. An affiliation network matrix depicts actors (i.e., users) as rows and events (i.e., projects) as columns; each cell takes a value of 1 if the user works on a project or 0 if the user does not (see Online Appendix A in the electronic companion, available as part of the online version that can be found at http://mktsci.journal.informs.org/).</p><p>Because our objective is to study newly founded projects initiated in a connected network, we applied a snowballing procedure <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">(Wasserman and Faust 1999)</ref> in which we listed all projects whose development efforts formally initiated in the first 10 days of January 2003, and we then listed all 966 developer users working on these initiatives. We next listed other (existing) projects on which these 966 developer users had worked, excluding the first set of 817 projects, and identified 624 additional projects. Finally, we listed all developer users working on these 624 projects and thereby identified 1,723 additional individuals. This procedure produced a network of 1,441 projects and 2,689 developer users. We again transformed these relational data into an affiliation network, in which a 1 in a cell indicates that the user identified by the column works as a contributor on the project identified by the row and a 0 indicates the absence of such </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Measures</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Time to Product Release</head><p>We use the time until the first release of the product as our dependent variable. Of the 817 projects, 468 (57.3%) experienced a product release and thus provide an observed time to product release. We treat the remaining 349 projects (42.7%) as right-censored observations. With hours as the unit of time, we employ a continuous time modeling approach; the dependent variable is a time measure and can only take positive values, so we log transform it <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Kalbfleisch and Prentice 1980</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">, Kiefer 1988</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">, Sinha and Chandrashekaran 1992</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Project Founders' Social Capital</head><p>Scholars use various embeddedness operationalizations, depending on the context, but the most widely employed measures include degree centrality, betweenness centrality, and closeness centrality <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Ronchetto et al. 1989)</ref>; we employ all three. Degree centrality is the number of existing projects connected to any given project founder in the network; in our study context, it captures the project founders' diverse contacts in the network. Betweenness centrality measures how well the network member can mediate flows of information; it is a count of all the shortest possible paths that include a founder and represents the ease with which the project founder can facilitate a transfer of resources over the network. To assess the efficiency of access to other locations by the shortest paths, we use closeness centrality. This measure is the sum of the shortest paths between the project founder and all other projects in the network. Greater closeness means the founder relies more on other members in the network <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Ronchetto et al. 1989)</ref>. Because closeness centrality is a summed measure, after being normalized, a higher value means the project founder is less embedded; we use the inverse of this summed measure.</p><p>To measure brokerage, we follow prior research <ref type="bibr">(Ahuja 2000, Fleming and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Waguespack 2007)</ref> and apply a version of what <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Burt (1992)</ref> calls "constraint," or the degree to which a network member depends on directly connected neighbors to connect to others in the network. Therefore, brokerage measures the degree of opportunity available to the founder to form new connections in the network. Higher constraint implies lower brokerage, so we inverse code this measure by subtracting it from 1. When a project has multiple founders, we use an average to develop a composite measure. We provide the intuition underlying the measures in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> and the technical details regarding their calculation in Appendix A of the electronic companion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.">Interplay of Developer Users and End Users</head><p>The number of bugs reported provides our measure of the degree of user engagement <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Grewal et al. 2006</ref>). This measure is highly correlated with the number of bugs resolved and thus captures the degree of product quality to a large extent, because resolved bugs signal the degree to which problems in the product have been addressed. A more engaged user community can benefit the development process and lead to better products <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Crowston et al. 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">, Lee et al. 2009</ref>). The number of reported bugs varies over time, so we obtained the data at six distinct times: Following prior research <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Subramaniam et al. 2009</ref>), we also characterize projects according to the product's audience focus as developer-focused or user-focused. We constructed a dichotomous measure from information in the project details table in the data warehouse, such that 1 indicates a user-focused project and 0 a developer-focused project.   et al. 1999), which would benefit product development. Therefore, we measure founders' experience as the cumulative time since they registered in the open source community. When a project has multiple founders (34% of sample projects), we sum their experience. We also obtained data about whether the project development process relies on the community forum to communicate with users <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Madey 2005)</ref>. This control variable, forum usage, indicates the extent of use of the community feature provided by the website. Projects that use the forum may benefit more than projects that do not, so we control for this effect (1 if the project uses a forum and 0 if not). In the OSS context, different licenses grant different degrees of control over the source code <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Stewart et al. 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">, Subramaniam et al. 2009</ref>). The most common include the general public license (GPL) and the less restrictive limited general public license (LGPL). Because GPL is the most widely used, we code the type of OSS license as a dichotomous variable, where 1 indicates use of GPL and 0 otherwise. Finally, we include variables that measure the size of the released project files (file size at release) and number of project members (team size). Some projects lead to product releases immediately after registration because the development team has been working on the source code before registering. To control for prior code availability, we include a dichotomous variable that measures whether prior code was available at the time of registration (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Subramaniam et al. 2009</ref>), which equals 1 if a prior code was available and 0 otherwise.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4.">Control Variables</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.5.">Descriptive Statistics</head><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">1</ref> provides descriptive statistics. The mean for product's audience focus is 0.52, indicating that 52% of projects in our sample were user-focused. The mean for type of license is 0.33, indicating that 33% of projects used the GPL. A mean of 0.15 for prior code availability indicates that 15% of the projects had a prior code at the time of registration, and a mean of 0.89 for forum usage indicates that 89% of projects used the community forum. The average project had 3.55 bug reports during the observation window, with a team size of 1.82 at the end of the first month (founders and non-founders) and 112 days of project founders' experience. Of the projects that released a product file, the average file size at release was 0.44 MB, released after 487 hours, or a time to product release of roughly 20 days.</p><p>6. Results</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.">Model Selection</head><p>Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Sinha and Chandrashekaran (1992)</ref>, we use a two-step procedure to select the appropriate model functional form (see Appendix B of the electronic companion). First, we seek an appropriate functional form for the timing distribution; we investigated the hazard function using Kaplan-Meier estimator, which suggests the hazard is nonmonotonic. Thus, we ruled out the exponential and the Weibull models, as these have constant and monotonic hazard functions, respectively. We then tested the log-logistic, log-normal, and the gamma specifications, all of which accommodate nonmonotonic hazards. Second, in the log-logistic model, a comparison of a probit (M4) versus a logit (M5) specification for the probability of eventual product release in the split-hazard specification <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Schmidt and</ref><ref type="bibr">Witte 1989, Sinha and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Chandrashekaran 1992)</ref> shows that the logit specification fits the data better (M5: BIC M5 = 3 187 46, CAIC M5 = 3 942 46; M4: BIC M4 = 3 797 78, CAIC M4 = 3,861.78). We also find a statistically significant improvement in this logistic distribution specification for the hazard with logit link function specifications for the probability when we account for unobserved heterogeneity in the model (M6). The final model (M6) outperforms the best model from the second stage (M5) on various fit criteria (BIC M6 = 3 796 16, CAIC M6 = 3 861 16). We estimated M6 using simulated maximum likelihood estimation with a sequence of 30 Halton draws instead of the standard normal random draws 3 <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bhat 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">, Train 2003</ref>. In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">2</ref>, we present the results from this final model.</p><p>2 BIC is the Bayesian information criterion; CAIC is the consistent Akaike information criterion. <ref type="bibr">3</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bhat (2003)</ref> finds, in a simulation study, that Halton draws increase processing speed without producing significant effects on</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.">Probability of Eventual Product Release</head><p>The results from the logit portion of the split-hazard formulation reveal which projects eventually lead to a product release (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">2</ref>). As degree centrality increases, the probability of eventual product release increases at an increasing rate (positive quadratic term; b = 0 04, p &lt; 0 01); as closeness centrality increases, this probability increases (positive linear term: b = 0 61, p &lt; 0 10). As brokerage increases, the probability of eventual release increases at a decreasing rate (positive linear effect: b = 1 14, p &lt; 0 01; negative quadratic effect: b = −0 54, p &lt; 0 01). The embeddedness measures pertaining to betweenness (b = 0 17, p &lt; 0 01) and closeness (b = 0 83, p &lt; 0 01) centrality strengthen the positive effect of brokerage on the probability of eventual product release.</p><p>Developer-focused projects are more likely to experience product release than are user-focused projects (b = −0 69, p &lt; 0 01), though projects that use a GPL are less likely to do so (b = −0 33, p &lt; 0 05). The probability of eventual product release increases with greater founders' experience (b = 0 21, p &lt; 0 01), and using a community forum increases the probability of eventual product release (b = 0 60, p &lt; 0 05). The results for the interplay of developer user and end user communities reveal that increasing brokerage increases the probability of eventual release at a faster rate for end user than for developer user products (b = 0 21, p &lt; 0 10).</p><p>In summary, the results indicate that the social capital of the project founders significantly impacts the probability of eventual product release. Projects that are developer-focused, use community forums, and were started by experienced founders are also more likely to release products eventually than projects that are user-focused, do not use forums, or were started by less experienced founders.</p><p>6.3. Time to Product Release 6.3.1. Project Founders' Embeddedness and Brokerage. In support of H 1 , time to product release decreases at a decreasing rate across projects as embeddedness increases, where embeddedness is measured by degree centrality (negative linear effect: b = −0 10, p &lt; 0 10; positive quadratic effect: b = 0 01, p &lt; 0 01) and closeness centrality (negative linear effect: b = −0 56, p &lt; 0 05; positive quadratic effect: b = 0 39, p &lt; 0 01). In contrast, time to product release increases at a decreasing rate as betweenness centrality increases (positive linear effect: b = 0 01, p &lt; 0 01; negative quadratic effect: b = −0 02, p &lt; 0 01). The the simulation results; the results are robust to a number of Halton draws that is slightly higher than the square root of the number of observations. We use 30 draws for our sample size of 817.   a The coefficient and standard error were multiplied by 10 2 for ease of presentation. * p &lt; 0 1; * * p &lt; 0 05; * * * p &lt; 0 01.</p><p>findings related to betweenness centrality are consistent with other studies that show varying results concerning the strength and direction of relationships involving betweenness centrality <ref type="bibr">(Ronchetto et al. 1989, Fleming and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Waguespack 2007)</ref>. Because betweenness centrality measures a founder's location on the shortest pathways in the network, it is possible that information overflow along the shortest pathways may lead to information overload <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Rosa et al. 1999)</ref>. In that case, founders occupying such locations can slow down both the NPD process and the time to product release.</p><p>Consistent with H 2 and extant research on diminishing returns to (social) capital <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Elfenbein and</ref><ref type="bibr">Zenger 2009, McFadyen and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Cannella 2004)</ref>, as brokerage increases, the time to product release decreases at a decreasing rate (negative linear effect: b = −0 92, p &lt; 0 01; positive quadratic effect: b = 0 50, p &lt; 0 01). Thus, brokerage offers benefits, but the rate of return decreases as the level of brokerage increases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3.2.">Interaction of Embeddedness and Brokerage.</head><p>In support of H 3 , regarding the synergy between embeddedness and brokerage in OSS product development, we find that the magnitude of the decrease in the time to product release with an increase in embeddedness increases as brokerage increases. However, this effect is only significant for embeddedness measured by degree centrality (b = −0 42, p &lt; 0 01) and closeness centrality (b = −0 68, p &lt; 0 01). The significance of the interaction between embeddedness and brokerage implies that projects whose founders are endowed with both high embeddedness and high brokerage see first releases quicker than projects founded by people who score high only on one of the social capital constructs. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Ai and Norton (2003)</ref> indicate that in nonlinear models, the parameter value of an interaction effect does not appropriately reflect the marginal interaction effect. Following <ref type="bibr">Greene (2010), 4</ref> in addition to the statistical significance of the interaction effects presented here, we also present a detailed analysis of the interactions in our model in the appendix. These additional analyses confirm the conclusions drawn from the coefficients of the interaction terms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3.3.">Interplay of Developer Users and End</head><p>Users. As the degree of user engagement for a project increases, 5 time to product release decreases (b = −0 05, p &lt; 0 01). Consistent with H 4a , we find a decrease in the time to product release as the degree of user engagement increases when embeddedness increases (degree: b = −0 09, p &lt; 0 01; betweenness: b = −0 05, p &lt; 0 05). Thus, our findings support the conjecture that the developer user community leverages the activity of the end user community in the OSS context. <ref type="bibr">4</ref>  <ref type="bibr">Greene (2010, p. 295</ref>) notes that "partial effects are neither coefficients nor elements. They are implications of the specified and estimated model [t]he most informative point in the analysis at which to do hypothesis testing is at the model building step, not at the analysis step." As partial effects are an artifact of the functional form, we test hypotheses using the interaction effects estimated in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">2</ref>. However, to understand the nature of the interactions, we examine both the partial interaction effects and the effect on the dependent variable visually in the appendix (Greene 2010). <ref type="bibr">5</ref> We included the residual error term from the regression of bugs reported on bugs resolved as an explanatory variable in an alternative analysis. The variable instruments the project team's innate ability to resolve bugs above and beyond bugs reported. The effect of the residual error term was −0 02 (p &lt; 0 05).</p><p>Consistent with H 5a , the shortened time to product release as embeddedness increases across projects becomes even shorter for user-focused projects than for developer-focused projects (degree: b = −0 007, p &lt; 0 01; closeness: b = −0 25, p &lt; 0 10). In contrast, when betweenness centrality increases, the shortening of the time to product release is greater for developer-focused projects than for user-focused projects (b = 0 35, p &lt; 0 05).</p><p>In summary, founders' embeddedness seems more relevant than brokerage in the interaction with degree of user engagement and product's audience focus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3.4.">OSS Project and Product Characteristics.</head><p>As the project founders' experience increases, the time to product release decreases (b = −0 15, p &lt; 0 01), and projects that use community forums experience a shorter time to product release than projects that do not (b = −0 80, p &lt; 0 01). Projects with a prior code at the time of registration on SourceForge release products at a faster rate than projects without this code (b = −0 69, p &lt; 0 01). Finally, the effects of the type of open source license, size of first release file, and size of project team are insignificant.</p><p>6.4. Robustness Checks and Model Validation 6.4.1. Sampling Frame. To rule out the possibility that our results are specific to our sampling frame, we created three random subsets from the 817 projects that constitute our sample. We then created three different samples by combining two random samples at a time: subsample 1 (n = 582), subsample 2 (n = 510), and subsample 3 (n = 542). We estimated three splithazard models with unobserved heterogeneity, one for each subsample. The results from all three models are consistent with those from the entire sample.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4.2.">Predictive Validity.</head><p>To assess the predictive validity of the duration model, we divided the sample into two random subsets, A for estimation (n = 410, censored = 177) and B for predictive validation (n = 407, censored = 172). We estimated two models using the sample A data: one with only project feature variables and another that includes both the social capital variables and the interplay of the developer user and end user communities. We account for censoring by following <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Grewal et al. (2004)</ref> and removing censored observations from the holdout sample before calculating the predictive validity scores. With the sample B data, we compared the two models in terms of their root mean square errors (RMSE), mean absolute errors (MAE), and Thiel's U statistic (TUS) <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Greene 2003)</ref>. The model that includes the network measures provides superior predictions than the one without them (RMSE improves by 12.4%, MAE by 17.8%, and TUS by 11.3%). We validate the predictive ability of the eventual product release (i.e., logit part of the split hazard model) for the overall sample <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Sinha and Chandrashekaran 1992)</ref>. With a correct prediction rate of 0.82, 6 our model specification outperforms the naïve criteria of C pro = 0 51 and C max = 0 57 <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Morrison 1969</ref>). 7 6.4.3. Alternative Dependent Measures. We conducted post hoc analyses of downloads and page views for projects in our sample. The time to first release, as expected, is negatively correlated with the cumulative number of downloads (−0 39) and page views (−0 19) before the first release date. The more the working version is downloaded or the more page views it garners, the shorter the time to release, which validates our premise that success measures such as downloads correlate with our dependent variable and in the right direction. We also ran two regression models, with downloads or page views as the dependent variable. We find that the explanatory variables that increase downloads also decrease time to product release. For example, project founder's degree centrality has a negative effect on time to product release (−0 10, p &lt; 0 10) but increases downloads (0.01, p &lt; 0 01) and page views (0.03, p &lt; 0 01). Similarly, brokerage decreases time to product release (−0 92, p &lt; 0 01), whereas it increases both downloads (0.66, p &lt; 0 05) and page views (0.04, p &lt; 0 05).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">Discussion</head><p>As the economic significance of user-generated content continues to grow, it becomes critical to understand how such content is created, managed, and used in various contexts. We study the factors that drive the success of new OSS projects, an important type of user-generated content. We conceptualize the interplay of two communities, developer users and end users, as the necessary basis for the creation and maintenance of user-generated content. Therefore, the time to product release of new OSS projects is influenced by the project founders' social capital, aspects of the interplay of developer user and end user communities, and the OSS project and product characteristics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1.">Theoretical Contributions</head><p>In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">3</ref>, we summarize our study's findings with respect to extant research in innovation, social networks, and OSS product development. Several of our hypotheses are new, and our findings add to sparse research on specific factors that influence NPD success in an OSS context. <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Grewal et al. (2006)</ref> consider the role of networks in the technical and commercial success of OSS products, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Hahn et al. (2008)</ref> examine how prior ties affect the formation of new OSS project teams. Other studies investigate the role of OSS project features on success <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Stewart et al. 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">, Subramaniam et al. 2009</ref>). We extend this body of literature by studying the effect of all three factors simultaneously on time to product release.</p><p>Emerging literature in OSS also recognizes the importance of social networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Hahn et al. 2008)</ref>; we extend this research in two ways. First, rather than studying product outcomes such as commercial success <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Grewal et al. 2006)</ref>, we consider the NPD process with time to first product release as an NPD process metric. Second, together with embeddedness <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Grewal et al. 2006</ref>), we consider brokerage, which captures a founder's access to diverse information sets and thus creativity <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Burt 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">, Obstfeld 2005</ref>. Our results regarding the nonlinear main effect of brokerage and the interaction between embeddedness and brokerage (see Figure A.1) support the inclusion of both measures in a conceptualization of social capital in the OSS context.</p><p>Our work explicitly recognizes the role of two subcommunities in the network and their interplay, which is important for two reasons. First, it is central to the OSS NPD process and common in other user-generated contexts, such as pictures on Flickr and videos on YouTube. Second, it represents a contrast from the firm-centric NPD process; that is, although firms may seek user feedback during the NPD process, the level and intensity of such feedback is a managerial decision, not driven by users themselves.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2.">Managerial Implications</head><p>Our research has particular implications for managers of firms that participate in open source projects. Project founders' social capital plays a critical role, beyond the interplay of the developer user and end user communities or the impact of OSS project and product characteristics. If a firm engaged in the OSS community were to choose between, say, users 714 and 426 (see Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3</ref>; actual members of SourceForge) to collaborate on a project, it should consider their embeddedness scores: user 714 is likely to bring a project to market almost a full year (357 days) before user 426 would. Similar metrics might consider user and project data, as outlined in our model. For example, projects achieve a 51% decrease in their time to product release when the founder has high embeddedness (degree centrality in particular) and brokerage, but the decrease is only 12% when the founder • <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Grewal et al. (2006)</ref>: Positive effect on technical and commercial success in OSS networks.</p><p>• <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Ronchetto et al. (1989)</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>New hypothesis</head><p>Boundaries of social capital in the presence of interplay between developer user and end user communities.</p><p>• <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Grewal et al. (2006)</ref>: Degree of user engagement as a control variable. <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">• Subramaniam et al. (2009)</ref>: Community interest as a dependent variable.</p><p>-Not applicable, because the moderator variables are specific to the OSS context. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>New hypothesis</head><p>Boundaries of social capital in the presence of interplay between developer user and end user communities.</p><p>• <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Subramaniam et al. (2009)</ref>: License and audience focus as determinants and controls of OSS success measured by user interest, developer interest, and project activity. <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">• Stewart et al. (2006)</ref>: License as a determinant of user interest and development activity.</p><p>-Not applicable, because the moderator variables are specific to the OSS context.</p><p>Note. B2B, business to business.</p><p>has a high degree centrality alone (see <ref type="bibr">Figure A.1,</ref><ref type="bibr">panel A.2)</ref>. Recognizing the existence of two subcommunities helps managers find new ways to speed products to market too. They might offer more product versions targeted toward end users to encourage end user participation (e.g., beta testers) and increase bug reports. All else being equal, an increase of one standard deviation in bugs reported (42 bugs on average), or user engagement, reduces time to product release for the average project by 11%. Finally, the effects of OSS project and product characteristics have managerial relevance. Experience pays off, and our findings help quantify that payoff; a one-standard-deviation increase (54 days on average) in the cumulative experience of project founders reduces the time for the average project by 15%. Our results also can help managers justify the use of community collaboration tools: projects that use forums experience an 80% shorter time to product release than do projects that do not use forums.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.3.">Limitations and Research Opportunities</head><p>Our research centers on one user-generated content domain, whereas other contexts, including blogs and wikis, may not involve the same success metrics. By featuring only SourceForge, with its unique institutional idiosyncrasies, this study's propositions also require testing in other open source project domains. Our research is also limited by data availability and contains only structural network data;</p><p>Marketing Science 31(3), pp. 474-492, © 2012 INFORMS we observe the connections but not what they comprise (e.g., communication patterns, formal or informal hierarchies). Information about the type and quality of communication might enrich understanding of the process. Although time to product release is a critical NPD process metric in the OSS context, other metrics such as interrelease time may also be relevant.</p><p>It would be interesting to investigate whether and how our two subcommunity characterization applies to other user-generated contexts and how our findings about the role of social capital in innovation apply more broadly to the role of social networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Stephen and Toubia 2010)</ref>. For example, bloggers typically link to other popular bloggers, and active Facebook users tend to have large social networks. Investigating the mechanics of network formation and growth in these contexts should enable managers of online social networking sites to develop new ways to manage and monetize traffic on their sites.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.4.">Conclusion</head><p>In the modern networked world, innovative models of communication and collaboration emerge rapidly, creating the need to investigate new phenomena <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Reibstein et al. 2009</ref>). The emergence of usergenerated content, for example, is changing how consumers share information, form communities, and connect, which has serious implications for marketing strategy. The OSS context represents one such important domain; as we show, the social network of developer users and the interplay between the developer user and end user communities have critical impacts on NPD process success. Social network analysis provides effective concepts and tools to address these new opportunities, and an emerging networked environment presents many important challenges for research. We hope our work has added insight and stimulates further research in this challenging and important domain.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Electronic Companion</head><p>An electronic companion to this paper is available as part of the online version that can be found at http://mktsci.journal .informs.org/. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Ai and Norton (2003)</ref> indicate that in nonlinear models, the parameter value of an interaction effect does not appropriately reflect the marginal interaction effect. Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Greene (2010)</ref>, in addition to the statistical significance of the interaction effects presented earlier, we also present a detailed analysis of the interactions in our model in this appendix. To examine the interaction effects in detail, we first note that an interaction effect between two independent variables, say, v1 and v2, is the change in the partial effect of v1 on the dependent variable, say, z1 (i.e., the partial derivative of the z1 with respect to v1) for a unit change in v2. Following Greene (2010), we investigate these effects through two types of plots-in the first we depict the partial effect, and in the second we investigate the impact on the dependent variable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Interaction of Embeddedness and Brokerage</head><p>In panel A.1 in Figure A.1, we show how the partial effect (plotted on y axis), varies with degree centrality (x axis, 1-9 represents the sample range) across two levels of brokerage (25th versus 75th percentile), keeping all the other variables constant at their means. The changing distance between the two curves in panel A.1 shows that the partial effect differs across two levels of brokerage, establishing the interaction effect. In the second plot, shown in panel A.2 in Figure <ref type="figure">A</ref>.1, we plot the effect of degree centrality (x axis) on the predicted value of time to product release (y axis, measured in log-hours) at two levels of brokerage, keeping all the other variables constant at their means. The plot in panel A.2 shows the impact of the interaction of degree centrality and brokerage on time to product release. From panel A.2, time to product release decreases by a maximum of 31% before increasing, as degree centrality changes from low to high under high brokerage, compared with an 11% decrease under low brokerage.</p><p>In panel B.1 in Figure A.1, we show how the partial effect varies with closeness centrality (x axis, 0.05-0.5 represents the sample range) across two levels of brokerage (25th versus 75th percentile), fixing all the other variables at their means. The changing distance between the two curves establishes the interaction effect. In panel B.2, we plot the effect of closeness centrality on the predicted value of time to product release for two levels of brokerage. From panel B.2, we see that time to product release decreases by 5.5% as closeness centrality increases under high brokerage compared with a 3.5% decrease under low brokerage.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Interaction of Founder's Social Capital and Degree of User Engagement</head><p>In panel A.1 in Figure A.2, we show how the partial effect of degree centrality (x axis, 1-9 represents the sample range) on time to product release varies across two levels of user engagement (25th versus 75th percentile), and in panel A.2, we plot the effect of degree centrality on time to product release across the two levels of user engagement. The changing distance between the curves in panel A.1 establishes the interaction effect, and from panel A.2, we see that time to product release decreases by 83% as degree centrality increases with a high degree of user engagement, compared with a 40% decrease for a low value.</p><p>In panel B.1 of Figure A.2, we depict how the partial effect of betweenness centrality varies across two levels of degree of user engagement, and in panel B.2 we plot the effect of betweenness centrality on time to product release across the two levels of degree of user engagement. From panel B.2, we see that time to product release decreases by 10% as closeness centrality increases from low to high for user-focused projects, compared with a 5% decrease for developer-focused projects. Notes. We used the 25th and the 75th percentile values in the sample for the low and high conditions of brokerage. For degree and closeness centrality, plotted on the x axis, we used their sample range. The partial effect, plotted on the y axis in panels A.1 and B.1, is the unit change in time to product release for a unit change in degree and closeness centrality, respectively. Time to product release, plotted in panels A.2 and B.2, is the predicted value of the dependent variable in log-hours from the estimation. Notes. We used the 25th and the 75th percentile values in the sample for the low and high conditions of degree of user engagement. For degree and betweenness centrality, plotted on the x axis, we used their sample range. The partial effect, plotted on the y axis in panels A.1 and B.1, is the unit change in time to product release for a unit change in degree and betweenness centrality, respectively. Time to product release, plotted in panels A.2 and B.2, is the predicted value of the dependent variable in log-hours from the estimation. Notes. Product's audience focus is measured by a dichotomous variable: user-focused versus developer-focused. For degree and closeness centrality, plotted on the x axis, we used their sample range. The partial effect, plotted on the y axis in panels A.1 and B.1, is the unit change in time to product release for a unit change in degree and closeness centrality, respectively. Time to product release, plotted in panels A.2 and B.2, is the predicted value of the dependent variable in log-hours from the estimation.</p><p>Interaction of Founder's Social Capital and Product's Audience Focus In panel A.1 in Figure A.3, we see how the partial effect of degree centrality on time to product release varies across the two types of audience focus, and in panel A.2, we plot the effect of degree centrality on the predicted value of time to product release for the two types. The changing distance between the curves in panel A.1 establishes the interaction effect, and panel A.2 depicts the impact of the interaction on the dependent variable. From panel A.2, we see that time to product release decreases by 98% as degree centrality increases from low to high for user-focused projects, compared with an 86% decrease for developer-focused projects.</p><p>In panel B.1 of Figure A.3, we see how the partial effect of closeness centrality on time to product release varies across the two types of audience focus, and in panel B.2, we plot the effect of closeness centrality on time to product release for the two types. The changing distance between the curves in panel B.1 establishes the interaction effect, and panel B.2 shows the impact of the interaction on the dependent variable. From panel B.2, time to product release decreases by 10% as closeness centrality increases from low to high for user-focused projects, compared with a 5% decrease for developer-focused projects.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Conceptual Framework</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2Illustration of Brokerage and Embeddedness</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3Representation of the Network Sample of Open Source Projects and Users</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>November 2004, February 2005, June 2005, October 2005, February 2006, and June 2006. This variable is the time-varying covariate in the model.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Project founders develop coordination and product development skills through interactions in the open source community (O'Mahony and Ferraro 2007), and greater experience might enable them to foresee and respond to problems better (Chandrashekaran</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>0 01 −0 01 −0 02 0 03 −0 02 −0 01 −0 13 1 (10) Project team size 1 82 2 27 −0 06 0 03 −0 03 −0 01 −0 09 0 17 −0 03 −0 02 −0 01 1 (11) Founder's experience 2683 63 1303 23 −0 23 0 14 0 08 0 34 0 03 0 05 0 07 −0 00 −0 04 0 01 1 (12) File size at release 1207 13 18,799,094 −0 09 0 06 0 06 0 07 0 02 0 08 0 02 0 02 −0 03 0 07 −0 04 1 (13) Time to product release a 487 34 7 956 −0 12 −0 21 −0 04 −0 09 −0 01 0 04 −0 05 0 02 0 02 −0 44 −0 04 −0 03 1a To calculate the mean for this variable, we only used those projects that released a product during the observation window.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>* * * (0.11) Interplay of developer users and end users Degree of user engagement Bugs reported (BR) −0 05 * * * (0.02) 0 05 (0.04) Product's audience focus (PA) 0 22 (0.22) −0 69 * * (0.18) Interaction between embeddedness and brokerage (</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Marketing</head><label></label><figDesc>Science 31(3), pp. 474-492, © 2012 INFORMS</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure A.1 Plots for the Interaction of Embeddedness and Brokerage</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure A.2 Plots for the Interaction of Founder's Social Capital and Degree of User Engagement</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure A.3 Plots for the Interaction of Founder's Social Capital and Product's Audience Focus</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The source code of projects is publicly available; registered users can download and use or modify it to develop new versions as long as they adhere to the product's open source user license. Prior studies also employ data from SourceForge (e.g.,<ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Grewal et al. 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">, Hahn et al. 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">), and von Krogh and von Hippel (2006</ref> cite it as an attractive venue for research into user communities and hybrid innovation models.</figDesc><table><row><cell>4. Research Context and Data</cell></row><row><cell>4.1. SourceForge.net: Data Context</cell></row><row><cell>SourceForge.net is a collaborative product develop-</cell></row><row><cell>ment platform that enables users to coordinate their</cell></row><row><cell>open source product development efforts (Hahn et al.</cell></row><row><cell>2008). As of September 2011, more than 2.7 mil-</cell></row><row><cell>lion users worked on approximately 311,121 open</cell></row><row><cell>source projects, including database tools, application</cell></row><row><cell>software, games, text and programming editors, and</cell></row><row><cell>utility tools. With the platform's collaborative capa-</cell></row><row><cell>bilities, a project founder can advertise and recruit</cell></row><row><cell>volunteer users and organize product development</cell></row><row><cell>through the Internet.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Descriptive Statistics and Bivariate Correlations n = 817</figDesc><table><row><cell>Variable</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>SD</cell><cell>(1)</cell><cell>(2)</cell><cell>(3)</cell><cell>(4)</cell><cell>(5)</cell><cell>(6)</cell><cell>(7)</cell><cell>(8)</cell><cell>(9)</cell><cell>(10) (11) (12) (13)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Effects of Social Network Variables and Product Characteristics n = 817</figDesc><table><row><cell>Time to</cell><cell>Probability of</cell></row><row><cell>product</cell><cell>eventual</cell></row><row><cell>release</cell><cell>product release</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Summary of Results and Contributions</figDesc><table><row><cell>Prior literature in</cell></row><row><cell>social networks</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">This success metric has limitations(Bayus et al. 1997, Langerak  and<ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Hultink 2006)</ref>, but research also shows that by investing heavily in product research and development (R&amp;D), firms release more frequent product upgrades<ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bayus et al. 1997)</ref>, capture and maintain market share<ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Smith 1999)</ref>, and increase future market valuation<ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Hendricks and Singhal 1997)</ref>.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">We revisited the data in 2011 to verify how many of those projects eventually released a product. Of 349 censored projects, 189 remained as a work in progress, with code still available; 121 released a product; and 39 were abandoned. 7 C pro is the total proportion of correctly classified projects that do and do not release a product, and C max is the minimum expected proportion of projects that release a product.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This paper is based on the dissertation of the first author.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix. Analysis of Interaction Effects</head></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collaboration networks, structural holes, and innovation: A longitudinal study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ahuja</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Admin. Sci. Quart</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="425" to="455" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interaction terms in logit and probit models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Norton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="123" to="129" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trends and drivers of success in NPD practices: Results of the 2003 PDMA best practices study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Barczak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Griffin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Product Innovation Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pajek-program for large network analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Batagelj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mrvar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Connections</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Too little, too early: Introduction timing and new product performance in the personal digital assistant industry</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bayus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Jain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="50" to="63" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simulation estimation of mixed discrete choice models using randomized and scrambled Halton sequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bhat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transportation Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="837" to="855" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Structural Holes: The Social Structure of Competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Burt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The contingent value of social capital</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Burt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Admin. Sci. Quart</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="339" to="365" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structural holes and good ideas</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Burt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. J. Sociol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="349" to="399" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Brokerage and Closure: An Introduction to Social Capital</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Burt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Market motives, distinctive capabilities, and domestic inertia: A hybrid model of innovation generation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chandrashekaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mehta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Chandrashekaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Grewal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="112" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social capital in the creation of human capital</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Coleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. J. Sociol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="120" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Defining open source software project success</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Crowston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Annabi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Howison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Internat. Conf. Inform. Systems, Association for Information Systems</title>
				<meeting>Internat. Conf. Inform. Systems, Association for Information Systems<address><addrLine>Atlanta</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="327" to="340" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Open Source Products: Founder&apos;s Social Capital and Time to Product Release Marketing Science</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Grewal</forename><surname>Mallapragada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lilien</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>© 2012 INFORMS 491</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="474" to="492" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Long-run abstinence after narcotics abuse: What are the odds?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Dekimpe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Van De Gucht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hanssens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Powers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1478" to="1492" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The economics of relational (social) capital: Exploring the value of exchange relationships in industrial procurement. Working paper, Washington University in</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Elfenbein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Zenger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ssrn.com/abstract=1351852" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<pubPlace>St. Louis, St. Louis</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision-making under uncertainty: Capturing dynamic brand choice processes in turbulent consumer goods markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Erdem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Brokerage, boundary spanning, and leadership in open innovation communities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Waguespack</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="165" to="180" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collaborative brokerage, generative creativity and creative success</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mingo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Admin. Sci. Quart</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="443" to="475" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The strength of weak ties</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Granovetter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. J. Sociol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1360" to="1380" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Economic action and social structure: The problem of embeddedness</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Granovetter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. J. Sociol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="481" to="510" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Econometric Analysis</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Upper Saddle River, NJ</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Prentice-Hall</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>5th ed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing hypotheses about interaction terms in nonlinear models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="291" to="296" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Location, location, location: How network embeddedness affects project success in open source systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Grewal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lilien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mallapragada</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1043" to="1056" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The timing of repeat purchases of consumer durable goods: The role of functional bases of consumer attitudes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Grewal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mehta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Kardes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="101" to="115" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emergence of new project teams from open source software developer networks: Impact of prior collaboration ties</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Moon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inform. Systems Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="369" to="391" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why some new products are more successful than others</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Henard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Szymanski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="362" to="375" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Delays in new product introductions and the market value of the firm: The consequences of being late to the market</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Hendricks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Singhal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="422" to="436" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Statistical Analysis of Failure Time Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Kalbfleisch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Prentice</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Economic duration data and hazard functions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kiefer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Literature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="646" to="679" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Knowledge of the firm, combinative capabilities, and the replication of technology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Kogut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Zander</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="383" to="397" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How open source software works: &quot;Free&quot; user-to-user assistance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lakhani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hippel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Res. Policy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="923" to="943" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of product innovativeness on the link between development speed and new product profitability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Langerak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hultink</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Product Innovation Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="214" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring open source software success</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S.-Y</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H.-W</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Omega</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="426" to="438" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building a network theory of social capital</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Social Capital: Theory and Research</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Cook</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Burt</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">De</forename><surname>Gruyter</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Hawthorne, New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="29" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">SourceForge.net research data archive</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Madey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.nd.edu/∼oss/Data/data.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-04" />
			<pubPlace>Notre Dame, IN.</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Notre Dame</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploration and exploitation in organizational learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>March</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="87" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social capital and knowledge creation: Diminishing returns of the number and strength of exchange relationships</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mcfadyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cannella</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acad. Management J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="735" to="746" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the interpretation of discriminant analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="156" to="163" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evolution of R&amp;D capabilities: The role of knowledge networks within a firm</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nerkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Paruchuri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="771" to="785" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social networks, the tertius iungens orientation, and involvement in innovation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Obstfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Admin. Sci. Quart</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="100" to="130" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The impact of user-generated content on product innovation. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>O'hern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rindfleisch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Schweidel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Antia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ssrn.com/abstract=1843250" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<pubPlace>Madison</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Wisconsin-Madison</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The emergence of governance in an open source community. Acad</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>O'mahony</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Ferraro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1079" to="1106" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simulated maximum likelihood estimator for the random coefficient logit model using aggregate data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="531" to="542" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Cathedral and the Bazaar: Musings on Linux and Open Source by an Accidental Revolutionary</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Raymond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<pubPlace>O&apos;Reilly, Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is marketing academia losing its way?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Reibstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Day</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wind</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="3" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Environments and strategies of organization start-up: Effects on early survival</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Romanelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Admin. Sci. Quart</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="369" to="387" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Embedded influence patterns in organizational buying systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Ronchetto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hutt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Reingen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sociocognitive dynamics in a product market</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rosa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Porac</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Runser-Spanjol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Saxon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="64" to="77" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Special issue</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A nested frailty model for survival data, with an application to the study of child survival in northeast Brazil</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sastry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="426" to="435" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting criminal recidivism using &quot;split population&quot; survival time models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Witte</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="159" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-functional product development teams, creativity, and the innovativeness of new consumer products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sethi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="85" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motivation, governance, and the viability of hybrid forms in open source software development</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Shah</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1000" to="1014" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A split hazard model for analyzing the diffusion of innovations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Sinha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chandrashekaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="127" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From experience: Reaping benefit from speed to market</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Product Innovation Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="222" to="230" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A cross-national comparative study of new product development processes: Japan and the United States</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Parry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="18" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deriving value from social commerce networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Stephen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Toubia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="228" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impacts of license choice and organizational sponsorship on user interest and development activity in open source software projects</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Ammeter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Maruping</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inform Systems Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="126" to="144" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Organizations and Social Structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Stinchcombe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1965" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Open Source Products: Founder&apos;s Social Capital and Time to Product Release 492</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Grewal</forename><surname>Mallapragada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lilien</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="474" to="492" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determinants of open source software project success: A longitudinal study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Subramaniam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decision Support Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="576" to="585" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Marketing alliances, firm networks, and firm value creation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Swaminathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Moorman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="52" to="69" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Train</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Discrete Choice Methods with Simulation</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social structure and competition in interfirm networks: The paradox of embeddedness</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Uzzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Admin. Sci. Quart</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="67" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Endogeneity in brand choice models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Villas-Boas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Winer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1324" to="1338" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The promise of research on open source software</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Von Krogh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hippel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="975" to="983" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wasserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Faust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Social Network Analysis: Methods and Applications</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Zucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Darby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Brewer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Peng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Collaboration Structure and Information Dilemmas in Biotechnology</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Sage, Thousand Oaks, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
