<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Procuring Commodities: First-Price Sealed-Bid or English Auctions?</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2012-02-16">February 16, 2012.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Shachat</surname></persName>
							<email>jason.shachat@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Wang Yanan Institute for Studies in Economics (WISE)</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">MOE Key Laboratory of Econometrics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Xiamen University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>361005</postCode>
									<settlement>Xiamen</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Wang Yanan Institute for Studies in Economics (WISE)</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">MOE Key Laboratory of Econometrics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Xiamen University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>361005</postCode>
									<settlement>Xiamen</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Lijia</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Wang Yanan Institute for Studies in Economics (WISE)</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">MOE Key Laboratory of Econometrics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Xiamen University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>361005</postCode>
									<settlement>Xiamen</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Wang Yanan Institute for Studies in Economics (WISE)</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">MOE Key Laboratory of Econometrics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Xiamen University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>361005</postCode>
									<settlement>Xiamen</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Procuring Commodities: First-Price Sealed-Bid or English Auctions?</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 (print)</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2012-02-16">February 16, 2012.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1120.0704</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: February 14, 2009; accepted: November 21, 2011; Eric Bradlow and then Preyas Desai</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:28+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Large organizations, which procure a wide range of goods and services, are increasingly finding themselves contemplating changes from traditional request for quote mechanisms to dynamic reverse auctions. Practitioners <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Purchasing 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">, Chafkin 2007</ref>) and academics <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Jap 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">, Elmaghraby 2007</ref>) commonly suggest that when organizations consider this change they should start with their commodity purchases. For current purposes, commodities are goods for which the organization considers price the sole differentiating attribute among suppliers. When price is the sole determinant of supplier choice, a request for quote mechanism reduces to a first-price sealed-bid auction (FPA), and a dynamic reverse auction reduces to an English auction (EA). This raises the need for some basic comparative empirical knowledge of the two auction formats for procurement officials in such organizations. Toward filling this need, this study provides insights into the relative empirical price performance between the FPA and the EA in the context of procuring commodities, the nature of how suppliers bid when having little to no experience in such auctions, and how their bidding behaviors adjust as they gain experience.</p><p>We conduct a controlled laboratory experiment designed so that inferences on performance, behavior, and dynamics are made without concern for estimating suppliers' costs or the procuring organization's willingness to pay. We report statistical tests comparing properties of the empirical price distributions generated within the FPA and EA versus each other and against theoretical benchmarks. The results of these tests show that the mean and variance of prices are lower in the FPA, prices in the EA first-order stochastically dominate those in the FPA, and the Nash equilibrium predictions regarding prices and individual bids are accurate in the EA but not in the FPA.</p><p>Our investigation of the procurement context is an important extension in the broader experimental study of FPA and EA auctions with independent and private information. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Previous experimental and behavioral studies have almost exclusively considered the forward context; i.e., the auctioneer is selling an object, and a bidder's private information is his valuation of that object. Our results demonstrate that the previously observed robustness of gametheoretic predicted performance in the EA extends to the procurement context. Likewise, we replicate previous deviations from Nash equilibrium predictions in the FPA; however, the procurement setting permits us to identify a new explanation for these deviations. Namely, there is a discrete heterogeneity in the bidding rules subjects follow. Two of these rules are nonstrategic and have more sensible interpretations in the Shachat and Wei: Procuring Commodities</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>318</head><p>Marketing Science 31(2), pp. 317-333, © 2012 INFORMS procurement setting than in the forward one. One rule is to use an absolute markup in which a constant amount is added to a bidder's realized cost. We believe that demanding a constant profit margin is a more natural decision heuristic in a selling context relative to its forward auction counterpart, in which a bidder demands a constant amount of consumer surplus independent of the valuation. The other nonstrategic rule is to use a fixed proportional markup of realized cost. Requiring a certain rate of return is a common rule of thumb used by businesses when setting prices, and it generates a positive relationship between costs and the absolute amount of profit demanded. In a procurement FPA, this rule is distinct from Nash equilibrium bidding, which generates a negative relationship between cost and profit demanded. In contrast, both these rules generate an increasing relationship between valuation and demanded consumer surplus in the forward FPA. This makes econometric identification of the Nash equilibrium and percentage markup rules difficult, if not impossible, in the forward FPA.</p><p>To explain and estimate this discrete bidding heterogeneity, we present a quasi-equilibrium model of bidding in the FPA based on a mixture of strategic and rule-of-thumb bidders. Then a dynamic version of this model is estimated as a hidden Markov model; the latent variable is the rule a subject follows in each auction period. In the initial stage of the experiment, we estimate about three-quarters of the subjects follow a strategic bidding rule, and the remaining subjects follow either an absolute or a percentage markup rule. The estimated dynamics are surprising because bidders become less strategic as they gain experience. During the sequence of 30 auctions, the proportion of strategic bidders falls below two-thirds, and there is a corresponding rise in the proportion of bidders who simply bid a small constant absolute amount above cost.</p><p>The rest of this paper proceeds as follows. In §2, we review the relevant literatures. This is followed by the development of hypotheses regarding the performance of the two auction types in §3. Next, we present the details of the experimental design and procedures in §4. Then, in §5, there is an empirical analysis of the price performance and bidder behavior in the experiment.</p><p>In §6, we discuss the theoretical mixture bidding model for the FPA, and the estimation results of a hidden Markov dynamic version of the model are presented in §7. In §8, we demonstrate the robustness of this model through specification tests against multiple alternative models found in the literature. We conclude the paper in §9 by commenting on implications of the results and possible extensions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Related Auction Literature</head><p>Our evaluation of the relative price performances of the procurement FPA and EA contributes to the extensive experimental literature testing the revenue equivalence theorem in basic auction formats. The original version of the theorem <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Vickrey 1961)</ref> states that expected prices are the same for the FPA, the Dutch auction (a dynamic auction with the same normal game form as the FPA), the second-price sealed-bid auction (which has the same normal game form as the EA), and the EA when bidder types are independent and identically distributed private information. As far as we know, all other experimental tests of the revenue equivalence theorem use forward auctions. Most of these early studies focus on making comparisons within pairs of normal game form-equivalent auctions. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Coppinger et al. (1980)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Cox et al. (1982)</ref> find that the EA and the second-price sealed-bid auction generate the same expected prices, whereas the FPA generates higher prices than the Dutch auction. In a well-known field experimental study, <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Lucking-Reiley (1999)</ref> finds the same revenue equivalence between the EA and the second-price sealed-bid auction but observes that the average Dutch auction price exceeds that of the FPAcontradicting the results of earlier laboratory studies. These and other studies speak little to the comparison of the EA and the FPA, which vary both in the normal game form and Nash equilibrium solution. However, the nature of our applied procurement problem begs this comparison.</p><p>Considering the procurement rather than the forward context is a key aspect of our study, despite this difference in context having no effect on Nash equilibrium and the prediction of revenue equivalence. The impact in auctions of nonstrategic factors, such as context and framing, has many precedents. Many auction formats have the same normal game form representations as the second-price auction, and researchers often exploit this relationship by analyzing such auctions as second-price ones. However, <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Zeithammer and Adams (2010)</ref> demonstrate that in EAs with bidder proxies on eBay, this second-price auction abstraction fails. <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Hossain and Morgan (2006)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Brown et al. (2010)</ref> find a failure of revenue equivalence in a series of eBay auctions that are identical except for the framing of fixed shipping and handling fees. An additional example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Dholakia and Simonson (2005)</ref> demonstrate in a field experiment that including explicit reference points to competing prices-which does not impact the equilibrium predictions-raises auction prices. In a related work, <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Fay (2004)</ref> shows that multiple-bid versus singlebid formats of name-your-own-price auctions are not empirically revenue equivalent-the auctioneer's profit increases in the multiple-bid format as the number of sophisticated bidders grows. In response to the revenue equivalence failure, each of these studies formulates an appropriate behavioral model to capture the effect of the framing variation. We also argue from a behavioral perspective that the procurement context facilitates the adoption of simple pricing heuristics, which have less intuitive counterparts in the forward context.</p><p>The performance of an auction is a product of the individual bidding behavior, as these previous studies found that identifying better models of individual behavior leads to better explanations of auction performance. Thus identification of the bidding behavior is crucial to understanding why auction formats perform differently. A large segment of the structural econometric modeling of auctions literature proceeds by assuming that bidders follow Nash equilibrium strategies and then use properties of the Nash equilibrium to establish identification and consistent estimation of parameters such as the bidder's underlying values and beliefs. <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Hendricks and</ref><ref type="bibr">Porter (1988), Laffont et al. (1995)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Guerre et al. (2009)</ref>, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Krasnokutskaya (2011)</ref> represent a very incomplete list of examples from this literature that analyze the private value, single object case. Reliance on the strong rationality assumptions of Nash equilibrium is a natural criticism of this approach. In response, recent alternatives have built structural empirical bidding models without relying on the Nash equilibrium assumption for identification <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Goeree et al. 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">, Park and Bradlow 2005</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">, Chan et al. 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">, Yao and Mela 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">, Abbas and Hann 2010</ref> or have taken a reducedform approach <ref type="bibr">Naik 2008, Bradlow and</ref> to build forecasting models. In many ways, our work is in the spirit of structural models that relax the assumption of Nash equilibrium, although, given the nature of our experimental data, we mostly focus on the estimation of bidding rule parameters and the distribution of rules in the population.</p><p>The performance differences we observe between the EA and the FPA are driven by individual deviations from Nash equilibrium bidding in the FPA. Thus our modeling approach to individual bidding brings new insights into the extensive literature examining non-Nash bidding in FPA forward auctions. In one of the earliest experimental studies of a forward FPA with independent private values, <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Cox et al. (1982)</ref> find that the vast majority of bids exceed the Nash equilibrium-predicted ones, thus leading to higherthan-predicted prices. They further propose a new Nash equilibrium model in which the bidders are characterized by heterogeneous risk attitudes. Their simple elegant solution is highly scrutinized by <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Kagel and Levin (1993)</ref> and others (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Kagel 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Kagel and</ref><ref type="bibr">Levin 2008, 2012</ref> for thorough reviews), who generate data that cannot be explained by models of risk aversion. Proposed alternatives to explain the data from these subsequent experiments use principles from behavioral economics such as anticipated regret <ref type="bibr">Katok 2007, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Filiz-Ozbay and Ozbay 2007)</ref> and nonlinear probability weighting <ref type="bibr">(Armantier and Treich 2009a, b)</ref>, or they adopt alternative game-theoretic solutions to the Nash equilibrium <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Goeree et al. 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">, Morgan et al. 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">, Ockenfels and Selten 2005</ref>.</p><p>Our alternative behavioral model for bidding in the FPA, in its static form, follows a recent approach of allowing discrete strategic heterogeneity. In an influential study, <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Crawford and Iriberri (2007)</ref> replace the stringent belief assumptions of Nash equilibrium with a level-k strategic model to analyze FPAs. In the level-k model, each bidder is characterized by a nonnegative integer k, indicating the number of steps of iterated best response he performs when selecting a strategy. The iterated best-response process starts with some boundedly rational rule for step k = 0. For the forward FPA, Crawford and Iriberri consider two possible k = 0 strategies: bid the true value or bid randomly according to a uniform distribution over the interval from the minimum allowable bid to value. A k = 1 type believes all other bidders follow a particular k = 0 strategy and best responds; correspondingly, a k = 2 type believes all other bidders are k = 1 and best responds, and so on. Crawford and Iriberri apply this model to an FPA experiment with a discrete valuation space reported in <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Goeree et al. (2002)</ref> and find that it performs quite favorably to other models. Moreover, they estimate a full mixture model and find that approximately 4%, 76%, and 20% of the subjects follow the level k = 0, 1, and 2 rules, respectively.</p><p>In a second paper using mixtures of bidding rules, <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Kirchkamp and Reiss (2008)</ref> consider a model of two bidders in which there is some probability a bidder bids a fixed markdown of his valuation; otherwise, the bidder is rational and best responds while taking full account of the mixture distribution of rational and fixed markdown bidders. This model differs from <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Crawford and Iriberri (2007)</ref> because it specifies a different k = 0, and the k = 1 type best responds according to the true distribution of the level types rather than the belief that all bidders are k = 0. <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Kirchkamp and Reiss (2008)</ref> test their model in a series of forward FPAs that allow bids less than the lowest possible valuation. By estimating individual bid functions, they find that roughly 30% of the subjects follow the markdown, whereas the remaining subjects follow the more rational rule. It should be noted that these models are static; Crawford and Iriberri ( <ref type="formula">2007</ref>) state that their level-k formulation is a model of how inexperienced individuals bid (accordingly, they only consider the first five rounds of each experimental session in their analysis), and the <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Kirchkamp and Reiss (2008)</ref> model is quasi-equilibrium. Our model first extends the Kirchkamp and Reiss model by allowing multiple participants and additional bidding heuristic rules. Moreover, we take a step forward in this modeling approach by allowing bidders to switch rules over time and model this dynamic to examine how individuals adapt with experience.</p><p>Our dynamic extension is a significant advance in identifying how bidders in the FPA adapt with experience. Despite the large number of FPA studies, surprisingly few of them address how individuals learn to bid over time. The most developed empirical literature on learning in FPAs focuses on the impact of the informational feedback provided to bidders. If a forward FPA provides the winning bid, or the whole vector of bids, then bid functions are estimated to increase to levels above the Nash equilibrium <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">(Selten and Buchta 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">, Guth et al. 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">, Neugebauer and Selten 2006</ref>. However, in the absence of this feedback, behavior converges toward the risk-neutral Nash equilibrium <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Neugebauer and Perote 2008)</ref>. The workhouse dynamic principle of this literature is the directional learning model introduced by Selten and Buchta (1998). Directional learning is more of a behavioral principle than a complete model, as it only specifies that individuals adjust their strategy toward those who offer ex post higher payoffs conditional on available information.</p><p>The set of investigations regarding structural learning models is less developed. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bajari and Hortacsu (2005)</ref> find that econometric models that assume subjects follow an adaptive learning process do not outperform equilibrium models with risk aversion in recovering structural parameters. Recent efforts to study learning in FPA auctions using <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Camerer and Ho's (1999)</ref> experienced weighted attraction (EWA) model also have had limited success. <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">James and Reagle (2009)</ref> find that EWA models can generate aggregate data similar to aggregate human subject data, but the EWA parameters are extremely difficult to recover econometrically. Furthermore, <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Dittrich et al. (2011)</ref> find great between-subject heterogeneity in their EWA model estimates as well as significant estimated loss aversion. The dynamic rule-switching model we study advances these efforts by demonstrating that individual heterogeneity is well explained by a small set of discrete rules and that observed increasing (or decreasing, in our procurement setting) deviations from Nash equilibrium in FPA arises from individuals increasingly adopting absolute markup strategies that demand small profit margins.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Environment Formulation and the Development of Auction Performance Hypotheses</head><p>Let us begin by considering the simple situation with a procurement official whose task is to purchase an indivisible unit of a commodity as cheaply as possible. There are n potential suppliers indexed by i. Each supplier can provide a unit of the commodity for the cost of c i , which is incurred only if they supply the unit. The cost c i is only known by supplier i-i.e., it is private information-and will typically vary across suppliers. Suppliers are symmetric in that none has an ex ante cost advantage. Specifically, each supplier's costs is an independent realization from a random variable whose distribution is uniform on the interval c L c H . Whereas each supplier knows his own realized costs, the other suppliers and the procurement official only know its distribution. We consider two sourcing methods for this scenario. First is the EA, which starts at an initial high price, and all n suppliers are still participants. Then the price sequentially decrements. At each decrement, a participant can take the action to irreversibly exit the auction, after which he is no longer considered a participant. At each decrement, the number of remaining participants and current price are publicly posted. The auction closes when the second-to-last participant exits. The last remaining participant wins the auction and receives the closing auction price, p. This winning supplier i receives a profit of p − c i , and all other suppliers receive zero profit. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> The EA has a weakly dominant strategy: a supplier chooses to exit the auction when the price equals his unit cost. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> When everyone follows the weakly dominant strategy, the losing suppliers reveal their true costs, and the supplier with the lowest realized cost wins the auction and subsequently receives a price equal to the second-lowest realized cost. Consequently, the price paid by the procurement official is a random variable whose distribution is the second-order statistic of the n suppliers' cost realizations.</p><p>In an FPA, each supplier privately submits a price. Then the procurement official purchases from the lowest-priced supplier, and that supplier receives a price equal to his bid. Under the crucial assumption bids depend on the associated costs that the suppliers are all risk neutral, the pure-strategy symmetric Nash equilibrium calls for a supplier to submit a price according to the following function of his realized cost and the number of potential suppliers (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Vickrey 1961)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">b i c i = c H + n − 1 c i n</formula><p>This bidding strategy has an interesting behavioral interpretation; a supplier's bid is equal to the expected second-lowest realized cost conditional on his cost being the lowest. Thus, the unconditional expected winning price is the amount that the unconditional lowest expected cost type bids. One can show that this is just the unconditional expected value of the second-lowest realized cost, same as the expected auction price in the EA. This is an example of the revenue equivalence theorem 4 and forms our first hypothesis.</p><p>Hypothesis 1. The expected prices in the FPA and the EA are the same. Let us consider an example with three suppliers whose costs are independent and uniformly distributed on the interval 0 20 . In this case the expected value of the lowest, second-lowest, and highest costs are 5, 10, and 15, respectively. Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> depicts the expected outcomes in both auction formats. In the EA, the winner's expected cost is five. Furthermore, the expected second-lowest cost, and the corresponding auction price, is 10. In the FPA, we expect the winning supplier's cost is also 5 and for him to bid 10, the expected second-lowest cost conditional upon 5 being the lowest.</p><p>Of course, although the expected-or averageprices are the same, the distributions of prices are not. In the EA it is easy to see that the actual winning price can occur anywhere on the interval 0 20 . At the same time, Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> shows that the support of possible prices in the FPA is smaller. The lower end of this support occurs when a supplier's cost is 0 and he bids 6 2 3 . The upper end of this support occurs when the lowest supplier's cost is 20 and he bids 20. Thus the distribution of prices in the EA is a mean preserving spread of the prices in the FPA. In fact, <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Vickrey (1961)</ref> shows that with independent and uniformly distributed costs and n bidders, the variance of the price in the EA is</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">2 n − 1 c H − c L 2 / n + 2 n + 1 2</formula><p>and in the FPA is n − 1 c H − c L 2 / n n + 2 n + 1 2 . So the variance in the EA price is greater than that of the FPA by a factor of 2n / n − 1 ; this is our second hypothesis.</p><p>Hypothesis 2. The variance of price in the EA is greater than in the FPA.</p><p>Next we formulate an alternative hypothesis by setting aside the assumption that suppliers are risk neutral, and instead, we assume that they are risk averse. Because risk neutrality is a necessary condition for revenue equivalence, we should now be able to order the expected price in the two auctions. First, in the EA, because it has a weakly dominant strategy, risk aversion does not affect suppliers' predicted behavior or the expected price. This is not true for the FPA. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Holt (1980)</ref> shows that if all suppliers have the same risk-averse, von Neumann-Morgenstern expected utility function, then there exists a symmetric Nash equilibrium in which the expected price is lower than that of the EA. Consequently, we have the following alternative to Hypothesis 1.</p><p>Hypothesis 3. The expected or average price in the FPA will be lower than in the EA.</p><p>Note that replacing the assumption of risk neutrality does not change the hypothesis regarding ranking of price variances.</p><p>So far, we have only considered the procuring organization's welfare-price in this case-but what about the suppliers? First, under the assumption of risk neutrality, the expected profit is the same in both the EA and the FPA. This is the expected lowest cost less the expected second-lowest cost multiplied by the probability of being the lowest-cost supplier. In our example, this is $1.67. However, the difference is the variance of a supplier's payoff (profit) is much higher than for the price. The variances for a supplier's profit</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">in the EA is n c H − c L 2 / n − 2 n + 1 2 and in the FPA is c H − c L 2 / n n + 2 n + 1 2</formula><p>; the difference is a factor of n 2 . We summarize these observations with the following pair of hypotheses.</p><p>Hypothesis 4. The expected profit of a supplier in the FPA and the EA is the same.</p><p>Hypothesis 5. The variance of a supplier's profit in the EA is greater than in the FPA.</p><p>Once again, replacing the assumption of supplier risk neutrality with risk aversion gives us an alternative hypothesis to equal expected supplier profit. Hypothesis 6. The expected profit of a supplier is lower in the FPA than in the EA. Note. This figure illustrates that although the expected prices are the same, the distribution of prices differs for the EA and FPA.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Experimental Design and Procedures</head><p>All experimental sessions were conducted at the Economics Laboratory at the University of California, San Diego (UCSD) and at the National University of Singapore (NUS) School of Business. All participants were either undergraduates or master's students at one of the two universities. FPA and EA sessions were conducted at both facilities. The number of participants in an experimental session consisted of some multiple of 3 between 9 and 18. Experimental sessions lasted no more than one hour, and subjects earned between $8 (S$12) and $60 (S$89) inclusive of a show-up fee. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> provides these and further details. We adopted the simple previous three-supplier example as the basis for our experiment. In a session, the subjects participated in series of 32 rounds of either FPAs or EAs. In each round, the subjects were randomly repartitioned into a set of triads. The first two rounds were for practice; the subjects earned no money and the data are not reported. For the remaining rounds, the participants' earnings were given in an experimental currency. The exchange rates were one experimental dollar to $0.33 (or S$0.50). In total, we conducted 720 FPAs and 360 EAs. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Each subject sat in a partition designed to ensure privacy and made decisions using a personal computer running a custom-designed software program. In the FPA, at the start of each period each subject is shown his realized private cost (a new cost was drawn each period), the period number, and the number of participants in the auction. Then he was prompted to submit a price (restricted to be between 0 and 30), but he could take as much time desired to do so. After all prices were submitted, the auction results were revealed. These results consisted of his bid, the amount of the winning bid, and his period profit. This information, along with the cumulative profit, was then entered into a display at the bottom of the computer screen for future reference. At the conclusion of the experiment, subjects were privately paid their total earnings.</p><p>The EA sessions followed the same procedures, except for the execution of the auction. The computer screen contained a display of the current auction price and a button that a subject clicked on to irreversibly exit the auction. The auction started with an initial price of $21. Then the price was decremented at the rate of 10 cents every half a second. As auction participants exited the auction, subjects could observe the decrement of the displayed number of participants remaining in the auction. At the close of the auction, the subject's cost, exit price, auction price, period profit, and cumulative profit were entered in his or her history viewing area.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Data Analysis and Performance Results</head><p>We first address the relative performance of the two alternative procurement procedures and observe that procurement costs are lower and less variable in the FPA. Furthermore, the empirical distribution of EA prices first-order stochastically dominates that of the FPA. For suppliers, average profits are higher but, at the same time, more variable in the EA. We start by considering the distributions of realized FPA and EA prices. Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> presents the empirical cumulative distribution function (CDF) of prices for each auction types. For now, let us assume that each of the m = 720 FPA prices is an independent realization from the continuous distribution W FPA generating the empirical CDF, W FPA , and that each of the n = 360 EA prices is an independent realization from the continuous distribution W EA generating the empirical CDF, W EA . We test the hypothesis that these two distributions are equal, versus the alternative that are not, with the Kolmogorov-Smirnov two-sample test. The test statistic isS max p = W FPA p − W EA p = 0 372 and has a p-value of essentially 0. The hypothesis test clearly rejects the underlying distributions of auction prices are the same. Casual inspection of Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> also suggests that W EA first-order stochastically dominates W FPA ; in other words, for every p, W EA p ≤ W FPA p . We use the <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Barrett and Donald (2003)</ref> test to evaluate this hypothesis versus the alternative that for some p,</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">W EA p &gt; W FPA p . The test statistic is S = mn m + n 1/2 W FPA p − W EA p = 0 002</formula><p>The p-value of this test statistic is greater than 0.999, which leads us to not reject the hypothesis of first-order stochastic dominance. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Under the firstorder stochastic dominance criteria in decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">(Seshadri et al. 1991</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">, Levy 1992</ref>, the EA more strongly favors the suppliers rather than the procurement official.</p><p>Result 1. Procurement prices in the EA first-order stochastically dominate those in the FPA.</p><p>The FPA delivers lower average price and lower price variability to the procurement official. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> presents the means and variances of the two price distributions and the differences in these values. The first column shows the mean, the standard error of the mean, and the percentage difference in means. Twotailed t-tests reject that the EA mean price (5% level of significance) and the FPA mean price (1% level of significance) are equal to the risk-neutral Nash equilibrium prediction of 10. Moreover, we reject that the mean prices are the same in favor of the hypothesis that the FPA mean price is lower by conducting a t-test for unequal variances (1% level of significance). <ref type="bibr">6</ref> The p-value of this test statistic is calculated as exp 2S 2 . Result 2. Procurement prices are lower-25.5%, in fact-for the FPA. We reject Hypothesis 1 in favor of its alternative, Hypothesis 3.</p><p>In the second column, we report information for the variance of prices. Under the risk-neutral Nash equilibrium bidding models, the variance of the prices in the EA and FPA are 20 and 6 2 3 , respectively. We give the sample variances, and beneath those, we give bootstraps of the 95% confidence intervals of the variance under Nash equilibrium. We cannot reject that the variance is equal to the predicted value in the EA, but we do reject this for the FPA, as the estimated variance is well above the confidence interval. When comparing the variances, we reject the hypothesis that they are the same in favor of the hypothesis that the EA price has greater variance (Levin F -tests for heterogeneous variances at the 1% level of significance). However, the price variance in the EA is only twice as large (i.e., the −50 4% change noted in the table <ref type="table">)</ref>, not triple as predicted by Nash equilibrium. Thus, unless a procurement organization is very risk loving, the lower average price and lower price variability make the FPA the better method in the commodity situation.</p><p>What about the welfare of the suppliers? As we see in the third column, we cannot reject (t-test at 1% level of significance) that the mean supplier profit in the EA is equal to the theoretical value of 1.67. The average supplier profit in the FPA is 46.3% lower, and we reject these profits are the same as the risk-neutral Nash equilibrium prediction and the empirical mean of the average profit in the EA experiments (both at the 1% level of significance). Although suppliers actually do better, on average, in the EA, the variability of the payoffs are about two-and-a-half times more volatile.</p><p>Result 4. Supplier's profits are higher in the EA rather than the FPA, and we reject Hypothesis 4 in favor of its alternative, Hypothesis 6. And we also find that these profits have greater variance in the EA as well, confirming Hypothesis 5.</p><p>The relative performances of the two procurements methods are most consistent with the risk-averse Nash equilibrium model. However, it is natural to ask how robust these results are to other types of procurement environments. Recall that the Nash equilibrium model with risk-averse bidders is formulated as a description of individual-level behavior. So a likely necessary condition for the generalization of our results on performance is that the model explains what happens at the individual level as well.</p><p>As noted earlier, risk aversion does not affect the weakly dominant strategy in the EA. Accordingly, we should observe those who exit an auction to do so at their true costs. Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref> plots sellers' exit prices Auction price Second-highest cost R 2 = 0.9341 versus their realized costs. Whereas much of the data adhere closely to the 45 line as expected, there is a surprising amount that does not. Much of these occurrences are at high cost levels, and the seller opts out as soon as the auction opens at the price of $21. Perhaps such a bidder is frustrated by receiving a high cost? It is a different story for the observed exit prices below cost. In most of these cases, the errant subject remains in the auction while there are still two other remaining suppliers. Then, as soon as one of the other suppliers exits, this individual exits as well.</p><p>We filter these likely nonsalient observations to see how price-determining bids depend on the associated costs. In Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref>, we plot the realized auction price versus the second-to-exit participant's realized cost.</p><p>Here, we see much crisper conformity with the 45 line. To quantify this we present an ordinary least squares (OLS) fitted trend line through the origin. The slope coefficient is essentially 1, and this regression explains more than 93% of the variation as indicated by the R 2 statistic. Now let us turn our attention to the individual bids in the FPA sessions. Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref> plots the 2,160 submitted  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>325</head><p>FPA bids versus realized costs, the risk-neutral Nash equilibrium bid function, the bid equal to cost line (the 45 line), and an OLS-fitted line for the data.</p><p>Clearly, the majority of bids are above cost but below the risk-neutral Nash equilibrium bid line-just as a risk-averse Nash model predicts. However, there is also a surprising amount of bids outside (particularly above) this "cone of risk-averse bids." We proceed by conjecturing that there is significant heterogeneity in how subjects behave in the FPA. Then we formulate a model of general discrete heterogeneity in bidding strategies that accord rationality only to some bidders.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">A Model of Sophisticated and Rule-of-Thumb Bidders</head><p>The structure of the first-price auction and the uniform distribution of costs allow us to consider the special case of linear functions for both the rational and boundedly rational bidders. Consider a setting in which a supplier follows a rule r that belongs to a set of rules R = AM P M BR . Let denote a probability distribution on this set for which r is the probability a supplier is a bidder of type r. An AM, or absolute markup, bidder always demands a fixed profit amount independent of his costs. In other words, AM bidders price according to</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">b AM c i = c i +</formula><p>where is the fixed absolute markup. A P M, or proportional markup, bidder always demands a fixed percentage margin based on realized costs. His bidding rule is b P M c i = 1 + c i where is the proportional markup. A BR, or strategic best-response, bidder selects a price that maximizes his expected utility conditional on the parameters , , and and his realized cost. When a BR bidder formulates his bidding strategy, it is assumed that he knows the parameters , , and . Also, we assume he has the von Neumann-Morgenstern expected utility function U y = y 1/ , where y is a nonnegative change in wealth. In the appendix we show there is a symmetric BR price rule of the form</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">b BR c i = c H + AM 1 + 1 + 1 − P M M + M − 1 M c i where M = N − 1 + 1.</formula><p>There are several interesting things to note about the BR bid function. It is linear in cost, with the slope depending only on the parameter of the expected utility function and the number of other bidders. Most surprising is that the probabilities of the absolute and percentage markup bidders, and the size of these From this general static model, we can generate several alternative models with appropriate parameter restrictions and formulations of beliefs. The Bayes Nash equilibrium model occurs when AM = P M = 0 and = 1. We can replace the equality constraint on with the appropriate inequality constraint to obtain the risk-averse Nash equilibrium model. The model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Kirchkamp and Reiss (2008)</ref> is recovered by setting P M = 0 and setting N = 2. Finally, we can obtain a level-k model by setting either AM = 1 or P M = 1. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> With respect to predicted change in performance of the FPA under this heterogeneous bidding mode, the mean and variance of the winning FPA price depends on the distribution of each supplier i's bid. This is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">Q z = Pr p i ≤ z = r∈R r F b −1 r z</formula><p>and the distribution of the winning, or minimum, bid is</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">Q 1 z = 1 − Q z N −1</formula><p>When calculating the expectation and variance of the winning FPA price, it will involve piecewise integration of this function. The boundary points of these integrals depend on the intersection points of the three bidding rules. Figure <ref type="figure">6</ref> depicts the scenario found in the subsequent data analysis. in practice, we incorporate adaptation into our model through the switching of bidding rules. We start by assuming that there is an initial portion of subjects adopting each of the three bidding rules. Then rule switching is described by a stationary Markov chain. Finally, we assume a bidder follows his adopted rule with some random noise, thus making his bidding rule a latent variable. Such a state-space model with latent states is called a hidden Markov model (HMM).</p><p>HMMs are a natural way to model dynamic decision making with hidden information. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> Consider the following dynamic process. Let z it be the rule used by subject i in period t, and let z i be the 30 element sequence of rules seller i adopts over the course of the experiment. Define r1 as the probability a seller follows rule r in period 1, let 1 be the multinomial probability distribution these initial probabilities constitute, and let A be the matrix of transition probabilities with element a sr . In other words, this is the probability that a subject who uses rule s in period t − 1 transitions to rule r in the subsequent period, a sr = Pr z it = r z it−1 = s . Also, denote rt as the proportion of the subjects who are using rule r in period t. And finally, let rt be the period t probability a randomly selected subject is using rule r, which is rt = s∈R st−1 a sr A key element of our HMM is that subjects follow rules imprecisely, resulting in an unbiased random perturbation to each submitted bid. In particular, we assume that when a subject follows rule r, the price he submits is an independent random variable that follows a normal distribution G with mean b r c it and rule-specific variance 2 r . The probability densities of the three bidding rules are</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">h AM p it c it = G c it + 2 AM h P M p it c it = G 1 + c it 2 P M and h BR p it c it t = G c H + AMt 1 + 1 + 1 − P Mt M + M − 1 M c it 2 BR</formula><p>The set of parameters of this model is = M B , where M is the set of variables governing the stochastic process of rule adoption, 1 A , and B is the set of parameters that determine the bidding rules, r . The likelihood of subject i's</p><p>8 For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Netzer et al. (2008)</ref> study the relationships between charitable donors and institutions, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Hui et al. (2009)</ref> present an HMM framework for general forms of path data over time. However, ours is the first example we know of that defines the state space as the strategies within a multiperson interaction and the Harrovian adjustments as an adaptive learning process.</p><p>sequence of prices conditional on the parameters and the realization of z i is</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">L i p i1 p i30 z i = 30 t=1</formula><p>h z it p it c it and the likelihood of z i conditional on B is</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">L i z i M = z i1 30 t=2 a z it−1 z it</formula><p>We can express the likelihood of the joint sequences of bids and bidding rule adoption as</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">L i p i1 p i30 z i = L i p i1 p i30 z i L i z i M</formula><p>However, because the realized sequence of states is not observable, we need to integrate out the marginal likelihood of z i by summing over all possible sequences of rule adoption:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">L i p i1 p i30 = z i ∈Z L i p i1 p i30 z i L i z i M</formula><p>Finally, the likelihood for the whole sample is</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">L X = 72 i=1 z i ∈Z L i p i1 p i30 z i L i z i M (1)</formula><p>A common way to find the parameter values that maximize Equation ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>) is to use the Baum-Welch algorithm, which is a special case of the EM algorithm. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> The output of this algorithm provides posterior modes of M , an estimated most likely patĥ z i for each subject, and maximum likelihood estimates of B .</p><p>One issue remains that prevents us from estimating the model as specified; the intercept term of strategic bidding rule depends on the distribution over types and thus is a function of the parameters in M . To address this issue, we change the specification of b BR to a fixed-effect model:</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">b BR c it = 30 d=1 I d=t t + M − 1 M c it where M = N − 1 + 1 (<label>2</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_15">)</formula><p>and I is an indicator function. We call this specification HMM with fixed effects specifications (HMM FE hereafter). Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref> presents the maximum likelihood estimates of the parameters of each of the three bidding rules. Note that all parameter estimates are significant. For the AM rule, we see the estimated markup is a mere Note. The dash for t-statistic indicates that this parameter is constrained and is the given value by the model.</p><p>80 cents, which suggests quite aggressive bidding to win the FPA. On the other hand, for the P M rule the estimated markup is 30% over costs, which is consistent with bidding aggressively for a large reward from winning the auction. The standard error for this rule is much higher than the standard errors of the other two rules, symptomatic of possible heterogeneity in the percentage markup across subjects. For the BR bidding rule, the inferred value of is 1.84, which yields a constant coefficient of relative risk aversion of 0.56-consistent with the estimates from other studies of private value first-price sealed-bid auctions. 10 After estimating the HMM FE, we calculate the theoretical values of the intercept of b BR for each period t based on the maximum likelihood estimates of the markups and the proportions of subjects estimated to be using each rule in period t according to theẑ i . Then we compare these theoretical calculated intercepts to the estimated dummy variables. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">7</ref> presents a comparison of these estimated fixed effects versus the theoretical values of the BR rule intercepts. Visual inspection reveals that the theoretical value of the intercept varies little over time and that the dummy variable model also does not vary a lot. In fact, only three of the fixed effects are significantly different than the mean effect, suggesting that there is little dramatic movement in the use of different rules over time. We now examine this more explicitly.</p><p>The posterior mode estimates of the transition probabilities reveal three surprising results: (1) there is inertia in rule adoption, (2) subjects only switch between the sophisticated rule and a rule of thumbor vice versa-but never switch between the two simple rules of thumb, and (3) overall subject sophistication decreases over time. The estimated initial distribution over the rules isˆ 1 = ˆ AM1 ˆ P M1 ˆ BR1 = 0 12 0 14 0 74 , and the estimated matrix of transition probabilitiesÂ is given in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">4</ref>. The strong inertia in the rules subjects follows from the high estimated continuation probabilities that range from 78% to 88%. The estimated transition matrix also indicates that there is no switching between the two simple <ref type="bibr">10</ref> For example, consider some other estimates of constant coefficient of relative risk aversion of 0.67, 0.52, 0.48, and 0.57, respectively, from <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Cox and Oaxaca (1996)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Goeree et al. (2002)</ref>  While it is not surprising that subjects switch from simple markup price rules to the more strategically sophisticated strategy, it is surprising that there are subjects who switch from the BR rule to simple markup strategies. In these cases, it is mostly the absolute markup rule that is switched to. Why would someone make such a switch? A natural conjecture is that estimated AM rule has a small markup and that following that rule will lead to more frequent wins in the auction. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> The dynamics of the estimated model suggest that the rule adjustments mostly occur early in the experiment and involve a decaying proportion of sophisticated sellers. In Figure <ref type="figure">8</ref>, we present the sequence of estimated proportions of subjects for each period in time, rt . Notable here is that initially 76% of the subjects are estimated to be using a strategic bestresponse strategy, but that proportion over the course of 30 auctions falls to 64%. Meanwhile, we see an accordingly strong increase in the proportion of AM bidders from 11% to 29%, and the percentage of P M bidders falls from 13% to 9%. In this estimated ruleswitching model, would the subjects learn to be more sophisticated in a much longer sequence of auctions? Actually, the prospect of further learning is not strong. The limiting distribution of the matrix of transition probabilities is = 0 28 0 10 0 62 . Inspection of Figure <ref type="figure">8</ref> shows that the experiment has already converged close to these values.</p><p>Does this estimated model explain the deviations of price performance from the predictions of the riskneutral Nash equilibrium model? The sample mean has a small but statistically significant negative time trend, and the sample variance appears to have a   negative time trend but is not significant. Figure <ref type="figure">9</ref> depicts the theoretical mean and variance calculated using the estimated rule-switching model parameters as well as the empirical measurements of price mean and variance. Visual inspection suggests that the ruleswitching model qualitatively captures the values and trend, and we find this encouraging. However, regressions of the observed averages on the theoretical predictions are not significant-although the coefficients are close to one in both cases. For this experiment the time variance of price average and variance dynamics adjust too little over time to provide a dynamic model a strong opportunity to explain, or fail to explain, these dynamics. There is a plan to run future experiments that we hope will create such an opportunity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.">Specification Test of the Dynamic Rule-Switching HMM</head><p>Our HMM framework provides a behaviorally intuitive formulation and a tractable extension to both strategic heterogeneity and learning in FPAs, and it can be estimated with well-developed econometric tools. Furthermore, the insights it provides into bidding behavior, the mixture of strategic/heuristic bidders, and the learning to be unsophisticated are thought provoking and could reorient the direction of behavioral game-theoretic models of auctions. These successes, however, are predicated on the HMM FE being a better specification than other existing alternative models. In this penultimate section, we report on a series of specification hypothesis tests in which we evaluate the HMM FE against an assortment of alternative models. The first set of alternative specifications we consider is a variety of static models that are nested within the HMM FE; appropriate restrictions to parameters in the HMM FE yield each of the alternative models. Each of these static models requires that the Markov transition matrix be restricted to the identity matrix, whose size equals the number of bidding rules in the alternative. We evaluate the following homogeneous static models: linear bidding, a Nash equilibrium bidding rule (linear bidding with the restriction that the highest-cost-type demands zero profit), P M, and AM. Each of these models is estimated by maximum likelihood and the results reported in columns 2-5 of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">5</ref>. For each of the rules, we report estimates of the appropriate intercepts, coefficients, and standard deviations of errors in terms of our HMM parameter labels. We also report the number of free parameters of the model in the row labeled "Parameter count." For evaluating specifications, in the last three rows we report the loglikelihood value of the estimated model, the Akaike information criteria (AIC), and the likelihood ratio test statistic along with the result of the hypothesis test that the restricted model is true versus the unrestricted HMM FE. For reference, we provide the relevant results of the estimated HMM FE in the last column. Clearly, the likelihood ratio test soundly rejects each of the homogeneous static models we consider, which is confirmed by the relative ranking of the AIC values.</p><p>Next we consider a subset of nondegenerate static mixture models that are a special case of the HMM FE. In particular, we consider the mixture of P M&amp;BR, the mixture of AM&amp;BR (this is the Kirchkamp and Reiss 2008 model for multiple bidders), and the full mixture of all three models. In addition to the previous pointed-out parameter estimates, we also report the estimated mixture probabilities that in the case of the HMM FE are the initial probabilities, 1 . Each of the static mixture models is estimated by the EM algorithm. Here, we once again soundly reject each static mixture model in favor of the dynamic HMM FE in both likelihood ratio tests and in AIC comparison.</p><p>The level-k model of Crawford and Iriberri ( <ref type="formula">2007</ref>) is an obvious alternative model for comparison. In the static formulation, the HMM FE and level-k model follow a similar approach; however, several key differences should be raised before making this comparison. First, if one uses Crawford and Iriberri's specified k = 0 rules in our setting, then the corresponding k = 1 strategies are simply the Nash equilibrium ones. 12 To avoid making this comparison trivial, we adopt the AM and P M as the k = 0 rules. Second, there are two k = 1 types: BR P M , who believes with probability 1 the other bidders follow the P M rule; and BR AM , who believes with probability 1 the other bidders follow the AM rule. This is in contrast to the HMM FE in which the BR bidders form accurate beliefs regarding the distribution over the bidding rules at each point in time. A consequence of having two k = 1 types is that neither the level-k model nor the HMM FE nests the other. Third, the level-k model is a formulation of how individuals initially bid in an FPA. Correspondingly, we introduce an additional model that expands the scope of the level-k model by incorporating an exogenous firstorder Markov rule-switching process; we call this the level-k Markov model. This will allow us to separate differences in model performance that relate to the bidding rule structure and subjects' beliefs from those that relate to adaptation through rule switching.</p><p>The Baum-Welch algorithm estimates of the relevant level-k and level-k Markov model parameters and other statistical measures are presented in the first two columns of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">6</ref>. Because we cannot apply a likelihood ratio for model specification, we report the values of the Bayesian information criteria (BIC). The estimation results for our version of the static level-k are strikingly similar to those of <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Crawford and Iriberri (2007)</ref>. We find our estimated P M rule has a markup of = 0, which collapses to their bid-yourcost type k = 0. Also, we find that no subjects follow the P M rule nor the best response to our AM rule BR AM . The subjects are roughly divided between the AM rule and the best response to P M (which is the Nash bidding strategy). However, the model performs poorly against the HMM FE when comparing the respective AIC and BIC values. When we allow rule switching in the level-k Markov model, we observe a sharp increase in the log-likelihood value, and the parameter estimates move toward those in our HMM models. But we can see this model specification still fares poorly with respect to our HMM FE in both the AIC and BIC.</p><p>Finally, we consider dynamic mixture specifications that are nested within the HMM FE. We consider three such models: an HMM with BR&amp;P M, an HMM  with BR&amp;AM, and an HMM with all three bidding rules. Both HMM models with only two bidding rules are strongly rejected by the likelihood ratio test.</p><p>On the other hand, the pure HMM is only rejected at the 10% level of significance by the likelihood ratio test. This is not surprising, as we reported earlier that only 3 of the 29 effects were statistically significant. However, we still believe the HMM FE retains value as it allows the BR rule to track changes in the relative proportions at which bidders adopt the differing bidding rules. In conclusion, the battery of specification test suggests that the HMM and HMM FE approaches are a strong improvement in the explanations of heterogeneity and learning in FPAs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9.">Discussion</head><p>The insights of this study should prove valuable to both the procurement practitioner and the researcher interested in behavioral models of bidding in auctions. Our experiments provide a clear demonstration of the relative performance of the FPA versus the EA in a commodity procurement setting. In light of these results, any procurement organization should proceed cautiously when initiating a new auction strategy for the purchase of commodities. From the procurement organization's perspective, EAs not only deliver higher expected prices but also greater price variability. It is worth noting that increased price variability may have a negative impact beyond a procurement organization's distaste of increased price uncertainty.</p><p>Recent studies, such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Jap (2007)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Jap and Haruvy (2008)</ref>, document that the relationship between the supplier and buyer is negatively impacted by the adoption of the EA. The documented increase in price variance could be a partial source of this increased animosity. Despite this negative result, we can offer some thoughts regarding when changing from an FPA to an EA might be successful. In this study we make several strong assumptions, and relaxing any of these could lead to different outcomes. For example, we assume suppliers independently draw costs from the same distribution. However, a likely scenario is that one supplier has a clear advantage in location and a likely lower cost; in this case it is not clear which auction format is better. Theoretical studies, such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Maskin and Riley (2000)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Cantillon (2008)</ref>, suggest that whether an EA will lead to a lower expected price depends crucially on the distributions of costs. One area where EA-like auctions show promise is in the procurement of goods for which price is not the sole differentiating attribute between suppliers. Researchers have studied two cases: when nonprice attributes are exogenous and when these attributes are endogenously determined within the auction. In the first case, Engelbrecht-Wiggans and Katok (2007) find significant gains to the procurement official when suppliers bid on price, and then the buyer chooses the winner (as opposed to awarding the contract to the lowest bidder). The performance of the buyer determined winner EA versus the FPA in these settings is studied in <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Haruvy and Katok (2008)</ref>, and they find the FPA is better if suppliers have accurate and precise information regarding the quality of other sellers. On the other hand, <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Shachat and Swarthout (2010)</ref> find that an EA with buyer-assigned bidding credits can provide better outcomes than the FPA for both the buyer and the suppliers. For the latter case, there is also a large and promising literature on successful dynamic reverse auction examples where the quality is determined within multiattribute versions of the EA-for example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Chen-Ritzo et al. (2005)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Parkes and Kalagnanam (2005)</ref>.</p><p>Our HMM of sophisticated and rule-of-thumb bidders both answers some questions and raises others. Our results provide strong evidence for discrete heterogeneous bidding behavior, and the procurement setting has allowed for easy identification of some bidding rules of thumb. Furthermore, we make a significant advancement in the learning of bidding behavior through the introduction of a rule-switching dynamic. Somewhat disconcerting is the conclusion that individuals unlearn strategic sophistication as they gain experience. Clearly, a next step is to generalize the transition probabilities from being purely exogenous to being functions of the subjects' experiences. There must be something in the way participants cognitively process feedback that leads them from the expected utility-maximizing strategy. One conjecture we find attractive is that subjects more strongly react to whether they win or lose when following a particular strategy than they do to the full opportunity costs of following alternative strategies. To test such a conjecture, as well as others, one would need experimental sessions with many more repetitions to obtain significant estimates on transition probability covariates. Another direction of inquiry is to ask whether the simple bidding heuristics we observe also hold in the forward auction case. The experiments and subsequent analysis in <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Kirchkamp and Reiss (2008)</ref> suggest that they do, particularly the absolute markup strategy. But to identify the percentage markup strategy, experiments need to be run for which the number of auction participants is a withinsubject treatment variable. Finally, an important question is whether one can use a model like ours in a structural econometric estimation to recover individual parameters and improve upon approaches that assume pure Nash equilibrium play.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Nash Equilibrium Bidding Behavior</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2Empirical Cumulative Distribution Functions of FPA and EA Prices</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3Exit Price vs. Cost in the EA</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure5FPA Submitted Bid vs. Cost</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 6Crossing Pattern of Bidding Functions</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, Chen and Plott (1998), and Berg et al. (2005).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 7</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7Theoretical Values of the BR Rule Intercept Over Time and Estimated Fixed Effects of the BR Rule</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 8The Estimated Sequence of Proportions of Subjects Using the Three Rules</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Summary of Experimental Sessions</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>No. of</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Minimum Maximum</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">Session Treatment Location subjects Rounds earnings earnings</cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell>FPA</cell><cell>UCSD</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>32</cell><cell>16 72</cell><cell>52 62</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>FPA</cell><cell>UCSD</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>32</cell><cell>11 00</cell><cell>58 98</cell></row><row><cell>3</cell><cell>FPA</cell><cell>UCSD</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>32</cell><cell>13 23</cell><cell>42 45</cell></row><row><cell>4</cell><cell>FPA</cell><cell>NUS</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>32</cell><cell>23 24</cell><cell>48 94</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell>FPA</cell><cell>NUS</cell><cell>18</cell><cell>32</cell><cell>21 60</cell><cell>55 72</cell></row><row><cell>6</cell><cell>EA</cell><cell>UCSD</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>32</cell><cell>7 05</cell><cell>62 70</cell></row><row><cell>7</cell><cell>EA</cell><cell>NUS</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>32</cell><cell>30 78</cell><cell>87 84</cell></row><row><cell>8</cell><cell>EA</cell><cell>NUS</cell><cell>18</cell><cell>32</cell><cell>32 84</cell><cell>88 74</cell></row></table><note>Notes. Earnings are US$ for UCSD sessions and S$ for NUS sessions; the exchange rate at the time of the sessions was approximately US$1 = S$1.5. The show-up fee was US$5 at UCSD and S$10 at NUS.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Summary Statistics on Prices and Profits Price variance is greater in the EA than the FPA. Our experimental results are consistent with Hypothesis 2.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>Variance</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>Price</cell><cell>supplier</cell><cell>supplier</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>price</cell><cell>variance</cell><cell>profit</cell><cell>profit</cell></row><row><cell>EA</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Observed</cell><cell>10 60</cell><cell>19 11</cell><cell>1 68</cell><cell>10 67</cell></row><row><cell>Theoretical</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>20</cell><cell>1 67</cell><cell>15 03</cell></row><row><cell>Std. error or CI</cell><cell>0 230</cell><cell>[18 47 21 61]</cell><cell>0 099</cell><cell>[12 79 17 14]</cell></row><row><cell>FPA</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Observed</cell><cell>7 90</cell><cell>9 63</cell><cell>0 90</cell><cell>3 04</cell></row><row><cell>Theoretical</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>10 67</cell><cell>1 67</cell><cell>1 67</cell></row><row><cell>Std. error or CI</cell><cell>0 116</cell><cell>[5 63 7 69]</cell><cell>0 037</cell><cell>[1 50 1 84]</cell></row><row><cell>% Difference</cell><cell>−25.5</cell><cell>−50.4</cell><cell>−46.3</cell><cell>−71.5</cell></row></table><note>Notes. Because the distribution of prices under Nash equilibrium is not normal, simple t-tests of the estimated variances are not valid. Accordingly, we construct 95% confidence intervals (CIs) by bootstrap with 10,000 draws from the known distribution.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Shachat and Wei: Procuring Commodities    </figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science 31(2), pp. 317-333, © 2012 INFORMS</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Estimates of Bidding Rule Parameters in the HMM FE</figDesc><table><row><cell>Model</cell><cell>Intercept</cell><cell>t-Statistic</cell><cell>Slope</cell><cell>t-Statistic</cell><cell>2 r</cell></row><row><cell>AM</cell><cell>0 80</cell><cell>37 36</cell><cell>1 00</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0 50</cell></row><row><cell>P M</cell><cell>0 00</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>1 30</cell><cell>10 93</cell><cell>5 27</cell></row><row><cell>BR</cell><cell>4 43</cell><cell>25 59</cell><cell>0 79</cell><cell>35 54</cell><cell>1 30</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Posterior Mode Estimates of Rule-Switching Probabilities</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Specification Tests of the HMM FE with Respect to Alternative Static Pure and Mixture Models</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Restricted</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Linear</cell><cell>linear model</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Mixture</cell><cell>Mixture</cell><cell>Full</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>model</cell><cell>b BR 20 = 20</cell><cell>Pure P M</cell><cell>Pure AM</cell><cell>P M&amp;BR</cell><cell>AM&amp;BR</cell><cell>mixture</cell><cell>HMM FE</cell></row><row><cell>Intercept</cell><cell>4 04</cell><cell>4 30</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>3 78</cell><cell>3 79</cell><cell>4 40</cell><cell>4 71</cell></row><row><cell>Cost</cell><cell>0 83</cell><cell>0 79</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0 82</cell><cell>0 82</cell><cell>0 79</cell><cell>0 79</cell></row><row><cell>BR</cell><cell>2 14</cell><cell>2 15</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>1 44</cell><cell>1 40</cell><cell>1 49</cell><cell>1 30</cell></row><row><cell>1 +</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>1 13</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>1 23</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>1 23</cell><cell>1 30</cell></row><row><cell>P M</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>2 96</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>4 38</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>4 44</cell><cell>5 20</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>2 31</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>3 52</cell><cell>1 16</cell><cell>0 82</cell></row><row><cell>AM</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>2 37</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>3 49</cell><cell>0 98</cell><cell>0 50</cell></row><row><cell>BR1</cell><cell>1 00 a</cell><cell>1 00 a</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0 81</cell><cell>0 78</cell><cell>0 61</cell><cell>0 74</cell></row><row><cell>P M1</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>1 00 a</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0 19</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0 18</cell><cell>0 14</cell></row><row><cell>AM1</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>1 00 a</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0 22</cell><cell>0 21</cell><cell>0 12</cell></row><row><cell>Parameter count</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>44</cell></row><row><cell>Log-likelihood</cell><cell>−4 704</cell><cell>−4 720</cell><cell>−5 404</cell><cell>−4 923</cell><cell>−4 359</cell><cell>−4 275</cell><cell>−4 231</cell><cell>−3 943</cell></row><row><cell>AIC</cell><cell>9,414</cell><cell>9,445</cell><cell>10,811</cell><cell>9,850</cell><cell>8,731</cell><cell>8,561</cell><cell>8,480</cell><cell>7,974</cell></row><row><cell>LRT: model vs. HMM FE</cell><cell>1,522  *  *  *</cell><cell>1,556  *  *  *</cell><cell>2,921  *  *  *</cell><cell>1,960  *  *  *</cell><cell>832  *  *  *</cell><cell>663  *  *  *</cell><cell>576  *  *  *</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Note. LRT, likelihood ratio test.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>a Indicates a value that is set by model constraint and not estimated. * * * Statistically significant at the 1% level; * * statistically significant at the 5% level; * statistically significant at the 10% level.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Specification Tests of the HMM FE with Respect to Level-k and Alternative Dynamic Mixture Models</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Level-k</cell><cell cols="2">Level-k Markov</cell><cell>HMM</cell><cell>HMM</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>BR P M</cell><cell>BR AM</cell><cell>BR P M</cell><cell>BR AM</cell><cell>BR&amp;P M</cell><cell>BR&amp;AM</cell><cell>HMM</cell><cell>HMM FE</cell></row><row><cell>Intercept</cell><cell>6 67 a</cell><cell>7 19</cell><cell>8 61</cell><cell>7 08</cell><cell>3 93</cell><cell>3 61</cell><cell>4 44</cell><cell>4 71</cell></row><row><cell>Cost</cell><cell>0 67 a</cell><cell>0 67 a</cell><cell>0 67 a</cell><cell>0 67 a</cell><cell>0 83</cell><cell>0 84</cell><cell>0 79</cell><cell>0 79</cell></row><row><cell>BR</cell><cell>2 66</cell><cell>0 76</cell><cell>5 21</cell><cell>1 74</cell><cell>1 19</cell><cell>1 04</cell><cell>1 30</cell><cell>1 30</cell></row><row><cell>1 +</cell><cell>1.00</cell><cell></cell><cell>1.29</cell><cell></cell><cell>1 28</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>1 29</cell><cell>1 30</cell></row><row><cell>P M</cell><cell>0.82</cell><cell></cell><cell>1.57</cell><cell></cell><cell>4 99</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>5 13</cell><cell>5 20</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>1.57</cell><cell></cell><cell>1.24</cell><cell></cell><cell>-</cell><cell>4 28</cell><cell>0 81</cell><cell>0 82</cell></row><row><cell>AM</cell><cell>1.33</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.94</cell><cell></cell><cell>-</cell><cell>3 44</cell><cell>0 50</cell><cell>0 50</cell></row><row><cell>BR1</cell><cell>0 54</cell><cell>0 00</cell><cell>0 09</cell><cell>0 35</cell><cell>0 79</cell><cell>0 71</cell><cell>0 73</cell><cell>0 74</cell></row><row><cell>P M1</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.09</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 21</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0 17</cell><cell>0 14</cell></row><row><cell>AM1</cell><cell>0.46</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.47</cell><cell></cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0 29</cell><cell>0 10</cell><cell>0 12</cell></row><row><cell>Parameter count</cell><cell>11</cell><cell></cell><cell>23</cell><cell></cell><cell>8</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>44</cell></row><row><cell>Log-likelihood</cell><cell cols="2">−4 538</cell><cell cols="2">−4 224</cell><cell>−4 182</cell><cell>−4 061</cell><cell>−3 964</cell><cell>−3 943</cell></row><row><cell>AIC</cell><cell>9,094</cell><cell></cell><cell>8,491</cell><cell></cell><cell>8,439</cell><cell>8,197</cell><cell>7,958</cell><cell>7,974</cell></row><row><cell>BIC</cell><cell>8,610</cell><cell></cell><cell>8,610</cell><cell></cell><cell>8,649</cell><cell>8,407</cell><cell>8,043</cell><cell>8,224</cell></row><row><cell>LRT: model vs. HMM FE</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell>478  *  *  *</cell><cell>236  *  *  *</cell><cell>42</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>* -Note. LRT, likelihood ratio test.a Indicates a value that is set by model constraint and not estimated. * * * Statistically significant at the 1% level; * * statistically significant at the 5% level; * statistically significant at the 10% level.</note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">"Independent and private" here refers to the fact suppliers' costs are independent random variables for which the realizations are private information.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">There are other formats of the EA. For example, in an open outcry format, individual suppliers can announce successively lower bids until there is no supplier willing to improve on the current existing price. The supplier submitting the last price wins the auction at that price. In the strategic analysis, optimal bidder behavior is equivalent in the open outcry format and the version we describe.3  One can find standard arguments for this weakly dominant strategy in texts such as<ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Krishna (2002)</ref>. A weakly dominant strategy in this context means that regardless of the other suppliers' strategies, there is never an instance in which the supplier can strictly increase his expected payoff by deviating from this strategy.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">The revenue equivalence theorem was first proven by<ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Vickrey (1961)</ref> and is applicable to our scenario. It was proven for a wider class of scenarios by<ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Myerson (1981)</ref>. The version used here states that if sellers are risk neutral, if they have independent and symmetric costs, and if payment is a function of the bid only, then the FPA and the EA will have the same expected price.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">We collected an unbalanced sample because the data in the EA strongly agreed with the weakly dominant bidding strategy.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">In this example, k ≥ 1 results in the same bid function, b BR .</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">For details on these two algorithms, we refer the reader to the classic presentation in<ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Rabiner (1989)</ref>.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="11">The natural way to explore hypotheses of this nature would be to model the transition probabilities as functions of the history of actions and payoffs. Unfortunately, there simply is not enough variation in the rule switching to generate estimated transitional probabilities that have covariates.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="12">When types are independent draws from identical uniform distributions, the Nash equilibrium strategy is also a best response against any linear strategy for which the bidder bids his own value for the least competitive type.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>Ernan Haruvy, J. Todd Swarthout, John Wooders, James C. Cox, Elana Katok, Mark Walker, Peter Reiss, Eric T. Bradlow, Teck Ho, and especially two anonymous referees provided helpful comments on earlier drafts of the paper. The paper has benefitted from audience members' comments in departmental seminars at Georgia State University, the University of Arizona, Xiamen University, Shanghai University of Finance and Economics, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, and others. The authors thank the University of California, San Diego, and the National University of Singapore for allowing them to conduct experiments in their facilities. For financial support, they also thank Xiamen University and the Fujian Province High Talent Program. The authors also acknowledge the IBM T. J. Watson Research Lab for financial support and use of their software.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix. Derivation of the Best-Response Bidding Rule</head><p>Here, we derive the best response (BR) bidding rule assuming the multinomial distribution function over the set of bidding rules R = AM P M BR . For now, let us assume that a BR bidder prices according to a strictly increasing bounded function, thus having an inverse, denoted as b BR c i . When a BR bidder formulates his bidding strategy, it is assumed that he knows the parameters , , and . Also assume that he also has the von Neumann-Morgenstern expected utility function U y = y 1 , where y is a nonnegative change in wealth. If the BR wins the forward auction, his award is his value minus his bid; otherwise, there is no award. The BR bidder's expected utility is the utility of his profit times the probability of winning the FPA, i.e., the probability his bid is lower than all other bids. This probability is</p><p>As each of the three bidding rules has an inverse, we can restate this probability as</p><p>where F denotes the uniform distribution. In an FPA with N − 1 other suppliers, the probability of winning with a submitted price p j is Pr p j &lt; p</p><p>Thus the expected utility of a bid p j conditional on realized value c j is</p><p>The first-order condition of maximizing expected utility with respect to the bid price is</p><p>Now if one assumes that all the BR bidders are using the same bid function, the above expression reduces to the following differential equation:</p><p>Shachat and Wei: Procuring Commodities </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring risk aversion in a nameyour-own-price channel</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Abbas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I.-H</forename><surname>Hann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decision Anal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="123" to="136" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Star-shaped probability weighting functions and overbidding in first-price auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Armantier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Treich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="85" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subjective probabilities in games: An application to the overbidding puzzle</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Armantier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Treich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1079" to="1102" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Are structural estimates of auction models reasonable? Evidence from experimental data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bajari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hortacsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="703" to="741" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consistent tests for stochastic dominance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Donald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="104" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk preference instability across institutions: A dilemma</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Berg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dickhaut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Mccabe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4209" to="4214" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian estimation of bid sequences in Internet auctions using a generalized recordbreaking model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Bradlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y.-H</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="218" to="229" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shrouded attributes and information suppression: Evidence from the field. Quart</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hossain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="859" to="876" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experience-weighted attraction learning in normal form games</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T.-H</forename><surname>Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="827" to="874" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of bidders&apos; asymmetries on expected revenue in auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Cantillon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Games Econom. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="25" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reverse auctions: A supplier&apos;s survival guide</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chafkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://inc.com/inctr/2007/04/reverse-auctions-a-suppliers-survival-guide.html" />
		<editor>Inc.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-04-25" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Willingness to pay and competition in online auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Chan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kadiyali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y.-H</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="324" to="333" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonlinear behavior in sealed bid first price auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K.-Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Plott</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Games Econom. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="34" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Better, faster, cheaper: An experimental analysis of a multiattribute reverse auction mechanism with restricted information feedback</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C.-H</forename><surname>Chen-Ritzo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kwasnica</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1753" to="1762" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incentives and behavior in English, Dutch, and sealed-bid auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Coppinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Titus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is bidding behavior consistent with bidding theory for private value auctions?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Cox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Oaxaca</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Experimental Economics</title>
		<editor>R. M. Issac</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="148" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>JAI Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Theory and behavior of single object auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Cox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Roberson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Experimental Economics</title>
		<editor>V. L. Smith</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="537" to="579" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
			<publisher>JAI Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Level-k auctions: Can a nonequilibrium model of strategic thinking explain the winner&apos;s curse and overbidding in private-value auctions?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Crawford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Iriberri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1721" to="1770" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of explicit reference points on consumer choice and online bidding behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dholakia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Simonson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="206" to="217" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Loss aversion and learning to bid</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A V</forename><surname>Dittrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Guth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kocher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pezanis-Christou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economica</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-08-18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Auctions within e-sourcing events</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Elmaghraby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Production Oper. Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="409" to="422" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Regret in auctions: Theory and evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Engelbrecht-Wiggans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Katok</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="101" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Regret and feedback information in first-price sealed-bid auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Engelbrecht-Wiggans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Katok</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="808" to="819" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Partial-repeat-bidding in the name-your-own-price channel</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="407" to="418" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Auctions with anticipated regret: Theory and experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Filiz-Ozbay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ozbay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">97</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1407" to="1418" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantal response equilibrium and overbidding in private-value auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Goeree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Holt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Palfrey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="247" to="272" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonparametric identification of risk aversion in first-price auctions under exclusion restrictions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Guerre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Perrigne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Vuong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1193" to="1227" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning to bid-An experimental study of bid function adjustments in auctions and fair division games</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Guth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ivanova-Stenzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Konigstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Strobel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">487</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="477" to="494" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An experimental investigation of buyer determined procurement auctions. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Haruvy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Katok</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Pennsylvania State University, University Park</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical study of an auction with asymmetric information</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hendricks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Porter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="865" to="883" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competitive bidding for contracts under alternative auction procedures</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Holt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Jr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="433" to="445" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Plus shipping and handling: Revenue (non) equivalence in field experiments on eBay</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hossain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://works.bepress.com/john_morgan/1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Anal. Policy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Path data in marketing: An integrative framework and prospectus for model building</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Bradlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="320" to="335" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experience weighted attraction in the first price auction and Becker Degroot Marschak</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>James</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Reagle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">18th World IMACS Congress MODSIM09 Internat. Congress Modelling Simulation, Modelling and Simulation Society of Australia and New Zealand and International Association for Mathematics and Computers in Simulation</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Anderssen</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Braddock</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T H</forename><surname>Newham</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1437" to="1441" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online reverse auctions: Issues, themes, and prospects for the future</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Jap</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Acad. Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="506" to="525" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of online reverse auction design on buyer-supplier relationships</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Jap</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="159" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interorganizational relationships and bidding behavior in industrial online reverse auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Jap</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Haruvy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="550" to="561" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">BidAnalyzer: A method for estimation and selection of dynamic bidding models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Jap</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Naik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="949" to="960" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Auctions: A survey of experimental research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kagel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Handbook of Experimental Economics</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kagel</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Princeton, NJ</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="501" to="586" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Independent private value auctions: Bidder behavior in first-, second-, and third-price auctions with varying numbers of bidders</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kagel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">419</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="868" to="879" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Auctions: Experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kagel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1087/9780230226203.0072</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The New Palgrave Dictionary of Economics</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Durlauf</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Blume</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Basingstoke, Hampshire, UK.</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Palgrave McMillan</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Auctions: A survey of experimental research 1995-2008</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kagel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Handbook of Experimental Economics</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kagel</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Princeton, NJ. Forthcoming</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heterogeneous bids in auctions with rational and markdown bidders-Theory and experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Kirchkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Reiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Jena Economic Research Paper</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Friedrich-Schiller-University Jena, Max-Planck-Institute of Economics</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identification and estimation of auction models with unobserved heterogeneity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Krasnokutskaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="293" to="327" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Econometrics of first-price auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Krishna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-J</forename><surname>Laffont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ossard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Vuong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="953" to="980" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Auction Theory</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stochastic dominance and expected utility: Survey and analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="555" to="593" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using field experiments to test equivalence between auction formats: Magic on the Internet</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lucking-Reiley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1063" to="1080" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Asymmetric auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Maskin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Riley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="413" to="438" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The spite motive and equilibrium behavior in auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Steiglitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Reis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">B. E. J. Econom. Anal. Policy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal auction design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Myerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Math. Oper. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="58" to="73" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A hidden Markov model of customer relationship dynamics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Netzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lattin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="185" to="204" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bidding &quot;as if&quot; risk neutral in experimental first price auctions without information feedback</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Neugebauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Perote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Experiment. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="190" to="202" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual behavior of first-price auctions: The importance of information feedback in computerized experimental markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Neugebauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Selten</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Games Econom. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="183" to="204" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impulse balance equilibrium and feedback in first price auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ockenfels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Selten</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Games Econom. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="170" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An integrated model for bidding behavior in Internet auctions: Whether, who, when, and how much</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y.-H</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Bradlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="470" to="482" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Models for iterative multiattribute procurement auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Parkes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kalagnanam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="435" to="451" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">E-auction playbook</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Purchasing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-06-21" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="S1" to="S3" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A tutorial on hidden Markov models and selected applications in speech recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Rabiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. IEEE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="257" to="286" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experimental sealed bid first price auctions with directly observed bid functions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Selten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Buchta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Games and Human Behavior: Essays in Honor of Amon Rapoport</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Budescu</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Zwick</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Mahwah, NJ</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="79" to="102" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiple source procurement competitions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Seshadri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Chatterjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lilien</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="246" to="263" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Procurement auctions for differentiated goods</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shachat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Swarthout</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decision Anal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Counterspeculation, auctions and competitive sealed tenders</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Vickrey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Finance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8" to="37" />
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online auction demand</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Mela</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="861" to="885" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The sealed-bid abstraction in online auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Zeithammer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Adams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="964" to="987" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
