<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">New Perspectives on Customer &quot;Death&quot; Using a Generalization of the Pareto/NBD Model</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2011-06-06">June 6, 2011.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kinshuk</forename><surname>Jerath</surname></persName>
							<email>kinshuk@cmu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
							<email>faderp@wharton.upenn.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Bruce</forename><forename type="middle">G S</forename><surname>Hardie</surname></persName>
							<email>bhardie@london.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Tepper School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>15213</postCode>
									<settlement>Pittsburgh</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>19104</postCode>
									<settlement>Philadelphia</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">London Business School</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>NW1 4SA</postCode>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">New Perspectives on Customer &quot;Death&quot; Using a Generalization of the Pareto/NBD Model</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2011-06-06">June 6, 2011.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1110.0654</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: February 9, 2011; accepted: March 16, 2011; Steve Shugan served as the acting</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:24+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>As marketing researchers become more sophisticated in building models of customer behavior, they begin to scrutinize, test, and improve upon underlying assumptions of their models that were originally taken for granted. Within the domain of noncontractual customer-firm relationships, the assumptions made about the timing and nature of customer "death" (i.e., unobserved and unobservable dropout) are ripe for such improvements. For years, the gold standard for such models has been the Pareto/NBD <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Schmittlein et al. 1987)</ref>, which was the first to capture and exploit a customer death process in such a setting.</p><p>Applications of the model (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Fader et al. 2005b</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, Reinartz and Kumar 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">, Schmittlein and Peterson 1994</ref> have utilized the Pareto/NBD dropout process (namely, an exponential timing process with gammadistributed heterogeneity across customers) without questioning it or testing alternative mechanisms.</p><p>The first paper to raise such questions was <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Fader et al. (2005a)</ref>, which replaced the continuous-time gamma-exponential process operating in "calendar time" with a beta-geometric process operating in "transaction time" (i.e., the customer can only die immediately after a transaction). The resulting model, called the BG/NBD, was viewed as a "quick and Jerath, Fader, and Hardie: New Perspectives on Customer "Death" Marketing Science 30(5), pp. 866-880, © 2011 INFORMS 867 easy" alternative to the Pareto/NBD, because it offers a much more straightforward parameter estimation process with no substantial loss in the model's fit and forecasting capabilities. Beyond these computational benefits and aggregate indicators of overall model performance, however, not much attention was paid to the death process itself.</p><p>In this paper we propose and carefully investigate a new process for customer death in the noncontractual setting. The resulting model is a generalization of the Pareto/NBD and offers new insights about the death process. This new framework, called the periodic death opportunity (PDO) model, assumes that customers act in accordance with the discrete "coinflipping" story associated with the geometric process, but these "coin flips" arise at periodic intervals in calendar time instead of transaction time (as in the BG/NBD model).</p><p>The differences in the assumed customer death process associated with these "buy-till-you-die" models of buyer behavior in noncontractual settings are illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>. The first dimension on which they differ is whether the customer can "die" at any point in time (continuous) or only at discrete points in time. A second dimension appears when death occurs at discrete points in time: whether these points are discrete points in calendar time or are on a different timescale defined by the point in time at which transactions occurred. In all cases, it is assumed that opportunities for transactions (while alive) occur in continuous time; this is implicit in the use of the NBD to characterize buying behavior while alive. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The PDO model allows us to take a closer look at how assumptions about customer death influence model fit as well as managerial inferences and diagnostics that emerge from the model. By varying the length of the time interval after which each customer makes her dropout decision, which we call the period length, we effectively vary the customer dropout dynamics. When the period length is very large, the dropout component is "shut off," and our model becomes the standard "no-death" negative binomial distribution (NBD) model <ref type="bibr">(Ehrenberg 1959, Morrison and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Schmittlein 1988)</ref>. At the other extreme, when the period length tends to zero, our discrete-time dropout process converges into the continuous-time dropout process of the Pareto/NBD; we prove this convergence analytically. For intermediate values of period 1 When the opportunities for transactions occur in discrete time (e.g., the NBD is replaced by the beta-binomial (BB) model), the "Continuous time" row in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> collapses into the "Discrete time" row (as time is discretized), and the distinction between "Calendar time" and "Transaction time" disappears (because they become one and the same timescale). Thus all three models collapse to the BG/BB model ) when transactions can only occur at discrete points in time. length, we can explore the full continuum of models that lie between these two extremes. We find in our empirical analysis that the PDO model works better than both the NBD and the Pareto/NBD models for intermediate values of the period length, both in the calibration samples and longitudinal holdout periods. Hence, the PDO model acts as a unifying framework between the widely used Pareto/NBD and NBD models. We also find that the PDO model produces different estimates of some key managerial quantities compared to the alternative models. For instance, for both the data sets that we analyze, the PDO model predicts that the average customer in the cohort purchases slower while alive but lives longer, compared to the Pareto/NBD model.</p><p>We also compare the PDO model to the BG/NBD model and find that customer-death-related inferences are vastly different for the BG/NBD model. Recent research has focused on using death estimates obtained from buy-till-you-die models to augment managerial decisions regarding customer retention programs <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Gopinath et al. 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kumar 2000, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Schweidel and Knox 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Wübben and Wangenheim 2008)</ref>. Our results show that different models can lead to very different conclusions about customer death. In light of this, we assert that the model employed to generate these metrics should be chosen carefully, and the PDO model offers a rich framework for this analysis.</p><p>In the next section, we formally develop the PDO model. In §3, we carry out an empirical analysis in which the performance of the proposed model is compared to that of the Pareto/NBD, BG/NBD, and NBD models on two data sets-one using transactions from an online retailer of music CDs and the other using transactions from a grocery store. In §4, we extend the basic model to allow for heterogeneity in the period Marketing Science 30(5), pp. 866-880, © 2011 INFORMS length parameter and estimate this new model on both data sets. Finally, we conclude with a recap of the model, a brief discussion of its limitations, and some suggestions for related future research opportunities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Model Development</head><p>The PDO model is based on the following six assumptions.</p><p>Assumption 1. A customer's relationship with a specific firm can be characterized as first being alive for some period of time, then becoming permanently inactive (dead).</p><p>Assumption 2. While alive, the number of transactions made by a customer follows a Poisson process with mean . (This is equivalent to assuming that the interpurchase times are independent and identically distributed exponential with rate .) Assumption 3. Heterogeneity in transaction rates across customers follows a gamma distribution with shape parameter r and scale parameter :</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">f r = r r−1 e − r<label>(1)</label></formula><p>Assumption 4. Let the random variable denote the unobserved time at which the customer dies. We model the death process by assuming that every units of time (where time starts at zero), the customer can drop out with probability . (This implies that the customer can drop out at 2 t/ in the interval 0 t , where • denotes the "floor" function.) Therefore, the probability that the customer has died by time t is</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">P ≤ t = 1 − 1 − t/</formula><p>and the mean lifetime of the customer is E = / . We refer to as the period length parameter and assume that it is the same for all customers. (We relax this assumption in §4.) Assumption 5. Heterogeneity in follows a beta distribution with probability density function (pdf )</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">f a b = a−1 1 − b−1 B a b (2)</formula><p>Assumption 6. The transaction rate and the dropout probability vary independently across customers.</p><p>Note that the first three assumptions are identical to the corresponding assumptions of the Pareto/NBD model; the difference lies in the assumptions regarding the nature of the death process.</p><p>It follows from Assumptions 4 and 5 that the mean lifetime of a randomly chosen customer is</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">E a b = a + b − 1 a − 1 (3)</formula><p>and the probability that she died by t is</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">P ≤ t a b = 1 − B a b + t/ B a b (4)</formula><p>The Pareto/NBD assumes that individual lifetimes follow an exponential distribution (in place of Assumption 4) and that heterogeneity in the underlying death rate follows a gamma distribution with shape parameter s and scale parameter (in place of Assumption 5). This implies that, for a randomly chosen customer, E s = s − 1 and ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>)</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">P ≤ t s = 1 − + t s (6)</formula><p>On the face of it, these two models for the underlying death process seem quite different: in the PDO model a customer can die only at fixed points in time, whereas in the Pareto/NBD model a customer can die at any point in time. However, one can see that as (in the PDO model) becomes smaller and smaller, the points in time when a customer can die come closer and closer. Extending this argument, as we let approach zero, the customer can die at any point of time. The geometric "discrete" process then becomes an exponential "continuous" process. (We could think of the customers as continually flipping their coins to decide whether to drop out or not.) We can begin to see how the PDO model nests the Pareto/NBD as a special case.</p><p>Consider a customer who made x transactions in the interval 0 T , with the transactions occurring at t 1 t 2 t x ; by definition, t x = 0 when x = 0. We define K 1 = t x / and K 2 = T / . Since t x is the time of the last recorded transaction, the customer must have been alive at time K 1 , which implies that the customer definitely survived the first K 1 opportunities to die. Because the customer was observed until time T , K 2 is the total number of opportunities the customer had to die (out of which she surely did not die in the first K 1 opportunities). The meanings of, and relationships between, K 1 and K 2 will become clearer in the derivation below.</p><p>When K 1 = K 2 , we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">0 2 × t 1 … K 1 K 2 × t x T (K 2 + 1)</formula><p>The fact that a purchase occurred at t x implies the customer must have been alive at K 1 , which occurs with probability 1 − K 1 . Since K 1 = K 2 , the customer must still be alive at T . Given the model assumptions, the likelihood function for this case is</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">L t 1 t x T = e − t 1 e − t 2 −t 1 • • • e − t x −t x−1 e − T −t x 1 − K 2 = x e − T 1 − K 2</formula><p>When K 1 &lt; K 2 , we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">0 2 × t 1 K 1 × t x K 2 T (K 2 + 1) (K 1 + 1)</formula><p>As before, the fact that a purchase occurred at t x implies the customer must have been alive at K 1 . There are, however, a number of possible explanations for the lack of purchasing in the remaining interval t x T :</p><p>• The customer died at K 1 + 1 , having made no purchase in the interval t x K 1 + 1 , with likelihood function</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">x e − K 1 +1 1 − K 1 • The customer died at K 1 + 2 , having made no purchase in the interval t x K 1 + 2 , with likelihood function x e − K 1 +2 1 − K 1 +1</formula><p>• The customer died at K 1 + 3 • The customer died at K 2 , having made no purchase in the interval t x K 2 , with likelihood function</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">x e − K 2 1 − K 2 −1</formula><p>• The customer did not die at K 2 and made no purchase in the interval t x T , with likelihood function</p><p>x e − T 1 − K 2 Note that in both cases (K 1 = K 2 , K 1 &lt; K 2 ), information on when each of the x transactions occurred is not required; we can replace t 1 t x T with (x t x T ). In other words, t x and x are sufficient summaries of a customer's transaction history. (Using direct marketing terminology, t x is recency and x is frequency. 2 ) Combining these two cases, we see that the individual-level likelihood function is</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">L x t x T = x e − T 1 − T / + T / &gt; t x / • T / − t x / j=1 x e − t x / +j 1 − t x / +j−1 (7)</formula><p>Taking the expectation of ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>) over the distributions of and , (1) and ( <ref type="formula">2</ref>), results in the following expression for the likelihood function for a randomly chosen customer with purchase history (x t x T ):</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">L r a b x t x T = 1 0 0 L x t x T f r f a b d d = r + x r r 1 + T r+x B a b + T / B a b + T / &gt; t x / • T / − t x / j=1 1 + t x / + j r+x • B a + 1 b + t x / + j − 1 B a b (8)</formula><p>The five model parameters (r a b and ) can be estimated via the method of maximum likelihood in the following manner. Suppose we have a sample of I customers, where customer i had x i transactions in the interval 0 T i , with the last transaction occurring at t x i . The sample log-likelihood function is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">LL r a b = I i=1 ln L r a b x i t x i T i (9)</formula><p>We find the maximum of this function using a line search for coupled with standard optimization methods for the other four parameters.</p><p>In Appendix A, we show that as → 0, (8) becomes the likelihood function associated with the Pareto/ NBD model. As → , T / = 0 and T / &gt; t x / = 0, in which case (8) collapses to r + x r r 1 + T r+x which is simply the timing-model analog of the basic NBD model <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Gupta and Morrison 1991)</ref>. (Strictly speaking, the PDO model collapses to the NBD whenever &gt; max T i i = 1 I .) Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Schmittlein et al. (1987)</ref>, three quantities of managerial interest in a customer-base analysis exercise are as follows.</p><p>• The expected number of transactions in a time interval of length t is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">E X t r a b = rt B a b + t/ B a b + r t/ j=1 j B a + 1 b + j − 1 B a b<label>(10)</label></formula><p>(This quantity is central to computing the expected transaction volume for the whole customer base over time.)</p><p>Marketing Science 30(5), pp. 866-880, © 2011 INFORMS</p><p>• The probability that a customer with observed behavior x t x T is still alive at time T is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">P &gt; T r a b x t x T = r + x r r 1 + T r+x • B a b + T / B a b L r a b x t x T (11)</formula><p>• The expected number of transactions in the interval T T + t for a customer with observed behavior x t x T is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">E X T T +t r a b x t x T = 1 L r a b x t x T × r +x +1 r r 1 +T r+x+1 • B a b + T +t / B a b t + T +t / − T / j=1 B a+1 b + T / +j −1 B a b • T / +j −T<label>(12)</label></formula><p>(See Appendix B for the associated derivations.)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Empirical Analysis</head><p>We now examine the performance of the PDO model using the CDNOW data set used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Fader et al. (2005a, b)</ref> and a grocery purchase data set used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Batislam et al. (2007)</ref> (henceforth, the Grocery data set).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">The CDNOW Data Set</head><p>This data set tracks 2,357 individuals who made their first-ever purchases at the CDNOW website in the first 12 weeks of 1997 and records their repeat purchasing through June 1998. The first 39 weeks of data are used for model calibration; the remaining 39 weeks of data are used as longitudinal holdout for model validation. Fitting the Pareto/NBD model to these data yields a log-likelihood of −9,595.0; fitting the NBD model yields a log-likelihood of −9,763.7.</p><p>Clearly, the Pareto/NBD model does much better than the NBD model while using only two extra parameters (likelihood ratio test 2 2 = 337 4, p &lt; 0 001). Our focus, however, is on the performance of the PDO model. Is its fit bounded between these Pareto/NBD and NBD limits, or does it provide a superior fit to the data?</p><p>Varying from 0.01 weeks to 40 weeks (in increments of 0.001), we find the maximum likelihood estimates of the remaining four model parameters by maximizing the log-likelihood function given in ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>).</p><p>The corresponding values of the log-likelihood function are plotted in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>. This figure shows that the log-likelihood function is discontinuous in at multiple values of . <ref type="bibr">3</ref> These discontinuities occur as a result of the discrete nature of the floor functions in (8), which have as an argument. At certain values of , a very small increase in causes a large discrete change in the values of the floor functions (i.e., for a very small increase in , the value of the floor function can decrease by one for several cohort members), which leads to a discontinuity in the sample log-likelihood function in ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>). (More specifically, this occurs when t x is a multiple of .) Despite the presence of discontinuities in the sample log-likelihood function, the following patterns are clearly discernible.</p><p>When is very small ( = 0 01 weeks, LL = −9,595.3), the fit of the PDO model is almost exactly the same as that of the Pareto/NBD. As increases from 0.01, the log-likelihood increases from the Pareto/NBD limit to a maximum value of −9,585.6 at = 3 001, then starts declining toward the much lower value associated with the NBD. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> As soon as &gt; 6 weeks, the fit of the PDO model is strictly worse than that of the Pareto/NBD. When is large (&gt;39 weeks in this empirical setting), the PDO model yields the same log-likelihood as that of the NBD model.</p><p>The PDO model (with = 3 001) provides a significant improvement in calibration-period model fit over the Pareto/NBD (likelihood ratio test 2 1 = 18 8, p &lt; 0 001). The parameter estimates of the best-fitting PDO model and the Pareto/NBD model are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. <ref type="bibr">5 6</ref> To illustrate more clearly the relationship between the Pareto/NBD, the NBD, and the PDO models with various values of , we present the parameter estimates and other summary statistics for these models <ref type="bibr">3</ref> We thank Albert Bemmaor and Nicolas Glady for bringing this point to our attention. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> We could use an adaptive line search that switches to a finer incremental in the region of the maximum value of . For example, if we switch to an increment of 1e−06 in the region of = 3 001, we find that the optimal value of is 3.000001 with an associated log-likelihood of −9,585.3. (There is no change in the other parameter estimates to two decimal places and no change in any derived quantities of managerial interest, such as forecasts of repeat sales.) This implies the "truly" optimal value of is 3 + , where → 0 + . For the sake of simplicity, we stay with the nonadaptive line search with an increment of 0.001 for the analyses presented in this paper. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Note that the log-likelihood function for the PDO model is discontinuous around = 3 001 (where it attains its maximum). The standard errors that we report here are obtained by local smoothing of this function in the neighborhood of = 3 001 <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Barnett 1966</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">, Daniels 1961</ref>). Specifically, we report the values provided by the fmincon function in Matlab, which uses quadratic local smoothing. Other methods, such as bootstrap or jackknife, may also be used to obtain standard errors. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> The NBD parameter estimates arer = 0 38 andˆ = 12 07. Note. The right-hand plot presents a "zoomed-in" view for small values of .</p><p>in Table <ref type="table">2</ref>. Note how the parameters of the PDO model tend toward those of the Pareto/NBD model as → 0 (a → s, b → ). This is in accordance with the pattern predicted theoretically in Appendix A.</p><p>Beyond the raw parameter estimates, we also see an interesting range of values for two summary statistics of the underlying behavioral characteristics-namely, the mean transaction rate and the median lifetime.  First, comparing the two extreme models, we expect that under the Pareto/NBD, we would have shorter lifetimes and therefore higher average transaction rates when compared with the NBD. Pursuing this logic further, it follows that increases in would be associated with declining average transaction rates and increasing median lifetimes. What is not known, however, is how quickly these statistics will change with and whether the rates of change are similar or different when we compare them. The data in Table <ref type="table">2</ref> confirm the expected directional changes for these two statistics as a function of , but they also reveal some differences. As rises from 0 (i.e., Pareto/NBD model) to 3.001, the mean transaction rate falls by about 5%, but the median lifetime rises by about 10%. These differences are not dramatic, but they suggest that the estimated death rates, rather than the mean transaction rates, are more sensitive to changes in . Because the reduction in transaction rate is smaller than the increase in lifetime, the best-fitting PDO model generates a slightly higher estimate of total repeat sales over time than that produced by the Pareto/NBD model. But is this good or bad? As rises from 0 (i.e., Pareto/NBD model) to 3.001, the mean transaction rate falls by about 5%, but the median lifetime rises by about 10%. To examine this we create total repeat sales forecasts for each of the specifications reported in Table <ref type="table">2</ref>. In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref> we report the mean absolute percentage error (MAPE) numbers for both cumulative total repeat sales and weekly total repeat sales over weeks 40-78.</p><p>Looking at the cumulative MAPE numbers, we see that all of the PDO models with a finite period length forecast the cumulative sales trajectory extremely well; it is hard to discern meaningful differences in a plot of these curves. In contrast, when we look at errors on an incremental (week-by-week) basis, there are greater deviations (as would be expected). Overall, however, there is strong empirical support for  the performance of the PDO model (particularly with = 3 001) as a worthy alternative to the Pareto/NBD. Do these results prove that customers are actually "flipping their coins" every three weeks? Of course not; however, they do suggest that there is room for improvement in modeling the death process beyond the starting point established by the Pareto/NBD, and they provide some reasonable evidence to support the general idea of the discrete-time "story" being told here. The consistency of these results and their superiority to a very strong benchmark (represented by the Pareto/NBD) are hard to deny. To make our study consistent with that of <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Batislam et al. (2007)</ref>, we use the first 78 weeks for calibration and the last 13 weeks as longitudinal holdout for model validation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">The Grocery Data Set</head><p>Fitting the Pareto/NBD model to these data yields a log-likelihood of −67,925.8, and fitting the NBD model yields −71,000.5. Fitting the PDO models by varying from 0.01 weeks to 80 weeks, we confirm the pattern we observed for the CDNOW data setwhen is very small (i.e., = 0 01 weeks), the fit of the PDO model is identical to that of the Pareto/NBD; when is large (&gt;78 weeks in this empirical setting), the PDO model yields the same log-likelihood as that of the NBD model. The values of the log-likelihood function as varies from 0.01 to 10 weeks are plotted in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">3</ref>. (This is the equivalent of the "zoomedin" right-hand plot in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>.) Note that, as in the Log-likelihood case of the CDNOW data set, the log-likelihood function for the Grocery data set is discontinuous at multiple values of . The maximum log-likelihood value is achieved when = 1 001 and is −67,757.3. Compared with the Pareto/NBD model, this is a highly significant improvement in model fit at the cost of just one additional parameter (likelihood ratio test 2 1 = 337, p &lt; 0 001). In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">4</ref>, we present the parameter estimates of the best-fitting PDO model and the Pareto/NBD model. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> As expected, we also observe exactly the same patterns as in Table <ref type="table">2</ref> for the parameter estimates, mean underlying transaction rates, and median lifetimes for the different PDO models as varies, and we observe the same qualitative relationships between these models and the Pareto/NBD model. For instance, for the best-fitting PDO model, the mean underlying transaction rate is 0 11 per week and the median lifetime is 45 2 weeks; for the Pareto/NBD model, the mean underlying transaction rate is the same (0 11 per week) and the median lifetime is smaller (41 8 weeks). Furthermore, for the 13-week holdout period also, we observe similar patterns as in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref>. For the PDO ( = 1 001) model, the cumulative MAPE is 0 9% and the weekly MAPE is 3 6%; for the Pareto/NBD model, the cumulative MAPE is 0 5% and the weekly MAPE is 3 7%.</p><p>To summarize, the best-fitting PDO model performs significantly better than the Pareto/NBD model in terms of in-sample fit for the Grocery data set, and we observe similar relationships between the Pareto/NBD, NBD, and various PDO models in this data set as we did in the CDNOW data set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Comparison with the BG/NBD Model</head><p>A natural question that arises is, what about the original BG/NBD model (with "coin flips" tied to transactions instead of occurring periodically in calendar  <ref type="bibr">et al. (2005a)</ref>, is slightly better than that of the PDO model with = 3 001 (and therefore substantially better than that of the regular Pareto/NBD). However, for the Grocery data set, the BG/NBD model (LL = −68 007 0) significantly underperforms both the PDO model and the Pareto/NBD model. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> In terms of out-of-sample performance on the summary statistics shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref>, the BG/NBD consistently performs slightly worse than the PDO model-for the CDNOW data set, the BG/NBD model's cumulative MAPE is 2.6% and weekly MAPE is 19.4% (both slightly worse), and for the Grocery data set, the BG/NBD model's cumulative MAPE is 8.8% (much worse) and weekly MAPE is 4.0% (slightly worse). Overall, these fit statistics offer mixed evidence about the superiority of the PDO model vis-à-vis the BG/NBD, and none of it is particularly dramatic. Further insight into the three models can be obtained by comparing interferences we may draw concerning underlying buyer behavior. In particular, we compare the estimates for the mean transaction rate and the median lifetime with uncertainty in the maximum-likelihood (ML) estimates taken into account. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">4</ref> plots the estimates for the mean transaction rate with uncertainty in the ML estimates taken into account. For both data sets, there are notable differences in the mean purchasing rates; a randomly (We note that the estimates for these quantities are sharper for the Grocery data set than the CDNOW data set because in the former we have data for almost twice the number of individuals compared with the latter.) Noting that the BG/NBD model probability of a randomly chosen customer having died by t is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">P ≤ t = 1 − + t r 2 F 1 r b a + b t + t<label>(13)</label></formula><p>where 2 F 1 • is the Gaussian hypergeometric function, we can compute the median lifetime for all three models with uncertainty in the ML estimates taken into account-see Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref> for the associated plots.</p><p>In both empirical settings, there is a slight (but systematic) difference in the median lifetimes as implied by the PDO and Pareto/NBD models, with the PDO model predicting that a randomly chosen customer in the cohort lives longer; however, the results for the BG/NBD model cast a dubious light on its validityeven when its overall fit is superior. Specifically, we note that, for both data sets, the median lifetimes as implied by the BG/NBD are so vastly different than those of the two former models that they cannot be plotted on the same scale.</p><p>Compared with the Pareto/NBD model, the PDO model predicts (in these empirical settings) that a randomly chosen customer in the cohort lives longer but purchases slower while alive. Under the BG/NBD model, a randomly chosen customer not only lives much longer but also purchases at a slightly higher rate. How do we reconcile this with the finding that the BG/NBD underestimates cumulative repeat sales when compared to the Pareto/NBD model <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Batislam et al. 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">, Fader et al. 2005a</ref>)? In contrast to the cumulative death probability for the PDO and Pareto/NBD models, ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>), respectively, the cumulative death probability for the BG/NBD model, (13), is a function of the parameters of the distribution that characterizes heterogeneity in buying rate while alive. This follows from the fact that death can only follow a purchase. Although the mean of the gamma heterogeneity distribution is highest for the BG/NBD model for both data sets, it is also the most heterogeneous (as indicated by the coefficient of variation, which equals 1/ √ r). This pool of customers with a very low buying rate means that their opportunities for death occur very infrequently, which results in very long (unobserved) lifetimes.</p><p>These questionable results for the BG/NBD highlight the practical implications of the death process associated with the class of buy-till-you-die models; assessing measures of model fit is not sufficient to judge the suitability of a model for inferential purposes. As more researchers and managers make managerial judgments that directly relate to the death process <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Gopinath et al. 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kumar 2000, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Schweidel and Knox 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Wübben and Wangenheim 2008)</ref>, the theoretical benefits of the PDO framework become much more tangible. The BG/NBD has no direct connection to the Pareto/NBD, and there is no way to equate the parameters across these different specifications. These conceptual benefits help demonstrate the value of the PDO framework, especially for researchers with a focal interest in the nature of the death process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Heterogeneity in</head><p>In the previous sections, we have treated the parameter as homogeneous for all customers; in reality, however, the nature of the period length is likely to vary across them. In this section, we allow for heterogeneity in . Specifically, we assume that varies across customers according to a gamma distribution with pdf</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">f m = m m−1 e − m<label>(14)</label></formula><p>(Using other heterogeneity distributions, such as a log-normal distribution or a normal distribution truncated below at zero, yields similar results.) Under this specification, the individual-level process is the same as before, and the likelihood function for a randomly chosen customer is obtained by taking the expectation of (8) over the distribution of , i.e., evaluating the integral 0</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>L r a b f m d</head><p>As this does not have an algebraic solution, we turn to Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) methods for estimating this heterogeneous PDO (henceforth HPDO) model; see Appendix C for details.</p><p>We estimate the HPDO model on both data sets. Our inferences are based on 50,000 iterations, following a burn-in of 20,000 iterations. The resulting   parameter estimates after the Markov chains converge are presented in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">5</ref>. (The associated logmarginal density numbers, calculated using the harmonic mean of the likelihoods across iterations (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Newton and Raftery 1994)</ref>, are −8,577.1 and −63,746.2 for the CDNOW and Grocery data sets, respectively.) Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">6</ref> shows the distribution of for both data sets. Clearly, there is significant heterogeneity in in both data sets. Note that the expected value of is larger for the CDNOW data set compared with the Grocery data set; this is in line with the value of for the best-fitting PDO model (i.e., without heterogeneity in ) being larger for the CDNOW data set compared to the Grocery data set. However, although the HPDO model offers new insights into the dropout process and a large improvement in in-sample fit, it performs slightly worse in terms of out-of-sample predictions than the PDO models without heterogeneity in . For the CDNOW data set, for weeks 40-78, the cumulative MAPE is 1 92% and the weekly MAPE is 20 55%. For the Grocery data set, for weeks 78-91, the cumulative MAPE is 1 5% and the weekly MAPE is 8 1%. Furthermore, using simulated data for various "HPDO worlds," we found that the HPDO model is unable to do a satisfactory job of recovering the true individual-level period lengths, which we conjecture is because the individual-level likelihood function has floor functions that make it discontinuous in . Similar simulations for the basic PDO model Marketing Science 30(5), pp. 866-880, © 2011 INFORMS covering a wide variety of purchasing characteristics in the cohorts show that, in contrast to the HPDO model, it is able to recover its original parameters with good accuracy in spite of the discontinuity issues that we discussed in §3. (In the case of the basic PDO model, we are able to conduct a line search to find the optimal value of for the cohort.) For these reasons, the simpler PDO model may be the preferred alternative. Nevertheless, we believe that the HPDO model is a worthwhile extension to consider and might offer value to future researchers, particularly if they want to test hypotheses about how the nature of the dropout process varies across customers (perhaps related to customer characteristics or contextual factors).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Discussion and Conclusions</head><p>We have proposed the PDO model as a new way to better understand and capture the death process associated with buy-till-you-die type models that are frequently used to model customer buying behavior in noncontractual settings. We demonstrated (both analytically and empirically) that the PDO model nests both the Pareto/NBD and the traditional nodeath NBD as special cases, and we found strong evidence that customers behave as if their death process is somewhere in between these two extremes. Because the PDO model has a more flexible death process, it widens the scope of what we can infer about the nature of the customer dropout process when compared to the Pareto/NBD model. Because the purchase process is estimated jointly with the death process, we can also expect to see differences in inferences for the quantities related to the purchase process. In accordance with these insights, we found that the PDO model can indeed offer different estimates for some important characteristics of purchase and death dynamics in a cohort-for instance, for both the data sets that we analyzed, we found that the average customer lives longer but purchases slower in the PDO model than in the Pareto/NBD model.</p><p>Although this paper questions (and improves upon) one aspect of the original Pareto/NBD paradigm, it does not necessarily mean that the Pareto/NBD itself is obsolete and should be avoided. We continue to encourage using the Pareto/NBD model when the manager's primary goal is forecasting purchases, as opposed to a principal focus on the death process, per se. Although in our data sets the best-fitting PDO models (and the HPDO model) offer consistent and significant improvements in the calibration sample, the improvements in predictions for the holdout period are not especially dramatic. On the other hand, when inferences about customer dropout are central to the manager's goals, the PDO framework deserves her attention. This paper has focused on the underlying structure of the death process in the buy-till-you-die models of buyer behavior in noncontractual settings, as illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>. All the models assume that an individual customer's unobserved (and unobservable) lifetime is characterized by a memoryless process (i.e., an exponential or geometric distribution) and that buying behavior while alive can be characterized by the Poisson distribution coupled with gamma heterogeneity (i.e., the NBD). Staying within the buytill-you-die paradigm, there are obvious extensions. We can replace the memoryless lifetime distribution (associated with any of the three cells in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>) with one that exhibits some form of duration dependence. For instance, if we find that the Pareto/NBD is underpredicting repeat sales or overpredicting the number of zero repeat buyers, or both, we could replace the exponential lifetime distribution with a Weibull (or some other distribution with a more flexible hazard function that has the ability to "slow down" the death process). We can also relax the assumption of a memoryless interpurchase distribution associated with the NBD. For example, the NBD can be replaced by the CNBD <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Chatfield and</ref><ref type="bibr">Goodhardt 1973, Schmittlein and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Morrison 1983)</ref>, as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Platzer's (2008)</ref> CBG/CNBD-k model and the work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Schweidel and Knox (2010)</ref>.</p><p>The emergence of simulation-based estimation methods for the Pareto/NBD model <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abe 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">, Ma and Liu 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">, Singh et al. 2009</ref>) means that it is now much easier for the researcher to tinker with the basic "building blocks" of the model, i.e., the ability to utilize other probability distributions instead of those used by the early researchers in this area. Although this kind of flexibility seems like a welcome addition to the modeler's toolkit, it may create an overly complex model that lacks a meaningful "as-if" story. We feel that a more reflective approach to extending the model, such as stepping back and questioning the implicit assumption that "death can occur at any time," may result in better performance (particularly in a holdout period) as well as improved diagnostics (such as the nature of the death process).</p><p>A logical extension of our hierarchical Bayesian estimation procedure for the HPDO model would be the use of covariates to help explain how the death process varies across customers. Several researchers have explored such extensions to the Pareto/NBD model using time-invariant covariates (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Abe 2009, Fader and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hardie 2007)</ref> and time-varying covariates (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Schweidel and Knox 2010)</ref>. This could help managers manage customer attrition in an effective manner. These issues, however, go beyond the PDO model proposed here (and may not offer substantial benefits to justify their additional complexity). Before rushing ahead with these potential improvements, we encourage researchers to contemplate the basic PDO model and take advantage of its desirable theoretical properties.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Classifying Differences in Assumed Customer Death Processes</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2 Plot of the PDO Model Log-Likelihood for the CDNOW Data Set as a Function of the Period Length Parameter</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>in the case of the Pareto/NBD model ( = 0).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Batislam et al. (2007)</ref> used a data set covering 5,479 individuals at a Turkish grocery store who made their first-ever purchases between August 2001 and October 2001, recording their repeat purchasing through April 2003. For every individual, we have data on the recency and frequency of repeat purchasing and the length of time for which this individual was observed.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3 Plot of the PDO Model Log-Likelihood for the Grocery Data Set as a Function of the Period Length Parameter</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4Expected (Latent) Transaction Rate for a Randomly Chosen Customer for the CDNOW and Grocery Data Sets, Accounting for Uncertainty in the ML Estimates, for the Best-Fitting PDO, Pareto/NBD and BG/NBD Models</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Marketing</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 5Median (Latent) Lifetime for a Randomly Chosen Customer for the CDNOW and Grocery Data Sets, Accounting for Uncertainty in the ML Estimates, for the Best-Fitting PDO, Pareto/NBD, and BG/NBD Models</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6Histogram of Posterior Draws of Across Customers from One Iteration After Convergence for the CDNOW Data Set (Left) and the Grocery Data Set (Right)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 Parameter</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>PDO</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Pareto/NBD</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>Std. error</cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>Std. error</cell></row><row><cell>r</cell><cell>0.52</cell><cell>0 008</cell><cell>0.55</cell><cell>0 026</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>10.40</cell><cell>0 008</cell><cell>10.58</cell><cell>0 632</cell></row><row><cell>a</cell><cell>0.43</cell><cell>0 015</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>b</cell><cell>2.61</cell><cell>0 002</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>3.001</cell><cell>0 002</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>s</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.61</cell><cell>0 025</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>11.67</cell><cell>0 307</cell></row><row><cell>LL</cell><cell>−9,585.6</cell><cell></cell><cell>−9,595.0</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Table 2</cell><cell cols="3">Estimation Results for the CDNOW Data Set for the</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Pareto/NBD Model = 0 , the NBD Model →</cell><cell>and the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">PDO Model for Various Values of</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Transaction</cell><cell>Death</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>Estimates and Standard Errors for the PDO and Pareto/NBD Models for the CDNOW Data Set</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Measures of Model Forecasting Performance for the Pareto/NBD Model = 0 , the NBD Model → and the PDO Model (for Various Values of )</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">MAPE (Weeks 40-78)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Cumulative (%)</cell><cell>Weekly (%)</cell></row><row><cell>(0)</cell><cell>1 35</cell><cell>20 89</cell></row><row><cell>0.010</cell><cell>1 35</cell><cell>20 89</cell></row><row><cell>0.100</cell><cell>1 34</cell><cell>20 53</cell></row><row><cell>1.001</cell><cell>1 14</cell><cell>20 13</cell></row><row><cell>2.001</cell><cell>1 09</cell><cell>19 81</cell></row><row><cell>3.001</cell><cell>0 85</cell><cell>19 06</cell></row><row><cell>4.001</cell><cell>0 85</cell><cell>19 06</cell></row><row><cell>5.001</cell><cell>0 88</cell><cell>19 33</cell></row><row><cell>10.001</cell><cell>0 70</cell><cell>19 18</cell></row><row><cell>20.001</cell><cell>0 92</cell><cell>19 25</cell></row><row><cell>( )</cell><cell>10 37</cell><cell>36 22</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Parameter Estimates and Standard Errors for the PDO and Pareto/NBD Models for the Grocery Data Set</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>PDO</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Pareto/NBD</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>Std. error</cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>Std. error</cell></row><row><cell>r</cell><cell>0 46</cell><cell>0 001</cell><cell>0 48</cell><cell>0 001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>4 38</cell><cell>0 019</cell><cell>4 38</cell><cell>0 014</cell></row><row><cell>a</cell><cell>0 62</cell><cell>0 004</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>b</cell><cell>22 19</cell><cell>0 011</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>1 001</cell><cell>0 000</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>s</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0 57</cell><cell>0 002</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>17 64</cell><cell>0 031</cell></row><row><cell>LL</cell><cell>−67,757.3</cell><cell></cell><cell>−67,925.8</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="5">time)? The answer is quite interesting. In terms of in-</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">sample fit, the BG/NBD performs at least as well as</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">all of the PDO models for the CDNOW data set; its</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">log-likelihood value of −9,582.4, as reported in Fader</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Parameter Estimates for the HPDO Model for the CDNOW and Grocery Data Sets</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>CDNOW</cell><cell></cell><cell>Grocery</cell></row><row><cell>Posterior</cell><cell></cell><cell>Posterior</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>mean</cell><cell>95% interval</cell><cell>mean</cell><cell>95% interval</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">If x = 0, then t x = 0. Note that this measure of recency differs from that normally used by the direct marketing community, who measure recency as the time from the last observed transaction to the end of the observation period (i.e., T − t x ).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8">The BG/NBD model parameter estimates, along with the standard errors in parentheses, arer = 0 24 0 013 ,ˆ = 4 41 0 366 ,â = 0 79 0 189 , andb = 2 43 0 695 for the CDNOW data set; andr = 0 28 0 004 ,ˆ = 2 34 0 008 ,â = 0 40 0 022 , andb = 2 09 0 178 for the Grocery data set.9  To account for uncertainty in the estimates, we take 1,000 draws of the relevant parameters from a multivariate normal distribution, where the means are the ML estimates of the relevant parameters and the covariance matrix is given by the inverse of the Hessian (to account for the correlations between parameter estimates).</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank Emine Batislam, Meltem Denizel, and Alpay Filiztekin for making the Grocery data set available and Albert Bemmaor, Nicolas Glady, and Marcel Goić for helpful discussions. The first author acknowledges the support of the i-Lab at Carnegie Mellon University, the second author acknowledges the support of the Wharton Customer Analytics Initiative, and the third author acknowledges the support of the London Business School Centre for Marketing.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix A. The Pareto/NBD as a Limiting Case</head><p>In this section we show that the PDO model likelihood function approaches that of the Pareto/NBD model as → 0.</p><p>The individual-level likelihood function for the Pareto/ NBD model is <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Fader and Hardie 2005)</ref>:</p><p>Assuming heterogeneity in and is distributed gamma with parameters (r ) and (s ), respectively, it follows that the likelihood function for a randomly chosen customer is found by solving ). This proof will make use of the following results:</p><p>(We note that (A2) is a standard result, (A3) results from the application of L'Hôpital's rule, and (A4) follows from Abramowitz and Stegun 1972, Equation <ref type="formula">6</ref>.1.46.) Noting that</p><p>we can rewrite the individual-level likelihood function (7) as</p><p>) Also let a = s and b = / . It follows that PDO likelihood function for a randomly chosen customer, L r a b , can be written as</p><p>where</p><p>(Note that the only difference between 2 and 3 is t x versus T .) We now take the limit of (A5) as → 0. Noting that T / &gt; t x / = 1 as → 0, we have</p><p>Noting t x / t x / and T / T / as → 0, and using (A2)-(A4), </p><p>It follows that</p><p>Substituting ( <ref type="formula">A7</ref>)-( <ref type="formula">A9</ref>) in (A6) and simplifying gives us</p><p>which is exactly the integral for the Pareto/NBD likelihood function, (A1). Q.E.D. This proof establishes the equivalence between the likelihoods of observing the same data under the PDO model when → 0 and the Pareto/NBD. We use this fact somewhat liberally to "prove" that the two models are equivalent under this special condition ( → 0). (Using a similar procedure and the same substitutions, it is easy to show that all the expressions for the PDO model-e.g., ( <ref type="formula">10</ref>)-( <ref type="formula">12</ref>)-are identical to those of the Pareto/NBD as → 0.)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix B. Derivations of Key Results</head><p>Derivation of (10). Let the random variable X t denote the number of transactions occurring in the interval 0 t . Conditional on , it follows from the assumption of Poisson purchasing that E X t is simply t if the customer is active at t, if the customer dies at , 2 if the customer dies at 2 , 3 if the customer dies at 3 , and t/ if the customer dies at t/ . Multiplying these quantities by the probability that the customer dies at 2</p><p>gives us</p><p>Taking the expectation of this over the distributions of and , (1) and ( <ref type="formula">2</ref>), gives us the expression in (10). Derivation of (11). The probability that a customer with purchase history x t x T is alive at time T is simply the probability that she was alive at K 2 . Referring back to our derivation of the individual-level likelihood function, (7), the application of the Bayes' theorem gives us</p><p>(We note that if t x / = T / (i.e., K 1 = K 2 ), P &gt; T x t x T = 1.) By Bayes' theorem, the joint posterior distribution of and is given by</p><p>Taking the expectation of (B1) over this joint posterior distribution gives us (11). Derivation of (12). Let the random variable X T T + t denote the number of purchases made in the interval T T + t . We are interested in computing the conditional expectation E X T T + t x t x T , the expected number of purchases in the interval T T + t for a customer with purchase history (x t x T ).</p><p>Let us assume the customer is alive at T (i.e., &gt; T ). Conditional on , it follows from the assumption of Poisson purchasing that the expected number of purchases in T T + t is simply t if the customer is active at T + t, T / + 1 − T if the customer dies at T / + 1 , T / + 2 − T if the customer dies at T / + 2 , … , and T + t / − T if the customer dies at T + t / . Multiplying these quantities by the probability that the customer dies at T / + 1 , T / + 2 , … , gives us</p><p>Taking the expectation of the product of (B1) and (B3) over the joint posterior distribution of and , (B2), gives us (12).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix C. MCMC Procedure for the HPDO Model</head><p>Customer i with period length i makes her dropout decision at i 2 i 3 i Whether the customer dropped out or not and, if so, when she dropped out, is unobserved. To aid with the model estimation, we generate these unobservables using data augmentation <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Tanner and Wong 1987)</ref>. Specifically, we use the indicator variable Z i (with the realization z i ) to denote whether the customer died between t x i and T i : if the customer is still alive at T i , Z i = 1; if the customer died at i i , where</p><p>Recalling the logic of the derivation of ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>), the likelihood function of customer i is given by</p><p>and the customer died at i i ). Therefore,</p><p>The parameters of the heterogeneity distributions for , , and specified earlier act as priors for i , i , and i , respectively. Hence, i ∼ gamma(r ), i ∼ beta(a b), and i ∼ gamma(m ). We derive expressions for the conditional densities of the relevant individual-level parameters in the following manner.</p><p>Jerath, Fader, and Hardie: New Perspectives on Customer "Death" Marketing Science 30(5), pp. 866-880, © 2011 INFORMS 879</p><p>• The conditional posterior distribution of i is proportional to L i i i x i t x i T i z i i × f i r , which in turn is proportional to r+x i −1 i e − i +z i T i + 1−z i i i . Therefore,</p><p>• The conditional posterior distribution of i is proportional to L i i i x i t x i T i z i i × f i a b , which in turn is proportional to</p><p>• The conditional posterior distribution of i is proportional to L i i i x i t x i T i z i i × f i m , which gives us</p><p>We can sample from this distribution using Metropolis-Hastings methods.</p><p>• Recalling (B1),</p><p>where</p><p>Note that if T i / i = t x i / i , customer i is definitely alive at T i because she did not get a chance to flip her death coin after her last purchase (which occurred at t x i ); as such,</p><p>• If Z i = 0, then we also generate an integer i ∈ t x i / i + 1 T i / i , where t x i &lt; i i &lt; T i is the point in time at which customer i died. Assuming a (discrete) uniform prior on i ,</p><p>The joint conditional posterior distributions of the population-level parameters are given by</p><p>where , , and denote the current vectors of the individual-level parameters. We use fully diffuse hyperpriors for r, , a, b, m, and . (Although these parameters are only allowed to take on positive values, in our case this is not a problem because the two data sets we use have a large number of individuals in them; i.e., while sampling from the posterior distribution, the data likelihood strongly dominates the prior specification.) Metropolis-Hastings methods are used to sample the pairs r , a b and m . The resulting MCMC procedure used in the estimation is as follows:</p><p>1. Set initial values for r a b m and , as well as for i i i z i and i ∀ i = 1 I. 2. Iterate until convergence:</p><p>(a) For each customer i, sample i , i , and i using (C1), (C2), and (C3), respectively. (b) For each customer i, generate z i using (C4). If z i = 0, generate i using (C5). (This is the data augmentation step.) (c) Sample the pairs r , a b , and m using (C6), (C7), and (C8), respectively.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Counting your customers&quot; one by one: A hierarchical Bayes extension to the Pareto/NBD model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Abe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="541" to="553" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Handbook of Mathematical Functions</title>
		<editor>Abramowitz, M., I. A. Stegun</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
			<publisher>Dover Publications</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluation of the maximum-likelihood estimator where the likelihood equation has multiple roots</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Barnett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biometrika</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="165" />
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empirical validation and comparison of models for customer base analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Batislam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Denizel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Filiztekin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Res. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="209" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A consumer purchasing model with Erlang inter-purchase times</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Chatfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Goodhardt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">344</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="828" to="835" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The asymptotic efficiency of a maximum likelihood estimator</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Daniels</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 4th Berkeley Sympos</title>
				<meeting>4th Berkeley Sympos<address><addrLine>Berkeley</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>University of California Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="163" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The pattern of consumer purchases</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S C</forename><surname>Ehrenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="1959" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A note on deriving the Pareto/NBD model and related expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">G S</forename><surname>Hardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://brucehardie.com/notes/009/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-04-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Incorporating time-invariant covariates into the Pareto/NBD and BG/NBD models. Retrieved</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">G S</forename><surname>Hardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://brucehardie.com/notes/019/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-04-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Counting your customers&quot; the easy way: An alternative to the Pareto/NBD model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">G S</forename><surname>Hardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="284" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">RFM and CLV: Using iso-value curves for customer base analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">G S</forename><surname>Hardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="415" to="430" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Customer-base analysis in a discrete-time noncontractual setting</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">G S</forename><surname>Hardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1086" to="1108" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Are revived customers as good as new? Working paper, Northwestern University</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gopinath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Blattberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Malthouse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ssrn.com/abstract=1356851" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<pubPlace>Evanston, IL</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating heterogeneity in consumers&apos; purchase rates</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="264" to="269" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The MCMC approach for solving the Pareto/NBD model and possible extensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S.-H</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-L</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 3rd Internat. Conf. Natural Comput. (ICNC 2007)</title>
				<meeting>3rd Internat. Conf. Natural Comput. (ICNC 2007)<address><addrLine>Washington, DC</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="505" to="512" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="866" to="880" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalizing the NBD model for customer purchases: What are the implications and is it worth the effort?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Schmittlein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Econom. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="159" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Approximate Bayesian inference with the weighted likelihood bootstrap</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Newton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Raftery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Roy. Statist. Soc. Ser. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="48" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Stochastic models of noncontractual consumer relationships</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Platzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<pubPlace>Vienna</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Vienna University of Economics and Business Administration</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Master&apos;s thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the profitability of long-life customers in a noncontractual setting: An empirical investigation and implications for marketing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Reinartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="35" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of customer relationship characteristics on profitable lifetime duration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Reinartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="99" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prediction of future random events with the condensed negative binomial distribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Schmittlein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">382</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="449" to="456" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Customer base analysis: An industrial purchase process application</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Schmittlein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Peterson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="67" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Counting your customers: Who are they and what will they do next?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Schmittlein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Colombo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Incorporating strategic direct marketing activity into &quot;buy &apos;til you die&quot; models. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Schweidel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Knox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ssrn.com/abstract=1670060" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<pubPlace>Madison</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Wisconsin-Madison</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A generalized framework for estimating customer lifetime value when customer lifetimes are not observed</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Borle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Jain</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="181" to="205" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The calculation of posterior distributions by data augmentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Tanner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">398</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="528" to="540" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Instant customer base analysis: Managerial heuristics often &quot;get it right</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wübben</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Wangenheim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="82" to="93" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
