<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Impact of Tariff Structure on Customer Retention, Usage, and Profitability of Access Services</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2011-07-15">July 15, 2011.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Raghuram</forename><surname>Iyengar</surname></persName>
							<email>riyengar@wharton.upenn.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kamel</forename><surname>Jedidi</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Skander</forename><surname>Essegaier</surname></persName>
							<email>sesseghaier@ku.edu.tr</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Danaher</surname></persName>
							<email>peter.danaher@monash.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">The Wharton School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>19104</postCode>
									<settlement>Philadelphia</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Columbia Business School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>10027</postCode>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>New York</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">College of Administrative Sciences and Economics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Koç University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>34450</postCode>
									<settlement>Istanbul</settlement>
									<country key="TR">Turkey</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Marketing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Monash University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Caulfield East</addrLine>
									<postCode>3145</postCode>
									<settlement>Victoria</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Impact of Tariff Structure on Customer Retention, Usage, and Profitability of Access Services</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2011-07-15">July 15, 2011.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1110.0655</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: March 7, 2010; accepted: March 23, 2011; Duncan Simester, guest</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:31+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>The pricing of subscription services has become a key issue for many firms, particularly in the technology sector <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Danaher 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">, Essegaier et al. 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">, Lambrecht and Skiera 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">, Narayanan et al. 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">, Sundararajan 2004</ref>. For example, when launching their new cell phone service in the United States, Virgin Mobile considered three pricing options: (i) matching the industry standard of a two-part tariff (TPT), where consumers are charged a monthly access fee and a marginal price per use with price levels set equal to competitors; (ii) the same as in (i) but with lower price levels than competitors; and (iii) introducing a pay-per-use (PPU) scheme with no monthly fee and no contract <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(McGovern 2003)</ref>. Such a decision faced by Virgin Mobile-TPT versus PPU-is fundamental to many subscription services as they grapple with a need to understand how consumers may react to alternative pricing structures. Other examples include the pricing of online music by iTunes <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Mark and White 2007</ref>) and Amazon's Prime service that limits overnight shipping charges to just $3.99 on all items to those who pay an annual fee.</p><p>Past work on nonlinear pricing suggests that a TPT pricing structure will allow firms to generate higher profits than a PPU structure <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Oi 1971</ref>). However, this result relies on the assumption that, given the same level of marginal price, the demand curve is the same under both PPU and TPT pricing structures. In contrast, research in psychology and marketing suggests that myriad pricing-related factors may affect consumer demand above and beyond the traditional <ref type="bibr">Iyengar et al.:</ref> The Impact of Tariff Structure Marketing Science 30(5), pp. 820-836, © 2011 INFORMS 821 marginal price perspective. For example, the price format can influence consumers' perception of value and their consumption (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Prelec and Loewenstein 1998)</ref>. Similarly, <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Heath and Fennema (1996)</ref> find that subjects assigned to a TPT condition-being a combination of an entry fee to a bar and a per-game charge-expect to play less pool games than those assigned to the PPU condition (no entry fee and only a per-game charge) even after controlling for differences in income (i.e., the effect of entry fee) across the two conditions. Other examples include the systematic effects of payment schedule-monthly or annual payment-on service usage and retention <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Soman and Gourville 2001)</ref> and price-ending format on consumers' purchase decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Anderson and Simester 2003)</ref>. Overall, this research stream suggests that "pricing can transform, as well as capture, the utility of an offer" <ref type="bibr">(Bertini and Wathieu 2008, p. 236)</ref>.</p><p>The purpose of this paper is to assess the impact of pricing structure on consumer demand for access services and firm profitability. We investigate this issue in the context of PPU and TPT, two common pricing structures for access services (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Danaher 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">, Essegaier et al. 2002</ref>. We develop a utility-based model of consumer usage and retention of a subscription service and allow the model parameters to vary with the type of pricing structure faced by the customer. We test the model on data from a field experiment for a cellular phone service where participants are randomly assigned to a TPT or PPU plan. Access and usage prices are varied at intervals over a 13-month period, with subjects able to relinquish the service at any time. A unique feature of the field experiment is the joint manipulation of pricing structure and price levels. We capitalize on this variation to assess the impact of pricing structure on consumer usage and retention, estimate demand parameters for each pricing structure, and derive optimal PPU and TPT tariffs.</p><p>Our results indicate that consumers derive lower utility from using the service when they are under a TPT plan compared with a PPU plan, resulting in both lower retention of customers and lower usage of the service. This negative impact of TPT pricing (which we label the "access fee effect") is true even after controlling for income effects, heterogeneity across customers, and observable and unobservable time-varying factors. Our results also show an average decline of 10.5% in the annual retention rate and a 38.7% decrease in the yearly usage relative to PPU pricing after controlling for income effects (10.5% of this drop in usage is due to consumer churn and 28.2% is due to reduction in usage conditional on retention). Despite the higher customer churn and lower usage, we find that TPT is still the profitmaximizing pricing structure for the firm. However, we find that the firm would overcharge customers for the access fee and undercharge them for the perminute price if it ignores the access fee effect. In terms of profitability, the failure to account for this effect leads to an 11% reduction in firm profit.</p><p>Previous research on multipart pricing of services has focused on consumers' preferences for tariffs and usage behavior. Several studies have shown that consumers have a "flat-fee bias," namely, a preference for unlimited usage in return for a fixed monthly fee (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Kridel et al. 1993, Lambrecht and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Skiera 2006)</ref>. By contrast, <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Miravete (2003)</ref> reports evidence for consumers exhibiting a PPU bias. In addition, a number of empirical studies have used either observational data (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Iyengar et al. 2007)</ref> or natural experiments (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Ascarza et al. 2011</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">, Narayanan et al. 2007</ref>) to analyze tariff choice and usage behavior. Recent work has also considered three-part tariffs, where the access fee permits a certain usage allowance beyond which a usage price is charged (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Iyengar et al. 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Iyengar et al. , 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Lambrecht et al. 2007)</ref>. In this paper, we exploit the richness of the field experiment to examine how customers differentially respond to PPU versus TPT pricing once they are on one of these plans. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> In addition, we evaluate the impact of pricing structure on customer retention and usage and firm profitability. To the best of our knowledge, none of this prior research has investigated these issues together.</p><p>The rest of this paper is organized as follows. In §2, we describe the field experiment. In §3, we discuss our proposed model. Section 4 contains the results of our estimation. In §5, we explain our results and describe how we rule out alternative explanations. In §6, we determine the impact of pricing structure on retention and consumption. Section 7 contains the results on pricing policy optimization. Section 8 concludes the paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Field Experiment</head><p>The data come from a field experiment of a product trial for a new subscription-based telecommunication service offered by a firm in an OECD (Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development) country and have been previously used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Danaher (2002)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> The firm has a monopoly over the provision of fixed line services but faces competition in the wireless services. Being the first of its kind in this country, the 822 Marketing Science 30(5), pp. 820-836, © 2011 INFORMS new service integrates features that combine the benefits of a fixed phone line and a cellular phone. We use these data to understand how customers differentially respond to PPU versus TPT pricing and to assess the impact of pricing structure on customer retention, usage, and optimal pricing.</p><p>Trialists were residential, fixed line customers who agreed to try this new "combined" fixed-cellular line service. At the time of the service trial, the overwhelming majority of trialists did not have a cellular phone. The duration of the experiment consisted of 13 monthly periods (starting from October). Each trialist was randomly assigned to either a PPU condition or a TPT condition. Once assigned to one of the tariff conditions, a trialist remained in that condition for the duration of the experiment. Thus the data do not suffer from self-selection biases.</p><p>Whereas the tariff structure (the experimental condition) assigned to a trialist did not change throughout the experiment, the price levels within a tariff condition were modified by the firm. Before a price change, a customer was informed about the new price levels he or she would be facing for the coming period: a consumer in the PPU condition was informed about the next period per-minute price, and a consumer in the TPT condition was informed about both the per-minute price and the fixed fee for the following period. Note that this method of disseminating price-related information to customers precludes them from forming any expectations of when a price change may occur and by how much the price would change. The experimental price variability allows us to estimate a customer's price sensitivity and determine whether it differs by tariff type.</p><p>Trialists were able to drop out of the service at the end of any of these 13 periods. Any time a customer decides to drop out, he or she would inform the company. As such, the company is able to observe, over the duration of the trial period, if and when a trialist from the pool decides to drop the new service. At the end of each period, trialists who still subscribe to the service face a keep/drop decision: stay with the new service or drop it.</p><p>Trialists were not aware of other types of pricing schemes being offered to other customers for the same service. Also, because the experiment was conducted during a prelaunch trial phase for the product, there was no specific advertising or promotional activity. Thus, across-customer comparisons are very unlikely. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> contains a description of the field experiment and the price changes that took place over the 13-month period. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The average usage in the first month in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> is statistically insignificant across conditions (p &gt; 0 1). Thus, if the experiment was run for one month, one may conclude that there is no significant difference in usage between PPU and TPT. This explains why the sponsoring firm ran the experiment for 13 months. The longer duration was required because it takes time for consumers to adapt to the new service, and the firm was also interested in the impact of tariff structure on customer churn, which is unlikely to be observed in a short period of time.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> suggests that TPT pricing leads to higher churn than PPU. This result, however, cannot solely be attributed to the pricing structure effect because customers in different conditions faced different price levels. The model we propose will separate out these two effects.</p><p>Note that there are two different TPT conditions-TPT1, wherein there were increases in the fixed fee but the per-minute price remains the same ($0.10 per minute); and TPT2, wherein there were increases in both the fixed fee and the per-minute price. As our interest lies in exploring the access fee effect, we consider a trialist to be in a TPT condition if he or she is either in a TPT1 or in a TPT2 condition. Pooling trialists in TPT1 and TPT2 conditions into a single TPT condition does not pose any significant problems because our proposed model controls for the effect of pricing differences through a budget constraint. Furthermore, our model accounts for consumer heterogeneity using a hierarchical Bayes specification. Thus any residual differences between consumers in TPT1 and those in TPT2 are captured by the individual-level parameters. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Finally, it is important to mention that the field experiment data also included a second PPU condition (not shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>) where customers were charged $0.10 per minute for the entire duration of the experiment. We do not include this condition in our analysis because there is no pricing variability in these data to allow the estimation of consumer-level price sensitivity. However, we can use this condition to assess the empirical validity of our model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Model</head><p>In each period t (t = 1 T , customer i chooses whether to keep or drop the service. This decision depends on the consumer utility from anticipated usage. Conditional on renewal, the customer a Percent dropout is the cumulative percentage of customers in the treatment group who dropped out of the service during the whole experiment.</p><p>then uses the service over the period. Our modeling approach reflects the joint nature of the choice and usage decisions. We build on the traditional unified framework of discrete/continuous consumer choices in which both choices flow from the same underlying utility maximization decision <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Hanemann 1984</ref>). In §3.1, we present the consumer utility function. In § §3.2 and 3.3, we discuss how to use this utility function to model the keep/drop and usage decisions, respectively. We conclude the model development in §3.4 by describing how we capture the impact of pricing structure while controlling for the effects of observed and unobserved sources of consumer heterogeneity and time dependence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Utility Function</head><p>Let Y it = 1 0 if customer i keeps (drops) the service in period t. Then, for a usage level q it by customer i in period t and consumption z it of an outside good (representing the customer expenditures on all other telecommunication services), we specify the following Stone-Geary <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Geary 1950</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">, Stone 1954</ref>) utility function to represent customer i's utility for keeping the service:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">U it Y it = 1 q it z it = it + it Log q it + 1 + it Log z it + 0 (1)</formula><p>where it is an intercept parameter, it &gt; 0 and it &gt; 0 are satiation parameters, and 0 and 1 are translation parameters that allow the indifference curves to intersect the axes. Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Kim et al. (2007)</ref>, we set 0 = 0 to ensure that there is always an interior solution for the composite good and fix 1 = 1 to identify it . <ref type="bibr">5</ref> In Equation ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>), customer i derives his or her utility from accessing and using the service and from consuming the composite good. If the customer decides to drop the service, his or her utility function is then given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">U it Y it = 0 q it = 0 z it = it Log z it (2)</formula><p>Note that we set the intercept of Equation (2) to zero because only differences in intercepts are identified in discrete choice models. Consequently, it in Equation (1) captures the additional utility or disutility a customer derives from having the option to access the service.</p><p>The Stone-Geary utility function we specify in Equation (1) has a number of desirable features. First, it allows diminishing marginal returns from consumption and therefore captures satiation. This is important in our context because more than one unit of usage time is consumed. Second, as we subsequently show, the specification allows the utility function to depend on income (a factor that Danaher 2002 found to be significant) and leads to a tractable demand function. For these reasons, the Stone-Geary utility function has been adopted in past research (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Du and</ref><ref type="bibr">Kamakura 2008, Wales and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Woodland 1983)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Next, we describe how the specified utility function guides the keep/drop decision and the subsequent usage decision.</p><p>Marketing Science 30(5), pp. 820-836, © 2011 INFORMS</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Keep/Drop Decision</head><p>Let I i be customer i's income, and let i be the proportion of his or her income allocated to telecommunication category spending. Thus, i I i represents his or her telecommunication budget. We assume that this budget is constant over the duration of the experiment. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> Let x i be an indicator variable that takes a value of 1 (0) if customer i is assigned to a TPT (PPU) plan. Let F it be the access fee, and let p it be the perminute usage rate for the plan at time t. Note that F it = 0 when x i = 0 (i.e., customer i has a PPU plan). Then assuming a unit price for the composite good z it , customer i faces the following budget constraint:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">p it q it + z it + x i F it ≤ i I i</formula><p>(3)</p><p>A utility-maximizing consumer will exhaust the budget, in which case z it = i I i − x i F it − p it q it Note that we use the telecommunication budget i I i as the relevant income. In such a case, z it represents all other telecommunication goods. This specification is consistent with the finding in past work that consumers often set budgets for categories of expenses (e.g., entertainment) and track expenses against their budget (see e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Thaler 1985)</ref>. It is also consistent with the <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Allenby et al. (2004)</ref> specification of a category-specific budgetary allotment. One implication of using a category-specific budget is that the consumer's expenditure on the service can no longer be considered negligible. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> Because it is not quasilinear, the Stone-Geary specification has the desirable property of allowing for such an income effect. In addition, a log specification captures the decreasing marginal utility of income: a higher price has a lower impact on the utility of high-income consumers than it has on the utility of low-income consumers <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Sudhir 2001)</ref>. Thus, higher (lower) income consumers are more (less) likely to stay with a more expensive plan.</p><p>The decision to continue with the service depends on the maximum level of utility that a consumer can derive from it. To determine this level of utility, a rational customer maximizes his or her utility <ref type="bibr">7</ref> It is possible that the budget changes over time because of, for example, category expansion. We empirically tested for this possibility by specifying a time-varying budget (i.e., it I i . This specification, however, did not improve model fit nor did it affect the empirical results. In particular, consumers in the TPT condition obtain lower utility from the same level of consumption compared with those in the PPU condition ( c = −0 57 with 95% C.I.</p><p>[−0 83 −0 22]). <ref type="bibr">8</ref> A recent report indicates that consumers on average spend approximately 3%-4% of their after-tax income on telecommunications <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Cox and Alm 2008)</ref>. Assuming that consumers spend 4% of their after-tax income on telecommunications, a descriptive analysis of our data set reveals that the average expenditure on the service among our trialists is of the order of 10% of their total telecommunication budget, which is far from negligible.</p><p>in Equation ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>) subject to the budget constraint in Equation (3). Solving this utility maximization problem gives the following optimal quantity: <ref type="formula">1</ref>), we obtain the maximum utility that customer i obtains in period t if he or she continues with the service. This is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">q * it = it it + it i I i − x i F it p it − it it + it (4) Substituting q * it and z it = i I i − x i F it − p it q * it into Equa- tion (</formula><formula xml:id="formula_4">V it Y it = 1 p it F it I i = it + it log q * it +1 + it log i I i −x i F it −p it q * it (5)</formula><p>where q * it is given by Equation ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>). Note that pricing (access fee F it and per-minute usage price p it affects consumer utility directly through the budget constraint and indirectly through the optimal quantity q * it . Similarly, the indirect utility from dropping the service is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">V it Y it = 0 I i = it Log i I i (6)</formula><p>Thus the difference between the indirect utilities derived from keeping the service versus dropping it, which drives the customer keep/drop decision, is</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">w it p it F it I i = it + it log q * it + 1 + it log i I i − x i F it − p it q * it i I i (7)</formula><p>To capture random error in the customer keep/ drop decision, let it be a normally distributed error term. The random utility for the keep/drop decision for customer i in period t is</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">W it p it F it I i = w it p it F it I i + it (8)</formula><p>We assume that it has a mean of 0 and a variance of 2 u1 2 u2 if customer i is assigned to the PPU (TPT) condition. We specify tariff-specific variances to examine whether there is any differential impact of PPU and TPT on consumer uncertainty. Thus, the probability that customer i keeps the service, P Y it = 1 p it , F it , I i = P W it &gt; 0 , in the PPU condition is w it / u1 and in the TPT condition is w it / u2 , where • denotes the cumulative normal distribution function.</p><p>As in any random utility model, the satiation parameters it it and the variance parameters ( 2 u1 2 u2 ) are not separately identified. For identification, we can fix i t = 1 or set either of the variance parameters equal to 1. However, only the ratio it / it + it is estimable (see Equation ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>)). Thus, the parameters it and it cannot be separately identified. Therefore, to ensure that both the utility and the quantity components of our model are identified, we follow <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Allenby et al. (2004)</ref> and arbitrarily set it = 1 (alternatively, we could set it = 1).</p><p>Recall that 0 &lt; i &lt; 1 represents the proportion of income that customer i allocates to telecommunication spending. Our field experiment has data on customers' monthly income but lacks information on the proportion each customer allocates to telecommunication spending. We estimate this latter quantity directly from the data by specifying</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">i = 1 1 + e + i (<label>9</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_9">)</formula><p>where is a parameter that reflects the average percentage expenditure of total income allocated to the telecommunication category, and i is a personspecific random effect, normally distributed with a mean of 0 and a variance of 2 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Usage Decision</head><p>Because of the temporal difference between the time the consumer makes the keep/drop decision and the time he or she consumes the service (which happens during the period), the optimal quantity q * it in Equation ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>) may deviate from the observed quantity q Actual it Following common practice (e.g., Danaher 2002), we postulate a log-log relationship between these two quantities. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> To avoid taking logs of a zero quantity in a particular month, let Q it = q Actual it + 1, and let Q * it = q * it + 1 Then we postulate the following loglog regression of Q it on Q * it :</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">Log Q it = Log Q * it + it = Log it it + 1 + Log i I i − x i F it + p it − Log p it + it (<label>10</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_11">)</formula><p>where it is a random error term.</p><p>To account for time dependence, we decompose the random component it as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">it = q t + it (11)</formula><p>where q t is a period-specific shock, and it is random white noise. We assume that it is normally distributed with a zero mean and a variance of 2 q1 2 q2 when the customer is assigned to the PPU (TPT) condition. We specify tariff-specific variances to examine whether there is any differential impact of PPU and 9 A descriptive analysis of the usage data shows that usage (in minutes per month) in each of the three groups is skewed (with the mean always exceeding the median), and some consumers have extremely high usage. <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Mosteller and Tukey (1977)</ref> recommend a log transformation. Analysis of the log-transformed usage data shows that, for each group, the mean and median are very close, and the histograms of the usage are normally distributed.</p><p>TPT on consumer usage uncertainty. To account for time dependence in customer usage, we specify the following state-space formulation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">q t = q q t−1 + q t q t ∼ N 0 2 q (12)</formula><p>where the initial condition parameter q 0 and the decay parameter q 0 &lt; q &lt; 1) are to be estimated from the data. This error specification represents a stationary, autoregressive process that accounts for time dependence in usage.</p><p>Overall, Equations ( <ref type="formula">8</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_10">10</ref>) specify how customers make the keep/drop and usage decisions. We now discuss how we capture the impact of pricing structure in these models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.">Impact of Tariff Structure</head><p>We use a varying-parameter approach to model the impact of tariff structure (PPU versus TPT) on customers' base-level utility for the service, it , and their utility from consumption, it (see Equation ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>)), while controlling for both observed and unobserved sources of variance resulting from customer heterogeneity and time dependence. 10 3.4.1. Impact on Base-Level Utility. Let QTR jt be a quarterly dummy for period t j = 1 4), where QTR 1t corresponds to the January-March quarter, QTR 2t to the April-June quarter, QTR 3t to July-September quarter, and QTR 4t to the October-December quarter. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> Recall that x i = 1 0 if customer i is assigned to a TPT (PPU) plan. Then we reparametrize the base-level utility parameter it as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">it = u x i + 3 j=1 u j QTR jt + 3 j=1 j x i ×QTR jt + u i + u t (<label>13</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_15">)</formula><p>where u captures the tariff-structure effect, u j j = 1 3 are parameters to capture quarterly seasonality/time effects (with QTR 4t as the baseline quarter), and j j = 1 3 captures how these effects <ref type="bibr">10</ref> The tariff structure may also affect how consumers react to marginal prices. We estimated an ad hoc model where TPT consumers are allowed to react differentially to marginal price. Specifically, the budget constraint is specified as 1</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">+ x i p it q it + z it + x i F it ≤ i I i ,</formula><p>where is a parameter that captures the differential effect. We find that this additional parameter is not significant ( = 0 01 with 95% C.I. [−0 01 0 03]). <ref type="bibr">11</ref> We follow <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Danaher (2002)</ref>, who uses quarterly dummies to capture seasonality. To check the robustness of our results, we estimated our model using two other parsimonious operationalizations of seasonality: (i) a quadratic specification with month and month squared, and (ii) a sine-cosine specification to capture any cyclical variations over time. Both cases resulted in worse model fit than that of our proposed model, which uses a quarterly dummy specification for seasonality. In addition, our key results are not affected by how seasonality is measured.</p><p>Marketing Science 30(5), pp. 820-836, © 2011 INFORMS vary across tariff conditions. The individual-specific parameter u i captures unobserved influences that affect customer i's preference for the service. We assume that u i ∼ N 0 2 u ). Finally, u t is a time-specific error term that captures the unobserved temporal influences on consumer preferences.</p><p>Note that because we observe only 13 months of data, the quarterly dummies confound seasonality and trend effects. In addition, as the marginal and access fee prices were varied over time, these quarterly dummies may seem to confound the experimental price changes as well. However, this is not the case because the price changes are not exactly synchronized over the quarters (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>). For instance, in January (QTR1), we see that the marginal price is $0.15 per minute, whereas in February and March (also in QTR1), the marginal price is $0.30 per minute. More precisely, the correlations of QTR1 with the access fee (F ) and with the per-minute price (p) are, respectively, −0.15 and −0.29. The corresponding correlations for QTR2 are 0.11 and 0.16; those for QTR3 are 0.16 and 0.37. Thus, given these low correlations, the quarterly dummies do not appear to confound the price changes over time.</p><p>Given our context of a new service, consumers can have uncertainty about the quality of the service provider, which they may learn about over time. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Iyengar et al. (2007)</ref> show that quality uncertainty and learning can be captured using a state-space specification. Following their approach, we adopt a state-space specification:</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">u t = u u t−1 + u t u t ∼ N 0 2 u (<label>14</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_18">)</formula><p>where the intitial condition parameter u 0 and the decay parameter u 0 &lt; u &lt; 1) are to be estimated. This specification allows for past service valuation to affect current valuation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.2.">Impact on Utility from Consumption.</head><p>Recall that the satiation parameter it captures the effect of consumption on the utility of the service. As it &gt; 0 we reparametrize it as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">it = exp c 0 + c x i + log q Actual i t−1 + 3 j=1 c j QTR jt + c i (<label>15</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_20">)</formula><p>where c 0 is an intercept, and c is a moderating parameter that captures the impact of tariff structure on it . A positive (negative) c indicates that consumers in the TPT condition obtain higher (lower) utility with the same level of consumption compared with those in the PPU condition. This parameter allows us to assess the impact that the mere presence of an access fee in a TPT scheme, compared with a PPU scheme, may have on consumer utility for the service.</p><p>In addition to the quarterly dummies, we also include in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_19">15</ref>) past consumption (q Actual i t−1 as a covariate to capture the effect of habit formation (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Pollak and Wales 1992)</ref>. Thus, a positive (negative) coefficient indicates that the utility from consumption it increases (decreases) with past usage. As the optimal quantity q * it (see Equation ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>)) is a function of it , such a reparametrization captures how customers update their belief about how much to consume in a future month. Such information guides the service renewal decision (see Equation ( <ref type="formula">8</ref>)). Finally, c</p><p>i is an individual-specific random variable to capture consumers' unobserved heterogeneity. We assume that c i ∼ N 0 2 c . We adopt a Bayesian framework for simulationbased inference. The details of the Bayesian estimation are available from the authors upon request. Before discussing the estimation results, we briefly discuss identification of the model parameters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5.">Identification</head><p>The identification of the model parameters is dependent on consumers' observed churn and consumption decisions as a result of exogenous price changes. For the 13-month duration of the experiment, we observe whether consumers defect or stay with the service. For those who stay, we observe their monthly consumption. We also observe the monthly access fees and per-minute prices that the firm charged across the TPT and PPU conditions.</p><p>Consumers' monthly churn allows us to identify the intercept ( it and the variance terms 2 u1 2 u2 of the utility function. The latter parameters are identified because we fixed the outside good's satiation parameter to 1 (i.e., it = 1 . Both the monthly churn and service usage data, along with the price changes, allow us to identify the effect on utility from consumption ( it and the proportion of income allocated to the telecommunication service ( it . In addition, because consumers are randomly assigned to the PPU and TPT conditions, we can identify the access fee effect as captured by the parameters u and c . That is, we can separately identify utility intercepts and consumption effects for each experimental condition.</p><p>The identification of consumer unobserved heterogeneity is possible because of the panel structure of the data (repeated observations), but it is aided by the changing price levels during the experiment. With every price change, consumers' utilities of staying with the service are changed, leading to different probabilities of churn and different levels of consumption. These variations in the data permit the identification of the distributions of heterogeneity.</p><p>The state-space error structure for both the keep/ drop and usage decisions are identified because of the time-series nature of the churn and usage data. For the same reason, the quarterly effects ( j s) and the habit formation parameter ( are also estimable. It is important to note that, because we observe each quarter only once, the quarterly effects confound any possible seasonality and trend effects.</p><p>Finally, note that our descriptive results in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> indicate that TPT pricing leads to higher churn than does PPU pricing. This result, however, cannot solely be attributed to the impact of pricing structure because customers in different conditions faced different price levels. Moreover, it would be hard to disentangle these underlying effects by only considering summary statistics from data. As a consequence, a formal model is needed to assess the impact of structure on consumer behavior. The identification of the parameters u and c then relies on our choice of the Stone-Geary utility function. This function is ideal for our context: it allows for diminishing marginal returns from consumption, has a tractable demand function, and has good predictive validity (see §4.2). Furthermore, our main results are robust to the choice of utility function (see footnote 6).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Estimation Results</head><p>We estimate our model and four nested models that we now describe. First, to assess the effect of price structure, we estimate a nested model where PPU and TPT pricing do not differentially affect the consumer utility function (i.e., we set the parameters u , c , 1 2 , and 3 to 0). A comparison of the fit of this null model with our model fit can give an indication of the effect size of tariff structure on consumer decisions. We refer to this model as the "no pricestructure effect model." The second nested model, which we call "no time dependence model," assumes no unobserved temporal dependence in consumer preferences. A comparison of the fit of this model with that of our model shows the benefit of accounting for the unobserved sources of time dependence, which we capture through the state-space specification. To assess the magnitude of habit formation, we estimate a third nested model where we set the parameter in Equation (15) to 0. We call this null model "no habit formation model." Finally, to assess the magnitude of heterogeneity in our data, the fourth model constrains all model parameters to be fixed across customers. We refer to this model as the "no heterogeneity model."</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Model Comparison</head><p>We use Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) methods to estimate the five models described above. For each model, we ran sampling chains for 100,000 iterations and assessed convergence by monitoring the time series of the draws. We report the results based on 70,000 draws retained after discarding the initial 30,000 draws as burn-in iterations.</p><p>4.1.1. Goodness of Fit. To compare models, we use the Bayes factor (BF), which accounts for model fit and penalizes model complexity. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> reports the log-marginal likelihoods (LMLs) for all the models. <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Kass and Raftery (1995)</ref> suggest that a value of log BF = (LML M1 −LML M2 greater than 5 provides strong evidence for the superiority of a model. Hence the LML results provide strong evidence for the superiority of our model relative to all other models. Thus, it is important to account for heterogeneity, time dependence, and habit formation effects in the model. More importantly, we note that the no price structure effect model is significantly worse in fit than our model. This shows that TPT and PPU pricing has a significant differential effect on a consumer's decision to keep/drop the service and how much to consume. Later, we discuss the results from a demand analysis that illustrates the consequences of ignoring this effect on pricing the new service.</p><p>We use each model's estimated parameters to assess its fit. We use two measures of fit. The first is the mean absolute deviation for percentage churn (MADchurn), which captures how closely the model predicts actual monthly churn. (Note that we cannot use the mean absolute percentage error because it cannot be calculated for months with no churn.) The second is MAD-usage, which assesses how well the model predicts actual monthly usage (in logarithm scale). Based on these MAD criteria, Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> shows that our proposed model (in bold) has the best fit to the data.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>(a) contrasts actual and predicted churn over time under PPU (panel a) and TPT (panel b) pricing for our model. Note that we only show predictions for months 2 to 13 because the data from month 1 were not used for model estimation as a result of the lagged quantity specification. Similarly, Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Predictive Validity</head><p>Recall that there was a PPU condition in the experiment that did not experience any price change (we dropped this condition from the analysis because the data do not allow us to estimate individual-level price sensitivity parameters). However, we can make use of the data for this condition to assess the out-of-sample predictive validity of our model. For each MCMC draw, we use the population-level distribution to generate parameters for each consumer in the holdout PPU condition. We use these parameters to predict consumer-level churn and usage behavior. Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> Both figures clearly show that our out-of-sample predictions fit the churn and usage data well. In particular, the MAD for percentage churn is 1.90 and that for log usage is 0.23. In addition, we checked for any systematic bias in our churn and usage predictions.    We find an average relative bias for quantity to be 0.01, and the average relative bias for churn is 0.18. These biases are very low in magnitude. Thus our model has good out-of-sample predictive validity, and there is no systematic bias in predictions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Parameter Estimates</head><p>We now discuss the parameter estimates from our model. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref> summarizes the posterior distributions of the parameters by reporting their posterior means and posterior 95% confidence intervals. The results show that the parameter u is positive but insignificant. In addition, none of the interaction effects of TPT with QTR1-QTR3 is significant. These results indicate that, on average, the pricing structure does not have a significant impact on the base-level utility of the service. The pricing structure, however, appears to affect consumer utility from consumption. Specifically, the moderating parameter c is significant and negative. This indicates that consumers in the TPT condition obtain lower utility from the same level of consumption compared with those in the PPU condition. Later, we quantify the size of this "access fee effect" by examining its impact on customer churn and consumption. <ref type="bibr">12</ref> The results also show a significant and positive habit formation effect. Thus, the utility from consumption increases with an increase in customer usage of the service over time, which results in lower likelihood of churn and higher expected usage. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref> shows that all usage quarterly dummies are significant. This suggests that consumption varies significantly over time. Using Equation (9), we find that customers allocate an average of 3.9% (=1/ 1 + exp 3 19 ) of their income to telecommunication spending, consistent with the 3%-4% range reported in <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Cox and Alm (2008)</ref>. We also find that the utility and usage variances do not vary significantly Marketing Science 30(5), pp. 820-836, © 2011 INFORMS across the two pricing conditions. This indicates that the pricing structure does not differentially affect consumer churn and usage uncertainties. Finally, as reflected by the large improvement in LML (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref>), we find significant unobserved heterogeneity in customers' base-level utility, utility from consumption, and budget allocated to telecommunication spending as measured by the parameters 2 u , 2 c , and 2 , respectively. Recall that we specify a state-space formulation to govern the time dependence of customer churn and usage over time. We find the initial value of the base utility, u 0 , to be positive and significant (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref>). This suggests that customers draw positive utility from having access to the service when they initially joined. In contrast, the initial value parameter for usage q 0 is insignificant. We also find significant decay parameters u and q This suggests that both the utility and usage variances are stabilizing over time. Finally, the magnitude of the statespace variance parameters 2 u and 2 q suggests that the observed habit formation and quarterly effects do not fully capture time dependence.</p><p>In sum, we find consumers derive lower utility for TPT compared with PPU plans, resulting in both lower retention of customers and lower usage of the service. This negative impact on retention and usage is true even after controlling for income effects, heterogeneity across customers, and observable and unobservable time-varying factors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Discussion</head><p>We now provide theoretical support for our results and discuss possible alternative explanations and how we rule out such alternatives.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Theoretical Support</head><p>Our finding that TPT customers derive lower utility from the same level of consumption compared with those in the PPU condition supports predictions from the price-partitioning literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bertini and Wathieu 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">, Chakravarthi et al. 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">, Cheema 2008</ref>. This literature suggests that consumers pay more attention to partitioned versus consolidated prices. In addition, payments are more painful when they are decoupled from the benefits of consumption <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Prelec and Loewenstein 1998)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> Furthermore, <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Hamilton and Srivastava (2008)</ref> provide empirical evidence of an <ref type="bibr">13</ref> The flat-fee bias literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Lambrecht and Skiera 2006)</ref> suggests that consumers prefer a flat-fee plan over a PPU plan even when it is the more expensive option. This is because, under a flat-fee plan, consumers know the size of the bill ahead of time, which facilitates any mental prepayment of the expense in their mind <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Prelec and Loewenstein 1998)</ref>. This theory does not apply in our context of TPT for two reasons. First, unlike a flat-fee tariff, consumers do not know the size of the final bill ahead of time.</p><p>inverse relationship between price sensitivity and consumption utility. Thus, as there are no tangible benefits associated with the access fee, consumers in the TPT condition are likely to pay more attention to price and derive less utility from consumption than those in the PPU condition, where the marginal price is directly associated with consumption. <ref type="bibr">14</ref> Our result is also consistent with prospect theory and mental accounting, which suggests that consumers tend to perceive multiple prices as more punishing than a single price of equal amount <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Kahneman and</ref><ref type="bibr">Tversky 1979, Thaler and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Johnson 1990)</ref>. This theory provides a cogent argument in favor of PPU, resulting from a characterization of access services as a bundle of two components. When consuming access services, consumers purchase a bundle of two related but different product components, each with its specific benefit and value driver. The first one is the "access component," that is, the right to access the service if and when desired over the length of the subscription period (option value); and the second one is the "usage component," being the time spent actually using the service (usage value). Under a TPT pricing structure, the price of a service is partitioned, which facilitates a mental accounting assignment of the per-minute price to the usage component of the product bundle and the access fee to its access component. By contrast, under a PPU pricing structure, there is a single consolidated price for the product bundle, and multiple losses are integrated (the component prices), which according to mental accounting would contribute to a rise in the evaluation for the PPU service. Mental accounting would then postulate that a TPT has lower consumer utility because two price components are more punishing than one <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Thaler 1985)</ref>.</p><p>Finally, at first glance, our finding may seem inconsistent with the sunk cost fallacy <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Arkes and Blumer 1985)</ref>. It is important to note, however, that the sunk cost fallacy has been found in the context of flat-fee pricing and not in the context of TPT pricing. We use the findings in <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Heath and Fennema (1996)</ref> to clarify the distinction and to show that our results are consistent with theirs. In a between-subject experiment, Heath and Fennema asked subjects to state how many pool games they would expect to play given an entry fee to a bar and a per-game price for playing pool. The entry fee was varied at three levels ($0, $2, and Second, unlike a flat fee, a TPT has a per-unit charge that acts like a "meter" and maintains the tight coupling between payment and consumption. <ref type="bibr">14</ref> Our model captures the joint effect of the impact of pricing structure on consumption utility and price sensitivity because the satiation parameter ( it and the budget coefficient ( it cannot be separately identified (see Equation ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>)).</p><p>$6), and the per-game price was varied at two levels ($0 and $0.50), leading to six conditions. Note that these conditions include the following: only entry fee and no-per game price (a flat-fee condition), no-entry fee and only a per-game price (a PPU condition), and both an entry fee and a per-game price (a TPT condition). In the flat-fee condition, they found that as the flat fee increased, subjects expected to play more games, which is consistent with the sunk cost fallacy. However, this was not the case in the TPT condition. As the entry fees increased, subjects expected to play fewer games. This result persisted even after controlling for the income effect, which they manipulated by "endowing" subjects in another experimental condition with the equivalent of the entry fee. Thus, the sunk cost fallacy does not appear to hold in a TPT context. Heath and Fennema also find that subjects in the TPT condition expected to play fewer games than those in a PPU condition even after adjusting for income effect. This result is clearly consistent with our access fee finding.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Alternative Explanations</head><p>Recall that all customers faced price increases during the experiment. Those in the TPT condition faced access fee and/or marginal price increases, whereas those in the PPU condition faced only marginal price increases. Thus the access fee effect could alternatively be explained by consumers' differential reactions to price increases. For example, TPT customers may experience higher usage regret than PPU customers because they faced both access fee and marginal price increases. They may also experience a sticker shock or reference price effect. The access fee effect could also be explained by consumers' forward-looking expectations that stem from changing prices. We discuss how we rule out these alternative explanations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.1.">Differential Reactions to Price Increases.</head><p>In principle, the psychological effect of price increases should cancel out because every subject in the experiment experienced a certain price increase, regardless of whether the subject is assigned to a PPU or TPT condition. However, because the price increases are more pronounced in the TPT than the PPU condition, the access fee effect may be accentuated.</p><p>To investigate this issue, recall that the experiment has two two-part tariff conditions-TPT1, where the marginal usage price is fixed and the access fee is increased over the duration of the experiment; and TPT2, where both the marginal and access fees increased. If the magnitude of price increases were the underlying mechanism, then we should expect to find a stronger access fee effect in the TPT2 condition than in the TPT1 condition. We investigated this possibility in two ways. First, we tested for differences between the individual-level parameters for consumers in TPT1 and those in TPT2, but we found no significant difference in these estimates across the two samples (p &gt; 0 05). Second, we estimated our model separately for TPT1 versus PPU and TPT2 versus PPU. We find that our key result still holds and is not statistically different across the two conditions. Specifically, for TPT1 we find c = −0 77 (95% C.I. [−1 03, −0 43]), and for TPT2, c = −0 40 (95% C.I. [−0 63, −0 17]). Thus the magnitude of the price increases does not appear to accentuate the access fee effect.</p><p>Our external validation results (see §4.2) also provide additional evidence that consumers in the TPT and PPU conditions did not react differentially to price changes. Recall that the out-of-sample consumers did not experience any price change. Thus, if price increases are an issue, then we should expect to observe a systematic bias in our predictions. However, our results show that our predictions do not suffer from any systematic biases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.2.">Reference Price Effects.</head><p>To account for such possible effects, we extend our model by including price increases (sticker shocks) as additional covariates. Let Rp it and RF it be the marginal and access fee reference prices in month t, respectively. Then we measure the access fee sticker shock by F it = F it − RF it and the marginal price sticker shock by p it = p it − Rp it . Following the reference price literature (e.g., Neslin and van Heerde 2009), we measure reference prices in three ways: the first month price, the last month price, and an average past price based on all previous months. Note that the use of last month price to measure reference price may be ambiguous as F it takes a zero value for both TPT and PPU conditions when the access fee does not change from month to month. However, F is always positive when the reference price is defined otherwise.</p><p>We estimated our model with the two sticker shock measures as covariates. Specifically, the intercept of the utility function ( it and the coefficient of consumption ( it are as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">it = u x i + 3 j=1 u j QTR jt + 3 j=1 j x i × QTR jt + u 1 F it + u 2 p it + u i + u t (16a) it = exp c 0 + c x i + log q Actual i t−1 + 3 j=1 c j QTR jt + c 1 F it + c 2 p it + c i (16b)</formula><p>Regardless of how we measure reference prices, the results show that our finding of lower utility from consumption for participants in the TPT condition still Marketing Science 30(5), pp. 820-836, © 2011 INFORMS holds. For example, when the reference price is measured by the average past price, we find c = −0 42 with a 95% confidence interval (−0 56 −0 30). We also find that the access fee sticker shock F it is not significant in both the intercept (Equation (16a)) and the coefficient of consumption (Equation ( <ref type="formula">16b</ref>)). Thus the access fee effect is valid and does not confound the sticker-shock effect.</p><p>5.2.3. Forward-Looking Expectations. Our results show a significant and positive habit formation effect (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref>). A possible interpretation of this finding is that consumers use the price changes that they observe in the past to form expectations about future price changes. Because price increases in the TPT condition are higher in magnitude than those in the PPU condition, TPT consumers may reduce their consumption at a faster rate than PPU consumers to avoid an expensive "addiction" in the future. Thus, the differences in price expectations between the TPT and PPU conditions may explain the lower utility from consumption we find for TPT customers.</p><p>It is feasible to embed price expectations into our model, but there are a few design aspects about our field experiment that make this extension unnecessary. First, it is important to note that phone minutes cannot be stored for the new service in our experiment (i.e., no rollover minutes). Thus, there is no benefit in a consumer deliberately using the phone less this month to store minutes for later use (at a possibly lower rate). Second, participants in the experiment were not prewarned of the entire schedule of price changes. They were told in the prior month about pending tariff changes, but they were not told about changes beyond that month. This makes it difficult for participants to anticipate later tariff changes and to change their phone calling behavior in anticipation of tariff increases, because they were unaware of the frequency and amount of the future price changes. Finally, if reference prices are any indication of future price expectations, then our results show that such variables are insignificant, and the access fee effect is robust. For these reasons we do not specifically model consumer expectations.</p><p>To summarize, although it is beyond the scope of this paper to ascertain which underlying mechanism(s) is responsible for the access fee effect, we believe that our key result supports predictions from the price partitioning literature and is consistent with prospect theory and mental accounting. Furthermore, the results of our additional analyses provide sufficient evidence that the access fee effect is not an artifact of the experimental design. Our investigation is focused on empirically documenting the existence of an access fee effect and assessing the magnitude of its impact on service demand and profitability, which we discuss next.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Impact of Tariff Structure on Demand</head><p>We now examine how the demand for the new service is affected by tariff structure and by variations in the per-minute rate and access fee. For each tariff j, we use the MCMC draws of the parameters to predict each customer's monthly keep/drop decision and his or her usage for the month if he or she stays with the service. It is important to note that a customer will exit the service permanently if the model predicts churn in a particular month, and his or her usage is then set to zero thereafter. Note also that the parameters we use to predict demand vary depending on whether tariff j is TPT or PPU. Let R kj be the percentage of retained customers by the end of the year computed from the kth MCMC draw of the parameters given tariff j k = 1 K . Then we measure annual retention under tariff j R j by the average percentage of retained customers across the MCMC draws R j = k R kj /K . Similarly, let C kj be the predicted average yearly usage of the service in the sample using the kth MCMC draw of the parameters given tariff j. Then we measure annual usage under tariff j C j by the average predicted yearly usage across the MCMC draws C j = k C kj /K . In this simulation we use K = 300 simulated draws of the parameters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.">Impact on Annual Retention</head><p>Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref> shows how annual retention varies as a function of tariff structure (PPU versus TPT), per-minute rate, and access fee. Regardless of pricing structure, annual retention decreases with increasing per-minute rate and access fee. More importantly, TPT pricing results in uniformly lower annual retention than PPU pricing, even when the access fee is as low as $10 per month.</p><p>The lower retention rate in the TPT condition stems from two effects. One, for the same level of marginal price, customers in the TPT condition have to pay an additional access fee F . This will decrease their optimal consumption level (see Equation ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>)) and therefore their utility from retaining the service compared with the PPU customers. We call this the "income effect." Two, in our empirical analysis, we found that TPT customers derive lower utility from consumption compared with those in the PPU condition (i.e., lower it . We call this the "access fee effect." To separate out these effects, we performed an additional TPT simulation where we adjusted for the income effect by "endowing" customers with the same amount of the access fee. Thus any remaining difference in annual retention between PPU and TPT is due to the access fee effect. The results of this simulation are shown in Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref> under the retention curve labeled "TPT-income adjusted." For instance, consider the retention values for a per-minute price of p = $0 20. Under this price, a PPU tariff leads to a 68% retention rate, a TPT tariff with an access fee of F = $20 yields a retention rate of 58%, and the income-adjusted TPT has a retention rate of 61%. Thus, the total 10% difference (=68% − 58%) can be split into 7% (=68% − 61%) because of the access fee effect and the remaining 3% because of the income effect. As expected, the contribution of the income effect increases with the level of access fee. For example, when p = $0 20 and F = $50, the retention rate is 42%, which is 26% lower than the retention rate of 68% in the PPU tariff of $0.20. Of this 24% difference, 7% (=68% − 61%) is due to the access fee effect, and the remaining 19% (=61% − 42%) is due to the income effect. A similar analysis can be performed for every per-minute price in Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref>. Overall, across all these price points, we find that TPT leads to a decline of 10.5% in the retention rate relative to PPU that is due purely to the access fee effect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.">Impact on Annual Usage</head><p>Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref> shows how tariff-structure (PPU versus TPT), per-minute rate, and access fee affect annual usage per customer. As expected, regardless of pricing structure, annual usage declines with increasing per-minute rate and access fee. More surprisingly, however, TPT pricing yields uniformly lower annual usage than PPU pricing.</p><p>The difference in usage between PPU and TPT pricing can, as before, be decomposed into income and access fee effects using the "TPT-income adjusted" consumption curve in Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref>. Again, consider a perminute price of p = $0 20. Under this price, the annual usage per customer in the PPU tariff is 2,963 minutes; a TPT with an access fee of $20 yields an annual TPT-Income adjusted usage of 1,518 minutes; and the corresponding "TPTincome adjusted" is 1,860 minutes. Thus, of the total difference of 1,445 minutes (=2963 − 1518), the access fee effect accounts for 1,103 (=2 963 − 1 860) minutes, whereas the income effect accounts for the remaining 342 (=1 860 − 1 518) minutes. Thus, TPT pricing (with F = $20) yields a 37% (= 2 963 − 1 860 /2 963) reduction in usage that is due purely to the access fee effect. As for retention, the contribution of the income effect increases with the level of access fee. Overall, across all price points, we find that TPT pricing leads to an average decrease of 38.7% in usage relative to PPU pricing that is due mainly to the access fee effect. Further decomposition shows that 10.5% of this drop in usage is due to consumer churn; the remaining 28.2% is due to reduction in usage conditional on retention.</p><p>In summary, we find that TPT pricing leads to lower retention and usage compared with PPU pricing over and above what is expected by the income effect. Overall, we find that the access fee effect accounts for 10.5% of the annual retention drop and 38.7% of the annual usage decline under the TPT scheme compared with PPU pricing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">Impact of Tariff Structure on Optimal Pricing Policy</head><p>Recall that our major goals from using the field experiment data are to (i) understand how customers differentially respond to PPU versus TPT pricing;</p><p>(ii) decide on which pricing structure to use when launching the new service; and (iii) depending on the structure chosen, determine the optimal price level(s). The demand analysis in the previous section has studied the first issue. In this section, we address the latter two.  For the purpose of illustration, suppose the variable cost for offering the new service is $0.15 per minute. <ref type="bibr">15</ref> We perform the following grid search to identify the optimal pricing plan for the new service. We evaluate all possible combinations of the pricing factors at discrete points: (1) access fee in increments of $5, ranging from $10 to $60 per month; (2) per-minute rate in increments of 5 cents, ranging from 15 cents per minute to 60 cents per minute; and (3) pricing structure (TPT or PPU). We then identify the pricing plan with the highest annual profit for the service provider. For every pricing plan, we use our proposed model parameters to predict customer annual usage by following the same approach we discussed in the previous section. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">4</ref> describes the pricing plan with the highest yearly profit per customer, one obtained assuming PPU pricing and the other assuming TPT pricing. The profit calculations are conditional on customer acquistion and do not account for acquisition cost. <ref type="bibr">16</ref> For comparison, Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">4</ref> also reports these same quantities obtained using the "no price structure" model, which ignores the access fee effect.</p><p>Despite the higher customer churn and lower usage, we find that TPT is still the profit-maximizing pricing structure for our proposed model. As expected, the optimal per-minute price of this TPT policy ($0.35/min) is lower than that of the PPU policy ($0.50/min). For PPU, our proposed model recommends a higher per-minute price than does the no price structure model. This is because of the higher PPU utility from consumption obtained from our model compared to that of the no price structure model. For TPT, our model identifies a lower access fee compared with the one suggested by the no price <ref type="bibr">15</ref> We can calculate the variable cost per minute by dividing the operating costs (revenue − EBITDA) of the provider by the total number of mobile minutes. For instance, for AT&amp;T, by September 2008, the total operating costs were $10,239 million, and the total number of minutes consumed by subscribers was 54,995 million minutes. This leads to a cost per minute of around $0.18 per minute. Other service providers such as Verizon have similar costs. <ref type="bibr">16</ref> It is possible that it may cost more to induce a customer to sign up for a TPT plan compared with a PPU plan. This will further diminish the difference in profitability from the optimal TPT and PPU plans. structure model. This difference stems from the lower TPT utility from consumption in our proposed model, which is due to the access fee effect that the no price structure model fails to capture.</p><p>Overall, ignoring the access fee effect results in underestimating the profitability of PPU pricing and overestimating it for TPT pricing. This falsely accentuates the difference between TPT and PPU profits. Using the proposed model, the optimal TPT scheme provides 12% (= 318 − 283 /283) higher annual profit per customer compared with the PPU tariff. In contrast, using the no price structure model, the optimal TPT scheme gives almost 59% (= 410 − 258 /2 584) higher annual profit per customer compared with the PPU tariff.</p><p>To further explore the managerial implications from ignoring the access fee effect, we use the proposed model to assess the profitability of the optimal pricing plans identified by the no price structure model. This mimics a scenario in which a firm may erroneously set the optimal prices without considering the access fee effect, when, in reality, their customers behave as indicated by our proposed model. Thus, this analysis indicates the magnitude of profit reduction that will ensue from using a misspecified model. We find that the firm should make an annual profit of $284 and $271 per customer under TPT and PPU pricing, respectively. Given that TPT pricing is optimal for both models, the firm would therefore be forgoing a $34 (=318 − 284) profit per customer per year. Put differently, the failure to account for the access fee effect leads to about an 11% (= 318 − 284 /318) reduction in the firm's profit.</p><p>Our profit estimates are biased upward because the model parameters for profit maximization are estimated with error (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Mannor et al. 2007</ref>). We adapted the Mannor et al. cross-validation approach to assess the magnitude of this bias. We randomly divided our sample of customers into two subsamples, a calibration sample and a validation sample. We used the calibration sample estimates from our proposed model to derive optimal PPU and TPT pricing tariffs. We then used the optimal tariffs to calculate the annual profit per customer in both the calibration and validation samples. The difference between the annual profits calculated from the calibration (Profit cal and the validation sample (Profit val provides an estimate of the bias. We find that the optimal PPU and TPT tariffs based on the calibration sample are the same as those obtained from the full sample (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">4</ref>), albeit with lower annual profit per customer as expected. Specifically, Profit cal for PPU (TPT) is $274.13 ($316.24), and Profit val for the PPU (TPT) is $262.90 <ref type="bibr">($308.80</ref>). Thus, we find an upward bias of 3.9% (= 274 13 − 262 90 /283) for PPU and 2.3% (= 316 24 − 308 80 /318) for TPT.</p><p>It may not be surprising that TPT is the optimal tariff structure because PPU is a special case of a twopart tariff when the access fee is zero. Therefore, the profit from PPU cannot exceed that from TPT <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Oi 1971)</ref>. This result, however, assumes that the demand curve is invariant to the pricing structure. That is, usage at a given per-unit price is the same regardless of whether the consumer has a PPU or a TPT plan. However, as we have shown in this paper, the price structure can influence consumers' consumption. In such a case, it is possible that a TPT scheme may not be optimal. See the electronic companion to this paper, available as part of the online version that can be found at http://mktsci.pubs.informs.org/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.">Conclusion</head><p>Past research in psychology and marketing suggests that the pricing structure a firm chooses can alter consumers' value for a product or a service. In this paper, we focus on two commonly used pricing structures (two-part tariff and pay-per-use) and empirically quantify their impact on consumer preferences. We develop a utility-based model of consumer usage and retention of a subscription service that allows the model parameters to vary with the type of pricing structure faced by the customer (PPU or TPT). An important feature of our model is its ability to disentengle the access fee effect from the income effect and to measure its impact on consumer retention and usage, as well as on pricing policy. Moreover, our model controls for various sources of observed and unobserved consumer heterogeneity and time dependence.</p><p>Using data from a pricing field experiment for a new telecommunication service, we find that consumers have significantly lower utility from consumption for TPT compared with PPU pricing plans, resulting in both lower retention of customers and lower usage of the service. Our demand analysis shows that a TPT structure leads to an average decline of 11% in the annual retention rate and an average decrease of 38.7% in yearly usage relative to PPU pricing, even after controlling for income effects. Despite the higher customer churn and lower usage, we find that TPT is still the profit-maximizing pricing structure. In particular, our results show that a firm would overcharge customers for the access fee and undercharge them for the per-minute price if it ignores the access fee effect. In terms of profitability, the failure to account for such an effect leads to a reduction of 11% in firm profit.</p><p>In this paper we considered the impact of PPU and TPT pricing structures on the demand for a new access service offered by a monopolist. Future research should generalize this investigation to include other pricing structures (e.g., three-part tariffs) and services that operate in a competitive environment. Our field experiment's design randomly assigned customers to PPU and TPT pricing conditions. As such, we cannot model consumers' choice between plans. Future research could examine the impact of pricing structure not only on retention and consumption but on consumer tariff choice as well. A related area of research concerns the use of CRM databases or natural experiments. Although such data are more realistic, they suffer from consumer self-selection issues and limited variability in prices over time compared with field experiment data. Finally, our model did not include consumer expectations about future price changes. It would be frutiful to extend the model in a dynamic, structural fashion to examine the differential impact of pricing structure on consumer demand.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9.">Electronic Companion</head><p>An electronic companion to this paper is available as part of the online version that can be found at http:// mktsci.pubs.informs.org/.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1(a) Actual vs. Predicted Churn by Pricing Condition (a) PPU</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(a) contrasts actual and predicted churn, and Figure 2(b) compares actual and predicted monthly service usage in minutes per trialist (in logarithm scale) averaged across the MCMC draws.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2(a) Actual vs. Predicted Churn for the Holdout Condition</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3Impact of Pricing Structure on Annual Retention</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 4Impact of Pricing Structure on Annual Usage</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Field Experiment Description</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Treatment group</cell><cell>PPU</cell><cell></cell><cell>TPT1</cell><cell></cell><cell>TPT2</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Number of trialists</cell><cell>75</cell><cell></cell><cell>69</cell><cell></cell><cell>70</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Number of dropouts</cell><cell>19</cell><cell></cell><cell>28</cell><cell></cell><cell>32</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Percent dropout a</cell><cell>25.3</cell><cell></cell><cell>40.6</cell><cell></cell><cell>45.7</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Avg. first-month usage</cell><cell cols="2">321.8 min.</cell><cell cols="2">371.6 min.</cell><cell>266.0 min.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Standard deviation</cell><cell>363.6</cell><cell></cell><cell>404.2</cell><cell></cell><cell>250.4</cell></row><row><cell>Prices changes</cell><cell>Access</cell><cell>Usage</cell><cell>Access</cell><cell></cell><cell>Usage</cell><cell>Access</cell><cell>Usage</cell></row><row><cell>over time</cell><cell>$/month</cell><cell>$/min.</cell><cell cols="2">$/month</cell><cell>$/min.</cell><cell>$/month</cell><cell>$/min.</cell></row><row><cell>Oct (First month)</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0 1</cell><cell>10</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 1</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>0 1</cell></row><row><cell>Nov-Jan</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0 15</cell><cell>15</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 1</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>0 15</cell></row><row><cell>Feb-Apr</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0 3</cell><cell>25</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 1</cell><cell>25</cell><cell>0 3</cell></row><row><cell>May-Oct</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0 6</cell><cell>35</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 1</cell><cell>35</cell><cell>0 6</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Model Performance Comparison</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Model</cell><cell>LML a</cell><cell>MAD-churn (%)</cell><cell>MAD-usage</cell></row><row><cell>Proposed</cell><cell>− 2 902 4 b</cell><cell>0 65</cell><cell>0 11</cell></row><row><cell>No price structure</cell><cell>−2 926 3</cell><cell>0 90</cell><cell>0 14</cell></row><row><cell>effect</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>No time dependence</cell><cell>−3 028 5</cell><cell>1 03</cell><cell>0 26</cell></row><row><cell>No habit formation</cell><cell>−3 115 4</cell><cell>0 97</cell><cell>0 15</cell></row><row><cell>No heterogeneity</cell><cell>−3 564 7</cell><cell>1 10</cell><cell>0 15</cell></row></table><note>a LML denotes log-marginal likelihood. b Selected model.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Parameter Estimates: Posterior Means and Posterior 95% Confidence Interval</figDesc><table><row><cell>Description</cell><cell>Param. label</cell><cell>Posterior mean a</cell><cell>95% posterior interval</cell></row><row><cell>Impact on base-level utility</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>TPT indicator (x i )</cell><cell>u</cell><cell>0 73</cell><cell>(−1.31, 2.23)</cell></row><row><cell>QTR1</cell><cell>u 1</cell><cell>0 93</cell><cell>(−1.21, 2.79)</cell></row><row><cell>QTR2</cell><cell>u 2</cell><cell>0 18</cell><cell>(−1.98, 2.39)</cell></row><row><cell>QTR3</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Optimal Pricing Policy</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Proposed</cell><cell cols="2">No price structure</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>model</cell><cell></cell><cell>model</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>PPU</cell><cell>TPT</cell><cell>PPU</cell><cell>TPT</cell></row><row><cell>Per-minute price ($)</cell><cell>0.50</cell><cell>0.35</cell><cell>0.40</cell><cell>0.25</cell></row><row><cell>Access fee</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>$40</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>$55</cell></row><row><cell>Annual usage</cell><cell cols="4">810 min. 513 min. 1,034 min. 1,065 min.</cell></row><row><cell>Annual retention (%)</cell><cell>62</cell><cell>45</cell><cell>61</cell><cell>46</cell></row><row><cell>Annual profit per customer ($)</cell><cell>283</cell><cell>318</cell><cell>258</cell><cell>410</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">In this paper, we do not study consumer choice between a PPU or a TPT plan. Instead, we examine consumption behavior given a customer subscription to a PPU or TPT plan.2  <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Danaher (2002)</ref> focuses on deriving the optimal pricing of the new subscription service regardless of the pricing structure effect. In contrast, this paper focuses on assessing the moderating impact of the pricing structure on consumer preferences, retention, and usage, as well as its implications for optimal pricing.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">We removed two outliers from the data because they had abnormally excessive usage during the experiment.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">In our empirical analysis, we found no significant differences between the parameter estimates of consumers in these two conditions. In addition, we performed two separate model estimations: PPU versus TPT1 and PPU versus TPT2. The empirical results show that our findings are statistically indistinguishable across these two comparisons.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">The restriction 1 = 1 ensures that the indifference curves will have finite nonzero slope at the axes, creating the possibility of a corner solution, whereby an active subscriber would optimally choose not to consume any minutes of usage (despite having access to the service). SeeDeaton and Muellbauer (1980, p. 65).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">For comparison, we also tested the following utility function:U it Y it = 1 q it z it = it + it q it + it Log z itThis specification, which also preserves income and has a tractable demand function, results in a poorer model fit than that for the Stone-Geary utility function. This suggests that capturing diminishing return is important for cell phone usage. More importantly, our empirical results are unaffected by the choice of the utility function. In particular, consumers in the TPT condition obtain lower utility from the same level of consumption compared with those in the PPU condition ( c = −0 40 with 95% C.I. [−0 58 −0 23]).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="12">Technically, the access fee effect combines the effects of pricing structure on both the base-level utility and the utility from consumption.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors benefited greatly from comments by Marco Bertini; Amar Cheema; the Marketing Science review team; and seminar attendees at the Olin Business School, Washington University at St. Louis; the Kenan-Flagler Business School, University of North Carolina; the Kellogg School of Management, Northwestern University; the Fall 2009 Wharton Brown Bag series, the 2009 Koç-Özyegin-Sabancı Marketing Workshop, the 2010 Eighth Triennial Choice Symposium, and the 2009 and 2010 INFORMS Marketing Science Conferences.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A choice model for packaged goods: Dealing with discrete quantities and quantity discounts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Shively</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Garratt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="108" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effect of $9 price endings on retail sales: Evidence from field experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Simester</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychology of sunk cost</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Arkes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Blumer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organ. Behav. Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124" to="140" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">When talk is &quot;free&quot;: The effect of tariff structure on usage under twoand three-part tariffs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ascarza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lambrecht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Vilcassim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Columbia University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Working paper</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Research note-Attention arousal through price partitioning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bertini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Wathieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="236" to="246" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Partitioned presentation of multicomponent bundle prices: Evaluation, choice and underlying processing effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Chakravarthi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Krish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Paul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Psych</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="229" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surcharges and seller reputation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cheema</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="167" to="177" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">You are what you spend</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Cox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Alm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/02/10/opinion/10cox.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New York Times</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-02-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal pricing of new subscription services: Analysis of a market experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Danaher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="138" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="820" to="836" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Economics and Consumer Behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Deaton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Muellbauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Where did all that money go? Understanding how consumers allocate their consumption budget</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>Du</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kamakura</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="131" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pricing access services</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Essegaier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="159" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A note on &quot;A constant-utility index of the cost of living</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Geary</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="1950" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When 2 + 2 is not the same as 1 + 3: Variations in price sensitivity across components of partitioned prices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="450" to="461" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discrete/continuous models of consumer demand</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Hanemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="541" to="561" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mental depreciation and marginal decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Heath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Fennema</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organ. Behav. Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="108" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model of consumer learning for service quality and usage</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Iyengar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ansari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="529" to="544" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A conjoint approach to multipart pricing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Iyengar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Jedidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kohli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="210" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prospect theory: An analysis of decision under risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="292" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayes factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Raftery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">430</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="773" to="795" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Product attributes and models of multiple discreteness</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rossi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">138</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="208" to="230" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Option value, telecommunications demand and policy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kridel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Lehman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Weisman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inform. Econom. Policy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="144" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Paying too much and being happy about it: Existence, causes, and consequences of tariff-choice biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lambrecht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Skiera</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="212" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does uncertainty matter? Consumer behavior under three-part tariffs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lambrecht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Seim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Skiera</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="698" to="710" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bias and variance approximation in value function estimates</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mannor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Simester</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Tsitsiklis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="308" to="322" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Apple&apos;s iPod system: iPod, iTunes and FairPlay. Case 9B06M080</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<pubPlace>London, ON, Canada</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Richard Ivey School of Business, University of Western Ontario</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Virgin Mobile USA: Pricing for the Very First Time</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mcgovern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>Harvard Business School Publishing</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Boston</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Data Analysis and Regression: A Second Course in Statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Mosteller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Tukey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Reading, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choosing the wrong calling plan? Ignorance and learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Miravete</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="310" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of self-selection, usage uncertainty and learning in the demand for local telephone service</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Narayanan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Miravete</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="34" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Neslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Heerde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Promotion dynamics. Foundations Trends Marketing</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="268" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Disneyland dilemma: Two-part tariffs for a Mickey Mouse monopoly. Quart</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Oi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="96" />
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Demand System Specification and Estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pollak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wales</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The red and the black: Mental accounting of savings and debt</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Prelec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transaction decoupling: How price bundling affects the decision to consume</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Soman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Gourville</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="30" to="44" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linear expenditure systems and demand analysis: An application to the pattern of British demand</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">255</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="511" to="527" />
			<date type="published" when="1954" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competitive pricing behavior in the auto market: A structural analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sudhir</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="42" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonlinear pricing of information goods</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sundararajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1660" to="1673" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mental accounting and consumer choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="214" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gambling with the house money and trying to break even: The effects of prior outcomes on risky choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="643" to="660" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimation of consumer demand systems with binding non-negativity constraints</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wales</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Woodland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="285" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
