<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Cryptocurrency Adoption with Speculative Price Bubbles</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2013-04">April 2013 to May 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Max</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Marshall School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>90089</postCode>
									<settlement>Los Angeles</settlement>
									<region>California</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Marshall School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>90089</postCode>
									<settlement>Los Angeles</settlement>
									<region>California</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><surname>Dukes</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Marshall School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>90089</postCode>
									<settlement>Los Angeles</settlement>
									<region>California</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Marshall School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>90089</postCode>
									<settlement>Los Angeles</settlement>
									<region>California</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Cryptocurrency Adoption with Speculative Price Bubbles</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 (print)</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2013-04">April 2013 to May 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.2020.1247</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: June 1, 2019 Revised: December 24, 2019; May 4, 2020 Accepted: May 28, 2020</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:30+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>product adoption</term>
					<term>diffusion</term>
					<term>cryptocurrency</term>
					<term>speculative bubbles</term>
					<term>currency marketing Cryptocurrency Adoption with Speculative Price Bubbles</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Currencies have been utilized for millennia as mediums of exchange in economic transactions. Governments have historically marketed new currencies to help facilitate trade in their economies. The most recent major currency launched by a government institution was the euro in 1999. Recently, even nongovernment agents are able to market new currencies in digital formats. Since bitcoin emerged in 2009, there have been more than 1,600 cryptocurrencies introduced. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> This research studies product diffusion in the context of a new cryptocurrency.</p><p>An important feature of a cryptocurrency is that it is particularly susceptible to speculative price bubbles, caused by investors who exploit currency exchange for speculative gains. Speculative beliefs of investors, very often detached from the fundamental value of a currency, can drastically affect the price that noninvestors, the users, pay to utilize the currency as a medium of exchange. Unlike a traditional currency, for which the government can manipulate the supply to combat bubbles, the supply of a cryptocurrency is typically set to follow a predetermined path, thereby making it more prone to price bubbles. A second important feature of a currency is its network externality. A user's benefit from adoption depends on the number of other users with whom to exchange. The symbiotic relationship between this network effect and speculative incentives implies adoption dynamics that are different than other new products (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bass 1969)</ref>. In light of this relationship, we ask, how does the presence of investors, who are interested in speculative returns, affect the diffusion of a new currency? And how does the adoption by users affect the creation of speculative price bubbles?</p><p>These questions are connected to the recent and heated attention around bitcoin, especially in the years 2013 and 2017, which witnessed surges in bitcoin price. It is tempting to attribute the price surges to overoptimistic expectation of growth in bitcoin usage. But we entertain the reverse mechanism by asking whether the bubbles may have contributed to growth of bitcoin usage. Indeed, absent a formalized model, it is hard to answer this question. On one hand, speculative investors holding bitcoins may have weakened the transactional role of bitcoins, reducing users' benefit of adoption. On the other hand, a bubble could boost adoption by virtue of the network effects spurred by investors.</p><p>Our formalization starts by considering the demand for currency speculation by investors only. This benchmark illustrates conditions for which bubbles can sustain without users. Investors decide whether to participate in the currency market based on expectations about tomorrow's price of the currency. Their expectations are rational, meaning that they are consistent with the realization of tomorrow's price. Investors also rationally expect crashes-events where the price drops to zero. In other words, our analysis focuses on fully rational investors who seek out shortterm gains. We refrain from adding behavioral factors (such as emotional responses or fears) to examine the most demanding environment for bubbles to form.</p><p>Without behavioral factors, the key requirement in the formation of bubbles is investor confidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Weil 1987)</ref>. A product can be valued above its fundamental value only if there is a minimum degree of confidence among agents that the currency will be no less valuable in the future, which, if fails to happen, implies a crash.</p><p>Next, we introduce currency adoption by users who demand currency as a medium of exchange and have no desire for speculative returns. The simultaneous presence of users and investors implies their interdependence on the equilibrium price path of the currency. Specifically, users must take into account the additional network externality implied by investors, who accept and provide liquidity for the currency. At the same time, investors take into account users' demand for currency as a medium of exchange as it affects the price tomorrow and subsequently the speculative return. Our model formally accounts for this interdependent demand and allows us to discern between the currency's speculative value and its fundamental value. The currency's fundamental value is defined as its price when no speculative investors participate in the market. Investors can drive up the price beyond this value, generating speculative value, in the form of a price bubble. A bubble may burst-dropping the price to the fundamental value.</p><p>We establish two results. First, the adoption of a currency is accelerated by the bubble generated by speculative investors. The literature on product diffusion has focused on products without financial or investment value <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bass 1969)</ref>. Our model demonstrates that the price bubbles induce faster adoption rates than without investors. This result has implications for any government or nongovernment agent whose objective is to induce diffusion of a currency. Specifically, it suggests that opening up the currency to investors at its launch can help to achieve adoption goals. Indeed, it is worthwhile to note that the European Monetary Union initially launched the euro in 1999 only to investors, before rolling it out as a physical currency in 2002 (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Wikipedia 2020)</ref>. Our theory provides a rationale for such a launch strategy.</p><p>Our second result states that the presence of users relaxes the conditions for a bubble to form and grow. Specifically, we show that the level of investor confidence needed to sustain a bubble decreases when there is more fundamental demand from users. Intuitively, the relaxation comes from an increased expectation in the currency's future fundamental value due to user adoption. What is interesting, however, is that even in the case where investing in the fundamental value provides zero expected return, <ref type="bibr">2</ref> we show that such relaxation still holds. This result is due precisely to the reinforcing interplay between investors and users, which raises an investor's expected return beyond the return from investing in fundamental value.</p><p>These effects may help us understand the path of bitcoin prices, which is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">1</ref>. Consider the steep ascent, around November 2013, when the Shared Coin service was offered publicly for free. This service offered anonymity in transactions by mixing cryptocurrency funds to obscure the trail back to a fund's original source <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Athey et al. 2016)</ref>. Arguably, this new service increased the potential user base for bitcoin. Through the lens of our model, the price volatility starting in late 2013 can be explained in a completely rational way by the relaxed confidence requirement to trigger a bubble. In other words, as Shared Coin attracted more users, the necessary confidence for bubbles had been relaxed, permitting easier conditions for speculative participation. By the end of 2015, the price stabilized around $250, which is greater than the price before Shared Coin's introduction. This, according to our model, would be reflective of the increased fundamental value of bitcoin as a medium of exchange. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The above story is not without limits, however. A rational bubble can unravel, which would negate the participation of investors and, consequently, any user-investor interaction. Specifically, as the price in a bubble grows, investors' confidence (i.e., expectation of tomorrow's price) must also grow for the expected return to stay nonnegative. A bubble becomes unsustainable at some point if it requires a level of confidence so high that is infeasible given the possible demand and supply for currency tomorrow. As early-period investors rationally anticipate this lack of sustainability, they refuse to participate and the bubble unravels. We find that a key moderator for the existence of bubbles is the financial role of investors relative to their role in adoption.</p><p>When investors have a large financial capacity to drive up today's price relative to the network externality they exert on adoption, bubbles are easier to unravel. In such cases, even those bubbles that do not unravel turn out to be likely to crash early on, before they grow to significant sizes. In fact, with model primitives realistic to the bitcoin's history, a bubble of any significance is almost impossible in a setting without users (or where investors exert little network externality on users).</p><p>Our work combines the product diffusion literature in marketing with the currency formation and asset bubble literature in macrofinance. In marketing, starting with <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bass (1969)</ref>, the product diffusion literature examines the path of consumer adoption following the introduction of an innovative product. Subsequent work augments the classic work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bass (1969)</ref> to include imitators and influencers <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Steffens and</ref><ref type="bibr">Murthy 1992, Van den Bulte and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Joshi 2007)</ref>. Much of that prior work implicitly assumes network externalities where the probability that a user adopts depends on the latest adopter population. Network externalities are a key property of currency and are an essential aspect of our main effects. There has also been great interest in marketing on the empirical evaluation of diffusion models and on network externalities (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bass et al. 1994</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">, Bronnenberg and Mela 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">, Garber et al. 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">, Shriver 2015</ref>. However, neither the theory nor the empirical literature has explored the role of price bubbles.</p><p>Within the finance literature, there are several groundlaying theory works on asset bubbles. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Blanchard (1979)</ref> first pointed out that bubbles do not necessarily indicate irrational behaviors-speculative bubbles followed by market crashes can be consistent with the assumption of rational expectations. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Tirole (1982</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Tirole ( , 1985</ref> showed that under rational expectation, shortterm investors (instead of infinitely lived agents) are necessary for sustaining speculative detachment from fundamental values. As a result, our model features investors seeking short-term gains. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Tirole (1982</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Tirole ( , 1985</ref> considered only deterministic models. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Weil (1987)</ref> extended the analysis to stochastic bubbles with the possibility of crashes. In doing so, he introduced the concept of confidence: a bubble can exist only if there is enough confidence that it will persist (not crash). Following his work, we focus on evaluating how the confidence level required for a bubble to exist is affected by the presence of user adoption.</p><p>Since then, there have been more studies exploring factors behind the formation of bubbles. While largely maintaining the assumption of rational expectations, these studies focus on various deviations from perfect markets in the form of market frictions. These include asymmetric information <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Allen and Gorton 1993)</ref>, the inability of arbitrageurs to synchronize selling strategies <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abreu and Brunnermeier 2003)</ref>, risk aversion <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Branch and Evans 2011)</ref>, and portfolio constraints <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Hugonnier 2012)</ref>. Our objective is not to provide another explanation of bubbles, per se, but rather to understand the interplay between speculative incentives and product adoption, or, put more broadly, the mutual impact between investors and users.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">The Market for Currency</head><p>The demand for currency in our model comes from two sources: investors and users. Investors demand currency on the expectation that they can sell it in the future for a speculative gain. Users demand currency to conduct transactions with others. Users can be interpreted as merchants and customers exchanging goods and services. We start by examining the demand for currency by investors only. By doing so, we illustrate how a currency bubble can survive from purely speculative demand. We then incorporate user demand for the full model to capture how these two sources of currency demand interact. Later, in Section 3, we derive equilibrium properties of the full model. We compare the bubbly and nonbubbly equilibria in the full model to analyze the effect of a bubble on adoption. We compare the bubbly equilibria in the full model and in the investor-only model to analyze the effect of user adoption on bubble formation.</p><p>Before detailing the model, it is useful to point out that we separate the roles of investors and users as a way to isolate the different mechanisms (speculative investment and transactional usage) and see how they interact. In reality, an agent may assume both roles. Our model does not forbid such a view, as long as the agent keeps separate accounts for transactional and investment purposes. Modeling the portfolio decision (how much to allocate across investments and transactions), however, is beyond the scope of this paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Investor Only</head><p>There are T discrete periods. In every period t 1, . . . , T, an investor is endowed with y dollars. She may invest in either the coins or an outside option. For simplicity, assume that the outside option provides an interest rate r 0. 4 Let p t denote the price of a coin in period t. A risk-neutral investor 5 decides whether to buy coins in period t based on the belief about the next period's price, E(p t+1 ). We parameterize the belief in the following way:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">p t+1</formula><p>L t ω t with probability ω t , 0 with probability 1 − ω t .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>{</head><p>(1)</p><p>In the investor's belief, ω t represents the probability that a positive price will sustain in t + 1, and L t &gt; 0 is the maximum possible price level in period t + 1. Both ω t and L t are determined by rational expectation, The single parameter ω t captures the level of investor confidence in the coin's price next period. A larger value of ω t simultaneously implies a stronger belief that a crash will not happen tomorrow and a higher expected price tomorrow: E(p t+1 ) L t ω 2 t . The notion of investor confidence is borrowed from <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Weil (1987)</ref>, who shows how currency bubbles can emerge in an overlapping generations model similar to ours. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> Specifically, an investor in period t is willing to buy coins at price p t only if the expected return satisfies</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">E(p t+1 ) p t</formula><p>≥ 1, or equivalently, L t p t ω t 2 ≥ 1. This describes the behavior of investors, who are price takers. Given a price p t , if confidence ω t is such that the expected return is larger than 1, then each investor's demand for coins is equal to y/p t &gt; 0. If the expected return is smaller than 1, the demand is zero.</p><p>We suppose that there is a supply of coins A t for period t. In what follows, we assume that the supply is increasing over time (i.e., no coins are destroyed). Let N &gt; 0 be the total mass of investors. Let n t &lt; N be the mass of investors that buy coins in period t. The remaining N − n t do not buy. Then, for the market to clear, we require the condition yn t p t A t .</p><p>The highest possible price level for period t, L t−1 , happens when every investor demands coins, so</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">yN L t−1 A t ,</formula><p>or simply L t−1 yN/A t . For any p t ∈ (0, L t−1 ), we must have some investors buying coins while some others do not buy (i.e., 0 &lt; n t &lt; N). 8 This requires investors to be indifferent between buying the coins and buying the outside good; the expected return must be 1:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">L t p t ω 2 t 1.<label>(2)</label></formula><p>This equality bears the same spirit as the arbitragefree condition that underlies the efficient market hypothesis in finance. 9 Throughout this paper, we employ the notion of rational expectations to compare outcomes across various settings. This requires investors to be correct about tomorrow's price in equilibrium. In other words, prices are realized exactly according to investors' beliefs in equilibrium. So, as long as the bubble is sustained (i.e., a crash has not happened), we have p t+1 L t ω t , which, together with equality in (2), implies the following recursive relationship:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">ω t+1 ̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅ ̅ A t+2 A t+1 ω t √ .<label>(3)</label></formula><p>This equation characterizes the evolution of investor's confidence in equilibrium. One obvious confidence path is ω t 0 for all t, which implies p t 0 for all t. This path actually corresponds to the nonbubbly equilibrium. In what follows, we shall focus on interior equilibria in which ω t ∈ (0, 1), and therefore a crash remains a meaningful, but uncertain, possibility. What we have characterized so far, a bubbly equilibrium, signifies a realized event in which investors' demand sustains a positive price from period to period. The price path is supported by demand from investors, who rationally expect such a price path as well as the risk of crash. We formally define a bubbly equilibrium as follows.</p><p>Definition 1. Given y, N, and {A t } T t 1 , a bubbly equilibrium is a sequence {ω t , n t , p t } T t 1 with ω t ∈ (0, 1) that satisfies the following conditions for t 1, . . . , T: (i) the market clears, yn t /p t A t ; (ii) the expected return is equal to 1, L t ω 2 t /p t 1; and (iii) price p t+1 is rationally expected as ω t L t .</p><p>It is important to note that a bubbly equilibrium is defined conditional on the bubble being sustained. When we say that {p t } T t 1 is part of a bubbly equilibrium, we mean that these will be the realized prices as long as the bubble does not crash. It is understood that in every period t, there is probability 1 − ω t−1 that the price ends up being 0 (the bubble bursts). When such an event happens, the prices and investor sizes will be zero thereafter.</p><p>Equation (3) says that a bubbly equilibrium, if it exists, is unique for any given ω 1 under our model specifications. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> To ensure the existence of a bubbly equilibrium, we must specify two boundary conditions. First, for a finite T, we must assume that the investors in period T + 1 are guaranteed an "exit interest rate" equal to 1. This assumption effectively eliminates the "end-period effect" because the investors in the last period need not form a belief on tomorrow's price. We allow T ∞ to capture the situation of no such exit interest rate. Second, we must keep the value of ω t meaningful. If A t is strictly increasing over time and we mechanically follow Equation (3), then ω t is strictly increasing over time too, and may become larger than 1 in some period t, which would imply the unraveling of the candidate bubble backward from t. Given any T, we can ensure that ω 1 , . . . , ω T &lt; 1 by starting with a sufficiently small ω 1 . In other words, there is an upper bound, Ω(T), such that the bubbly equilibrium exists for T iff ω 1 ≤ Ω(T). It is not difficult to see that Ω(T) is decreasing in T. The following lemma characterizes Ω(∞) under a specific supply path that we focus on later.</p><p>Lemma 1. In the investor-only setting with A t 1 − β t , β ∈ (0, 1), a bubbly equilibrium exists for T ∞ iff</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">ω 1 ≤ 1 − β 2 ( )∏ ∞ k 3 1 − β k ( ) 2 k−3 ≡ Ω ∞ ( ).</formula><p>For any T &lt; ∞, the above inequality becomes a sufficient condition for a bubbly equilibrium to exist.</p><p>The intuition behind this upper bound is that a high ω 1 leads to a high price being rationally expected in the second period, which makes coins unattractive to the second-period investors. The same logic applies to later periods. If ω 1 is so high that the investors in a later period are unwilling to buy coins even with full confidence, then the bubble unravels.</p><p>In Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">2</ref>, we numerically compute the upper bound Ω(T) for T ∞ (and T 5 for comparison). For reasonably large values of β, such as β &gt; 0.5, this upper bound is virtually zero. In such cases, even if a bubbly equilibrium may exist, it is most likely to crash in the early periods. In fact, the proof of the lemma (in Appendix B) shows that Ω(∞) is positive for β &lt; 0.5 and zero for β ≥ 0.5. As we will discuss later, the historical supply of bitcoins points to a relatively large β. So in the case of bitcoin, our model suggests that a bubble of any significance is unlikely without users present.</p><p>The exposition so far has established that a speculative bubble can be raised on an otherwise valueless item, where both the prices and the crash of the bubble are essentially self-fulfilled beliefs of investorscompletely detached from the fundamental value of the item (zero). In a bubble, both investor confidence and the coin price are increasing over time. Thus, we have the following mirror intuition: higher and higher confidence is required to sustain investors' demand in the face of increasing price, while simultaneously, the increasing price fulfills the higher and higher beliefs over time. This is the bubble environment we wish to also capture later in the extended model with user adoption.</p><p>In general, a level of confidence, as introduced by <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Weil (1987)</ref>, is a requirement on investors. A level of confidence close to 1 requires all investors in the market to believe that a crash will not happen. In our model, as the growing price "pressures" the confidence to grow, the bubble puts a higher and higher requirement on investors. So far, we have assumed that it is possible for ω t to approach 1 as long as it does not go beyond 1; however, we may also think of an a priori upper boundω &lt; 1 on confidence. In words,ω measures the maximum level of confidence that investors can psychologically hold up <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Weil 1987</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">, Shiller 2000</ref>. Obviously, thisω would put a more stringent condition on ω 1 than that in Lemma 1.</p><p>Finally, before we introduce users, it is useful to point out that we can normalize N 1. A mass of N &gt; 1 (or N &lt; 1) investors can always be thought of as a single unit of investors with each investor holding a smaller (or larger, respectively) amount of dollars.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">User Demand</head><p>We consider a mass of M 1 potential users who desire coins purely as a medium of exchange. For exposition, we first consider the case where no investors are present. We employ a Bass-like adoption model. In each period, a user decides whether to carry the coins or alternative currencies (such as dollars). The benefit of carrying coins is the ability to conduct transactions with them, which is increasing in the number of other users. We also account for costs associated with using a cryptocurrency. For example, we can think of the costs as the opportunity cost of not using dollars and the time and effort to maintain the required software, as well as technological and privacy risks. Let m t denote the mass of users who adopt the coins in a given period t. Then a user i has the following utility for adoption in period t + 1:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">U i,t+1 V m t ( ) − c i ,</formula><p>where c i ≥ 0 is the user's cost of using the coins in the period, and V(m t ) is the benefit from using the coins in the period. For simplicity, we assume the specification V(m t ) m t to capture the network effects inherent in currency markets. As in the Bass model, users' decisions in the current period are informed by the state of adoption in the previous period. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> We let the cost c i be distributed among the M 1 users according to a cumulative distribution function G(•). To obtain analytical solutions, we will make a linear specification:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">G c ( ) δ + λc if 0 ≤ c &lt; 1−δ λ , 1 otherwise, {<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where δ is the set of consumers with zero adoption costs, and λ &gt; 0 captures the density toward low adoption costs. 12 A higher value of λ indicates lower adoption costs among users. For the first period, m 1 δ naturally represents the size of the initial installed base of users. For later periods, a user i adopts the currency in t + 1 if and only if c i &lt; V(m t ). Assuming λ + δ &lt; 1, we have the adoption dynamics satisfy 13 m t+1 δ + λm t .</p><p>(5)</p><p>The adoption path {m t } ∞ t 1 will converge to some value m * ∈ (0, M). This convergent point is defined by the identity m * δ + λm * , or, equivalently,</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">m * δ 1 − λ .<label>(6)</label></formula><p>We refer to m * as the natural adoption ceiling, as it refers to the highest level of adoption that evolves without the influence of investors. Again, let p t &gt; 0 be the price of a coin in period t, and let A t be the total supply of coins in existence in period t. If each user demands x &gt; 0 dollars worth of coins to do exchanges, then the total demand for coins is given by m t x/p t . In order to match supply and demand for coins, we impose the market-clearing condition for users in the absence of investors:</p><p>x • m t p t A t .</p><p>Equation ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>) and the market-clearing condition above imply a sequence of prices and adoption levels:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">m t 1 − λ t 1 − λ • δ,<label>(7)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_10">p t x A t 1 − λ t 1 − λ ( ) • δ.<label>(8)</label></formula><p>We see A t enters the price equation above. The supply of a cryptocurrency often closely follows a predefined rule. First, the cryptocurrency creator typically sets a supply ceiling, which we will denote by A ∞ . Second, the cryptocurrency system controls its supply over time by constantly adjusting the difficulty of mining as well as regularly halving the output of mining. Consequently, we can model the cryptocurrency supply by A t A ∞ (1 − β t ) for some β ∈ (0, 1). In fact, the historical supply of bitcoin has followed this path very closely, 14 though the price of bitcoin has experienced large surges and falls. We note the size of A ∞ only has a nominal effect; a larger A ∞ simply inflates the coin price in every period. Hence, we can normalize A ∞ 1, and Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_10">8</ref>) becomes</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">p t x 1 − β t 1 − λ t 1 − λ ( ) • δ.</formula><p>When β λ, the above price for coins in the absence of speculative investors is constant over time:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">p t xδ 1 − λ .<label>(9)</label></formula><p>In what follows, we will focus on this case where the supply of coins is controlled so that the price resulting purely from user demand, in the absence of investors, is constant over time. The main reason to focus on β λ is to compare the settings with and without users on an equal footing-recall that in the setting without users (Section 2.1), the price absent of investors buying is also constant over time (at zero). It is instructive to consider a single, marginal investor. Investing in a constant p t provides a return equal to the outside option, so a single investor who has insufficient assets to swing the price all by herself will find no strict incentives to invest. However, if β &lt; λ, the p t in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_10">8</ref>) is increasing over time, which gives the investor a strict incentive to invest. Consequently, this case bears an obvious advantage in terms of bubble formation over the setting without users. Similarly, the β &gt; λ case bears an obvious disadvantage in terms of bubble formation. Hence, the condition β λ sets up a stage for us to cleanly identify the impact that users bring to the formation of a bubbly equilibrium, which we will focus on next. As in the setting without users, even though a single marginal investor finds no incentives to invest, collectively, investors can still "coordinate" to raise a bubble. Different from the setting without users, however, investors must account for how their actions will affect user adoption as well as how user adoption will affect coin prices.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Equilibrium with Users and Investors</head><p>We now bring together the two isolated settings described above ( <ref type="table">Section 2.1 and Section 2.2)</ref>. We use a two-sided user market to conceptualize the interaction between users and investors.</p><p>There are two sides of users: shoppers and vendors, as illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3</ref>. A shopper's benefit of adoption increases with the number of vendors and vice versa. At the same time, they both care about the number of investors who provide liquidity for coin exchange. We formalize a model for this two-sided market in Appendix A.3. The working of the model can be summarized as follows. Within a period, shoppers first decide whether to carry coins (instead of an alternative currency, such as dollars). A key factor in a shopper's decision is how many vendors accept coins. If a shopper decides to carry coins, he first exchanges his endowment x &gt; 0 into coins via an investor (e.g., bank). The ease of exchange (i.e., liquidity) depends on the number of coin-accepting investors. Next, the shopper goes to coin-accepting vendors for shopping. After transacting with shoppers, the vendors either deposit the received coins or exchange them into alternative currencies, such as dollars.</p><p>We show, in the appendix, that the above adoption dynamics can be reduced to a formulation similar to that in Section 2.2. Specifically, let m t be the mass of users (which tracks both the shoppers and vendors) and n t be the mass of investors in period t. Without loss of generality, we can let N 1, M 1, and x 1. 15 A user's benefit now depends on both the number of users and the number of investors, but potentially at different rates: 16</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">V m t + n t ( ) m t + φn t ,</formula><p>where φ captures the differential rate of network effects that investors exert on adoption. In period t + 1, a user with adoption cost c i adopts the currency if V(m t + n t ) &gt; c i , where c i is distributed among users according to Equation (4). Here, we require δ</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">+ λ + λφ &lt; 1 so that the support of G covers [0, M + φN].</formula><p>As a result, we have following adoption dynamics (compared with Equation ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>)):</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">m t+1 G m t + φn t ( ) δ + λ m t + φn t ( ) . (<label>10</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_16">)</formula><p>Compared with Equation (5), the adoption dynamics above suggests that the presence of investors n t accelerates adoption. However, the caveat is that for this result to hold, a bubble must form so that n t is nonzero. We will focus on the condition for bubble formation in Section 3.2, particularly in comparison with the no-user setting.</p><p>Next, consider an investor's belief and decision. As before, an investor holds y dollars and will purchase coins when he expects a nonnegative return. <ref type="bibr">17</ref> In the no-user setting with Equation (1), we specify an investor's belief of tomorrow's price as a detachment from the coin's fundamental value (zero in that setting). We will make a similar specification here. However, different from before, the adoption of users implies that there may be a positive fundamental value of the currency. Particularly, in the event of a crash, the price will drop to not zero, but rather this positive value, supported by the presence of users. It represents the value of the coin coming purely from users' demand for transactions. A bubble manifests itself as a detached price from the fundamental value. Accordingly, we specify an investor's belief as follows: p t+1 ω t L t + S t with probability ω t , S t with probability 1 − ω t .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>{</head><p>As in Equation ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>), a higher ω t denotes a higher level confidence among investors. In the above, S t &gt; 0 denotes the fundamental value expected in t for period t + 1. Under rational expectations, S t equals the price in t + 1 that can be supported even without any investor demand (n t+1 0). At the other extreme, L t denotes the maximum price detachment from S t . Under rational expectations, L t + S t will be the price in t + 1 if all investors decide to buy coins (n t+1 1). We derive expressions for S t and L t after defining the equilibrium. Now we can define the bubbly equilibrium with users present. In the equilibrium, users and investors are tied together by (i) the fact that they pay the same price for the currency and (ii) that investors exhibit network effects to user adoption, albeit at a possibly different rate compared with the network effects created by users.</p><p>Definition 2. Given a set of model primitives y, λ, δ, φ, T, and A t 1 − λ t , a sequence @ ≡ {p t , ω t , m t , n t } T t 1 with ω t ∈ (0, 1) constitutes a bubbly equilibrium if Equation (10) and the following three conditions are satisfied for all t:</p><p>i. Market clearing. The total demand for coins by investors and users equals the supply of coins:</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">n t • y + m t p t A t .</formula><p>ii. Rational expectation. The belief about the next period's noncrash price is exactly realized: p t+1 L t ω t + S t , ∀t.  As before, the bubbly equilibrium defined here focuses on cases where confidence is in the interior, so that a crash remains a meaningful, but uncertain, possibility. It is useful to point out that there is a nonbubbly equilibrium in which ω t 0 for all t. In this case, no investors participate in the coin market, the price p t tracks the fundamental value S t in all periods, and, importantly, m t follows the same path as in the user-only model (Section 2.2). The other extreme case where ω t 1 for all periods, however, generally cannot constitute an equilibrium. <ref type="bibr">18</ref> Applying Definition 2, we see that the lowest possible price expected for period t + 1, denoted by S t , must satisfy the market clearing with no investors (n t+1 0):</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">m t+1 + 0 S t A t+1 ⇒ S t δ + λm t + λφn t A t+1 .<label>(11)</label></formula><p>The currency's maximal speculative value, L t , is derived from the maximal price S t + L t that clears the market with full investor demand (n t+1 1):</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">m t+1 + y S t + L t A t+1 ⇒ L t y A t+1 . (<label>12</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_20">)</formula><p>Intuitively, L t depicts the maximum speculative value that is sustained through the demand from exactly N 1 investors. Before deriving the key properties of the bubbly equilibrium, it is useful to point out that the bubbly equilibrium is defined conditional on the bubble being sustained. When we say that {p t } T t 1 is part of a bubbly equilibrium, we mean that these will be the realized prices as long as the bubble does not crash. In each period, there is a self-fulfilled probability ω t that the bubble will crash tomorrow. If a crash is realized in a period t, we may assume that ω t and n t will be zero thereafter, and p t will track the fundamental values. 19</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Equilibrium Properties</head><p>Our analysis of the bubbly equilibrium is moderated by two primitives of the model: y and φ. The interpretation of these two parameters is linked to the two mechanisms that drive the dynamics of our model: the financial side that sets price through the marketclearing condition and the adoption side that follows Equation (10). Given the normalizations in the model (M N 1 and x 1), we can interpret y and φ, respectively, as the an investor's potential impact on the financial side and her potential impact on the adoption side, both relative to a user. So by varying y and φ, we decouple investors' roles on the financial side and the adoption side.</p><p>It seems reasonable to think that investors can (i) influence the financial side more than users, that is, y ≥ 1, but (ii) influence the adoption less than users, that is, φ ≤ 1. At the very least, it seems reasonable to restrict attention to cases where y ≥ φ, which is what we will focus on below.</p><p>Though the cases where y &lt; φ should be unlikely in reality, mathematically, Definition 2 of the bubbly equilibrium still applies to such cases. We will discuss the model behaviors in such cases toward the end of this section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Special Case (y φ)</head><p>We first consider the special case where y φ, which leads to relatively straightforward algebra and most clearly exposes the intuition of two of our main results: (i) a bubble accelerates user adoption, and (ii) a bubble with users is easier to form than an investoronly bubble, in the sense that it puts demanding conditions on the investor's confidence. The second result can be reinterpreted to mean that a bubble with users is less likely to crash compared with an investoronly bubble, as we will show. We use the y φ case to build some intuitions before we consider the general cases in Section 3.2. Now suppose sequence @ constitutes a bubble path (i.e., no crash happening). First, in period t under A t 1 − λ t , the market-clearing condition gives us p t m t + n t y 1 − λ t .</p><p>By ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_18">11</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_19">12</ref>), we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">S t m t+1 1 − λ t+1 δ + λ m t + yn t ( ) 1 − λ t+1 ; L t y 1 − λ t+1 .</formula><p>Setting the expected return in this period t equal to 1 gives us another expression for price p t :</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">p t L t ω 2 t + S t yω 2 t 1 − λ t+1 + δ + λ m t + yn t ( ) 1 − λ t+1 .</formula><p>Equating these two expressions for p t yields an expression for the masses of users and investors:</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">yn t + m t 1 − λ t 1 − λ yω 2 t + δ ( ) ,</formula><p>which leads us to an expression for next-period user mass:</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">m t+1 δ + λ yn t + m t ( ) 1 − λ t+1 1 − λ δ + λ − λ t+1 1 − λ yω 2 t . (<label>13</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_25">)</formula><p>Wei and Dukes: Cryptocurrency Adoption with Speculative Price Bubbles Note that ω 2 t &gt; 0 implies m t+1 &gt; 1−λ t+1 1−λ δ, which can be compared with Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_9">7</ref>), which describes the natural adoption without investors (which is also the user adoption path in the nonbubbly equilibrium). If we use superscript USER to indicate the setting without investors, then we have m t+1 &gt; m USER t+1 for all t 1, 2, . . . . In words, the adoption with a bubble is faster than the nonbubbly adoption.</p><p>The bubble price in t + 1 is rationally expected as</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">p t+1 L t ω t + S t yω t + m t+1 1 − λ t+1 ,</formula><p>which, together with the next-period market-clearing condition, p t+1 m t+1 +yn t+1</p><p>1−λ t+1 , implies a simple expression for n t+1 :</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">n t+1 ω t .</formula><p>This simple one-to-one relation between investor mass and confidence actually also holds in the more general case, as we will show. Intuitively, it says that investor confidence drives investor participation in the market. If confidence is zero, no investor will buy and the price will simply follow Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_12">9</ref>) and maintain a constant level over time, which is actually the nonbubbly equilibrium.</p><p>Finally, to obtain ω t+1 , we set the expected return in period t + 1 to 1:</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">p t+1 L t+1 ω 2 t+1 + S t+1 .</formula><p>To express ω t+1 in terms of the variables in period t, we use</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">S t+1 δ + λ m t+1 + yn t+1 ( ) 1 − λ t+2 ; L t+1 y 1 − λ t+2 ,</formula><p>together with the expressions for m t+1 , p t+1 , and n t+1 as we have derived just above. The algebra is a bit involved but it leads to a relatively simple expression for ω t+1 :</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">ω 2 t+1 ω 2 t + 1 − λ 1 − λ t+1 ω t − ω 2 t ( ) ω t − λ − λ t+1 1 − λ t+1 ω t − ω 2 t ( ) .</formula><p>Note that ω t − ω 2 t &gt; 0, so the first line above says ω t+1 &gt; ω t . In other words, investor confidence grows monotonically. On the other hand, the second line says ω 2 t+1 &lt; ω t or ω t+1 &lt; ̅̅̅ ̅ ω t √ . Compare this result with Equation (3) derived under the investor-only setting:</p><formula xml:id="formula_31">ω INV t+1 ̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅ ̅ A t+2 A t+1 ω INV t √</formula><p>(here, we use superscript INV to indicate the investor-only setting). We see that the investor confidence with users present need not grow as fast as when users are absent, implying that user presence relaxes the condition for bubble formation.</p><p>It turns out that for the general case y ≥ φ, the inequality ω t+1 &lt; ̅̅̅ ̅ ω t √ may not hold. <ref type="bibr">20</ref> Intuitively, this is because of the following. Compared with the special case, y ≥ φ assigns a smaller value for φ. The smaller impact that investors have on the user adoption, the less they can drive up tomorrow's fundamental price by buying today, which hurts the expected return. As a result, the confidence level has to grow faster to keep the expected return nonnegative. Nevertheless, for the general case, we will show that ω t+1 &lt; ̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅ A t+2 A t+1 ω t √ holds, so the investor confidence still grows at a slower rate compared with the no-user setting. A graphical comparison is made in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>.</p><p>An alternative way to look at the slowed growth of ω t is that if the highest required confidence levels are the same between the settings with and without users, ω T ω INV T , then we must have ω t &gt; ω INV t for all t 1, 2, . . . , T − 1. Because a crash happens in period t with probability 1 − ω t , these last inequalities indicate that the bubble with users present is less likely to burst (or more likely to sustain) than the bubble without users.</p><p>Finally, given ω t+1 &gt; ω t , we see from ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_24">13</ref>) that m t+1 &gt; m t for all t. In words, the user mass monotonically increases over time. This seemingly regular result is by no means easily granted in our context-it is conceivable that the presence of speculative investors could distort the adoption process so that the latter becomes nonmonotonic. The intuition behind this "unusually regular" result derives from the assumption of rational expectation, which asserts that if there were a period in which the user mass declines, investors in the prior period would have correctly expected it. However, this anticipation of a decline in Notes. The figure displays the paths of confidence ω t in three different bubbles. The first bubble assumes y φ, the second bubble assumes y 5φ, and the third bubble has no users present. The other primitives are same across the bubbles: φ 0.5, λ 0.6, and δ 0.1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Wei and Dukes: Cryptocurrency Adoption with Speculative Price Bubbles</head><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 40, no. 2, pp. 241-260, © 2020</ref> users (which translates to a decline in fundamental value) would make the very bubble difficult to sustain. This same intuition holds for the general case too.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">General Case</head><p>In this section, we consider the general case where y ≥ φ. First, we will extend the results derived in the special case (Section 3.1). Second, removing the assumption of y φ decouples investors' roles on the financial side and adoption side, and consequently allows us to explore how the relative size of these two roles affects bubble formation.</p><p>The first lemma breaks down the various conditions in Definition 2 to allow the computation of the bubbly equilibrium in a recursive fashion.</p><p>Lemma 2. With y ≥ φ, sequence {ω t ,m t , n t } T t 1 constitutes a part of a bubbly equilibrium @ iff for all t, we have ω t , n t , m t ∈ (0, 1) such that the mass of users satisfies</p><formula xml:id="formula_32">n t δ + yω 2 t ( ) 1 − λ t ( ) − 1 − λ ( )m t y 1 − λ t+1 ( ) − φλ 1 − λ t ( ) ,<label>(14)</label></formula><p>the mass of investors satisfies</p><formula xml:id="formula_33">m t+1 δ + λm t + λφn t ,<label>(15)</label></formula><p>and for t &lt; T, the investor's beliefs satisfy</p><formula xml:id="formula_34">ω 2 t+1 1 − λ ( )m t+1 + ω t y − φλ − yλ t+2 + φλ t+2 ( ) − δ + δλ t+1 y 1 − λ t+1 ( ) .<label>(16)</label></formula><p>In addition, in any bubbly equilibrium, we have, for all t, n t+1 ω t .</p><p>The possibility to compute a bubbly equilibrium in a recursive fashion implies that the bubbly equilibrium, if it exists, is unique for any given ω 1 .</p><p>Some intuitions can be gained from Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_34">16</ref>), which describes the evolution of investor confidence. We can rewrite it as follows (recall m * is the natural adoption ceiling given in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_8">6</ref>)):</p><formula xml:id="formula_35">ω 2 t δλ t + 1 − λ ( ) m t − m * ( )+ ω t−1 y − φλ − yλ t+1 + φλ t+1 ( ) y 1 − λ t ( ) .</formula><p>There are three terms in the numerator, all of which may exert "pressure" for ω t to grow, albeit driven by different factors. The first term, δλ t , vanishes as t → +∞ but is positive for finite t. It captures the pressure from the increasing supply of coins. The growth of supply suppresses future prices, which must be compensated by increases in confidence in order to keep investors in the market. The eventual convergence to zero of δλ t comes from the prefixed ceiling of supply, which says that the growth of supply will eventually flatten out.</p><p>The second term, (1 − λ)(m t − m * ), captures the effect of user adoption. For early periods where m t &lt; m * , the term is negative, so it actually relieves the pressure for confidence to increase. Intuitively, this is because the natural tendency for m t is to grow toward m * , which raises the coins' fundamental value and consequently helps keep investors in the market at lower confidence levels. However, in later periods where m t &gt; m * , the natural tendency in user adoption is for m t to revert back to m * (which will happen if investors leave the market). Unlike the earlier periods, this downward tendency puts more pressure for confidence to grow.</p><p>The third term in the numerator is a multiple of ω t−1 . It basically captures the feature of rational expectations; a higher ω t−1 from yesterday implies a higher rationally expected price today, which in turn demands a higher expectation for tomorrow, ω t , to sustain the bubble.</p><p>The next two propositions are based on Lemma 2 and provide bounds on the trajectory of ω t over time. The first proposition delivers a main result in this paper: the presence of users relieves the pressure for ω t to grow. In other words, the requirement for bubble formation is relaxed by the presence of users. The same result was derived in Section 3.1 for the special case y φ. Proposition 1. Suppose y ≥ φ and m 1 δ. In a bubbly equilibrium, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_36">ω t+1 &lt; ̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅ ̅ A t+2 A t+1 ω t √ ,</formula><p>for all periods t ≥ 1.</p><p>Proposition 2. Suppose y ≥ φ and m 1 δ. In a bubbly equilibrium, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_37">ω t+1 &gt; ω t ,</formula><p>for all periods t ≥ 1.</p><p>A quick intuition for how user presence makes a bubble "easier" is that the natural user adoption makes the coin's fundamental value increase over time, which gives investors more incentive to buy. Although this intuition may be true in general, it is not what underlies Proposition 1. What Proposition 1 shows is that, even if coin's fundamental value without bubbles is constant over time (see Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_12">9</ref>)), bubble formation is still easier when users are present.</p><p>The key intuition for this result comes from the interaction between users and investors. By buying the coins (and thus creating a bubble), investors can push adoption beyond the natural rate, which in turn raises the coins' value over time. It is this interaction, rationally foreseen by investors, that makes them more willing to participate in a bubble. <ref type="bibr">21</ref> We use the next proposition to formally address the existence of a bubbly equilibrium. However, from a more substantive point of view, it actually reinforces our main result delivered by Proposition 1.</p><p>Proposition 3. Given a set of primitives y, λ, δ, φ, T, and m 1 δ, (i) with y ≥ φ, a bubbly equilibrium exists as long as ω 1 takes a value such that a bubbly equilibrium exists for the investor-only case; (ii) for y φ, a bubbly equilibrium exists for any ω 1 ∈ (0, 1); and (iii) for y/φ → +∞, a bubbly equilibrium exists if and only if ω 1 takes a value such that a bubbly equilibrium exists for the investor-only case.</p><p>The proposition tells us that, compared with the nouser setting, the condition for bubble existence is relaxed by the presence of users, and it is most relaxed when y φ and least relaxed when y φ. The result suggests that bubbles become easier to form as y/φ decreases. Given the normalizations made in our model, a decrease in y can actually be represented by an increase in the number of potential users, M. <ref type="bibr">22</ref> Hence, not only do we have the "discrete result" that bubble formation is easier when users are present, but we also have the "continuous result" that bubble formation becomes easier when more users are present.</p><p>We use the following exercise to further illustrate the effect of y/φ on bubble formation. Recall that in the investor-only case, the condition for equilibrium existence is that ω 1 is sufficiently small such that ω t will not grow beyond 1 in some future period (Lemma 1). A similar requirement applies here. Specifically, for a given set of primitives, there is an upper bound for ω 1 such that a bubbly equilibrium exists for any T 1, 2, . . . , ∞ iff ω 1 is below this upper bound.</p><p>Although this upper bound does not have an analytical expression, it can be computed numerically. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">5</ref> displays this upper bound for ω 1 as a function of y/φ. The left plot assumes λ 0.4, and the right plot assumes λ 0.6.</p><p>There are two important observations: (i) the presence of users relaxes the bounds, and (ii) a larger ratio between y and φ tightens the bounds. These observations are consistent with what we have seen so far in Propositions 1-3.</p><p>Next, we turn our attention away from investor confidence to focus on user adoption. This leads us to another main result of this paper, which formalizes the insight that a bubble accelerates user adoption. The same result was derived in Section 3.1 for the special case y φ. To show this result in the general case requires the following lemma.</p><p>Lemma 3. Suppose y ≥ φ. Along the path of any bubbly equilibrium with m 1 &lt; m * , we have m t &lt; m t+1 , for all t ≥ 1 on the bubbly path.</p><p>Like we discussed in the y φ case, this seemingly regular result is by no means easily granted in our model-it is conceivable that the presence of speculative investors could distort the adoption process so that the latter becomes nonmonotonic. The intuition behind Lemma 3 has its roots in the assumption of rational expectation. The details of the intuition are the same as given in Section 3.1, so we shall not repeat them here.</p><p>With the monotonicity of m t , we can move to show that m t will eventually surpass m * , the adoption ceiling without investors. Of course, if T is too small, m t will not reach m * before the end period T. So we need to evoke the existence of a bubbly equilibrium for large T. Notes. The plots show the upper bound of ω 1 that permits a bubbly equilibrium for T ∞. The first-period user mass m 1 is set at δ. The specific values of δ and φ (or y) do not affect the curves shown here.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Wei and Dukes: Cryptocurrency Adoption with Speculative Price Bubbles</head><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 40, no. 2, pp. 241-260, © 2020</ref> Proposition 4. Suppose y ≥ φ, m 1 &lt; m * , and a bubbly equilibrium exits for T ∞; then there exists t * such that t &gt; t * implies m t &gt; m * .</p><p>It is important to point out that our results on m t are conditional on the sustenance of a bubble (as is our definition of bubbly equilibrium). When a bubble bursts, m t will break away from its trajectory in a bubbly equilibrium. However, m t will still stay above the levels of user sizes in natural adoption. To see this, suppose the bubble bursts in period s; then m t+1 δ + λm t for all t ≥ s. Because of the bubble, we have m s &gt; m USER s (recall that superscript USER denotes the user-only setting). Hence, m t &gt; m USER t holds for all t ≥ s. As a result, though we have shown only that user adoption is faster within a bubble, the same holds true ex ante accounting for the possibility of a crash.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Improper Case</head><p>So far, we have restricted attention to y ≥ φ. The inequality asserts that investors hold a stronger influence on the financial side than the adoption side, compared with users. As said, mathematically, our equilibrium definition also applies to cases where y &lt; φ. Although we think such cases are unlikely in reality, they do offer some interesting intuitions.</p><p>With y &lt; φ, a bubbly equilibrium may exhibit behaviors that are irregular compared with those behaviors derived in Section 3.2. Particularly, neither ω t nor m t needs to be monotonically increasing. <ref type="bibr">23</ref> Intuitively, this is because investors' participation can substantially accelerate adoption (because of a relatively large φ) without significantly raising today's price (because of a relatively small y). As a result, investors can easily raise the expected return of coins, which makes an increase in confidence sometimes unnecessary in sustaining a bubble.</p><p>More specifically, the monotonic growth of ω t in Proposition 2 is the result of several forces. First, in a bubble with rationally expected prices, the price must increase over time. The growing price puts pressure on the confidence level to grow as well (in order to keep the expected return nonnegative and thus sustain the bubble). Second, the coin supply is increasing over time, which suppresses future prices. This suppression pressures the investor confidence to grow (in order to keep the expected return nonnegative). Third, user adoption gradually raises the fundamental value of coins, which may relieve the pressure for confidence to grow. When y ≥ φ, the first two forces overcome the third. However, when y &lt; φ, investors can substantially accelerate user adoption without raising today's price, which allows the third force to overcome the first two. When this happens, the current-period confidence level will be lower than that in the last period. Furthermore, such a decline in confidence can translate into a decline in user adoption, as it implies a decline in investor participation thanks to rational expectations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Discussions and Conclusion</head><p>Our study is the first to look into the possible interactions between financial bubbles and product diffusion for new currency adoption. It best portrays currencies whose supplies evolve in a predictable fashion, such as cryptocurrencies. In that context, we explored conditions for when and how investors and users reinforce each other in sustaining speculative returns and adoption benefits, respectively. On one hand, users benefit from the network externality created by investors in a bubble, which then accelerates user adoption. On the other hand, investors expecting a more steady stream of users to buy currency do not need to rely as heavily on the confidence of their fellow investors to sustain a return. Our results point to the conclusion that a currency bubble is most likely to form (or less likely to crash once formed) when some event increases the base of potential users.</p><p>There were two major price surges in the bitcoin history before 2019. The first major surge happened around November 2013. Our conclusion above is consistent with our observations from the introduction about the impact of the Shared Coin service, which coincides with the timing of this price surge. The anonymity offered by the Shared Coin service expanded the potential user base. Under the lens of our model, this expansion can be interpreted as an increase in M (or an increase in y with our normalization), which therefore relaxes the level of the investor confidence required to form a bubble.</p><p>The surged price fell rapidly in early 2014. Although a bubble bursting could always be a selffulfilled, random event (as permitted in our model), our theory can offer a more concrete event-based explanation, rooted in the user-side of the market. In February 2014, one of the largest bitcoin exchanges, Mt. Gox, filed for bankruptcy amid reports of 750,000 bitcoins stolen, which caused a major upset among users regarding bitcoin's security. Supposing that this event scraped away the potential user base for bitcoin, then a bubble would be harder to sustain in terms of investor confidence, thereby compelling the crash.</p><p>The second major price bubble happened in late 2017. Earlier in 2017, several countries-Japan, Russia, and Norway-announced their legitimization of the cryptocurrency, thereby increasing the potential user base and subsequently, according to our model, relaxing the level of investor confidence required for a bubble. The price plummeted in early 2018. Although, again, a crash can be a self-fulfilling event without triggering causes, several events may have advanced the downfall, including the anticipation of China's and South Korea's bans on the trading of bitcoins as well as hacks at several cryptocurrency exchanges (e.g., the Coincheck hack). Even though these exchanges were trading not bitcoins but other cryptocurrencies, the hacks may have made investors worry about the security of cryptocurrencies in general.</p><p>Taking our results a step further, they seem to suggest that any entity introducing a currency can take advantage of bubbles to induce currency adoption. Indeed, it is worthwhile to note that the European Monetary Union initially launched the euro in 1999 to investors only as an accounting currency, before it became the European Union's standard medium of exchange. Our theory provides a rationale for such a launch strategy, as it shows the synergy between users and investors. Lessons from our model may be more widely applied now that nongovernment entities can easily market their own currencies. two-point distribution as follows while preserving the mean as well as the variance: p t+1 g t • L t with probability ω t , 0 with probability 1 − ω t .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>{ (A.1)</head><p>Using the formulas for the mean and variance for a beta distribution, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_38">g t ω t α t α t + 1/α t ; g 2 t 1 − ω t ( )ω t 1 α t + 1/α t (</formula><p>)</p><formula xml:id="formula_39">2 α t + 1/α t + 1 ( ) .</formula><p>These give us ω t and g t , both as functions of α t . For ω t , we have a closed-form expression:</p><formula xml:id="formula_40">ω t α 3 t + α 2 t + α t α 3 t + α 2 t + α t + 1 .</formula><p>It is seen that there is a one-to-one mapping from α t to ω t : [0, +∞) → [0, 1]. So, basically, α t represents the investor confidence in the continuous-belief model, playing the same role as ω t in the discrete-belief model.</p><p>Unfortunately there is no closed-form expression for g t . However, we can trace the values of g t and ω t as we vary α t , which gives us g t as a function of ω t . This function is plotted in Figure A.2. We see it is very close to the 45°line. So the discretized distribution (A.1) is closely approximated by the belief specification that we used in the main model (i.e., Equation ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>)).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.2. Bitcoin Supply</head><p>Government-backed currency is issued at a rate determined by the central bank, which takes into account the concurrent state and prospects of the economy. In the United States, the Federal Reserve System increases the monetary base by issuing dollars.</p><p>In the context of cryptocurrency, the bitcoin generation algorithm defines how currency will be created and at what rate. Particularly, the supply of bitcoins is controlled to follow a preset rule toward a preset ceiling. The result is a supply trajectory that has closely followed an exponential curve: A t A ∞ (1 − β t ), where A t is the supply in period t, A ∞ is the preset ceiling, and β &lt; 1 captures the growth rate.  Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science, 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 40, no. 2, pp. 241-260, © 2020</ref> The key cause behind this exponential supply curve is the control of mining. Bitcoins are supplied through mining. Miners are network computers that pack individual transaction records into blocks of transactions, which are then "chained" together by the bitcoin system to create an entire history of bitcoin transactions (hence, the term "blockchain"). Block creation is accompanied by the issuance of new bitcoins. The difficulty of packing blocks is adjusted by the bitcoin system so that regardless of the mining activities (e.g., the number of miners or the computational power of mining machines), blocks are created at a rate of six per hour. At the same time, the number of bitcoins issued per block is set to decrease geometrically, with a 50% reduction every 210,000 blocks, or approximately four years. The result is that the number of bitcoins in existence follows the exponential curve with a ceiling of 21 million (A ∞ ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.3. Two-Sided Market for Coins</head><p>In the main text, we rely on Equation (10) to describe the Bass-like adoption dynamic. Here, we present what can be seen as a microfoundation for Equation (10). It uses a twosided market to describe coin transactions and exchange. The two sides are the two types of users-shoppers and vendors.</p><p>In each period t, we denote the mass of shoppers that carry coins to do transaction by h t ∈ [0, H]; the mass of vendors that accept coins is denoted by d t ∈ [0, D]. Here, H is the total mass of shoppers, who may or may not have adopted the coins. Similarly, D is the total mass of venders. We normalize H 1. Typically, there are more shoppers than vendors, so D ≤ 1.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3</ref> in the main text summarizes the working of the two-sided market. Within a period, shoppers first decide whether to carry coins (instead of an alternative currency such as dollars). A key factor in a shopper's decision is how many vendors accept coins, an issue that we will take into account below when specifying the shopper's value from adoption (see Figure A.4 for an illustration). If a shopper decides to carry coins, he exchanges his unit endowment (x 1) into coins. He can do this exchange via a coininvesting bank or individual investor. The ease of exchange, or the liquidity of coins, depends on the number of coin-accepting investors, an issue that we will also account for when specifying the shopper's value from adoption.</p><p>Next, the shopper goes to one of the coin-accepting vendors for shopping. After transacting with shoppers, the vendors either deposit the received coins or exchange them into alternative currencies, such as dollars. Again, the ease of deposition and exchange depends on with the mass of coin-accepting investors.</p><p>In accordance with the above description of the twosided market, we specify a shopper's value of adopting coins in period t + 1, denoted by V h t+1 , as a function of the fraction of coin-accepting vendors and the fraction of coinaccepting investors. As in the Bass model, we assume that users are myopically adjusting their adoption decisions. Specifically,</p><formula xml:id="formula_41">V h t+1 d t /D + φn t /N d t /D + φn t ,</formula><p>where parameter φ allows the user's utility to put different weights on the ease of exchange (liquidity) and on the ease of transactions. Similarly for the vendors, we specify</p><formula xml:id="formula_42">V d t+1 h t /H + φn t /N h t + φn t .</formula><p>Under the same adoption cost distribution as specified in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_7">4</ref>) for both shoppers and vendors, the following adoption dynamics are implied:</p><formula xml:id="formula_43">h t+1 δ + λ d t /D + φn t ( ) , d t+1 /D δ + λ h t + φn t ( ) . (A.2)</formula><p>Intuitively, these two equations imply that in the market of coins, (i) the mass of shoppers tomorrow increases with the mass of vendors and the mass of investors today, and (ii) the mass of vendors tomorrow increases with the mass of shoppers and the mass of investors today. Taking the difference between these two adoption equations, we have It is natural to set h 1 δ and d 1 δD (which can be thought of as the consequences of d 0 0, h 0 0, and n 0 0). As a result, Equation (A.3) implies that for all t, h t d t /D. This equality says that the sizes of shoppers and vendors grow in parallel. This result should be intuitive: as more vendors accept coins, more shoppers are willing to carry coins; conversely, as more shoppers carry coins, more vendors find it compelling to accept coins. Now Equation (A.2) can be written as</p><formula xml:id="formula_44">h t+1 − d t+1 /D −λ h t − d t /D ( ) . (A.3)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_45">h t+1 δ + λ h t + φn t ( ) ,</formula><p>which is equivalent to Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_15">10</ref>), if we think of each shopper here as a user in the main model. Because the sizes of shoppers and vendors grow in parallel, tracking the number of shoppers also tracks the number of vendors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.4. Extensions on Adoption Values</head><p>A.4.1. Nonlinear Adoption Benefit We consider an extension where the network effects on user adoption are nonlinear. Specifically, suppose the benefits that a user derives from adoption are given by V m t , n t ( ) m t + ηm 2 t + φn t .</p><p>Intuitively, the nonlinear term creates a snowball effect where adoption itself accelerates the adoption rate. Following the line of thought in our benchmark model, this additional accelerating effect should further relax the condition for bubble formation.</p><p>This seems to be indeed the case. Figure A.5 displays the upper bound of ω 1 that permits a bubbly equilibrium, as a function of y/φ. The figure extends the comparison we made in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">5</ref>. The top curve in Figure A.5 displays the case with the snowball effect. The middle curve displays the case without the snowball effect (i.e., the model considered in Section 2.3). The bottom curve displays the case without users (i.e., the model considered in Section 2.1).</p><p>Higher upper bounds indicate more relaxed conditions for bubble formation. Hence, we see that the snowball effect relaxes the condition for bubble formation. This result is not specific to the model primitives used in Figure A.5. It holds for all of the many sets of primitives that we have examined.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.4.2. Investors Valuing Liquidity</head><p>We consider an extension where investors value liquidity. Specifically, in addition to demanding an expected return equal to that of the outside good, investors demand an extra return to compensate the relative low liquidity of coins (compared with the outside good, such as short-term government bonds). Accordingly, we specify the nonarbitrage condition as</p><formula xml:id="formula_46">L t p t ω t 2 1 + ι • 1 − n t ( ).</formula><p>Parameter ι calibrates investors' value for liquidity. The higher ι is, the more they need to be compensated for low liquidity. The liquidity increases with n t , the mass of investors, and reaches its highest level when all investors are trading coins (n t 1).</p><p>From the above nonarbitrage condition, we see that, compared with ι 0, any positive ι requires a higher ω t . Hence, intuitively, when investors care about liquidity, the confidence level must grow faster, which makes a rational bubble more difficult to sustain. Note that this intuition applies to both the settings with and without users. So the question is how the two settings compare in terms of bubble formation, when both have investors demanding extra return for liquidity. Notes. This plot illustrates the interaction between vendors (V) and shoppers (S) when there are four times the shoppers compared with vendors. When one of the shoppers decides to carry coins, each vendor sees one-eighth of its customers want to do transactions in coins. When one of the vendors decides to accept coins, each shopper sees half of his or her vendors accept coins. We see that for the setting with users, moving from ι 0 to ι 0.1 indeed tightens the upper bounds. However, for the setting without users, ι 0.1 effectively makes a rational bubble impossible (the bottom curve overlaps with zero). Hence, bubbles are easier to form in the setting with users compared with the setting without users, which is consistent with our findings in Section 3. This result is not specific to the model primitives used in Figure A.6. It holds for all of the many sets of primitives that we have examined.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix B. Proofs</head><p>Proof of Lemma 1. By Equation (3) and A t 1 − β t , we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_47">ω 2 2 1 − β 3 1 − β 2 ω 1 , ω 4 3 1 − β 4 1 − β 3 ( ) 2 ω 2 2 , ω 8 4 1 − β 5 1 − β 4 ( ) 4 ω 4 3 , . . . .</formula><p>Multiplying these equations, we have, for any t ≥ 3,</p><formula xml:id="formula_48">ω 2 t−1 t 1 1 − β 2 • 1 1 − β 3 • 1 1 − β 4 ( ) 2 . . . 1 − β t+1 ( ) 2 t−2 1 − β t ( ) 2 t−3 • ω 1 ω 1 • 1 − β t+1 ( ) 2 t−2 1 − β 2 • ∏ t k 3 1 1 − β k ( ) 2 k−3 . Let B k : 1 − β k ( ) 2 k−3 .</formula><p>Note 0 ≤ B k ≤ 1. We have</p><formula xml:id="formula_49">ω 2 t−1 t ω 1 • B t+1 1 − β 2 • 1 ∏ t k 3 B k . (B.1)</formula><p>First we show the sufficiency of ω 1 ≤ Ω(∞) for existence. If the condition in the lemma holds, then we must have, for any t ≥ 3,</p><formula xml:id="formula_50">ω 1 ≤ 1 − β 2 ( )∏ t k 3 B k ,</formula><p>which, together with (B.1), implies</p><formula xml:id="formula_51">ω 2 t−1 t ≤ 1 − β t+1 ( ) 2 t−2 ⇔ ω t ≤ ̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅ 1 − β t+1 √ &lt; 1.</formula><p>The case with t 2 can be directly verified, under which the condition in the lemma translates to ω 1 ≤ 1 − β 2 and ω 2 ≤ ̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅ 1 − β 3 √ . Next, we turn to the necessity of ω 1 ≤ Ω(∞) when T ∞. This part of the proof relies on first understanding the limit of</p><formula xml:id="formula_52">B k . Note log B k log(1 − β k )/2 3−k . Using L'Hôpital's rule, lim k→∞ log B k lim k→∞ −1 1−β k log β ( ) β k − log 2 ( )2 3−k log β ( ) 2 3 log 2 ( ) lim k→∞ 2β ( ) k .</formula><p>This result implies that (i) B k converges to 1 if β &lt; 0.5, (ii) to e −1/8 if β 0.5, and (iii) to 0 if β &gt; 0.5. Thus, we know ∏ ∞ k 3 B k equals 0 if β ≥ 0.5. As to what happens for β &lt; 0.5, we can use the ratio test on the series log B k :</p><formula xml:id="formula_53">lim k→∞ log B k+1 log B k 2 lim k→∞ 1 1−β k+1 log β ( ) β k+1 1 1−β k log β ( ) β k 2β,</formula><p>which says log B k is a convergent series, and thus ∏ ∞ k 3 B k is a positive finite number, for β &lt; 0.5. Case (i) (β &lt; 0.5). Taking limit of (B.1), we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_54">lim t→∞ ω 2 t−1 t ω 1 • 1 1 − β 2 • 1 ∏ ∞ k 3 B k .</formula><p>Thus, if the condition in the lemma fails, then we have lim t→∞ ω 2 t−1 t &gt; 1, which implies that there exists some t such that ω t &gt; 1, thereby violating Definition 1.</p><p>Case (ii) (β 0.5). The condition in the lemma amounts to ω 1 ≤ 0. With ω 1 &gt; 0, Equation (B.1) implies lim t→∞</p><formula xml:id="formula_55">ω 2 t−1 t ω 1 • e −1/8 1 − β 2 • 1 0 +∞.</formula><p>Therefore, we can find t such that ω t &gt; 1, violating Definition 1. Case (iii) (β &gt; 0.5). The condition in the lemma amounts to ω 1 ≤ 0. Note that</p><formula xml:id="formula_56">∏ t k 3 B k &lt; ∏ t k 3 1 − β t ( ) 2 k−3 1 − β t ( ) 2 t−2 −1 .</formula><p>Therefore, Equation (B.1) implies</p><formula xml:id="formula_57">ω 2 t−1 t &gt; ω 1 • 1 − β t 1 − β 2 • 1 − β t+1 1 − β t ( ) 2 t−2 .</formula><p>One can show that the exponential term on the right side goes to +∞ under β &gt; 0.5 by using L'Hôpital's rule on the its logarithmic expression. Thus, with ω 1 &gt; 0, we again can find t such that ω t &gt; 1. □ Proof of Lemma 2. We derive recursive formulae of ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">14</ref>), ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_33">15</ref>), and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_34">16</ref>) under coin supply A t 1 − λ t . Now suppose @ constitutes a bubble path (i.e., no crash happening). First, using the market-clearing condition, we get p t yn t + m t 1 − λ t .</p><p>by Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_18">11</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_19">12</ref>), we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_58">S t δ + λm t + λφn t 1 − λ t+1 , L t y 1 − λ t+1 .</formula><p>Setting the expected return in this period t equal to 1 gives us another expression for p t :</p><formula xml:id="formula_59">p t L t ω 2 t + S t y 1 − λ t+1 ω 2 t + δ + λm t + λφn t 1 − λ t+1 .</formula><p>Taking the two equations for p t together yields</p><formula xml:id="formula_60">yω 2 t 1 − λ t+1 + δ + λm t + λφn t 1 − λ t+1 yn t + m t 1 − λ t , which implies n t δ + yω 2 t ( ) 1 − λ t ( ) − 1 − λ ( )m t y 1 − λ t+1 ( ) − φλ 1 − λ t ( ) .</formula><p>The next-period bubble price is rationally expected as</p><formula xml:id="formula_61">p t+1 L t ω t + S t m t+1 + yω t 1 − λ t+1 , (B.2)</formula><p>where the next-period mass of users is given by ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_15">10</ref>)</p><formula xml:id="formula_62">m t+1 δ + λm t + λφn t .</formula><p>Market clearing in period t + 1 gives us</p><formula xml:id="formula_63">n t+1 p t+1 A t+1 − m t+1 y ω t .</formula><p>Next, we can compute S t+1 and L t+1 as</p><formula xml:id="formula_64">S t+1 δ + λm t+1 + λφn t+1 1 − λ t+2 , L t+1 y 1 − λ t+2 . (B.3)</formula><p>Setting the expected return in t + 1 to 1, we have the expression for ω t+1 as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_65">ω 2 t+1 p t+1 − S t+1 L t+1 .</formula><p>Using (B.2) and (B.3), we can show that</p><formula xml:id="formula_66">ω 2 t+1 1 − λ ( )m t+1 + ω t y − φλ − yλ t+2 + φλ t+2 ( ) − δ + δλ t+1 y 1 − λ t+1 ( ) ,</formula><p>which completes our proof. □ Proof of Proposition 1. Before establishing the result with m 1 δ, we show the inductive argument</p><formula xml:id="formula_67">ω 2 t &lt; 1 − λ t+1 1 − λ t ω t−1 ⇒ ω 2 t+1 &lt; 1 − λ t+2 1 − λ t+1 ω t .</formula><p>Fix a t, and suppose that</p><formula xml:id="formula_68">ω 2 t &lt; A t+1 A t ω t−1 1 − λ t+1 1 − λ t ω t−1 .</formula><p>By Lemma 2, which says n t ω t−1 , we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_69">n t &gt; ω 2 t 1 − λ t 1 − λ t+1 .</formula><p>The above inequality, together with ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">14</ref>) in Lemma 2, gives us</p><formula xml:id="formula_70">δ + yω 2 t ( ) 1 − λ t ( ) − 1 − λ ( )m t y 1 − λ t+1 ( ) − φλ 1 − λ t ( ) &gt; ω 2 t 1 − λ t 1 − λ t+1 ,</formula><p>which can be reduced to an upper bound on m t :</p><formula xml:id="formula_71">m t &lt; 1 − λ t ( ) δ 1 − λ t+1 ( ) + ω 2 t φ λ − λ t+1 ( ) [ ] 1 − λ ( )1 − λ t+1 ( ) .</formula><p>One can show that (16) in Lemma 2 can be reduced to the following, if we substitute m t+1 with m t using ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_33">15</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">14</ref>):</p><formula xml:id="formula_72">ω 2 t+1 1 − λ ( )y 2 ω 2 t + yδ + y − φ ( ) λm t ( ) y y − φλ + φλ t+1 − yλ t+1 ( ) + 1 − λ ( )1 − ω t ( )ω t 1 − λ t+1 − δ − λω t y − φ ( ) y . (B.4)</formula><p>Applying the upper bound of m t to the above expression produces an upper bound for ω 2 t+1 and, consequently, an upper bound for ω 2 t+1 − 1−λ t+2 1−λ t+1 ω t . One can show the last upper bound reduces to</p><formula xml:id="formula_73">ω 2 t+1 − 1 − λ t+2 1 − λ t+1 ω t &lt; − λφω t 1 − λ t+1 − ω t 1 − λ t ( ) [ ] y 1 − λ t+1 ( ) . Because 1 − λ t+1 − ω t (1 − λ t ) ≥ 1 − λ t+1 − (1 − λ t ) &gt; 0, we have ω 2 t+1 − 1 − λ t+2 1 − λ t+1 ω t &lt; 0,</formula><p>which is what we want to prove. </p><formula xml:id="formula_74">ω 2 2 − ω 1 • 1 − λ 3 1 − λ 2 ω 2 1 λφ 1 + λ ( )y + λ y − φ ( ) [ ] − ω 1 λφ y ≤ 0,</formula><p>with the equality holding only at ω 1 0. □ Proof of Proposition 2. By way of induction, we fix a t ≥ 2, assume that ω t &gt; ω t−1 , and then show ω t+1 &gt; ω t . Under the above assumption, Lemma 2 says n t ω t−1 , which gives us ω t &gt; n t .</p><p>Now, substituting n t in the above with ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">14</ref>) in Lemma 2, we get</p><formula xml:id="formula_75">m t &gt; δ 1 − λ t ( ) + λφω t 1 − λ t ( ) − yω t 1 − ω t + ω t λ t − λ t+1 ( ) 1 − λ .</formula><p>Applying this inequality to (B.4) produces a lower bound for ω 2 t+1 , which can be shown to reduce to</p><formula xml:id="formula_76">ω 2 t+1 &gt; ω 2 t + 1 − λ ( )1 − ω t ( )ω t 1 − λ t+1</formula><p>, which implies that ω t+1 &gt; ω t .</p><p>Now we let t 2 and show that ω 2 &gt; ω 1 . Assuming that m 1 δ, we can show by (B.4) with t 1 that</p><formula xml:id="formula_77">ω 2 2 − ω 2 1 ω 1 • y 1 + λ + λ 2 ( ) − λφ 1 + λ ( ) y 1 + λ ( ) − ω 2 1 • y + 2λ + λ 2 ( ) y − φ ( ) y + λy − λφ ( ) 1 + λ ( ) .</formula><p>The right-hand side in the above equation is quadratic and concave in ω 1 . Therefore, can check the endpoint cases ω 1 0 and ω 1 1. The first case makes the above right side zero. For the second case, the right-hand side reduces to</p><formula xml:id="formula_78">λ 2 y − φ ( ) 2 y y + λy − λφ ( )≥ 0.</formula><p>Hence, we have ω 2 &gt; ω 1 for any ω 1 ∈ (0, 1). □ Proof of Proposition 3. For part (i), to prove the existence, we need to show that n t , m t , ω t ∈ (0, 1) under the recursive characterization in Lemma 2. Propositions 1 and 2 rely on Lemma 2 to show that ω t increases over time but at a slower rate than ω INV t , where the superscript INV denotes the investor-only case and satisfies the condition in Lemma 1. Hence, if the primitives are such that ω INV t ∈ (0, 1) for all t, then we must have ω t ∈ (0, 1) for all t.</p><p>As to the mass of investors, with m 1 δ, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_79">n 1 δ + yω 2 1 ( ) 1 − λ ( )− 1 − λ ( )δ y 1 − λ 2 ( ) − φλ 1 − λ ( ) yω 2 1 y + y − φ ( ) λ ,</formula><p>which guarantees that n 1 ∈ (0, 1). For t ≥ 1, we have n t+1 ω t , so we have n t+1 ∈ (0, 1) as well.</p><p>As to the mass of users, it evolves by m t+1 δ + λm t + λφn t .</p><p>Recall the restriction on parameters that δ + λ + λφ &lt; 1, so we have m t ∈ (0,1) ⇒ m t+1 ∈ (0,1). As a result, with m 1 δ ∈ (0,1), we have m t ∈ (0, 1) for all t.</p><p>For part (ii), for the special case y φ, we have, from (B.4)</p><formula xml:id="formula_80">ω 2 t+1 ω t − λ − λ t+1 1 − λ t+1 ω t − ω 2 t ( ) ,</formula><p>which implies that ω 2 t+1 &lt; ω t as well as ω t+1 &gt; ω t . This guarantees us that ω t ∈ (0, 1) for any t, as long as ω 1 ∈ (0, 1).</p><p>For part (iii), finally, consider y → +∞. We have</p><formula xml:id="formula_81">ω 2 t+1 → 1 − λ ( )ω 2 t 1 − λ t+1 + 1 − λ ( )1 − ω t ( )ω t 1 − λ t+1 − δ + λω t 1 − λ t+2 1 − λ t+1 ω t .</formula><p>This relation is the same as in the investor-only case of Lemma 1. □ Proof of Lemma 3. Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">14</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_33">15</ref>) tell us that</p><formula xml:id="formula_82">m t+1 δ + λm t + λφ δ + yω 2 t ( ) 1 − λ t ( ) − 1 − λ ( )m t y 1 − λ t+1 ( ) − φλ 1 − λ t ( ) .</formula><p>Hence, for all t,</p><formula xml:id="formula_83">m t &lt; m t+1 ⇔ m t &lt; y δ 1 − λ t+1 ( ) + ω 2 t φ λ − λ t+1 ( ) 1 − λ ( )y − yλ t+1 + φλ t+1 ( ) .</formula><p>Now, fix any t. Given m t−1 &lt; m t , we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_84">m t−1 &lt; y δ 1 − λ t ( ) + ω 2 t−1 φ λ − λ t ( ) 1 − λ ( )y − yλ t + φλ t ( ) . (B.5)</formula><p>By contradiction, suppose that m t ≥ m t+1 . Then</p><formula xml:id="formula_85">m t ≥ y δ 1 − λ t+1 ( ) + ω 2 t φ λ − λ t+1 ( ) 1 − λ ( )y − yλ t+1 + φλ t+1 ( ) , (B.6) by (14) in Lemma 2, which implies ω t−1 n t ≤ yω 2 t 1 − λ t ( ) − δλ t y − y − φ ( ) λ t+1 . (B.7)</formula><p>The equality above also comes from Lemma 2. Next, using both ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">14</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_33">15</ref>), we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_86">m t δ + λm t−1 + λφ δ + yω 2 t−1 ( ) 1 − λ t−1 ( ) − 1 − λ ( )m t−1 y 1 − λ t ( )− φλ 1 − λ t−1 ( ) .</formula><p>Substituting m t−1 in the above with inequality (B.5) gives</p><formula xml:id="formula_87">m t &lt; y δ 1 − λ t ( ) + ω 2 t−1 φ λ − λ t ( ) 1 − λ ( )y − yλ t + φλ t ( ) ,</formula><p>which, under (B.7), implies that</p><formula xml:id="formula_88">m t &lt; y δ 1 − λ t ( ) + φ λ − λ t ( ) yω 2 t 1−λ t ( )−δλ t y− y−φ ( )λ t+1 1 − λ ( )y − yλ t + φλ t ( ) .</formula><p>We reach a contradiction if we can show that the left-hand side of the above inequality is smaller than the left-hand side of (B.6). It can be shown that the difference between the two left-hand sides amounts to</p><formula xml:id="formula_89">− yφλ t 1 − λ t ( ) δ + λφω 2 t + 1 − λ ( )yω 2 t [ ] 1 − λ ( )y − y − φ ( ) λ t [ ] y − y − φ ( ) λ t+1 [ ] &lt; 0.</formula><p>So we indeed reach a contradiction, which proves the inductive claim m t−1 &lt; m t ⇒ m t &lt; m t+1 .</p><p>Finally, let us look at the first period. We will show that m 1 &lt; m * implies m 1 &lt; m 2 . By Lemma 2, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_90">m 2 δ + λm 1 + λφ δ + yω 2 1 ( ) 1 − λ ( )− 1 − λ ( )m 1 y 1 − λ 2 ( ) − φλ 1 − λ ( ) .</formula><p>With the above expression for m 2 , it can be shown than</p><formula xml:id="formula_91">m 1 &lt; m 2 ⇔ m 1 &lt; y δ + λδ + λφω 2 ( ) y − λ 2 y − φ ( ) ⏟̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅⏞⏞̅̅̅̅̅̅̅̅⏟ Ξ .</formula><p>If m * &lt; Ξ, then m 1 &lt; Ξ and we are done. If m * ≥ Ξ, however, then δλ + λyω 2 1 − yω 2 1 ≥ 0, which can be shown to imply</p><formula xml:id="formula_92">δ + yω 2 1 ≤ Ξ.</formula><p>However, for the bubbly equilibrium to exist, we must have n 1 &gt; 0. Using (14) in Lemma 2, we see that n 1 &gt; 0 implies m 1 &lt; δ + yω 2 1 .</p><p>As a result, we have m 1 &lt; Ξ, and again we are done. □</p><p>Proof of Proposition 4. By Lemma 3, we know that m t is monotonically increasing, which, together with the fact that m t is bounded above by 1, implies that m t converges to a limit. We denote this limit asm. Similarly, we know that ω t converges and denote the limit byω. Using ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">14</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_33">15</ref>) in Lemma 2, we havē</p><formula xml:id="formula_93">m δ + λm + λφ δ + yω 2 ( ) − 1 − λ ( )m y − φλ ,</formula><p>which has the unique solution</p><formula xml:id="formula_94">m δ + λφω 2 1 − λ .</formula><p>Using ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_34">16</ref>) in Lemma 2, we havē</p><formula xml:id="formula_95">ω 2 1 − λ ( )m +ω y − φλ ( ) − δ y λφω 2 +ω y − φλ ( ) y ,</formula><p>which has two solutions, eitherω 0 orω 1. As long as ω 1 &gt; 0, it must be thatω 1. Hence,</p><formula xml:id="formula_96">m δ + λφ 1 − λ m * + λφ 1 − λ ,</formula><p>which completes our proof. □ Endnotes 1 Even Facebook plans to launch a cryptocurrency, Libra, in the near future (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Horwitz and Olson 2019</ref>).</p><p>2 This is achieved by focusing on the case where the positive effect of user adoption on the fundamental value is exactly offset by the negative effect of the growth in the cryptocurrency supply. Keeping the fundamental value constant allows us to compare the settings with and without users on an equal footing (the fundamental value in the no-user setting is constant at zero).</p><p>3 Our model tells a similar story to explain another major price spike of bitcoin in late 2017. Earlier in 2017, several countries-Japan, Russia, and Norway-announced their legitimization of the cryptocurrency, thereby increasing the potential user base and, subsequently, according to our model, relaxing the confidence required for a bubble.</p><p>4 It is not difficult to generalize our model to r &gt; 0 by introducing a growth rate on the investor population or the dollar holding of each investor. Results will remain the same qualitatively, albeit with more complex algebra.</p><p>5 Risk neutrality of all agents is assumed throughout the model. This assumption simplifies the analysis, though we acknowledge that assuming alternative risk preferences could affect the results. 6 In Appendix A.1, we show a one-to-one mapping between ω t ∈ (0, 1) and α t ∈ (0, +∞). To obtain analytical solutions, we make use of the discrete version in (1) throughout the main text. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> In <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Weil (1987)</ref>, however, the confidence is fixed constant. As a consequence, the speculative price does not surge up, as we often observe in real bubbles. We let confidence be time varying to more closely capture price surges. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> Under rational expectation, one can show that p t 0 implies either a crash has happened or the prices in all periods are 0 (the nonbubbly equilibrium). On the other hand, p t L t−1 implies the expected return in t is less than 1 so n t 0, which contradicts p t &gt; 0.</p><p>9 The best known application of this condition is perhaps the arbitrage pricing theory, introduced by <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Ross (1976)</ref>. Also see <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Roll and Ross (1980)</ref> and a more recent discussion in <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Malkiel (2003)</ref>.</p><p>10 Other equilibria may exist under alternative specifications of investor belief (1), for example, p t+1 ω 2 t L t or ̅̅̅ ̅ ω t √ L t with probability ω t .</p><p>We thank an anonymous referee for pointing this out. 11 There are a few empirical studies in marketing that extend adoption models to forward-looking consumers, including <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Song and Chintagunta (2003)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Nair (2007)</ref>.</p><p>Wei and Dukes: Cryptocurrency Adoption with Speculative Price Bubbles <ref type="bibr">Marketing Science, 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 40, no. 2, pp. 241-260, © 2020</ref> We acknowledge that adoption costs, in reality, may decline over time because of progresses in adoption and infrastructure. If so, adoption would accelerate further than shown here. For simplicity, therefore, we keep the adoption costs exogenous while allowing the benefits to be endogenous. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> In practice, holding a cryptocurrency poses risks associated with technological or legal disruptions. For example, some cryptocurrencies have experienced hacks of cryptoexchanges and trading bans by governments. Although our main model abstracts away from such risks, we discuss the impacts of these disruptions in Section 4. <ref type="bibr">14</ref> In Appendix, Section A.2, we discuss in more detail how our supply model reflects the institutional realities associated with bitcoin. <ref type="bibr">15</ref> To see this, first suppose N 2. We can transform it into N 1 by thinking of each investor in the model as representing two actual investors. We also need to double y, the dollar holding of each investor in the model. A similar transformation applies to M 1. As to x, notice that doubling the values for both x and y will only have a nominal effect: the prices in all periods double. Hence, between x and y, we can normalize one of them to 1. <ref type="bibr">16</ref> In Appendix A, Section A.4.1, we consider an extension allowing users to exert nonlinear network effects. 17 In Appendix A, Section A.4.2, we consider an extension where investors may also value liquidity (as users do) in addition to expected return. <ref type="bibr">18</ref> This can be seen from Proposition 2 extended to include ω t 1. The same proof will show that ω t+1 ≥ ω t with ω t+1 ω t with the equality holding only when y φ. Hence, aside from the y φ case, ω t 1 would imply ω t+1 &gt; 1, a contradiction. <ref type="bibr">19</ref> For such a postcrash state to be sustainable, investors must have no incentive to start buying coins again. We verify this as follows. Let t be the period when the crash has happened. Then, p t S t−1 m t /A t and p t+1 m t+1 /A t+1 . Because the bubble sped up adoption, we have m t &gt; 1−λ t 1−λ δ. So mt+1 mt δ+λmt mt &lt; 1−λ t+1 1−λ t . As a result, pt+1 pt &lt; 1. 20 Some readers might notice that ω t here evolves independently of m t . This result is also special to the y φ condition. <ref type="bibr">21</ref> Another way to see the intuition here is to note if we let m t follow its natural path by setting φ 0, Equation (16) reduces to (3). Hence, the natural user adoption by itself cannot produce Proposition 1. <ref type="bibr">22</ref> To see this, consider the case where there are M 2 units of users. We normalize M to 1 by treating every two actual users as one user in the model. However, this normalization means that each user in the model holds x 2 units of endowment. So we further normalize this endowment to x 1 by deflating dollars by a factor of two. A consequence of this deflation is that investor endowment, y, needs to be halved as well. <ref type="bibr">23</ref> For an example, y 0.25, φ 1, λ δ 0.25, and ω 1 0.5.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. (Color online) Upper Bounds of ω 1 for Bubble Existence, No Users</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3. Two-Sided User Market</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4. (Color online) Examples of Confidence Paths</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5. (Color online) Upper Bounds of ω 1 for Bubble Existence</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure A.3 shows both the historical supply of bitcoins and the fitted exponential curve. The yearly β is estimated to be around 0.825.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure A. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure A.1. (Color online) Probability Density Function of Beta(α, 1/α)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure A. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure A.2. Plot of g t (ω t ) Figure A.3. (Color online) Bitcoin Historical Supply</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure A. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure A.4. Vendor-Shopper Network</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure A.5. (Color online) ω 1 Upper Bounds for Bubble Existence, Nonlinear Adoption</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure A. 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure A.6. (Color online) ω 1 Upper Bounds for Bubble Existence, Investor (Inv.) Valuing Liquidity</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Wei and Dukes: Cryptocurrency Adoption with Speculative Price BubblesMarketing Science, 2021, vol. 40, no. 2, pp. 241-260, © 2020 which we will make clear below when deriving the equilibrium. This specification of investor belief is motivated by a discretization of the more flexible beta distribution: p t+1 ∼ L t • Beta(α t , 1/α t ), where a larger α t puts more probability on the larger values in [0, L t ].6   </figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Wei and Dukes: Cryptocurrency Adoption with Speculative Price Bubbles Marketing Science, 2021, vol. 40, no. 2, pp. 241-260, © 2020 INFORMS iii. Arbitrage-free. The expected return of investing in coins equals the outside good's return (normalized to 1):</figDesc><table><row><cell>E p t+1 ( p t</cell><cell>)</cell><cell>1 p t</cell><cell>(</cell><cell>L t ω 2 t + S t</cell><cell>)</cell><cell>1.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Wei and Dukes: Cryptocurrency Adoption with Speculative Price Bubbles Marketing Science, 2021, vol. 40, no. 2, pp. 241-260, © 2020 INFORMS Now suppose m 1 δ. By (B.4) with t 1, we can show that</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">MarketingScience, 2021, vol. 40, no. 2, pp. 241-260, © 2020 </note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank Fabio Caldieraro, Hongxun Ruan, Yi Zhu, and the participants of the 14th Bass FORMS Conference (University of Texas at Dallas) for comments, as well as Irina Osipova for research assistance. This paper was circulated previously with the title "Cryptocurrency Adoption: The Role of Speculative Price Bubbles in Product Diffusion."</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix A</head><p>A.1. Continuous Beliefs For our analytical results, we relied on a simplified discrete system of investor beliefs (see Equation ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>)). Below, we consider a continuous version for this belief.</p><p>Let us specify p t+1 ∼ L t × Beta(α t , 1/α t ). As Figure A.1 illustrates, the mass of this distribution moves away from 0 toward L t as α t increases from 0 to +∞. The distribution family includes the uniform distribution when α t 1. Also, Figure <ref type="figure">A</ref>.1 shows that the distribution family that we consider is inclusive with respect to mirror beliefs: the probability density function (p.d.f.) of Beta(α t , 1/α t ) is exactly the mirror image of the p.d.f. of Beta(α t , 1/α t ) with α t 1/α t .</p><p>The two-point specification in Equation ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>) is an approximate discretization of the continuous family. To see this, suppose that we want to discretize the beta family to a</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Abreu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brunnermeier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bubbles and crashes. Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="813" to="836" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Churning bubbles</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gorton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="813" to="836" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bitcoin pricing, adoption, and usage: Theory and evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Athey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Parashkevov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Sarukkai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<pubPlace>Stanford, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Working paper. Stanford University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new product growth model for consumer durables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="227" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why the Bass model fits without decision variables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Krishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Jain</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning about risk and return: A simple model of bubbles and crashes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Branch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am. Econ. J. Macroecon</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="191" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Market roll-out and retailer adoption for new brands</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bronnenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Mela</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="500" to="518" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Speculative bubbles, crashes and rational expectations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Blanchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="387" to="389" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From density to destiny: Using spatial dimension of sales data for early prediction of new product success</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Garber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Goldenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Libai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="419" to="428" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Facebook unveils cryptocurrency Libra in bid to reshape finance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Horwitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Olson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-unveils-crypto-wallet-based-on-currency-libra-11560850141" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wall Street Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-06-18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rational asset pricing bubbles and portfolio constraints</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hugonnier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2260" to="2302" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The efficient market hypothesis and its critics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Malkiel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Perspect</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="82" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intertemporal price discrimination with forwardlooking consumers: Application to the US market for console video-games</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Nair</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Mark. Econ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="292" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The arbitrage theory of capital asset pricing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="341" to="360" />
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical investigation of the arbitrage pricing theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Roll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Finance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1073" to="1103" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring bubble expectations and investor confidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Shiller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Psych. Financial Markets</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Network effects in alternative fuel adoption: Empirical analysis of the market for ethanol</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shriver</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="78" to="97" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A micromodel of new product adoption with heterogeneous and forward-looking consumers: Application to the digital camera category</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Mark. Econ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="371" to="407" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A mathematical model for new product diffusion: The influence of innovators and imitators</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Steffens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dnp</forename><surname>Murthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Math. Comput. Model</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the possibility of speculation under rational expectations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tirole</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1163" to="1181" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Asset bubbles and overlapping generations. Econometrica</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tirole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1499" to="1528" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New product diffusion with influentials and imitators</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Van Den Bulte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="400" to="421" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confidence and the real value of money in an overlapping generations economy. Quart</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Weil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wikipedia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Euro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euro" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-06-31" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
