<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Practice Prize Winner-Dynamic Marketing Budget Allocation Across Countries, Products, and Marketing Activities</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
							<email>marc.fischer@wiso.uni-koeln.de</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sönke</forename><surname>Albers</surname></persName>
							<email>soenke.albers@the-klu.org</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Nils</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
							<email>nils.wagner@uni-passau.de</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Monika</forename><surname>Frie</surname></persName>
							<email>monika.frie@bayer.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Cologne</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>D-50923</postCode>
									<settlement>Cologne</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Kühne Logistics University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>20457</postCode>
									<settlement>Hamburg</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Passau</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>D-94032</postCode>
									<settlement>Passau</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">Bayer Schering Pharma AG</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Practice Prize Winner-Dynamic Marketing Budget Allocation Across Countries, Products, and Marketing Activities</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1100.0627</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: June 1, 2010; accepted: October 14, 2010; Russell Winer served as the Practice Papers</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:24+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>resource allocation</term>
					<term>optimization</term>
					<term>sales force</term>
					<term>panel data</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Determining the marketing budget has been of paramount importance to marketers for many decades. Global players such as Procter &amp; Gamble (P&amp;G) spend approximately US$8.5 billion on advertising per year <ref type="bibr">(P&amp;G 2008)</ref>. Because marketing expenditures are immediately recognized as costs on the income statement, but their total impact on sales often fully unfolds only in future periods, they need to be evaluated in terms of an investment decision. In view of limited financial resources, the global annual marketing budget of a company is usually set in the previous year; i.e., it is fixed. If companies offer a broad product portfolio to customers from various countries and use a variety of communication channels, they need to break down the fixed annual budget into expenditures across countries, products, and communication activities. For many firms, this task requires determining individual budgets for hundreds of allocation units. As a result, firms face a complex decision problem: they need to allocate a fixed budget across a multitude of allocation units by evaluating the impact of these investment decisions on future cash flows. Technically, management needs to solve a dynamic optimization problem for an investment portfolio under a budget constraint. Because marketing budgets are set on an annual basis, this management challenge recurs regularly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.">State of the Art of Marketing Budget</head><p>Allocation Marketing practitioners frequently use heuristic methods when it comes to determining the marketing budget. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bigné (1995)</ref> reviews 16 studies published between 1975 and 1991 on actual budgeting behavior of North American and European firms from diverse industries. He finds that by far the most often used budget rules are the "percentage-of-sales," "objectiveand-task," and "affordability" methods. These rules usually yield results that are rather far from the optimal profit-maximizing budget. Analytic methods that <ref type="bibr">Fischer et al.:</ref> Dynamic Marketing Budget Allocation Across Countries, Products, and Marketing Activities Marketing Science 30(4), pp. 568-585, © 2011 INFORMS 569 are based on the principle of marginal returns analysis produce optimal budgets but are only considered by a minority of firms.</p><p>The academic literature has been dealing with budget questions for a long time. A large body of work focuses on optimizing the budget for a single product in a static environment (for an overview, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Hanssens et al. 2001</ref>). Among the earliest and most influential contributions is the work by <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Dorfman and Steiner (1954)</ref>. They derive necessary conditions that must hold for static profit maximization when optimal levels for several marketing-mix variables are set simultaneously. The solution offers important general insights into the budgeting problem but does not offer guidance for implementation into marketing practice. In addition, it does not consider dynamics and the perspective of a multicountry, multiproduct firm.</p><p>A large stream of papers takes a dynamic perspective (for an overview, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Erickson 2003)</ref>. The recent paper by <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Naik et al. (2005)</ref>, for example, considers interaction effects between advertising and promotion under dynamic oligopolistic competition. The focus of these studies, however, remains on single products. They do not inform on how budgets are simultaneously set for several products in view of limited financial resources.</p><p>This question can only be answered by an integrated allocation approach. Previous research (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Tull et al. 1986</ref>) has shown that profit improvement from better allocation across products or regions is much higher than from improving the overall budget. However, despite its high managerial relevance and potential for profit improvement, contributions by marketing scholars are rare <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Reibstein et al. 2009</ref>). 1 An important emerging literature stream (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Kumar et al. 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">, Reinartz et al. 2005</ref>) deals with the problem of resource allocation across customers. Typically, these approaches require data on individual customer behavior and focus on service industries. Other articles focus on problems of sales territory design and sales force size (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Skiera and</ref><ref type="bibr">Albers 1998, Zoltners and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Sinha 2005)</ref> but do not address allocation decisions for products in multiproduct, multicountry businesses. Only a few approaches are based on aggregate market response models that can be calibrated with sales and marketing data at the product level, which is the primary data source in many industries. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Lodish et al. (1988)</ref> propose an allocation algorithm for a specific type of market response that has been adopted by a pharmaceutical company. <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Doyle and Saunders (1990)</ref> derive a closedform allocation solution under a budget constraint <ref type="bibr">1</ref> We acknowledge other research traditions that deal with allocation problems. For example, international trade theory discusses issues of dynamic resource allocation across countries at a macro level (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Wong 1995)</ref>.</p><p>for the semi-log response model and apply it to a British retailer. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Albers (1998)</ref> generalizes the solution to the case of an arbitrary response function and allocation unit. Because a closed-form solution in terms of response parameters no longer exists, he proposes a heuristic rule and shows via simulation that it quickly converges to the optimal numerical solution. Although these approaches consider trade-offs among products of a portfolio for budget decisions, they are focused on short-term profit maximization. Marketing decisions, however, need to account for dynamics as well. On the one side, dynamic considerations result from lagged effects that can be represented by a marketing stock variable. On the other side, dynamic considerations arise from the fact that a portfolio mixes products with different ages and growth opportunities. Requirements for marketing support change as the product evolves along its life cycle. To the best of our knowledge, a dynamic marketing budget allocation approach for a product portfolio has not been suggested so far.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2.">Contribution to Allocation</head><p>Theory and Practice In this paper, we propose an allocation method for breaking down a global marketing budget into individual budgets at the country-productmarketing-activity level. We take the position of an international firm that offers a broad portfolio of products to customers from different countries. Products are promoted by various activities, including classical advertising, below-the-line activities, personal selling, etc. Each year the firm sets a global marketing budget that is to be spent by the various allocation units in the year ahead. The portfolio is composed of products that differ in their life cycle stage. The firm wishes to maximize the discounted total profits of its portfolio. Although we propose a method that recommends how to allocate the annual global budget across countries, products, and marketing activities, we do not address the tactical problem of intertemporal allocation of an individual budget within the year (for a summary of this literature, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Doganoglu and Klapper 2006)</ref>.</p><p>We contribute to allocation theory by offering a solution to the dynamic portfolio-profit maximization problem. The theoretical solution provides important insights into how individual budgets should be set so that they account for differences in profit contribution, marketing effectiveness, and growth potential. The optimal budget describes an endogenous relationship where various variables need to be in their global optimum. This relationship also holds under Nash competition. Under both monopoly and Nash competition, however, it can only be solved with numerical methods. Numerical optimization often Marketing Science 30(4), pp. 568-585, © 2011 INFORMS faces significant acceptance barriers in practice, which may be one reason for the frequent use of suboptimal budgeting heuristics <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bigné 1995)</ref>. Although the numerical method produces the optimal budget, the product manager cannot reproduce the result on its own. Therefore, he or she does not understand why the recommended budget level should be optimal for his or her product.</p><p>Hence, our second contribution is to allocation practice. We develop a near-optimal allocation rule that addresses the demand for simple allocation rules by practitioners. The rule is directly derived from the theoretical solution. It provides insights into the solution structure and can be used with a spreadsheet. In a simulation study, we demonstrate that the allocation heuristic quickly converges to the optimal solution under varying conditions. Although easy to understand and to implement, the heuristic goes beyond widespread budgeting rules such as the percentage-of-sales method (size of the business). Specifically, it integrates and trades off information about the following:</p><p>-the size of the business, -the profit contribution margin, -the (short-term) effectiveness of marketing investments, -the carryover effect of marketing investments, -the growth potential, and -the time value of money.</p><p>Together with the management of Bayer, we developed and implemented the heuristic for the product portfolio of Bayer's primary care business unit. This portfolio includes 36 products from four strategic therapeutic areas that are marketed worldwide. Product managers can choose among six different types of marketing activities such as detailing or print advertising. The project had significant impact on the marketing budgeting practice at Bayer. It initiated an important change in the understanding of the allocation task by providing structure and solution to a complex problem. The empirical application revealed a profit improvement potential of more than 50% or nearly E500 million of incremental discounted cash flows over the next five years. Finally, the project significantly contributed to an organizational change that resulted in the creation of a new marketing intelligence unit. One of the main tasks of this unit is to support top management in evaluating the financial impact of marketing decisions.</p><p>The rest of this paper is organized as follows. In the next section, we describe our analytic approach to derive the proposed heuristic allocation rule and the associated simulation study. Section 3 provides information about Bayer and the market background. The fourth section focuses on the empirical application. We discuss the data, the estimation of the market response model, and validation issues. Section 5 presents the implementation of the allocation heuristic in Excel. We further evaluate the empirical findings and the impact of the project on Bayer. We close with limitations and suggestions for future research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">A Heuristic Rule for Dynamic</head><p>Marketing Budget Allocation 2.1. Theory Assume an international firm that operates across the world and sells several products, which may belong to the same or different categories. The number of products offered may differ across countries. Product management can choose among various marketing activities, such as print advertising, personal selling, direct mailing, etc., to enhance current and future sales. At the end of each year, marketing investment plans for the next year are developed. We assume that the firm wishes to maximize the net present value of its product portfolio over a planning period T , e.g., five years. We further assume that a total marketing budget R has already been set at the firm level. We do not model this process; i.e., R is exogenous. In addition, the total budget is assumed to be constant over the planning horizon. Top management, however, may decide to adjust the level during next year's planning cycle.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.1.">Allocation Solution for an Arbitrary</head><p>Growth Function. Denote q t, S, Z) as the sales of a product in period t that depends on S, the marketing stock, and other variables (e.g., competitive marketing stock) that are summarized in the row vector Z. Without loss of generality, we focus on only one own stock variable. Let us decompose sales into two components,</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">q t S Z = g t S t f S t Z t (1)</formula><p>where g • is a growth function that represents a basic pattern of growth dynamics as known from diffusion and product life cycle research, and f • is a separate response function that measures the direct impact of S and Z on sales. Note that this decomposition is helpful for interpretation but does not limit the generality of our model development. The growth function describes the evolution of new product sales over the life cycle and is assumed to be influenced by investments in the marketing stock. Research on diffusion processes and product life cycles provides broad evidence for the dependence of growth dynamics on marketing-mix variables (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bass et al. 2000</ref>. The marketing stock S follows a dynamic process that satisfies the differential equation </p><formula xml:id="formula_1">dS dt = − S + x x ≥ 0 and S 0 known (2)</formula><p>where x denotes marketing expenditures and is the depreciation rate of the marketing stock. Let k denote the country with the index set K, and let i denote the product, whereas the set of products offered in country k may vary and is given by I k . Let n denote the type of marketing activity or spending category, respectively, and let N i be the associated index set that may vary across products. We omit the time argument unless it is needed for an unambiguous understanding. S ki is an N i -dimensional row vector summarizing the activity-specific marketing stocks for product i. Let ET measure the elapsed time since the launch of a product in t = 0; let r be a discount rate, 0 &lt; r &lt; ; let p denote price; let c be marginal cost; and let x n be activity-specific marketing expenditures. The constrained dynamic profit maximization problem of the firm is  The final stock S kinT is free but must be nonnegative and satisfy the budget constraint. In the appendix, we show how this problem can be solved by employing the calculus of variations together with the Lagrange approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Kamien and Schwartz 1991)</ref>. Specifically, the solution to the 1 + k∈K i∈I k N i Euler-Lagrange equations is</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">max S ki = T t=0 e −</formula><formula xml:id="formula_3">x * kin R = p ki −c ki q * ki f x * kin + g x * kin / r +1− kin • l∈K j∈I l m∈N j p lj −c lj q * lj f x * ljm + g x * ljm r +1− ljm + l∈K j∈I l m∈N j dS * ljm /dt −1 + 1 R dS * kin dt ∀ k ∈ K i ∈ I k n ∈ N i t ∈ 0 T (4)</formula><p>where f x denotes the current-period elasticity of sales with respect to marketing expenditures, g x measures the sales growth elasticity, measures the marketing carryover (with = 1− ), is the dynamic Lagrange multiplier, and all other terms are as defined earlier. The asterisk indicates that variable values correspond to the optimal solution for the marketing budget, which is measured as the optimal share in the fixed total budget R in Equation (4). In a common product portfolio, the number of allocation units tends to be quite large. Because the total budget R to be allocated is fixed, some stocks increase and others decrease in the dynamic optimum. As a result, gains and losses tend to cancel each other out, and the second summand in the denominator of Equation (4) is close to zero. Considering the restriction that optimal budget shares must sum to one (see the appendix), we obtain the following general solution for the optimal budget that is close to solution (4): </p><formula xml:id="formula_4">x * kin t max w * kin t 0 l∈K j∈I l m∈N j max w * ljm t 0 R ∀k ∈ K i ∈ I k n ∈ N i t ∈ 0 T<label>(</label></formula><p>where w is an allocation weight, and all other terms are as defined earlier.</p><p>The optimal solution considers dynamics in two different ways. First, it incorporates the dynamic effects of building and leveraging the marketing stock, which is reflected in the marketing carryover coefficient . Second, it accounts for the growth potential of a product that is related to marketing investments as reflected in the growth elasticity g x . Note that our sales response in Equation (1) includes a growth function, g • , that describes the evolution of new product sales along its life cycle. The growth elasticity measures the power of marketing to shape the life cycle. Hence, we assume that the Marketing Science 30(4), pp. 568-585, © 2011 INFORMS growth process is endogenous with respect to marketing expenditures. A recent empirical study on drugs by  supports this premise. The authors find that the shape of the life cycle is indeed influenced by investments in the marketing stock. More importantly, their results suggest that marketing investments in the growth potential of a new product have a strong impact on future cumulative sales and discounted cash flows. On the basis of a parametric growth model, we show subsequently how the optimal solution favors shifting marketing resources to newer products so that they can leverage their endogenous growth potential.</p><p>Equations ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_5">6</ref>) represent the first-order conditions of the constrained dynamic maximization problem. These conditions also need to be fulfilled by each firm under Nash competition. Here, each firm sets marketing budgets independently of its competitors by taking the competitor budgets as given. Equilibrium values may be obtained by numerically and simultaneously solving the budget equations for the portfolio of each competitor. Note that our general sales model in (1) assumes product sales being influenced by competitor variables such as competitive price and competitive marketing expenditures. Competitor actions thus have an impact on the optimal solution because they change q * , f x * , and g x * in Equation (6).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.2.">Allocation Solution for a Specific Growth</head><p>Function. We now introduce a parametric growth function and derive the growth elasticity for this specific case. This enables us to demonstrate the effects of the growth potential on the allocation solution in more detail. Following the study on drug life cycles by  and consistent with our empirical application at Bayer, we specify the growth function as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">g ki t S ki = ki t a ki S ki e −b ki S ki t</formula><p>with ki a ki b ki &gt; 0 and t ∈ 0 (7)</p><p>where is a scaling constant, and a and b are growth parameters that depend on the marketing stock. The model describes an asymmetric growth path that leads to a single peak in the life cycle, which occurs at t Peak = a/b. Hence, the growth parameters determine the time-to-peak sales and, as  also show, the height-of-peak sales. In addition, they define the shape of the life cycle. Equation ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>) is equivalent to the gamma distribution, which has been frequently used by researchers because of its flexibility to capture many shapes (see the appendix). For example, if a = 0, Equation ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>) reduces to the exponential distribution that is characteristic for many media products such as movies. Most importantly, we Sales (in $000)</p><p>Notes. See Equation ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>). Growth parameters in low investment case: a = 1 1, b = 0 10 (scale parameter = 1). Growth parameters in high investment case: a = 1 6, b = 0 15 (scale parameter = 1).</p><p>assume that marketing investments have a long-term impact on cumulative sales that is mediated by the growth parameters. Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> compares two life cycles that peak around the same time. Cumulative sales are, however, quite different because of the differences in growth parameters that are assumed to arise from either low or high marketing investments. In the appendix, we show that cumulative sales are always higher for the life cycle whose difference between growth parameters a and b is larger.</p><p>From Equation ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>), we obtain for the growth elasticity g x kin = a kin ln t a ki − b kin t b ki which can be inserted into (6) to yield the optimal allocation weight in planning period t</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">w * kin t = p ki −c ki q * ki f x * kin + * a kin ln ET ki +t a * ki − * b kin ET ki +t b * ki / r +1− kin (8)</formula><p>where a kin and b kin measure the elasticity of the growth parameters with respect to expenditures on marketing activity n, and all other terms are as defined earlier. Note that ET (elapsed time since the launch in t = 0) accounts for differences in launch times among products in the portfolio context.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.3.">Implications for Budget Allocation.</head><p>The optimal solution provides a number of intuitive insights into the allocation problem. Equations ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_5">6</ref>) show that a fixed budget should be allocated according to a simple proportional rule. The optimal budget for a product relative to other products increases with its contribution margin p −c and its sales base q. Similarly, the larger that product i's long-term marketing effectiveness for activity n is, the higher its budget. The long-term marketing effectiveness is composed of the short-term sales elasticity, the discount rate, and the marketing carryover: f x * / r +1− . Consequently, if long-term marketing effectiveness is larger across all of product i's activities compared with other products, the total budget for product i increases. Finally, Equations ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_5">6</ref>) reveal the importance of a product's growth potential for budget setting as reflected by the sales growth elasticity. This term varies over the life cycle. It is largest at the beginning when most of the sales are yet to come. Hence, the potential impact of marketing expenditures on future cash flows is greatest at this stage, which is why newer products get a higher allocation weight and thus a larger share in total budget. Because of the growth potential, the optimal marketing budget might even be higher than are the revenues of a new product at the beginning of its life; i.e., the solution may suggest spending money on products that involve a temporary loss.</p><p>The role of the growth potential term becomes clearer when we consider a specific growth function such as in Equation ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>). Now, the optimal allocation weight is expressed in terms of growth parameters. From ( <ref type="formula">8</ref>), it follows that the larger the difference * a ln ET +t a * − * b ET +t b * is, the higher the budget for a product. For products that have been launched in the same year, we know that cumulative sales are higher for those products for which the distance between a and b is larger (see the appendix). The distance may be enlarged by marketing investments to a certain extent as reflected in the elasticity parameters a and b . The growth expectations of a product also change over time. Because the growth potential term varies with t, this term accounts for this. To facilitate interpretation, assume that * a = * b = 1. Then, our measure simplifies to ln ET +t a * − ET +t b * . For mature products, it gets smaller and may turn negative at some point in time. In the decline stage, the budget is likely to be zero because the sum of the short-term marketing elasticity and the growth potential measure in Equation ( <ref type="formula">8</ref>) eventually becomes smaller than zero.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Proposed Near-Optimal Allocation Rule</head><p>The optimal budget for spending category n of product i in country k describes an endogenous relationship where various variables need to be in their optimum. To obtain the optimal values, we need to solve the profit maximization problem (3)-(3.3) numerically. The use of numerical methods, however, has two disadvantages. First, it requires that we explicitly specify the sales response function, which limits the generalizability of the solution approach. Second, marketing managers are reluctant to accept results from numerical optimization because they do not understand how the budget recommendation is derived. Although the optimization algorithm implicitly evaluates and trades off factors such as marketing effectiveness, growth potential, or the size of the business, this process is not transparent for the manager.</p><p>Consistent with <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Little (1970)</ref>, we believe that the simplicity of the allocation rule is important because it enables the manager to understand the allocation solution. The wide distribution of heuristic budget rules among companies (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bigné 1995)</ref> despite the advances in the analytical marketing literature seems to support the need for simplicity in allocation methods in practice. We derive an allocation heuristic directly from the theoretical solution that produces near-optimal budgets and is easy to understand for managers:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">x kint = w kint l∈K j∈I l m∈N j w ljmt R t ∀k ∈ K i ∈ I k n ∈ N i t ∈ 0 T (9) with w kint = kin t−1 r +1− kin Long-term marketing effectiveness • d ki •RV ki t−1 Profit contribution • kit Growth potential<label>(10)</label></formula><p>wherẽ</p><p>x kint Near-optimal budget for marketing activity n and product i in country k and period t; w kint Heuristic allocation weight for marketing activity n and product i in country k and period t; R t : Total budget to be allocated in period t; r: Discount rate (capital cost of firm, strategic business unit, etc.); kin : Carryover coefficient of marketing activity n for product i in country k; kin t−1 : Short-term sales elasticity with respect to product i's marketing expenditures on activity n in country k available from period t −1;</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">d ki : (Percentage) contribution margin for product i in country k = p ki −c ki /p ki ];</formula><p>RV ki t−1 : Revenue level of product i in country k available from period t −1 (= p ki t−1 •q ki t−1 ; and kit : Multiplier to measure the growth potential of product i in country k and period t.</p><p>The basic idea of the heuristic is to explicitly map Equations ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_5">6</ref>), the true optimum, to Equations ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) and (10), the heuristic approach. We do so by substituting currently available values for revenues and sales elasticity for their optimal values that are only endogenously determined by solving the equation system iteratively. We approximate the growth potential by a multiplier that divides expected revenues in five years (planning horizon) by the current revenue level. By this heuristic approach, we ensure that products get a greater share of the total budget as long as they are expected to grow. In contrast, when they are expected to turn into their decline stage, their budget is reduced. Current values of revenues are available from last year, and the contribution margin is a target figure decided by management. Data for the carryover coefficient, sales elasticity, and the growth multiplier are not readily available but must be estimated. In our empirical application, we specify a parametric response model to estimate these quantities econometrically. However, we note that this is not a prerequisite of the allocation heuristic. The user may adopt other, nonparametric approaches to estimate the required data.</p><p>Basically, the proposed heuristic is a simple proportional rule that integrates relevant information from three areas:</p><p>-the long-term effectiveness of marketing investments in the focal product, -the profit contribution of the focal product, and -the focal product's growth expectations.</p><p>The logic behind the selection and integration of information into a proportionality rule is well founded in theory but at the same time easy to understand for practitioners.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Testing the Near Optimality of the Allocation</head><p>Rule via Simulation By definition, the heuristic solution is likely to differ from the optimal solution, but it should not deviate too much to be useful. Because the heuristic rule is a contraction mapping on the theoretical optimum, it exhibits a fixed-point property. According to the Banach fixed-point theorem, an iterative sequence such as ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_8">10</ref>), where values are subsequently replaced by values closer to the fixed point, will converge to the fixed point, which is in our case the true optimum <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Granas and Dugundji 2003)</ref>. Note that this holds also under Nash competition because the Nash equilibrium establishes the fixed point. The interesting question is how fast the convergence process is.</p><p>To analyze the performance of the heuristic, we therefore conducted an experimental simulation study (for full details, see the electronic companion to this paper, which is available as part of the online version that can be found at http://mktsci.pubs.informs .org/). In this study, we analyze a firm with a product portfolio of four products. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> We consider two scenarios, a single-firm scenario and a competitive scenario including a second firm with a portfolio of four products. Sales are generated by a multiplicative market response function, the most frequent type of response in empirical studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Hanssens et al. 2001</ref>). The response function includes an asymmetric growth function, consistent with Equation ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>), and two expenditure categories whose stocks evolve according to Equation (2). Six factors that characterize the products in the portfolio were experimentally manipulated: current-period elasticities, carryover coefficients, size of the revenue bases, profit contribution margins, growth parameters, and launch dates as reflected in the elapsed times since launch. Each factor has two levels. The initial condition assumes equally distributed budgets across the two marketing activities and four products. We use a five-year planning horizon, and the objective criterion is the discounted profit over the five years.</p><p>Optimal budgets are obtained by numerically solving the dynamic optimization problem as described by Equations ( <ref type="formula">3</ref>)-(3.3). To reduce overall computation time, which is especially high in the competitive scenario, we construct an efficient Latin-square design that contains eight portfolio profiles. Profiles are randomly assigned to the two competitors. Consistent with practice, we simulate an annually recurring budget planning process and investigate 12 planning cycles. We compare the performance of the heuristic with the optimal solution in terms of (profit) suboptimality and match with the optimally allocated budget (for details, see the electronic companion). Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> shows how these two performance criteria develop over time (the number of planning cycles).</p><p>Values in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> represent mean values across the 16 experimental conditions. If we do not apply the heuristic rule to improve the initial naïve budget allocation, the deviation from discounted profits of the optimal solution amounts to 19.2% on average. This suboptimality increases to 28.6% after 12 planning cycles (not shown in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>). The match with the optimal budget allocation is 47.1% and remains around this level (50% after 12 planning cycles). As Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> shows, we already achieve a dramatic improvement with our heuristic rule in the first planning cycle (4.3% profit suboptimality and 74.6% match with optimal budget allocation). Moreover, the rule quickly converges to the optimal solution when it is repeatedly used in the following planning cycles (0.95% profit suboptimality and 90.7% match with optimal budget allocation). This result holds under both the single-firm and the competitive scenario. Hence, the proposed rule appears to be a useful allocation heuristic.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Background for Implementation in Practice</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Degree of suboptimality (discounted profits over 5 years)</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Match with optimal budget allocation</head><p>Planning cycle Planning cycle </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Market Background</head><p>The primary care business unit of Bayer comprises prescription drugs that operate in four separate competitive market environments or therapeutic areas, respectively. These drugs treat diabetes, hypertension, erectile dysfunction, and infectious diseases. The hypertension segment is the largest one and includes several subcategories, such as beta blockers, calcium channel blockers, angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitors, and AII-antagonists. Bayer has several offerings in this segment. With E626 million, the calcium channel blocker Adalat was its bestselling primary care drug <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bayer 2009</ref>) in 2008 and has been in the market since the mid-1970s. Although the drug has lost patent protection more than 20 years ago and is facing increasing generic competition, it contributes substantially to sales and profits of the primary care business unit. Avelox and To summarize, the primary care business unit of Bayer holds a broad portfolio of drugs that are at different stages in their life cycle, face varying conditions of competition, and differ in their contributions to sales and profits. Hence, the challenge for the management was to find a balance in the allocation of marketing resources that trades off the size of the business, the growth expectations, and, eventually, the effectiveness of marketing expenditures. The main objective was to improve the process and results of annual budget allocation in order to maximize discounted profits from the product portfolio over a planning horizon of five years.</p><p>Bayer invests substantial resources in marketing and sales activities. Total marketing and selling expenditures were E7.6 billion (∼23.1% of total sales) Marketing Science 30(4), pp. 568-585, © 2011 INFORMS in 2008. For confidentiality reasons, we cannot report the exact figures for the primary care product portfolio. The lion's share is spent on detailing targeted at general practitioners and specialists. Competitors spent a significant share of their budget on pharmacists' detailing. In addition, Bayer invests in print advertisements, direct mailing activities, invitations of physicians to symposia, and other marketing activities. The implementation of the allocation tool is targeted at the five main European countries that contribute the largest share to total sales. The U.S. market also provides a substantial portion of sales. However, the Bayer products are marketed here by licensee firms. Hence, budget decisions are not under the control of the Bayer management.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Data and Model Estimation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Data</head><p>To calibrate the heuristic allocation tool for Bayer, we need to estimate a number of input variables. Specifically, we require product-specific data on the shortterm sales elasticity of different types of marketing investments, carryover coefficients, and information to compute the growth multiplier. For this purpose, we use 10 years <ref type="bibr">(1996)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1997)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1998)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1999)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2000)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2001)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2002)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2003)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2004)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2005)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2006)</ref> of quarterly marketing and sales data at the product level to estimate a market response model for each product market. IMS Health, Inc., provided data on unit sales counted in standard units, revenues (all in euros), and the dates Notes. All units and EUR figures are on a quarterly basis. The marketing stock S kint for activity n of drug i in country k and period t is defined as S kint = t =0 1− TA x kint , where TA is the quarterly decay rate, specific for each therapeutic area TA, and x measures the marketing expenditures. We used a numerical search algorithm to estimate the decay coefficient in a first-stage nonlinear regression of Equation ( <ref type="formula">11</ref>) that minimizes the residual sum of squares. Because of the complexity of our model, we could only identify decay parameters at the level of the therapeutic area. With better data, a brand-and marketing activity-specific parameter may be obtained. If we did not observe initial stocks, we imputed the first quarter by dividing the average quarterly expenditures of the first observed year by the decay coefficient.</p><p>a Spending category was only rarely used by firms.</p><p>of product launches, which we use to obtain orderof-entry and life cycle information. We computed prices from revenues and unit sales. Via their CAM database, CEGEDIM, S.A., provided information on detailing expenditures targeted at general practitioners, specialists, and pharmacists. In addition, we have information available on professional journal advertising expenditures (including direct mailing); expenditures on physicians for invitations to symposia, meetings, etc. (hereafter denoted as meeting invitations); and other expenditures (hereafter denoted as OME).</p><p>The database covers the four strategic Bayer primary care prescription drug businesses, antidiabetes, hypertension, erectile dysfunction, and anti-infectives, in five countries, Germany, France, the United Kingdom, Italy, and Spain. Bayer management helped us to identify the relevant subcategories and competitors within each therapeutic area by country. Subcategories vary from 12 for anti-infectives to 1 for erectile dysfunction. Products vary from 15 for the erectile dysfunction area to 306 for the Hypertension area (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">1</ref>).</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">1</ref> also shows mean values and standard deviations for the variables used in estimation. The detailing stocks for general practitioners are highest, followed by the stocks for specialists. Stocks are computed consistent with Equation (2) (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Berndt et al. 1995)</ref>. Details on estimation are given in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">1</ref>. The carryover is highest for hypertension, which is a chronic disease, and lowest for anti-infectives, which   are usually used for a one-time therapy (see also Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">2 and 3</ref>). Note that not all marketing spending categories are equally utilized across the different markets. For example, OME for antidiabetes and antiinfective drugs are rarely used, so the data are not rich enough for estimating reliable marketing effects. Prices are highest in the youngest category, the erectile dysfunction category. Finally, we note that sample sizes differ to a great extent because of the number of brands. The erectile dysfunction category was launched only in 1998, so we have the smallest sample size here, which limits model estimation to some extent. Finally, note that the samples are unbalanced; i.e., several drugs were launched after the start of the observation period and a few drugs left the market during that period. Thus, we observe 25.6 quarters per drug on average.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Specification of Market Response Model</head><p>Following Fischer and Albers (2010), we specify a double-log sales response function for each therapeutic area. Let sales of drug i in country k and period t be defined as follows:   Notes. NS, not significant (p &gt; 0 05). Product-specific parameter estimates for Bayer brands cannot be shown for confidentiality reasons. Effects for country dummies and seasonal dummies are not shown but can be obtained from the authors upon request.</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">lnq kit = 0ki +</formula><p>a Because of the small number of observations and associated collinearity issues, we were unable to fit a model that includes competitor price and interactions of the elapsed-time-since-launch variables with total marketing stock. Therefore, results do not reflect interactions but main effects of elapsed time since launch.</p><p>b Spending category was only rarely used by firms. sOME kit : Stock of other marketing expenditures of drug i in country k and period t; scomp kit : Stock of cumulative marketing expenditures by drug i's competitors in country k and period t; prc kit : Price of drug i in country k and period t; comprc kit : Average price by drug i's competitors in country k and period t;</p><p>OE ki : Order of entry by subcategory of drug i in country k; stot kit : Stock of drug i's total marketing expenditures in country k and period t;</p><p>ET kit : Elapsed time since launch of drug i in country k and period t;</p><p>CTY k : Country dummy variable for country k (1 for k = l, 0 otherwise); SD ht : Seasonal dummy variable for quarter h and period t (1 if period t corresponds to quarter h, 0 otherwise); , , , ': (Unobserved) parameter vectors; , 2 : Error terms and error variances; i: Index for drug that belongs to country-specific set I k ; k = 1 2 l M (number of countries); t = 1 2 T i (number of periods per drug); and h = 1 2 H (quarters of the year). The 1−6 parameters measure the effects of the own marketing expenditure stock variables; 1 captures the effect of competitive marketing expenditures that are observable to competitors. We combine all expenditure types in a cumulative stock variable. We could have specified a greater number of more differentiated competitor variables. Because our interest does not rest on competitive effects, we save degrees of freedom by using a composite variable. The same argument applies for the average competitor price, which we include in addition to the own price. The sales model does not incorporate a distribution variable. Because pharmacies in Europe are required to list every prescription drug, there is no variation in this variable.</p><p>We include interactions of the stock of total marketing expenditures with elapsed time and the log of elapsed time to measure an asymmetric growth function that is consistent with Equation (7). By this specification, we assume that the growth parameters a and b are scaled by the stock, whereas 5 and 6 measure the two scaling factors and are to be estimated. Note that the resulting growth parameters a and b are drug-specific because they are determined by a drug's total marketing stock.</p><p>Finally, our model incorporates a number of control variables that have been shown to impact sales of pharmaceuticals. With order of entry, we control for the disadvantage of a late market entry (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Berndt et al. 1995)</ref>. Because order of entry is defined at the subcategory level, we may have more than one pioneer drug in a therapeutic area. We account for product quality, brand equity, and other unobserved time-invariant variables by specifying a random drugspecific constant ( 0ki . Because we include the randomness into the conditional mean function but not the error term, we avoid potential endogeneity issues that arise from the correlation of unobserved product quality, brand equity, etc., with marketing-mix variables <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Fischer and Albers 2010)</ref>. Even though we do not model endogeneity in budget setting, e.g., allocating resources to more effective activities as represented by elasticities 1−6 , we effectively control for it and obtain consistent parameter estimates. We account for market size differences by including country dummies. Seasonal dummy variables by country control for seasonal variation in demand.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Estimation and Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.1.">Estimation.</head><p>We estimate four models, one for each therapeutic area. The specification of the sales model accounts for heterogeneity in the constant term and marketing effectiveness. We impose the following heterogeneity structure on these parameters:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">kiv =¯ v + v1 1ki + v2 2ki with 1ki 2ki ∼ N 0 1 and Cov 1ki 2ki = 0 (12)</formula><p>where kiv represents an unknown drug-specific parameter associated with predictor v ∈ 0 6 ;¯ v , v1 , and v2 are heterogeneity parameters to be estimated; and 1ki and 2ki denote variance components that vary by drug and country. The implied variance of kiv is ( <ref type="formula">2</ref>v1 + 2 v2 . The variance-covariance matrix for ki is given by = '. We adopt the estimation approach used by <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Fischer and Albers (2010)</ref>. Estimation also produces a set of posterior means of the drug-specific elasticity parameters (for details, see Fischer and Albers 2010). <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">2 and 3</ref> show the results of model estimations. Because of confidentiality reasons, we cannot show individual estimates for Bayer products. Reported estimates therefore reflect market averages. In-sample model fit is very good across all four therapeutic areas. Pseudo R 2 , which is based on the squared correlation between predicted and observed values of the criterion variable, ranges from 0.933 (hypertension) to 0.973 (erectile dysfunction). Because we account for drug heterogeneity, it is quite high. In a few cases, a marketing spending category was used by only a very small number of firms, leading to an inflation of zero-stock values (e.g., OME for antidiabetes and anti-infectives). Estimation of marketing effects was unreliable in such cases, so we excluded this variable from the model. The relatively low number of 233 observations in the young erectile dysfunction category created collinearity issues for the interactions of total marketing stock with the elapsedtime variables and for the price variables. Because we could not separate the associated effects, we estimated only main effects with respect to elapsed time since launch and the own-price effect. In addition, we include a dummy variable for the pioneer Viagra, because only two competitors followed in the same quarter, and the common order-of-entry variable lacks variation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2.">Results. Tables</head><p>In a double-log model, parameter estimates for marketing-mix variables correspond to elasticities. These elasticities refer to marketing stock variables and reflect long-term elasticities with respect to current-period expenditures. To obtain short-term elasticities, the stock elasticity needs to be multiplied with the decay coefficient. Elasticities for detailing and other marketing activities vary substantially across the different therapeutic areas. In general, they are highest in the erectile dysfunction category, which is not surprising because this category is the youngest category and still in its growth phase. Among the detailing elasticities, GP detailing appears to be more effective than is detailing at specialists and pharmacists. However, considering that specialists account only for a share of approximately 20% in antidiabetes and approximately 27% in hypertension, segmentspecific specialist detailing elasticities are four to five times higher. Note that for the application of our allocation heuristic, the sales elasticities with respect to total brand sales as reported in Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">2 and 3</ref> are relevant. Elasticities for professional journal advertising, meeting invitations, and OME are usually considerably smaller than are elasticities for detailing at physicians. Finally, we note that the estimated effects are within the range of results of recent studies on pharmaceuticals (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Albers et al. 2010, Fischer and</ref>.</p><p>In terms of control variables, we find significant but inelastic own-price effects. For competitive prices, we find negative cross-effects. This finding is consistent with <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Fischer and Albers (2010)</ref>, who provide an explanation for negative cross-effects. The impact of competitive marketing expenditures is negative across all therapeutic areas, although it is not always Marketing Science 30(4), pp. 568-585, © 2011 INFORMS statistically significant. We find a negative elasticity for order of entry, as expected. Although not reported in Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">2 and 3</ref>, seasonal effects are only relevant for anti-infectives, which experience a high season in autumn and winter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.3.">Model Validation.</head><p>We checked whether our model specification and estimation are appropriate for the data in several ways. First, we split the data sets into an estimation and a holdout sample. For the holdout, we used the four quarters of the last year of our observation period. Pseudo R 2 in the holdout samples ranged from 0.922 (hypertension) to 0.972 (erectile dysfunction) and were only slightly lower than were those of the estimation samples. The same picture emerges with respect to the mean absolute percentage error (MAPE) that ranges from 1.14% (erectile dysfunction) to 4.24% (hypertension) and strongly supports the predictive validity of our response model. Second, we compared the suggested log-log brand sales model with a linear model, a semilog model, and an S-shaped model. The <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Davidson and MacKinnon (1981)</ref> test for unnested models suggests that the proposed specification is superior to the alternative specifications. By adding predicted values from an alternative response model to the predictor set of the focal model, the test checks for the additional explanatory power of the alternative specification. Finally, we checked whether the residuals follow an autoregressive process by using the test for common factors <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Greene 2006</ref>). We did not find evidence for it. Note that our sales model already incorporates dynamics in terms of marketing stock variables and the life cycle function.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Model Implementation and Impact</head><p>In this section, we describe how we implemented the allocation heuristic into a decision support tool in a spreadsheet environment. Furthermore, we discuss the various impacts the new tool and the project had on the Bayer organization.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Excel-Based Decision Support Tool</head><p>We developed a decision support tool that integrates the proposed allocation heuristic into an Excel-based software program. Excel is particularly suitable for applications in practice because it is widely used and easy to understand <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Albers 2000)</ref>. The tool is to assist the management with providing budget scenarios and their implications for the development of market shares and profits over the next five years. Specifically, the tool produces a recommendation for the allocation of the total marketing budget that is based on data on the effectiveness of marketing expenditures, including carryover and discounting effects, the size of the product's business, product profitability, and growth expectations (see Equations ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_8">10</ref>)).</p><p>The tool applies to Bayer's primary care product portfolio and covers expenditures in six spending categories for 36 products in four therapeutic areas and five countries as described previously. Hence, at the product-country-activity level, 36 (products)× 6 (spending categories) = 216 allocation decisions are made. It may easily be applied to other product portfolios that may be smaller or larger in size. Consistent with the periodicity of the response model estimation, metrics such as carryover coefficients, growth multipliers, etc., are defined at the quarterly level. The same applies to market share and profit simulations.</p><p>Based on the response model ( <ref type="formula">11</ref>), the tool demonstrates the impact of budget decisions on sales and profits by extrapolating the evolution of sales and profits over the next five years.</p><p>The heuristic rule requires us to compute an allocation weight for each marketing spending category and each drug (see Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_8">10</ref>)). Input data have been obtained either from econometric analysis or internal records. The plausibility of input data, especially the estimated sales elasticities, has been extensively discussed with different groups of managers in several workshops (global marketing, market research, product management, sales management, controlling, etc.). Internal records provided data on the discount rate, the profit contribution margin, and last year's product revenues. Estimation of the sales response model ( <ref type="formula">11</ref>) produced data on the carryover coefficient, short-term sales elasticities, and the growth potential multiplier. Computation of the growth potential multiplier is based on the life cycle function (7) that is incorporated into (11). Specifically, Growth potential multiplier kit</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>=</head><p>Elapsed Time since Launch kit + T Elapsed Time since Launch kit</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">â kit−1 •exp −b kit−1 •T (<label>13</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_13">)</formula><p>where T is the forecast horizon (20 quarters, or 5 years), andâ andb are estimated growth parameters. Because they depend on the marketing stock, we obtain estimated values from the last period. Following the needs of management, we extended the tool in two ways. First, we included a threshold for product budgets. Although our demand analysis did not find evidence for an S-shaped response that justifies a threshold, management required a threshold because of internal setup costs that are fixed at the product-and marketing-activity level. Second, we allowed for manual adjustments to budgets recommended by the heuristic. By this feature, management can account for exogenous restrictions to budget setting, e.g., to counter competitive attacks in a predetermined way. In addition, it enables management to investigate the effects of budget scenarios on market share and profit as well as on the recommended budgets for other products and marketing activities. Technically, the budget for an allocation unit is exogenously set and subtracted from the total budget. The remaining budget is allocated according to the heuristic.</p><p>The Excel-based decision support system offers a powerful tool to generate budget allocation options and analyze these options with respect to their economic consequences. The tool is easy to use and flexible enough to adapt to varying conditions of decision making.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Impact on Managerial Decision Making</head><p>The effort to develop and implement the budget allocation tool had significant impact on managerial decision making, which is reflected in several aspects.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.1.">Providing</head><p>Structure to the Problem. The suggested allocation heuristic provides structure to a complex decision problem: 216 budget decisions arise from allocating a total budget across six spending categories for 36 drugs that are marketed in different countries and therapeutic areas. The market positions of these products are quite diverse and are determined by product age and competition. Depending on age and expected changes in the competitive and market environment, products offer different growth potentials. As a first benefit, the allocation rule provides the required information to solve the problem. This information falls into three groups. The first group refers to the effectiveness of marketing expenditures to build goodwill and affect sales in the long run (short-run elasticity and discounted carryover). The second group includes information on a product's contribution to profit. This depends on the contribution margin (price minus marginal cost) as well as the size of the revenue base. The third group emphasizes the growth expectations of the product. It uses information on where the product stands in its life cycle.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.2.">Providing Solution to the Problem.</head><p>Although management had a good understanding of the type of information required for budget decisions, it benefited much from the new insights offered by the heuristic. Specifically, the allocation rule suggests that information on (1) long-term marketing effectiveness, (2) profit contribution, and (3) growth potential is to be combined in a multiplicative fashion. Implications from this rule are straightforward.</p><p>(1) Products that generate more incremental sales with the same budget should get a larger slice of the total budget. Of course, relative incremental sales tend to decline as sales and budgets increase because of saturation effects. The budget ratio of two products reflects their ratio in terms of sales elasticity.</p><p>(2) The same principle of proportionality applies to the size of sales or profit contribution, respectively. Products with a higher level of profit contribution generate more financial resources to cover their own marketing expenditures and contribute more to overall profits. (3) Marketing should support growing and not declining products and shift resources over the life cycle.</p><p>The rule also teaches that the drivers of a product's near-optimal budget share interact with each other; i.e., there exist synergies between them. Finally, it makes the trade-offs in budget allocation transparent. For example, a product with high marketing effectiveness but a low profit contribution level could get a lower budget than a product with a high level of profit contribution but lower marketing effectiveness. Even though that product's spending is less effective, it may still contribute more to overall profit because of its larger sales base.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>5.2.3.</head><p>Understanding the Limitations of Separate Return on Investment Analysis. Management was initially very focused on comparing incremental returns on investments (ROIs) that result from raising or lowering marketing expenditures for individual products and marketing activities (hereafter denoted as separate ROI analysis). Profit calculations with the allocation tool quickly revealed the limitations of such an analysis. First, separate ROI analyses for individual marketing activities do not consider synergies between marketing activities that interact with each other. Profit simulations for several brands, for example, showed that the ROI of a 10% budget increase in a specific spending category is negative but turns positive if the budget increase is accompanied by a reallocation across the different spending categories. Hence, the synergy between marketing activities is exploited only by the allocation heuristic but not by separate ROI considerations. Second, separate ROI analyses do not consider the trade-offs that exist with respect to potential profit improvements by other products and activities. For example, even though simulated ROIs for a few products were positive, the allocation heuristic suggested reducing the current budget on these products. The reason is that free budget resources were transferred to other products where the incremental return was even higher. Third, separate ROI analyses do not inform us about the magnitude of budget changes for products and activities, given a fixed total budget. Marginal returns analysis teaches us that the budget should be increased until the ROI reaches zero. However, if other products' budgets are also raised, the budget increase may exceed the total budget constraint. The allocation heuristic produces exact results for the recommended allocation of a fixed budget within one step.</p><p>Marketing Science 30(4), pp. 568-585, © 2011 INFORMS</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.">Organizational Impact</head><p>The introduction of the allocation tool had a considerable impact on the organization. The project was part of a larger effort aimed at revising the organization's tools and processes to evaluate marketing initiatives in terms of their financial implications. This effort had the full attention of the managing board of Bayer. Budget decisions are often associated with several rounds of intensive discussions that follow a bottom-up process; i.e., product and country managers communicate their budget needs for the next year upwards. Budget discussions in companies are probably never fully free of politics and individual agendas. The allocation tool adds an independent, top-down perspective. Because it is strictly based on a range of verifiable input information, its recommendations are fully fact based. Assumptions about marketing effectiveness and other drivers may be discussed. Their implications for budget allocation are immediately transparent through application of the tool. Because of its transparency and top-down perspective, the allocation tool ameliorates the decision process that often appears emotional and inefficient.</p><p>Although the allocation tool is not the only source used by Bayer to generate budget options, it had a significant impact on the efficiency and quality of the decision process. The project contributed substantially to an organizational transformation that eventually resulted in the creation of a completely new marketing intelligence unit called global business support. This unit supports global marketing management and sales, including the global management board with tools, results, and recommendations for a more efficient and effective use of marketing resources.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4.">Strategic Impact</head><p>Application of the tool initiated an important strategic discussion within the firm. The results suggested that some older products that still hold a strong position in sizable markets did not get sufficient marketing resources anymore. The allocation tool showed a substantial profit improvement potential from shifting more resources to these older products.</p><p>The results also initiated a discussion about the targets of sales calls and the relevance of accompanying marketing activities. In terms of targets, the results suggest reconsidering the strong focus on specialists. It seems that because of a higher frequency of sales calls at specialists by competitors, effectiveness is lower relative to sales calls at general practitioners. Consequently, the tool proposed reallocating resources between those two target groups. In addition, the results suggest that the potential of accompanying activities such as meeting invitations and OME were not yet fully exploited.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.5.">Financial Impact</head><p>The tool enables the user to simulate the financial impact of different budget allocation options. By analyzing the simulation results, it provides transparency about the impact of different assumptions on financial results. Based on data from the year 2007, the simulation suggested an increase in discounted profits of 55% over the next five years because of an optimized allocation. This is worth E493 million. In contrast, changing the overall budget by 20% promised a profit impact of less than 5%. Even if only a small portion of this increase can be realized, the additional profit for a business unit such as primary care with E3 billion worldwide sales is substantial.</p><p>Actual profit improvements are hard to evaluate. First, management did not completely follow the suggested reallocation by the tool for several reasons (e.g., varying personal experiences, concerns about errors in IMS data). Second, activities by competitors and exogenous influences on market dynamics affect profit results. Nevertheless, the business area Bayer HealthCare reports an increase in EBIT of 12% (E273 million) compared to a 4% revenue increase for the year 2008 <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bayer 2009</ref>). Although we have no validation from a field test, these results are consistent with prior observations that reallocation really focuses on the bottom line.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.6.">Generalizability</head><p>Although the tool was applied to prescription drugs, we emphasize that it is suitable for many other industries, such as consumer durables, consumer packaged goods, etc. In all these markets, rich information is available at the aggregate product level that allows the calibration of market response models; however, even if data on marketing effectiveness, carryover, etc., cannot be estimated with aggregate market response models, other data and methods including choice models and managerial experiments are available to generate the required input data for allocation. In this respect, we are not aware of a limitation to apply the allocation heuristic in other industries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusions, Limitations, and Future Research</head><p>In this paper, we suggest an innovative approach to allocate a global marketing budget across countries, products, and marketing activities. Based on the theoretical solution to the dynamic optimization problem, we derive a simple but comprehensive heuristic that accounts for dynamics in marketing effects and product growth. It suggests allocating a budget proportionally to the size of the business (sales and profit contribution margin), the effectiveness of the marketing activities (short-term elasticity and carryover coefficient), and the growth potential of the product (growth multiplier accounting for time discounting). A simulation study demonstrates that the heuristic quickly converges to the optimal solution under both monopoly and competitive conditions. The implementation of the heuristic at Bayer had various significant effects on the organization. It revealed substantial profit improvement potentials by reallocating marketing resources for the primary care business unit. It had a significant effect on the quality and efficiency of the budget allocation process and contributed to organizational change.</p><p>Our research has limitations that may stimulate future research. First, we have analyzed budget allocation issues under the assumption of a specific response function that has been found to best represent the data in this study. It would be interesting to extend the application to other response functions, including different growth functions. Second, our simulation study covers only a limited range of conditions. Additional conditions such as more competitors and errors in input data may be analyzed and the number of scenarios extended. It would also be useful to understand which conditions have a critical influence on the performance of the heuristic. Third, the tool may be extended to compute uncertainty bounds for recommended budget and market share and profit simulations. This would add a risk-analysis perspective to the application. Finally, we note that our research lacks an experimental field test that is hard to implement in a global portfolio worth E3 billion. Future applications to smaller portfolios might, however, overcome this limitation and test the superiority of the suggested heuristic. Finally, we assume that the overall marketing budget is set exogenously. Unless the budget level is optimal, there is still profit improvement potential. The flat maximum principle, however, suggests that this potential is very small, provided the budget is set within a reasonably wide range around the true optimal level <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Tull et al. 1986)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">Electronic Companion</head><p>An electronic companion to this paper is available as part of the online version that can be found at http:// mktsci.pubs.informs.org/. before marketing cost because these cost are fixed by the total budget and thus not relevant to the optimization. Using the state variable Equation (3.2) to substitute x kin in the objective function (3), we can write the following Lagrange objective functional: Recall that the budget constraint is binding and has to be satisfied in the optimum; i.e., R = k∈K i∈I k n∈N i x * kin ∀t ∈ 0 T . Because this constraint also applies to the end period, S kinT is free but only within the constraint. This turns the problem into a fixed-endpoint problem, and we do not need a general transversality condition. From (20), we obtain the optimal share of the budget that is allocated to marketing activity n of product i in country k by </p><formula xml:id="formula_14">−1 + 1 R dS * kin dt ∀k ∈ K i ∈ I k n ∈ N i t ∈ 0 T (21)</formula><p>which is equivalent to Equation (4).</p><p>From the budget constraint, we know that the following linear restriction must hold: In a typical product portfolio that includes several products of different ages and therefore different levels of marketing activity stocks, some stocks will increase and others will decrease from one period to the next because the total budget to be allocated is limited. For a fairly large number of allocations units, which are defined at the country-product-marketing-activity level, gains and losses in stocks tend to cancel each other out, so k∈K i∈I k n∈N i dS * kin /dt 0, with k = 1 l K, i = 1 j I k , and n = 1 m N i . As a result, we have 1 and obtain a solution for the optimal budget share that is very close to (21): Because we also need to satisfy the condition x * kin ≥ 0 that is violated if f x * kin + g x * kin &lt; 0 and g x * kin &lt; 0, the optimal marketing budget for marketing activity n of product i in country k is given by which is equivalent to Equation ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>).</p><p>The solution establishes a global maximum because the integrand F t S * kin dS * kin /dt * is concave in S * kin and dS * kin /dt. For a fixed-endpoint problem, the Euler-Lagrange Equations ( <ref type="formula">15a</ref>) and (15b) are sufficient for an absolute maximum <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Kamien and Schwartz 1991)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Parametric Growth Model</head><p>Consistent with (6), we consider the following parametric growth model g i t = i t a i e −b i t with i a i b i &gt; 0 and t ∈ 0 (24)</p><p>Equivalence with the Gamma Distribution. The probability density function of a gamma distributed random variable t is defined as follows gamma t = t −1 e − t (25)</p><p>where and are characteristic parameters that define the shape of the distribution. Let the parameters , a, and b of (24) be defined as = b a+1 / a+1 , a = −1, and b = . Then it can be shown that (24) results in (25).</p><p>Properties of Cumulative Sales. Let (24) measure unit sales. We obtain cumulative sales over the total lifetime of product i by solving the integral</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">CumSales i = i • 0 t a i •e − b i t dt = i • a i +1 b a i +1 i with i a i b i &gt; 0 (26)</formula><p>Let a i −b i = i measure the distance in growth parameters for i. Substituting b i for a i − i in (26) and differentiating this expression with respect to the distance i yields</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">dCumSales i d i = a i +1 i a i +1 a i − i −a i −2<label>(27)</label></formula><p>Expression ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_16">27</ref>) is always greater than zero because all terms are greater than zero. Note that a i − i &gt; 0 because a i , b i &gt; 0. From a i −b i = i , it follows that a i &gt; i .</p><p>Hence, cumulative sales increase with the difference in the growth parameters a and b. This result also holds for discounted cumulative sales. Discounting (24) at rate r and differentiating with respect to i leads to dCumSales i d i = a i +1 i a i +1 a i − i +r −a i −2 (28)</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Illustrative Product Life Cycles for Different Marketing Investment Levels</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>3.1. Company BackgroundTogether with the management of Bayer, we implemented and adapted the proposed heuristic to the specifics of Bayer's primary care business unit in the period 2005-2006 and derived budget recommendations for 2007. Bayer is one of the leading companies in the pharmaceuticals and chemicals business</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2Performance of Heuristic Rule Relative to Optimal Solution</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>p ki −c ki q * ki f x * kin + g x * kin / r +1− kin • l∈K j∈I l m∈N j p lj −c lj q * lj f x * ljm + g x * ljm / r +1− ljm −1</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fischer et al.: Dynamic Marketing Budget Allocation Across Countries, Products, and Marketing Activities    </figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science 30(4), pp. 568-585, © 2011 INFORMS</cell><cell>571</cell></row><row><cell>(Nerlove and Arrow 1962):</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Bayer HealthCare, Bayer CropScience, and Bayer MaterialScience. Bayer HealthCare is the largest area in terms of sales, contributing almost 50% to total sales. In 2008, the business area reported E15.4 billion in sales, positioning Bayer among the top 10 pharmaceutical firms worldwide. Bayer HealthCare is divided into a prescription drug business (pharmaceuticals, E10.7 billion) and an over-the-counter drug business (consumer health, E4.7 billion). The prescription drug business is composed of several business units. Primary care is the largest unit (E3.1 billion) and our focus for implementation of the allocation heuris-</figDesc><table><row><cell>Both scenarios</cell></row><row><cell>Monopoly</cell></row><row><cell>Duopoly</cell></row><row><cell>sector of the world. As of 2008, the company had</cell></row><row><cell>E32.9 billion sales and approximately 108,600 employ-</cell></row><row><cell>ees (Bayer 2009). Bayer consists of three major busi-</cell></row><row><cell>ness areas:</cell></row></table><note>tic. Three business units, women's health, diagnostic imaging, and specialized therapeutics, are rather new to the company because they mainly belong to Schering, a pharmaceutical competitor Bayer acquired in 2006.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Descriptive Statistics</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Antidiabetes</cell><cell cols="2">Hypertension</cell><cell cols="2">Erectile dysfunction</cell><cell cols="2">Anti-infectives</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>Std. dev.</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>Std. dev.</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>Std. dev.</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>Std. dev.</cell></row><row><cell>Unit sales (in thousand standard units)</cell><cell>16 319</cell><cell>20 674</cell><cell>11 891</cell><cell>16 649</cell><cell>1 008</cell><cell>649</cell><cell>5 291</cell><cell>8 004</cell></row><row><cell>Elapsed time since launch (in years)</cell><cell>14.50</cell><cell>12.69</cell><cell>10.00</cell><cell>7.42</cell><cell>2.75</cell><cell>1.91</cell><cell>12.25</cell><cell>10.45</cell></row><row><cell>Order of entry (median)</cell><cell>3</cell><cell></cell><cell>4</cell><cell></cell><cell>2</cell><cell></cell><cell>3</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Price in EUR per standard unit</cell><cell>0.16</cell><cell>0.26</cell><cell>0.50</cell><cell>2.96</cell><cell>7.00</cell><cell>0.48</cell><cell>2.01</cell><cell>1.97</cell></row><row><cell>Marketing stock variables</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Detailing at general practitioners (in thousand EUR)</cell><cell>22 519</cell><cell>36 566</cell><cell>64 595</cell><cell>87 134</cell><cell>55 026</cell><cell>30 326</cell><cell>44 259</cell><cell>34 930</cell></row><row><cell>Detailing at specialists (in thousand EUR)</cell><cell>2 081</cell><cell>4 068</cell><cell>8 803</cell><cell>13 701</cell><cell>14 498</cell><cell>12 771</cell><cell>10 380</cell><cell>11 353</cell></row><row><cell>Detailing at pharmacies (in thousand EUR)</cell><cell>588</cell><cell>1 453</cell><cell>1 930</cell><cell>3 039</cell><cell>a</cell><cell></cell><cell>1 766</cell><cell>2 598</cell></row><row><cell>Professional journal advertising (in thousand EUR)</cell><cell>149</cell><cell>341</cell><cell>a</cell><cell></cell><cell>458</cell><cell>502</cell><cell>165</cell><cell>295</cell></row><row><cell>Meeting invitations (in thousand EUR)</cell><cell>730</cell><cell>2 030</cell><cell>1 361</cell><cell>3 062</cell><cell>3 884</cell><cell>2 481</cell><cell>471</cell><cell>837</cell></row><row><cell>Other marketing expenditures (in thousand EUR)</cell><cell>a</cell><cell></cell><cell>2 558</cell><cell>9 278</cell><cell>3 912</cell><cell>4 404</cell><cell>a</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>No. of countries</cell><cell>5</cell><cell></cell><cell>5</cell><cell></cell><cell>5</cell><cell></cell><cell>5</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>No. of subcategories</cell><cell>6</cell><cell></cell><cell>10</cell><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell>12</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>No. of products</cell><cell>104</cell><cell></cell><cell>306</cell><cell></cell><cell>15</cell><cell></cell><cell>100</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>No. of observations</cell><cell cols="2">2,398</cell><cell cols="2">7,908</cell><cell>233</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">2,916</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Estimation Results for Market Response Models (Equation (11)): Antidiabetes and Hypertension Categories</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Antidiabetes</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Hypertension</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Est.</cell><cell></cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell></cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell></cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>parameter</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>parameter SD</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>parameter</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>parameter SD</cell><cell>SE</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Notes. NS, not significant (p &gt; 0 05). Product-specific parameter estimates for Bayer brands cannot be shown for confidentiality reasons. Effects for country dummies and seasonal dummies are not shown but can be obtained from the authors upon request.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Log likelihood</cell><cell>−11,859.02</cell><cell>−52,608.69</cell></row><row><cell>Pseudo R 2</cell><cell>0.949</cell><cell>0.933</cell></row><row><cell>No. of observations</cell><cell>2,398</cell><cell>7,908</cell></row><row><cell>No. of products</cell><cell>104</cell><cell>306</cell></row></table><note>a Spending category was only rarely used by firms.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>1ki lngp_sdet kit + 2ki lnsp_sdet kit + 3ki lnph_sdet kit + 4ki lnsadv kit + 5ki lnsmeet kit + 6ki lnsOME kit + 1 lnscomp kit + 2 lnprc kit + 3 lncomprc kit + 4 lnOE ki + 5 stot kit ×lnET kit + 6 stot kit ×ET kit + Unit sales of drug i in country k and period t; gp_sdet kit : Stock of detailing expenditures at general practitioners of drug i in country k and period t; sp_sdet kit : Stock of detailing expenditures at specialists of drug i in country k and period t; ph_sdet</figDesc><table><row><cell>M−1 l=1 lh SD ht ×CTY lk + kit with kit ∼ N 0 2 l CT Y lk q kit : Marketing Science 30(4), pp. 568-585, © 2011 INFORMS + M l=1 H−1 h=1 (11) where</cell></row></table><note>kit : Stock of detailing expenditures at pharmacists of drug i in country k and period t; sadv kit : Stock of professional journal advertising expenditures of drug i in country k and period t; smeet kit : Stock of expenditures on meeting invitations of drug i in country k and period t;</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Estimation Results for Market Response Models (Equation (11)): Erectile Dysfunction and Anti-infectives Categories</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Anti-infectives</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Erectile dysfunction</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell></cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell></cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell></cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>parameter</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>parameter SD</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>parameter</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>parameter SD</cell><cell>SE</cell></row><row><cell>Constant</cell><cell>8 95</cell><cell>0 216</cell><cell>1 50</cell><cell>0 054</cell><cell>0 138</cell><cell>0 626 NS</cell><cell>2 84</cell><cell>0 315</cell></row><row><cell>Ln(elapsed time since launch)</cell><cell>0 133×10 −7</cell><cell>0 885×10 −13</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0 477</cell><cell>0 130 a</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>×Total marketing stock</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Elapsed time since launch</cell><cell cols="2">−0 299×10 −9 0 516×10 −14</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>−0 036</cell><cell>0 017 a</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Note that the budget constraint (3.1) has to be fulfilled in each period, which may entail a time-varying Lagrange multiplier. A solution requires solving the 1+ k∈K i∈I k N i Euler-Lagrange equations, which constitute the first-order conditions * kin dS * kin /dt * is the Lagrangean integrand, and the asterisk indicates that variable values correspond to the optimal solution for the marketing budget. Note that each competitor has to satisfy these conditions under Nash competition. The required derivatives to solve (15a) areWe multiply both sides of Equation (19) with kin and use the identities kin S * kin = x * kin −dS * kin /dt, kin = 1− kin , f x * ), pp. 568-585, © 2011 INFORMS where measures the carryover coefficient, and f x * kin and g x * kin are (short-term) sales elasticities with respect to marketing expenditures.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="8">Marketing Science 30(4</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>T</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>L =</cell><cell>t=0</cell><cell cols="2">e −rt</cell><cell cols="5">k∈K i∈I k</cell><cell cols="3">p ki −c ki q ki</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="6">+ R−</cell><cell cols="2">k∈K i∈I k n∈N i</cell><cell>dS kin dt</cell><cell>+ kin S kin dt</cell><cell>(14)</cell></row><row><cell>F S kin</cell><cell cols="2">t S  *  kin</cell><cell cols="2">dS  *  kin dt</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>*</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">−</cell><cell>d dt</cell><cell>dS kin /dt</cell><cell>kin F t S  *</cell><cell>dt dS  *  kin</cell><cell>*</cell></row><row><cell cols="12">= 0 ∀k ∈ K i ∈ I k n ∈ N i t ∈ 0 T</cell><cell>(15a)</cell></row><row><cell>and</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>F</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">= 0 ∀t ∈ 0 T</cell><cell>(15b)</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">where F t S  F S kin</cell><cell cols="7">= e −rt p ki −c ki</cell><cell>q ki S kin</cell><cell>− kin</cell><cell>(16a)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="5">F dS kin /dt</cell><cell>= − e −rt</cell><cell>(16b)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">d dt</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">F dS kin /dt</cell><cell>= r e −rt</cell><cell>(16c)</cell></row><row><cell cols="12">Setting (16c) equal to (16a) yields</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="7">p ki −c ki</cell><cell>q ki S kin</cell><cell>= r + kin</cell><cell>(17)</cell></row><row><cell cols="12">From Equation (1), we obtain</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">q ki S kin</cell><cell cols="3">=</cell><cell>f ki S kin</cell><cell>g ki +</cell><cell>g ki S kin</cell><cell>f ki</cell></row><row><cell cols="12">which may be expanded into</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">q ki S kin</cell><cell>=</cell><cell cols="3">f ki S kin</cell><cell cols="3">S kin f ki</cell><cell cols="2">g ki f ki</cell><cell>1 S kin</cell><cell>+</cell><cell>g ki S kin</cell><cell>S kin g ki</cell><cell>f ki g ki</cell><cell>1 S kin</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="9">= f S kin + g S kin</cell><cell>q ki S kin</cell><cell>(18)</cell></row><row><cell cols="12">Inserting (18) into (17) and solving for S  *  kin yields</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">S  *  kin =</cell><cell cols="6">p ki −c ki q  *  ki f S  *  kin r + kin</cell><cell>+ g S  *  kin</cell><cell>(19)</cell></row><row><cell>f S  *  kin</cell><cell cols="4">, and g x  *  kin</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="6">= g S  *  kin</cell><cell>to obtain</cell><cell>kin</cell><cell>=</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">x  *  kin =</cell><cell cols="8">p ki −c ki q  *  ki f x  *  kin r +1− kin + g x  *  kin</cell><cell>+</cell><cell>dS  *  kin dt</cell><cell>(20)</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">We also tried larger product portfolios, e.g., with eight products. Results do not change, but computation time increases exponentially.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank Rafael Alcaraz, Eric Bradlow, Russ Winer, the area editor, and two anonymous reviewers for their many helpful suggestions.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix Derivation of Theoretical Allocation Solution for Arbitrary Growth and Response Functions</head><p>We consider the constrained dynamic profit maximization problem as stated in Equations ( <ref type="formula">3</ref>)-(3.3). We assume that the sales function in Equation ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>) is twice differentiable in t and S. Note that it is sufficient to maximize profit contribution</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Regeln für die Allokation eines Marketing-Budgets auf Produkte oder Marktsegmente</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Albers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Zeitschrift für betriebswirtschaftliche Forschung</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="235" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impact of types of functional relationships, decisions, and solutions on the applicability of marketing models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Albers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Res. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2-3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="175" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personal selling elasticities: A meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Albers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Mantrala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sridhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="840" to="853" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling the marketing-mix influence in the new-product diffusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Jain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Krishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">New-Product Diffusion Models</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wind</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="122" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information, marketing, and pricing in the U.S. antiulcer drug market</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">;</forename><surname>Bayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Bayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Germany</forename><surname>Leverkusen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Berndt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Reily</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Urban</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="100" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Annual Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advertising budget practices: A review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Bigné</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Current Issues Res. Advertising</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Several tests for model specification in the presence of alternative hypotheses</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Mackinnon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="781" to="793" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Goodwill and dynamic advertising strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Doganoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Klapper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal advertising and optimal quality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dorfman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Steiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="826" to="836" />
			<date type="published" when="1954" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiproduct advertising budgeting</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Doyle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Saunders</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dynamic Models of Advertising Competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Erickson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Boston</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Patient-or physician-oriented marketing: What drives primary demand for prescription drugs?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Albers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="121" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Drivers of peak sales for pharmaceutical brands</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S H</forename><surname>Leeflang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Verhoef</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="429" to="460" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fixed Point Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Granas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dugundji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Econometric Analysis</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Upper Saddle River, NJ</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>6th ed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hanssens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Parsons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Schultz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Market Response Models: Econometric and Time Series Analysis</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dynamic Optimization: The Calculus of Variations and Optimal Control in Economics and Management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Kamien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Amsterdam</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The power of CLV: Managing lifetime value at IBM</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Venkatesan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Bohling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Beckmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="599" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Models and managers: The concept of a decision calculus</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D C</forename><surname>Little</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>B-466-B-485</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1970" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sales force sizing and deployment using a decision calculus model at Syntex Laboratories</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lodish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Curtis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ness</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Simpson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Interfaces</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Planning marketing-mix strategies in the presence of interaction effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Naik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Raman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Winer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="34" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal advertising policy under dynamic conditions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Nerlove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Arrow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="142" />
			<date type="published" when="1962" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Investor fact sheet</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">;</forename><surname>Procter &amp; Gamble</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cincinnati</forename><surname>Procter &amp; Gamble</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.pg.com" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-11-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Guest editorial: Is marketing academia losing its way?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Reibstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Day</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wind</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="3" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Balancing acquisition and retention resources to maximize customer profitability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Reinartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">COSTA: Contribution optimizing sales territory alignment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Skiera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Albers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="196" to="213" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leveraged&quot; decision making in advertising: The flat maximum principle and its implications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Tull</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Duhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gillpatick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Helgeson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">International Trade in Goods and Factor Mobility</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sales territory design: Thirty years of modeling and implementation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Zoltners</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sinha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="331" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
