<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Online Display Advertising: Targeting and Obtrusiveness</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2011-02-09">February 9, 2011.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Avi</forename><surname>Goldfarb</surname></persName>
							<email>agoldfarb@rotman.untoronto.ca</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><surname>Tucker</surname></persName>
							<email>cetucker@mit.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Rotman School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Toronto</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>M5S 3E6</postCode>
									<settlement>Toronto</settlement>
									<region>Ontario</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">MIT Sloan School of Management</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02142</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>Massachusetts</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Online Display Advertising: Targeting and Obtrusiveness</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2011-02-09">February 9, 2011.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1100.0583</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: October 19, 2009; accepted: April 3, 2010; Eric Bradlow served as the</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:30+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Customers actively avoid looking at online banner ads <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Drèze and Hussherr 2003)</ref>. Response rates to banner ads have fallen dramatically over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Hollis 2005)</ref>. In reaction to this, online advertising on websites has developed along two strikingly distinct paths.</p><p>On the one hand, the $11.2 billion 1 online display advertising market has evolved beyond traditional banner ads to include many visual and audio features that make ads more obtrusive and harder to ignore. On the other hand, Google has developed a highly profitable nonsearch display advertising division (called AdSense) that generates an estimated $6 billion in revenues by displaying plain contenttargeted text ads: 76% of U.S. Internet users are estimated to have been exposed to AdSense ads. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> This paper explores how well these divergent strategies work for online advertising and how consumer perceptions of intrusiveness and privacy influence their success or lack of it, both independently and in combination. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> See <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Hallerman (2009)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Estimates generated from Google quarterly earnings report for June 30, 2009 Form 10-Q, filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p><p>We examine the effectiveness of these strategies using data from a large randomized field experiment on 2,892 distinct Web advertising campaigns that were placed on different websites. On average, we have data on 852 survey takers for each campaign. Of these, half were randomly exposed to the ad and half were not exposed to the ad but did visit the website on which the ad appeared. These campaigns advertised a large variety of distinct products and were run on many different websites.</p><p>The advertisers in our data used two core improvements on standard banner ad campaigns to attract their audience: (1) some Web campaigns matched the product they advertised to the website content, for example, when auto manufacturers placed their ads on auto websites; and (2) some Web campaigns deliberately tried to make their ad stand out from the content by using video, creating a pop-up, or having the ad take over the Web page. This paper evaluates whether targeted campaigns that complemented the website content, obtrusive campaigns that strove to be highly visible relative to the website content, or campaigns that did both were most successful at influencing stated purchase intent, measured as the difference between the group that was exposed to the ad and the group that was not.</p><p>We construct and estimate a reduced-form model of an ad effectiveness function. Consistent with prior 390 Marketing Science 30(3), pp. 389-404, © 2011 INFORMS literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Goldfarb and</ref><ref type="bibr">Tucker 2011, Wilbur et al. 2009)</ref>, our results suggest that matching an ad's content to the website content increased stated purchase intent among exposed consumers. Also, consistent with prior literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Spalding et al. 2009)</ref>, our results suggest that increasing the obtrusiveness of the ad increased purchase intent. Surprisingly, however, we find that these two ways of improving online display advertising performance negate each other: combining them nullifies the positive effect that each strategy has independently. These results are robust to multiple specifications, including one that addresses the potential endogeneity of campaign format by restricting our analysis to campaigns that were run both on sites that matched the product and sites that did not.</p><p>These results have important economic implications for the $664 million that we estimate is currently spent on ads that are both targeted and obtrusive. If advertisers replace ads that combine contextual targeting and high visibility with the standard ads that our estimates suggest are equally effective, our back-of-theenvelope calculations suggest that advertisers could cut ad spending by more than 5% without affecting ad performance.</p><p>It is not obvious why increasing visibility and increasing the match to content should work well separately but not together. It does not appear to be explained by differences in ad recall. Consistent with several laboratory experiments in other settings <ref type="bibr">(Mandler 1982, Heckler and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Childers 1992)</ref>, we find that contextually targeted ads are recalled less, whereas highly visible ads are recalled more. However, we find that highly visible ads are not recalled significantly less if they are matched to the context. This suggests that the negation mechanism is explained by a difference in how successful the ad is at influencing customer behavior after customers see it rather than because of differences in ad recall.</p><p>The literature on consumer response to persuasion attempts provides an alternative explanation: obtrusive ads may lead consumers to infer that the advertiser is trying to manipulate them, reducing purchase intentions <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Campbell 1995)</ref>. Specifically, increased processing attention may lead the consumer to think about why a particular advertising tactic was used <ref type="bibr">(Campbell 1995, Friestad and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Wright 1994)</ref>. If the tactic is perceived as manipulative, it will have a negative effect on consumer perceptions of the product advertised. Given that deception is particularly easy online, consumer awareness of manipulation is higher too <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Boush et al. 2009)</ref>. This suggests that targeted and obtrusive banner ads, by increasing the attention paid to the tactic of targeting, may generate consumer perceptions of manipulation. Therefore, although there is a relatively high consumer tolerance to targeted ads because the information is perceived as useful (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Cho and Cheon 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">, Edwards et al. 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">, Wang et al. 2008</ref>, this tolerance may be overwhelmed by perceptions of manipulation when the ad is obtrusive.</p><p>Why might the negative consequences of perceived manipulation from using techniques to make ads obtrusive be higher if they are targeted? Privacy concerns provide a possible answer. Both <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Turow et al. (2009)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Wathieu and Friedman (2009)</ref> document that customer appreciation of the informativeness of targeted ads is tempered by privacy concerns. When privacy concerns are more salient, consumers are more likely to have a prevention focus <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Van Noort et al. 2008</ref>) in which they are more sensitive to the absence or presence of negative outcomes, instead of a promotion focus in which they are more sensitive to the absence or presence of positive outcomes. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Kirmani and Zhu (2007)</ref> show that prevention focus is associated with increased sensitivity to manipulative intent, suggesting a likely avenue for the relationship between targeted ads, privacy concerns, and perceived manipulative intent that arises from making ads more obtrusive.</p><p>We explore empirically whether it is privacy concerns that drive the negative effect we observe of combining targeting and obtrusiveness. We find evidence that supports this view: contextual targeting and high visibility (obtrusiveness) are much stronger substitutes for people who refused to answer a potentially intrusive question on income. They are also stronger substitutes in categories in which privacy might be seen as relatively important (such as financial and health products).</p><p>In addition to our major finding that obtrusiveness and targeting do not work well in combination, and the link this has with consumer perceptions of privacy, we make several other contributions that help illuminate online advertising. Our examination of many campaigns across many industries complements the single-firm approach of the existing quantitative literature on online advertising effectiveness. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Manchanda et al. (2006)</ref> use data from a health-care and beauty product Internet-only firm in their examination of how banner ad exposures affect sales. Similarly, <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Lewis and Reiley (2009)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Rutz and Bucklin (2009)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Chatterjee et al. (2003)</ref>, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Ghose and Yang (2009)</ref> all examine campaigns run by just one firm. Those studies have given us a much deeper understanding of the relationship between online advertising and purchasing, but their focus on particular firms and campaigns makes it difficult to draw general conclusions about online advertising. In contrast, our research gives a sense of the average effectiveness of online advertising-it boosts stated purchase intent by 3% to 4%-and our research suggests that at current advertising prices, plain banner ads pay off if an increase in purchase intent by one consumer is worth roughly 42 cents to the advertiser. Our results also emphasize that there is a role for cross-category and campaign advertising studies, because they allow us to examine factors that vary across campaigns like campaign visibility and category characteristics.</p><p>The trade-off between perceived intrusiveness and usefulness may help explain the unexpected success of products such as Google's AdSense, which generates roughly one-third of Google's advertising revenues (the other two-thirds coming directly from search advertising). AdSense allows advertisers to place very plain-looking ads-they are identical in appearance to Google's search ads-on websites with closely matched content. Our findings suggest that making these ads more visually striking could be counterproductive, or at least waste advertising budget. More generally, the results suggest two alternative viable routes to online display advertising success: (1) putting resources into increasing the visibility of ads and (2) putting resources into the targeting of ads to context, but not doing both.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Data on Display Advertising</head><p>We used data from a large database of surveys collected by a media measurement agency to examine the effectiveness of different ad campaigns. These surveys are based on a randomized exposed and control allocation. Individuals browsing the website where the campaign is running were either exposed to the ads, or not, based on the randomized operation of the ad server. On average, 198 subjects were recruited for each website running a particular campaign, with an average of 852 subjects being recruited across all websites for each ad campaign. The average campaign lasted 55 days (median 49 days).</p><p>We excluded ad campaigns run on websites that were described as "other" because it was not possible to identify whether there was a contextual match. We also excluded ads for alcohol because there were no contextually targeted alcohol ads in the data. Finally, we excluded ads for prescription drugs because Federal Trade Commission regulations (which require reporting of side effects) restrict their format.</p><p>Both exposed and nonexposed (control) respondents were recruited via an online survey invitation that appeared after they finished browsing the website. Therefore, our coefficients reflect the stated preferences of consumers who are willing to answer an online poll. The company that makes these data available had done multiple checks to confirm the general representativeness of this survey among consumers. In §4.4, we find that the main negative interaction effect that we study is larger for people who refuse to answer an (intrusive) question on income, so it is even possible that the selection in our subject pool away from those who prefer not to answer surveys leads us to understate the magnitude of this negative interaction.</p><p>Because of the random nature of the advertising allocation, both exposed and control groups have similar unobservable characteristics, such as the same likelihood of seeing offline ads. The only variable of difference between the two groups is the randomized presence of the ad campaign being measured. This means that differences in consumer preferences toward the advertiser's product can be attributed to the online campaign.</p><p>This online questionnaire asked the extent to which a respondent was likely to purchase a variety of products (including the one studied) or had a favorable opinion of the product using a five-point scale. The data also contained information about whether the respondent recalled seeing the ad. After collecting all other information at the end of the survey, the survey displayed the ad, alongside some decoy ads for other products, and the respondents were asked whether they recalled seeing any of the ads. If they responded that they had seen the focal ad, then we code this variable as 1 and as 0 otherwise.</p><p>An important strength of this data set is that it contains a large number of campaigns across a variety of categories, including automotive, apparel, consumer packaged goods, energy, entertainment, financial services, home improvement, retail, technology, telecommunications, travel, and many others. Therefore, like the <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Clark et al. (2009)</ref> study of offline advertising, we can draw very general conclusions about online display advertising. Our data have the further advantage of allowing us to explore ad recall and purchase intent separately.</p><p>The survey also asked respondents about their income, age, and the number of hours spent on the Internet. We use these as controls in our regressions. We converted them to zero-mean standardized measures. This allowed us to "zero out" missing data. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> (Later, in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref>, we show robustness to a nonparametric specification for the missing data by discretizing the variables with missing information. We also show robustness to excluding the controls.)</p><p>In addition to data from this questionnaire for each website user, our data set also documents the characteristics of the website where the advertisement appeared and the characteristics of the advertisement Marketing Science 30(3), pp. 389-404, © 2011 INFORMS itself. We used these data to define both whether the ad was contextually targeted and whether it was obtrusive (or high visibility).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Defining Contextually Targeted Advertising</head><p>To define whether a product matched the website that displayed it, we matched up the 364 narrow categories of products, with the 37 categories of websites described in the data. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> A banner ad for a cruise would be a contextually targeted ad if it was displayed on a website devoted to travel and leisure. Similarly, a banner ad for a new computer would be a contextually targeted ad if it was displayed on a site devoted to computing and technology. As indicated in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>(a), 10% of campaigns were run on sites where the product and website content matched.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Defining High Visibility (Obtrusive)</head><p>Advertising We define an ad as highly-visible if it has one of the following characteristics.</p><p>• Pop-up: The ad appears in a new window above the existing window.</p><p>• Pop-under: The ad appears in a new window that lies underneath the existing window.</p><p>• In-stream video and audio: The ad is part of a video stream.</p><p>• Takeover: The ad briefly usurps the on-screen space a Web page has devoted to its content.</p><p>• Nonuser-initiated video and audio: The ad automatically plays video and audio.</p><p>• Interstitial: The ad is displayed before the intended destination page loads.</p><p>• Nonuser-initiated background music: The ad automatically plays background music.</p><p>• Full-page banner ad: The ad occupies the space of a typical computer screen.</p><p>• Interactive: The ad requests two-way communication with its user.</p><p>• Floating ad: The ad is not user-initiated, is superimposed over a user-requested page, and disappears or becomes unobtrusive after a specific time period (typically 5-30 seconds).</p><p>As indicated in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>(a), 48% of campaigns used high-visibility ads. Of these ads, the largest subgroup was interactive ads, which comprised 17% of all ads. Pop-under ads were the least common, representing less than 0.1% of all ads. (In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref>, we check the robustness of our results to our definition of high visibility.) <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Our data have detailed information about the categories, but to protect client privacy, the firm that gave us access to the data did not give us information on which specific advertisers sponsored particular campaigns and which specific websites displayed the campaigns. a A small fraction of respondents answered two out of the three questions on the measures we use as dependent variables. Therefore, the sample size varies slightly across variables.</p><p>b In our main specifications, we exclude observations where the random operation of the ad server meant that the respondent had been exposed to the ad multiple times. If we include these observations, the proportion of exposed to nonexposed is close to 50%. We confirm robustness to these excluded observations in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref>.    <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>(b) presents some summary statistics at the level of the survey site. Two things are immediately apparent. First, in general, the effect of exposure to a banner ad is small. On average, exposure shifts the proportion of people stating that they are very likely to make a purchase by less than 1%. Ad exposure increases the number of people who can actually recall seeing the ad by only 5%. Only 60% of campaigns generated an improvement in purchase intent, whereas 70% increased ad recall. Twenty-three percent of campaigns generate ad recall but do not increase stated purchase intent, and 13% of campaigns are associated with an increase in purchase intent but not ad recall. Perhaps this lack of impact is unsurprising given that we are assessing whether seeing a banner ad once changes intended behavior. What really matters is whether this small change in intended behavior is worth the price paid (0.2 cents per view, according to Khan 2009).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Methods</head><p>Our estimation strategy builds an effectiveness function for the individual ads. We focus on two aspects of online advertising: visibility and contextual targeting. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Specifically, assume the effectiveness of a campaign c (defined as a particular advertisement shown on a particular website) to individual j is</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Effectiveness c j = f j Context c HighVisibility c Context c × HighVisibility c</formula><p>For estimation, we convert this effectiveness function for viewer j into a linear model of visibility and targeting, which allows for some idiosyncratic features of the advertisement-website pair ( c ) and some idiosyncratic characteristics of the viewer ( c j ). As in any research that estimates a response function, there is a concern here that viewer characteristics may be systematically correlated with the propensity to view contextually targeted or highly visible ads (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Levinsohn and Petrin 2003</ref> for a discussion in the context of production functions). The randomized nature of our data means that we can address this by measuring the difference between the exposed group and a control group of respondents who did not see the ad. Substituting our measure of effectiveness (purchase intent) and adding a control for potential demographic differences between the treatment and control groups, we estimate the effect of being exposed to the ad using the following difference-indifference equation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Intent c j = Exposed c j + Exposed c j × Context c + Exposed c j × HighVisibility c + Exposed c j × Context c × HighVisibility c + X j + c + c j</formula><p>where X j represents a vector of demographic controls (specifically, an indicator variable for whether the respondent is female and mean standardized measures for age, income, and time spent online), c represents the campaign (advertisement website) fixed effects that control for any differences in purchase intent across products and websites, and c j is an idiosyncratic error term. The fixed effects capture the main effects (i.e., those that affect both the exposed and control groups) of context, visibility, and the interaction between context and visibility, as well as heterogeneity in the response to different campaigns. Whether context and visibility are substitutes or complements is captured by the coefficient . This equation can be interpreted as a reduced-form effectiveness function for advertising, in which the advertising produces purchase intent (our proxy for effectiveness).</p><p>In the main specifications in this paper, we use as our main dependent variable ("Intent c j ") whether the survey taker reported the highest score on the scale ("very likely to make a purchase"). As reported in our summary statistics (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>(a)), on average, one-fifth of respondents responded with an answer at the top of the scale. We discretize in this manner to avoid generating means from an ordinal scale (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Malhotra 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">, Aaker et al. 2004</ref>. Nevertheless, we recognize that whether such scales should be treated as continuous is a gray area in marketing practice (discussed by, e.g., Fink 2009, p. 26). <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bentler and Chou (1987)</ref>, while acknowledging that such scales are ordinal, argue that it is common practice to treat them as continuous variables because it makes little practical difference. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Johnson and Creech (1983)</ref> come to a similar conclusion. In addition, many researchers argue that properly designed scales are in fact interval scales, not ordinal scales (see Kline 2005 for a discussion). Some recent empirical research in marketing (e.g., Godes and Mayzlin 2009) has followed this interpretation and has treated ratings scales as interval scales. For these reasons, we have replicated all of our results in the appendix, treating the dependent variable as a continuous measure based on the full-scale responses. We show that this makes no practical difference.</p><p>Another issue from using purchase intention as our dependent variable is that it is a weaker measure Marketing Science 30(3), pp. 389-404, © 2011 INFORMS of advertising success than purchasing or profitability (as used by Lewis and Reiley 2009 and others), because many users may claim that they intend to purchase but never do so. For our purposes, as long as people reporting higher purchase intent are actually more likely to purchase (and the treatment group is truly random), our conclusions about the directionality of the relationship between contextual targeting, high visibility, and effectiveness will hold. This positive correlation has been well established in work such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bemmaor (1995)</ref> and, in particular, has been found to be higher for product-specific surveys such as the ones conducted in our data than for categorylevel studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Morwitz et al. 2007</ref>). However, we do not know whether the relative size or relative significance of the results changes for actual purchase behavior.</p><p>Our estimation procedure is straightforward because of the randomized nature of the data collection. We have an experiment-like setting, with a treatment group that was exposed to the ads and a control group that was not. We compare these groups' purchase intent and explore whether the difference between the exposed and control groups is related to the visibility of an ad and whether the ad's content matches the website content. We then explore how purchase intent relates to ads that are both highly visible and targeted to the content. Our core regressions are run using Stata's commands for linear regression with panel data. To adjust for intrawebsite and campaign correlation between respondents, heteroskedasticity-robust standard errors are clustered at the website campaign level using Stata's "cluster" function. Generally speaking, our method follows the framework for causal econometric analysis provided in <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Angrist and Pischke (2009)</ref>. We report our main results using a linear probability model where the coefficients are calculated using ordinary least squares, although we show robustness to a logit formulation. We primarily use a linear probability model, because it makes it feasible to estimate a model with more than 10,000 campaign website fixed effects using the full data set of nearly 2.5 million observations, whereas computational limitations prevent us from estimating a logit model with the full data. The large number of observations in our data means that inefficiency-a potential weakness of the linear probability model relative to probit and logitis not a major concern in our setting. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Angrist and Pischke (2009)</ref> point out that this increased computational efficiency comes at little practical cost. They show that in several empirical applications, there is little difference between the marginal effects estimated with limited dependent variables models and linear probability models.</p><p>One major concern about using the linear probability model is the potential for biased estimates and predicted probabilities outside the range of 0 and 1 (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Horrace and Oaxaca 2006</ref> for a discussion), but this is less likely to happen in our setting because the mass point of dependent variables is far from 0 or 1 and because our covariates are almost all binary variables. Indeed, all predicted probabilities in our model for purchase intent lie between 0.137 and 0.256. This suggests that the benefits of using a linear probability model as our primary estimation technique, combined with its computational advantages, outweigh the costs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">The Effect of Combining Highly Visible and</head><p>Contextually Targeted Ads Column (1) of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">2</ref> reports our key results, where we include an interaction between contextual targeting and high visibility. The main effect of exposure and the additional effects of contextual targeting and high visibility of ads are all positive. Contextual targeting seems to have a slightly larger marginal effect than high visibility. The crucial result is the interaction term between exposure, contextual targeting, and high visibility. It is negative and significant. This suggests that firm investments in contextual targeting and highly visible ads are substitutes. A Wald test suggests that high-visibility ads on contextually targeted sites perform worse than ads that are not highly visible (p-value = 0 001, F -stat 10.83). The respondent-level controls indicate that younger female respondents who have lower incomes and spend more time on the Internet are more likely to say that they will buy the product.</p><p>In columns (2)-( <ref type="formula">4</ref>), we present some evidence that reflects what a manager would conclude if he evaluated the incremental benefit of targeting or using high-visibility ads independently. Column (2) of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">2</ref> reports results that allow the effect of exposure to be moderated by whether or not the website matched the product. We find a positive moderating effect of contextual targeting; that is, for campaigns where the website matches the product, there is an incremental positive effect from exposure that represents a 70% increase from the base positive effect of exposure. However, it is noticeable that without the controls for visibility that we included in column (1), we measure the effect of contextual targeting less precisely. Column (3) reports results that allow the effect of exposure to be moderated by whether the ad was highly visible or not. We find a positive moderating effect of visibility on likelihood of purchase. Having a high-visibility ad almost doubles the effect of exposure on the proportion of respondents who  Female 0 0116 * * * 0 000 0 0116 * * * 0 000 0 0116 * * * 0 000 0 0116 * * * 0 000 0 00119 0 00119 0 00119 0 00119</p><p>Hours on Internet (standardized) 0 0113 * * * 0 000 0 0113 * * * 0 000 0 0113 * * * 0 000 0 0113 * * * 0 000 0 000344 0 000344 0 000344 0 000344</p><p>Income (standardized) −0 00194 * * * 0 000 −0 00194 * * * 0 000 −0 00194 * * * 0 000 −0 00194 * * * 0 000 0 000406 0 000406 0 000407 0 000407</p><p>Age (standardized) −0 00957 * * * 0 000 −0 00957 * * * 0 000 −0 00957 * * * 0 000 −0 00957 * * * 0 000 report themselves very likely to purchase. Column (4) measures the mean effect of exposure. The coefficient suggests that exposure to a single ad, relative to a mean of 0.20, increases purchase intent by 3.6%. This gives us a baseline that reflects the typical metric that advertisers use when evaluating the success (or failure) of a campaign, which we use in our calculations of the economic importance of our results. The fit of these regressions (measured by R-squared) is 0.141, with little difference across the four specifications. Given heterogeneous tastes for the products being advertised, we do not view the overall level of fit as surprising. Furthermore, most of this is explained by the fixed effects, with just 0.002 explained by our covariates for ad exposure and type. Again, we do not view it as surprising that seeing a banner ad once explains only a small fraction of the variance in purchase intent for the product. If seeing a banner ad once explained much more of the variance, we would expect the price of such advertisements to be much larger than 0.2 cents per view. Nevertheless, as we detail in §4.3, our estimates still have important economic implications for the online advertising industry. It is not overall fit at the individual level that matters; instead, it is the marginal benefit relative to the marginal cost.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">0</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Robustness Checks</head><p>We checked the robustness of the negative interaction effect that we find in column (4) of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">2</ref> to many alternative specifications. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref> displays the results. Column (1) shows a logit specification to check that our linear probability specification had not influenced the results. Limitations of computing power meant that we had to take a 5% sample of the original data to be able to estimate a logit specification with the full set of fixed effects. Even with this smaller sample, the results are similar in relative size and magnitude.</p><p>One issue of a logit probability model compared to a linear probability model is that the interpretation of interaction terms in logit and probit models is not straightforward <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Ai and Norton 2003)</ref>, as they are a cross-derivative of the expected value of the dependent variable. Specifically, for any nonlinear model where E y x 1 x 2 = F 1 x 1 + 2 x 2 + 12 x 1 x 2 + Z = F • , Ai and Norton point out that the interaction effect is the cross-derivative of the expected value of y:   These estimates for our key interaction and the effect of visibility were therefore larger than those reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, although the coefficient estimate for contextual targeting is no longer significant. This robustness check strongly supports our core finding that contextually targeted ads that are highly visible are less effective than ads that are either contextually targeted or highly visible, but not both. We also use the logit results to conduct an outof-sample prediction on the remaining 95% of the data. Our model correctly predicts 61.4% of successful campaigns (defined as ad campaigns on a specific website where the average purchase intent for the treatment group is higher than the control group). This is significantly better than the 52% of successful campaigns that we would predict by chance using random assignment. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> In column (2) of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref>, we use the full (1-5) scale of the dependent variable rather than discretizing it. Our results are robust. (In Tables A.1-A.3 in the appendix, we show the robustness of all results to this specification.) In column (3), we show that our results do not change if we exclude demographic controls for gender, age, income, and Internet use. This provides supporting evidence that the experiment randomized the treatment between such groups and that unobserved heterogeneity between control and exposed groups does not drive our results. Column (4) shows robustness to a nonparametric specification for the gender, age, income, and Internet use controls, where we include a different fixed effect for different values for age, income, and Internet use. This also allows us to include fixed effects for missing values or intentionally nonreported values of these controls.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">2 F • / x 1 x 2 = 1 F • + 1 x 1 + 12 x 1 x 2 2 x 2 +</formula><p>In column (5), we see whether our results are echoed in another measure of ad effectiveness: whether or not the respondent expressed a favorable opinion of the product. The results in column (5) are similar to those previously reported, although the point estimate for the effect of a contextually targeted ad is slightly smaller. This may be because contextually targeted advertising is more successful at influencing intended actions than at influencing opinions <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Rutz and Bucklin 2009)</ref>. In column (6), we show that our results are robust to our definition of ad visibility.</p><p>One concern with including pop-up ads is the development of pop-up blockers as a feature of internet browsers. This could influence our results, for example, if people who browsed sites with specific content were more likely to have pop-up blockers. However, the results in column (6) show the same pattern as before, even when we exclude such ads.</p><p>In column ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>) of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref>, we report results for all respondents, including those who because of the randomized nature of the ad server saw the ad more than once. We excluded these 730,000 respondents from the data we use to report our main specifications to simplify interpretation of what "exposed" means in our setting. The results are similar to before, though the effect of baseline exposure is slightly higher.</p><p>While the individual-level randomization of exposure to ads addresses the usual concerns about unobserved heterogeneity at the individual level, our result for this negative interaction between high visibility and contextual targeting relies on the assumption that contextually targeted, highly visible ads are not of worse quality than either highly visible ads that are not contextually targeted or contextually targeted ads that are not highly visible. This therefore assumes that the endogeneity of advertising quality will not systematically affect our core result. In column (8) of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref>, we explore the appropriateness of this assumption in our context. We look only at ads that were run on more than one website and where the websites sometimes were contextually targeted and sometimes not. Our core results do not change. Therefore, holding campaign quality fixed, we still observe substitution between visibility and contextual targeting.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Economic implications</head><p>Section 4.2 establishes that our results are statistically robust to many specifications, but we have not yet established that they are economically meaningful. First, we note that column (1) of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">2</ref> suggests that seeing one plain banner ad once increases purchase intention by 0.473 percentage points. Relative to a price of 0.2 cents per view, this means that online advertising pays off if increasing purchase intention to "very likely to purchase" is worth 42 cents to the firm (95% confidence interval, 29 to 78 cents). Therefore, although the coefficient may seem small, it suggests an economically important impact of online advertising. The effects of targeted ads and obtrusive ads are even larger, though the prices of such ads are also higher.</p><p>We combine information from our data with various industry sources to develop "back-of-theenvelope" calculations on the total magnitude of wasted advertising spending resulting from ads that are both targeted and obtrusive. Clearly, these estimates are all rough; the purpose of this subsection is simply to give a sense of the order of magnitude of the importance of our results.</p><p>To conduct this calculation, we require estimates of (a) the total size of online display advertising spending, (b) the percentage of these campaigns that are both targeted and obtrusive, (c) the cost of the targeted and obtrusive ads relative to plain banner ads, and (d) the effectiveness of targeted and obtrusive ads relative to plain banner ads.</p><p>For (a), "total ad spending," we use <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Khan's (2009)</ref> estimate that U.S. firms spent $8.3 billion on online display advertising in 2009. For (b), we rely on the fact that in our data we found 6.4% of the campaigns are both targeted and obtrusive. Our data set is the most commonly used source in industry for information on trends in online display advertising. For (c), we use our results on the relative effectiveness of plain banner ads and targeted and obtrusive ads in columns (2) and (3) of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">2</ref> to derive estimates of their relative costs. We use these estimates rather than actual industry costs because estimates vary widely about the relative cost of different types of ads (as do the list prices websites provide to advertisers). <ref type="bibr">7</ref> Our estimates suggest that advertisers should pay 74% more for high-visibility ads (95% confidence interval, 16% to 197%) and 54% (95% confidence interval, −6% to 147%) more for context-based ads. We conservatively assume that ads that are both targeted and highly visible have the same premium as highly visible ads (74%) relative to plain banner ads. 8 For (d), we use our estimates from Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">2</ref> to generate the relative effectiveness of targeted and obtrusive ads relative to plain banner ads.</p><p>Combining these data suggests that 8% (95% confidence interval, 7.9% to 9.2%) of total ad spending, or $664 million, is being spent on campaigns that combine high visibility and targeting. Because these ads are no more effective than standard banners, if advertisers replaced redundantly targeted and visible ads with cheaper, standard banner ads, they could cut ad <ref type="bibr">7</ref> For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Khan (2009)</ref> estimates the typical cost of a plain banner ad at $2 per 1,000 impressions or 0.2 cents per impression in 2009. Targeted ads and visible ads can cost much more. Confidential estimates from a large media company report that banner prices on Web properties that allow contextual targeting are priced 10 times higher than regular "run-of-the-network" ads <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Krauss et al. 2008)</ref>. Similarly, there are industry reports that basic video ads cost four times as much as regular ads; premium ads cost as much as 18 times regular banner ads <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Palumbo 2009</ref>). 8 Advertisers appear to pay a premium for ads that are both contextually targeted and highly visible. For example, http:// technologyreview.com, a website owned by MIT to distribute its research on technology, charges a price that is already 35 times higher than average for 1,000 impressions because it can attract technology advertisers who want to advertise to technology professionals. It then charges an additional 50% premium for advertisers who want to use video or audio ads.</p><p>Marketing Science 30(3), pp. 389-404, © 2011 INFORMS spending by 5.3% (95% confidence interval, 3.5% to 7.4%) without affecting ad performance.</p><p>There are some obvious caveats to the validity of this number. Using the estimates in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">2</ref> to calculate (c), the implied price premiums have the advantage of allowing us to provide a range of statistical confidence, but these estimated price premiums are likely too low given posted industry prices. Therefore it is likely that we understate the cost savings. Second, although our data are collected by a major advertising company on behalf of its clients and are one of the most used data sources for evaluating campaign performance in industry, it is not certain that they are representative of the display advertising sector, in general, when we use these data to project the fraction of campaigns that are targeted and obtrusive. This could bias the results in either direction. Therefore, despite reporting confidence intervals, validity concerns may overwhelm the reliability measures.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.">Underlying Mechanism</head><p>Having established the robustness of the result, we then explore the underlying mechanism. We first rule out differences in ad recall. Specifically, one potential explanation for why highly visible ads and contextually targeted ads work poorly together is that highly visible ads are less successful at distinguishing themselves if they appear next to similar content. For example, a nonuser-initiated video ad that is placed on a movie website may be less noticeable there than if it is placed on a cooking site.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">4</ref> reports the results of a specification similar to that in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">2</ref>, but here, the dependent variable is whether or not the survey respondent could recall seeing the ad on the website. Column (1) of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">4</ref> suggests that the effect of being exposed to the ad is larger for this measure than in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">2</ref>. This is unsurprising as the effect is more direct; there is a 20% increase from the baseline proportion of people who remembered seeing the ad compared to those who could not remember. Column (2) suggests that if an ad's content matches the website's content, it is less likely to be recalled. Thus, contextually targeted ads are associated with higher purchase intent for the product, but people who see contextually targeted ads are less likely to recall those ads than people who see other kinds of ads. This is consistent with findings in the product placement literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Russell 2002</ref>) that contextually appropriate ads can blend into the content, reducing recall but increasing purchase intent. Column (3) is consistent with our prior results: visible ads are more likely to be recalled. Column (4) suggests that there is no significant negative interaction between contextual targeting and high visibility for recall.</p><p>The difference in these results from Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">2</ref> suggests that the combination of high visibility and contextual  targeting does not predominantly affect recall but instead affects how effective the ad is at persuading the consumer to change her purchase intent. Indeed, making contextually targeted ads too "visible" seems to drive a wedge between the advertiser and the consumer. One interpretation of this result is that contextually targeted ads are not as directly noticeable and hence are viewed more favorably as background information; however, when contextually targeted ads are highly visible, they no longer blend into the underlying website.</p><p>We next explore what drives the negative interaction between contextual targeting and high visibility when purchase intent is the dependent variable. We show that privacy is an important moderator, both in terms of whether the respondent is particularly sensitive to intrusive behavior and in terms of the nature of the product itself. This is consistent with highly visible ads increasing consumer inferences of manipulative intent in targeted advertising <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Campbell 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">, Friestad and Wright 1994</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">, Kirmani and Zhu 2007</ref>.</p><p>We stratify our results by whether the respondent checked the box "I prefer not to answer that question" when asked about income. As documented by <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Turrell (2000)</ref>, people who refuse to answer questions on income usually do so because of concerns about privacy. A comparison between columns (1) and (2) of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">5</ref> shows that survey respondents who do not respond to an intrusive question also display stronger substitution between contextually targeted and highly visible ads than other respondents. When contextual targeting is highly visible, these respondents react   negatively to the ads. Interestingly, privacy-minded people do not react differently than others to ads that are highly visible or contextually targeted, but not both. The estimates in column (2) suggest that these privacy-minded people respond positively to high-visibility ads so long as they are not also contextually targeted. To assess the relative significance of the estimates in these two columns, we also ran a specification where we pooled the sample and included a four-way interaction between Exposed × Context Ad×High-Visibility Ad and whether the person kept their income secret. The results are reported in full in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_11">A</ref>.4 in the appendix. This four-way interaction suggested that indeed there was a large and statistically significant additional negative interaction for customers who kept their income secret.</p><p>In columns ( <ref type="formula">3</ref>)-( <ref type="formula">6</ref>) of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">5</ref>, we explored whether this potential role for intrusiveness as an underlying mechanism was also echoed in the kind of products that were advertised. We looked to see whether the effect was stronger or weaker in categories that are generally considered to be personal or private.</p><p>In columns (3) and (4), we looked across all categories and identified several that are clearly related to privacy. Specifically, these categories are banking, health, health services, over-the-counter medications, insurance, investment, mutual funds, retirement funds, loans, and other financial services. We identified health and financial products as categories where there may be privacy concerns on the basis of two factors. First, <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Tsai et al. (2011)</ref> offer survey evidence of customers about which products they considered private, and they confirm that health and financial information are categories where privacy is particularly important. Second, actual privacy policies tend to specify health and financial products as privacy-related. For example, Google's privacy policy states that "Google will not associate sensitive interest categories with your browser (such as those based on race, religion, sexual orientation, health, or sensitive financial categories), and will not use such categories when showing you interest-based ads" (http:// www.google.com/privacy_ads.html; italics added). Column (3) includes the categories where privacy concerns are readily apparent; column (4) includes all others. Substitution between visibility and contextual targeting is highest for categories related to privacy. We estimated a four-way interaction specification that indicated that this incremental negative effect is significant at the 10% level.</p><p>As noted in the information security and privacy literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Kumaraguru and Cranor's 2005</ref> extensive survey results), consumers consider health information and the use of medications to be especially personal information and something that should be protected online. This is also echoed in the special protections given to health information in the European Union data privacy law 2002/EC/58. In columns ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>), we focus on health and look for differences within a single category to compare health-related Marketing Science 30(3), pp. 389-404, © 2011 INFORMS products to other similar products. Specifically, we compare estimates for over-the-counter medications to food-based consumer packaged goods (CPG) categories. The results again suggest that the substitution between contextual targeting and high visibility was significantly larger for the privacy-related products. The incremental negative effect is evaluated to be significant at the 1% level in a four-way interaction specification.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Interpretation and Conclusion</head><p>Our study of 2,892 online display advertising campaigns across a variety of categories and website yields three core conclusions.</p><p>First, we find that although obtrusive (or highly visible) online advertising and context-based online advertising work relatively well independently, they appear to fail when combined. This result is more pronounced in categories of products likely to be more private and for people who seem to guard their privacy more closely. This suggests that the ineffectiveness of combining contextual targeting and obtrusiveness in advertising is driven by consumers' perceptions of privacy. Consumers may be willing to tolerate contextually targeted ads more than other ads because they potentially provide information; however, making such ads obtrusive in nature may increase perceptions of manipulation <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Campbell 1995)</ref>. When privacy concerns are salient, a prevention focus may increase sensitivity to manipulative intent of the targeted ads <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Kirmani and Zhu 2007)</ref>. This suggests a role for privacy concerns in models that optimize advertising content in data-rich environments by minimizing viewer avoidance (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Kempe and Wilbur 2009)</ref>. Second, the result that contextually targeted ads work at least as well if they do not have features designed to enhance their visibility can help to explain the unexpected success of products such as AdSense by Google. It also explains why online advertising is becoming increasingly divided between plain textbased highly targeted ads and more visually striking but less targeted ads. The results also suggest more generally the importance of more nuanced empirical models for advertising success. Not only is it important to separately model how ads affect awareness and preferences, but it is also important to include controls for the features and placement of ads in such specifications.</p><p>Third, our findings on privacy and intrusiveness have policy implications for the direction of government policy. There is mounting pressure in the United States and Europe to regulate the use of data on browsing behavior to target advertising (Shatz 2009). Our research suggests that regulators may need to consider a potential trade-off from such regulation. If regulation is successful at reducing the amount of targeting that a firm can do by using a customer's browsing behavior, then firms may find it optimal to invest instead in highly obtrusive ads. Customers may dislike having data collected about their browsing behavior, but they have also expressed dislike of highly visible ads in surveys <ref type="bibr">(Chan et al. 2004</ref>). Therefore, regulators should weigh these two potential sources of customer resistance towards advertising against each other.</p><p>As with any empirical work, this paper has a number of limitations that present opportunities for future research. First, we rely on stated expressions of purchase intent and not actual purchase data. It is possible that the type of advertising used may have a different effect on actual purchases. Second, we present evidence that suggests that the negative effect of combining both visibility and targeting is more pronounced in situations where privacy is important, but there are still further questions about what other triggers of privacy concerns there may be for ad viewers. In general, in academic marketing research, there have been few studies about how customer privacy concerns are triggered and what the implications are for firms. This study highlights the need for a better understanding of the behavioral processes that generate consumer privacy concerns. Third, we look only at the targeting of ads based on the customer's current website browsing patterns. We do not look at reactions to ads that are targeted on the basis of past browsing behavior, although these ads have become very controversial in recent discussions of the Federal Communications Commission. Given the growing commercial importance of behavioral targeting, this is an area where academic research could potentially help answer questions both about the usefulness of such ads and how customer perceive and react to being targeted by ads in this way.</p><p>More generally, we think there are several promising avenues for research to build on our findings. First, although there is a formal theoretical literature that discusses behavioral targeting of pricing and its implications for privacy (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Acquisti and Varian 2005</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">, Chen et al. 2001</ref><ref type="bibr">, Fudenberg and Villas-Boas 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">, Hermalin and Katz 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">, Hui and Png 2006</ref>, the literature on behavioral targeting of advertising remains sparse. What are the benefits of such targeting? What are the costs? How can we formalize the concept of privacy in the context of behaviorally targeted advertising? Second, it would be interesting to explore how our findings on privacy apply to websites where visitors reveal detailed personal information, such as social networking websites. Are visitors to such sites more aware of manipulation attempts? Is there a way to leverage the social network and ing and privacy concerns interact, we will develop a better understanding of when it is appropriate to target the increasingly visible ads generated by advances in online advertising design.    </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>* * * −0 0880 * * * −0 00435 * * * −0 00957 * * * −0 00893 * *</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Dependent variable: Respondent recalls seeing the advertisement. Fixed effects at ad site level; robust standard errors, clustered at ad site level.* p &lt; 0 10; * * p &lt; 0 05; * * * p &lt; 0 01.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Dependent variable: Purchase intent (scale of 1-5 where 5 is highest). Fixed effects at ad site level; robust standard errors, clustered at ad site level. * p &lt; 0 10; * * p &lt; 0 05; * * * p &lt; 0 01.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Dependent variable: Purchase intent (indicator for very likely to make a purchase). Fixed effects at ad site level; robust standard errors, clustered at ad site level. Numerous lower-order interactions not involving exposure included but not reported. Key coefficients are in bold. * p &lt; 0 10; * * p &lt; 0 05; * * * p &lt; 0 01.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>(a)</cell><cell cols="5">Summary Statistics at the Respondent Level</cell></row><row><cell>Variable</cell><cell></cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>Std. dev.</cell><cell>Min</cell><cell>Max</cell><cell>Observations</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Likely to purchase</cell><cell>0 20</cell><cell>0 40</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2,464,812 a</cell></row><row><cell>Saw Ad</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 26</cell><cell>0 44</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2,481,592 a</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Exposed (treatment) 0 34 b</cell><cell>0 47</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2,802,333</cell></row><row><cell>Context Ad</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 10</cell><cell>0 30</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2,802,333</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">High-Visibility Ad</cell><cell>0 49</cell><cell>0 50</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2,802,333</cell></row><row><cell>Female</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 53</cell><cell>9 49</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2,802,333</cell></row><row><cell>Income</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="4">62,760 55,248 15,000 250,000</cell><cell>2,019,996</cell></row><row><cell>Age</cell><cell></cell><cell>40 9</cell><cell>1 5 6</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>2,744,149</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Hours on Internet</cell><cell>13 4</cell><cell>1 0 2</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>31</cell><cell>1,853,893</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>(b)</cell><cell cols="4">Summary Statistics at the Survey Site Level</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Variable</cell><cell cols="3">Mean Std. dev. Min</cell><cell cols="2">Max Observations</cell></row><row><cell>No. of subjects</cell><cell>198</cell><cell>275 1</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>8,456</cell><cell>13 121</cell></row><row><cell>Context Ad</cell><cell>0 13</cell><cell>0 34</cell><cell>0</cell><cell></cell><cell>13 121</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">High-Visibility Ad</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Influence of High Visibility and Contextual Targeting on Purchase Intent</figDesc><table><row><cell>(1)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(2)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(3)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(4)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Coefficient</cell><cell></cell><cell>Coefficient</cell><cell></cell><cell>Coefficient</cell><cell></cell><cell>Coefficient</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>(std. error)</cell><cell>p-Value</cell><cell>(std. error)</cell><cell>p-Value</cell><cell>(std. error)</cell><cell>p-Value</cell><cell>(std. error)</cell><cell>p-Value</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Robustness Checks</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>(1)</cell><cell>(2)</cell><cell>(3)</cell><cell>(4)</cell><cell>(5)</cell><cell>(6)</cell><cell>(7)</cell><cell>(8)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Use full</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Only ads that</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>scale (i.e.,</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>appear on both</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>treat rating</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>matched and</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>scale as</cell><cell></cell><cell>Nonparametric</cell><cell>Favorable</cell><cell></cell><cell>Multiply</cell><cell>unmatched</cell></row><row><cell>Logit a</cell><cell>interval)</cell><cell>No controls</cell><cell>controls</cell><cell>opinion</cell><cell>No pop-ups</cell><cell>treated</cell><cell>context websites</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Influence of High Visibility and Contextual Targeting on Ad Recall</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Privacy Sensitivity Is Associated with Stronger Substitution Between Contextual Targeting and High Visibility</figDesc><table><row><cell>(1)</cell><cell>(2)</cell><cell>(3)</cell><cell>(4)</cell><cell>(5)</cell><cell>(6)</cell></row><row><cell>Does not reveal income</cell><cell>Reveals income</cell><cell>Private</cell><cell>Not private</cell><cell>Health CPG</cell><cell>Other CPG</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Dependent variable: Respondent very likely to purchase. Fixed effects at ad site level; robust standard errors, clustered at ad site level. Full results for four-way interaction specification on pooled data used to assess significance reported in TableA.4.    </figDesc><table><row><cell>Coefficient on four-way interaction</cell><cell>−0.0369  *  *  *</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">−0.0183  *</cell><cell cols="2">−0.0677  *  *  *</cell></row><row><cell>in alternative specification</cell><cell>(0.00919)</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">(0.0109)</cell><cell cols="2">(0.0258)</cell></row><row><cell>Observations</cell><cell>390,608</cell><cell>2,074,204</cell><cell>325,376</cell><cell>2,139,436</cell><cell>114,922</cell><cell>192,609</cell></row><row><cell>Log-likelihood</cell><cell>−152,023.4</cell><cell>−903,402.0</cell><cell>−119,800.1</cell><cell>−941,137.4</cell><cell>−57,285.5</cell><cell>−102,271.0</cell></row><row><cell>R-Squared</cell><cell>0.157</cell><cell>0.143</cell><cell>0.145</cell><cell>0.139</cell><cell>0.139</cell><cell>0.146</cell></row><row><cell>Notes.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>* p &lt; 0 10; * * p &lt; 0 05; * * * p &lt; 0 01.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Notes. Dependent variable: Purchase intent (scale of 1-5 where 5 is highest). Fixed effects at ad site level; robust standard errors, clustered at ad site level.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Observations</cell><cell>2,464,812</cell><cell>2,443,939</cell><cell>2,932,278</cell><cell>2,464,812</cell><cell>3,196,474</cell><cell>1,976,180</cell></row><row><cell>Log-likelihood</cell><cell>−4,165,117.9</cell><cell>−3,488,010.7</cell><cell cols="3">−4,958,771.8 −4,167,674.3 −5,409,175.6</cell><cell>−33,48,518.8</cell></row><row><cell>R-Squared</cell><cell>0.202</cell><cell>0.156</cell><cell>0.202</cell><cell>0.200</cell><cell>0.202</cell><cell>0.200</cell></row></table><note>* p &lt; 0 10; * * p &lt; 0 05; * * * p &lt; 0 01.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>Table A</head><label>A</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Replicates Table 5 with Continuous Scale</cell></row><row><cell>.3</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12"><head>Table A</head><label>A</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Four-Way Interaction Specification</cell></row><row><cell>.4</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Data are missing for two reasons: sometimes that question was not asked, and sometimes respondents refused to answer. We have no income information for 28% of respondents, no age information for 2% of respondents, and no hours online information for 34% of respondents.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">Of course, there are many features of the ad, the viewer, and the website that may influence advertising effectiveness but are not the primary focus on this study. Our analysis controls for these through the randomization of the exposed condition, the campaign-specific fixed effects, and the viewer characteristics.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="12">x 1 x 2 F • . The sign of this marginal effect is not necessarily the same as the sign of the coefficient 12 . We therefore used the appropriate formula for three-way interactions to calculate the marginal effect in this setting. The marginal effects at the means of</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">Because about 60% of campaigns are successful, the hit rate under random assignment is 52%, i.e., 40% × 40% + 60% × 60%</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Marketing Science 30(3), pp. 389-404, © 2011 INFORMS 401 overcome perceptions of manipulative intent? This latter question may apply to all online advertising settings. Once we have a richer formal theoretical framework for understanding how behavioral target-Appendix. Further Robustness Checks    </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Aaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Day</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Marketing Research</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>8th ed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditioning prices on purchase history</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Acquisti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Varian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="367" to="381" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interaction terms in logit and probit models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Norton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="123" to="129" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mostly Harmless Econometrics: An Empiricist&apos;s Companion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Angrist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-S</forename><surname>Pischke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Princeton, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting behavior from intention-to-buy measures: The parametric case</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Bemmaor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="176" to="191" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Practical issues in structural modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bentler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C.-P</forename><surname>Chou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sociol. Methods Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="78" to="117" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Deception in the Marketplace: The Psychology of Deceptive Persuasion and Consumer Self Protection</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Boush</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Friestad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When attention-getting tactics elicit consumer inferences of manipulative intent: The importance of balancing benefits and investments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Campbell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Psych</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="254" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consumers&apos; use of persuasion knowledge: The effects of accessibility and cognitive capacity on perceptions of an influence agent</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Campbell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kirmani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="83" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling the clickstream: Implications for Web-based advertising efforts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Chatterjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Hoffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Novak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="520" to="541" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual marketing with imperfect targetability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Narasimhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why do people avoid advertising on the internet?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C.-H</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Cheon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Advertising</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="97" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of advertising on brand awareness and perceived quality: An empirical investigation using panel data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Doraszelski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Draganska</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Internet advertising: Is anybody watching?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Drèze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F.-X</forename><surname>Hussherr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Interactive Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Forced exposure and psychological reactance: Antecedents and consequences of the perceived intrusiveness of pop-up ads</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Edwards</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Advertising</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="95" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How to Conduct Surveys: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fink</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>SAGE Publications</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Thousand Oaks, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>4th ed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The persuasion knowledge model: How people cope with persuasion attempts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Friestad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Behavior-based price discrimination and customer recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Fudenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Economics and Information Systems: Handbooks in Information Systems</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hendershott</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="377" to="436" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Villas-Boas</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical analysis of search engine advertising: Sponsored search in electronic markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ghose</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1605" to="1622" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Firm-created word-of-mouth communication: Evidence from a field test</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Godes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mayzlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="721" to="739" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Search engine advertising: Channel substituion when pricing ads to context</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Goldfarb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="458" to="470" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">US advertising spending: The new reality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hallerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.emarketer.com/Report.aspx?code=emarketer_2000576" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">eMarketer technical report</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of expectancy and relevancy in memory for verbal and visual information: What is incongruency?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Heckler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Childers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="475" to="492" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy, property rights and efficiency: The economics of privacy as secrecy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hermalin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="239" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ten years of learning on how online advertising builds brands</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Hollis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Advertising Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="268" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Results on the bias and inconsistency of ordinary least squares for the linear probability model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Horrace</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Oaxaca</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="327" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The economics of privacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K.-L</forename><forename type="middle">I P L</forename><surname>Hui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Png</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Economics and Information Systems: Handbooks in Information Systems</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hendershott</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="471" to="497" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ordinal measures in multiple indicator models: A simulation study of categorization error</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Creech</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Sociol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="398" to="407" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What can television networks learn from search engines? How to select, order, and price ads to maximize advertiser welfare. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wilbur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<pubPlace>Durham, NC</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Duke University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nothing but Net: 2009 Internet investment guide</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Khan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. P</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>Morgan</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vigilant against manipulation: The effect of regulatory focus on the use of persuasion knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kirmani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">(j</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="688" to="701" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Psychological Testing: A Practical Approach to Design and Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J B</forename><surname>Kline</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<publisher>Sage Publications</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Thousand Oaks, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bain/IAB digital pricing research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Krauss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Nitke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Pinto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-08" />
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
	<note>Interactive Advertising Bureau</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Privacy indexes: A survey of westin&apos;s studies. Working Paper CMU-ISRI-5-138</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kumaraguru</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Cranor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<pubPlace>Pittsburgh</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating production functions using inputs to control for unobservables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Levinsohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Petrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="317" to="341" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Retail advertising works! Measuring the effects of advertising on sales via a controlled experiment on Yahoo! Yahoo! Research technical report</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Reiley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<pubPlace>Sunnyvale, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Marketing Research: An Applied Orientation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Malhotra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<pubPlace>Upper Saddle River, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>5th ed. Pearson Education</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of banner advertising on Internet purchasing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Manchanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-P</forename><surname>Dubé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Goh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="98" to="108" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The structure of value: Accounting for taste</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mandler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Affect and Cognition: 17th Annual Carnegie Mellon Symposium on Cognition</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fiske</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Hillsdale, NJ</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="36" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When do purchase intentions predict sales?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morwitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Steckel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Forecasting</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="347" to="364" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online video media spend</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Palumbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.accustreamresearch.com/products/onlinevideo03-2010.htm" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Accu-Stream iMedia Research technical report</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating the effectiveness of product placements in television shows: The role of modality and plot connection congruence on brand memory and attitude</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="306" to="318" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The effects of Internet banner advertising exposure on within-site browsing behavior. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Rutz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bucklin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<pubPlace>New Haven, CT</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Yale University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Regulators rethink approach to online privacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Schatz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB124949972905908593.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wall Street Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-08-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The brand value of rich media and video ads</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Spalding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.dynamiclogic.com/na/research/industry_presentations/docs/Brand_Value_Rich_Media_Aug09.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">DoubleClick research report</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="389" to="404" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of online privacy information on purchasing behavior: An experimental study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Tsai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Egelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cranor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Acquisti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inform. Systems Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="261" to="278" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contrary to what marketers say, Americans reject tailored advertising and three activities that enable it. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Turow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hoofnagle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bleakley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hennessy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://graphics8.nytimes.com/packages/pdf/business/20090929-Tailored_Advertising.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annenberg School for Communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Income non-reporting: Implications for health inequalities research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Turrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Epidemiology Community Health</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="214" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The persuasiveness of online safety cues: The impact of prevention focus compatibility of Web content on consumers&apos; risk perceptions, attitudes, and intentions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Van Noort</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kerkhof</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fennis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Interactive Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="58" to="72" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of forced ad exposure on the Web</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H.-L</forename><surname>S.-H. Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Informatics Electronics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="38" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An empirical approach to understanding privacy concerns</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Wathieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>09-001</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<pubPlace>Berlin</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>ESMT European School of Management and Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">ESMT Working Paper</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Effects of advertising and product placement on television audiences. Marshall School of Business</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wilbur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Goeree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ridder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>MKT 09-09</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<pubPlace>Los Angeles</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Southern California</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Working Paper</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
