<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Noncompensatory Dyadic Choices</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2011-10-13">October 13, 2011.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Neeraj</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
							<email>narora@bus.wisc.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Ty</forename><surname>Henderson</surname></persName>
							<email>ty.henderson@mccombs.utexas.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Qing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<email>qliu@bus.wisc.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Wisconsin School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wisconsin-Madison</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>53706</postCode>
									<settlement>Madison</settlement>
									<region>Wisconsin</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">McCombs School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>78712</postCode>
									<settlement>Austin</settlement>
									<region>Texas</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Wisconsin School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wisconsin-Madison</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>53706</postCode>
									<settlement>Madison</settlement>
									<region>Wisconsin</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Noncompensatory Dyadic Choices</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2011-10-13">October 13, 2011.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1110.0667</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: June 24, 2010; accepted: June 25, 2011; Eric Bradlow and then Preyas Desai served as the</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:26+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>group decision making</term>
					<term>group welfare</term>
					<term>joint choice</term>
					<term>choice heuristics</term>
					<term>hierarchical Bayes</term>
					<term>consideration sets</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Existing research on the topic of how a group makes choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Davis 1970</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">, Corfman and Lehmann 1987</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">, Menasco and Curry 1989</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">, Arora and Allenby 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">, Aribarg et al. 2010</ref> assumes that the underlying utility function of a group is compensatory. That is, a group includes all available choice alternatives for consideration and trades off all product features against each other. This assumption is at odds with empirical evidence supporting the presence of consideration sets that suggests a noncompensatory choice process. Whereas attribute-based consideration at the individual level is well documented <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Elrod et al. 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">, Jedidi and Kohli 2005</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">, Gilbride and Allenby 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">, Yee et al. 2007</ref>, how this noncompensatory process unfolds in a joint choice context is not. The knowledge gap in how groups within an organization, or a family, make joint choices using noncompensatory decision rules is an important area of enquiry because it has direct implications for buyers and sellers.</p><p>The basic premise of this paper is that individual and dyadic consideration sets are inextricably related, and a careful investigation of this interrelationship, although important, has been largely neglected. Our goals in this paper are twofold. First, we develop a novel conceptual framework to empirically investigate the dyadic noncompensatory choice processes, and we evaluate both the quality and efficiency of those dyadic decisions. Second, we link dyadic noncompensatory choice processes to substantive marketing problems such as product design and pricing. We argue that a careful understanding of noncompensatory dyadic choices is of great interest to buyers and sellers alike. For buyers it provides prescriptions that maximize dyadic welfare when making joint choices and do so efficiently. For sellers, it provides actionable pricing and new product design insights that a compensatory model likely misses.</p><p>The dyadic choice process we propose builds on the two-stage "consider-then-choose" class of models <ref type="bibr">Arora, Henderson, and Liu: Noncompensatory Dyadic Choices</ref> Marketing Science 30(6), pp. 1028-1047, © 2011 INFORMS 1029 <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bettman 1979</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">, Gilbride and Allenby 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">, Jedidi and Kohli 2005</ref> and utility aggregation theories (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Harsanyi 1955</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">, Curry et al. 1991</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">, Arora and Allenby 1999</ref>. Our primary focus is on the consideration stage of the model, where an individual or a dyad can eliminate product alternatives from consideration because they contain undesirable attribute levels such as a high price. Based on parameters that capture such screening, we introduce a set of mutually exclusive, collectively exhaustive dyadic decision processes (DDPs) that capture alternative ways in which consideration set differences between dyad members are reconciled.</p><p>In our DDP framework, the intersection of memberlevel consideration sets leads to dyads that are either concordant or discordant. We describe dyadic concordance as the case when dyad members agree on which alternatives to consider. Within this concordant group, we study differences between dyads that engage in a compensatory decision process for all available alternatives versus dyads that agree to only consider a smaller subset of alternatives. When dyad members disagree on which alternatives to exclude from consideration, there is dyadic discordance. For the discordant group, we examine the differences between dyads that choose to expand their consideration set, thus electing to evaluate a larger choice set, versus those that choose to restrict it and evaluate a smaller choice set. We draw contrasts between the alternative decision processes that result when dyads reconcile their consideration set differences using a variety of measures that assess decision efficiency (e.g., how quickly a dyad decides) and decision quality (e.g., dyadic welfare).</p><p>Our methodological approach merges choice experiments with statistical modeling to uncover the nuances of the noncompensatory dyadic choice process. The underlying econometric model uses Bayesian methods to account for member and dyad heterogeneity in consideration sets and preferences. Data for the research were collected with the help of C&amp;R Research and involved a carefully constructed multiphase nationwide study of 265 husband-andwife dyads. We report results pertaining to three consumer electronics products (flat-panel televisions, digital cameras, and laptop computers) and test our dyadic consider-then-choose model. In-sample and out-of-sample fit statistics demonstrate that our model outperforms a dyadic compensatory model. We also show that stated data provide useful information about the consideration stage of the model and significantly add to the model fit.</p><p>Beyond superior model fit, a bigger difference between the dyadic noncompensatory and compensatory models is that the former allows us to uncover the DDP framework and its unique insights-the primary focus of this paper. In particular, comparisons between dyads that follow alternate decision processes uncover significant differences in their decision efficiency and decision quality. Among dyads that are concordant, those that consider only a subset of alternatives make quicker and better choices than those that consider all available alternatives. Among discordant dyads, when compared to dyads that expand their consideration set, dyads that restrict their consideration set make quicker decisions that result in higher dyadic welfare. These findings align with behavioral economics literature related to information overload and overchoice (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Iyengar and</ref><ref type="bibr">Lepper 2000, Schwartz 2004</ref>) but are at odds with the notion of equity, fairness, and reciprocity <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Deutsch 1975</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">, Albin 1993</ref>) likely present in intact dyads.</p><p>The dyadic noncompensatory model also offers a distinct substantive advantage over the extant compensatory model. For example, we show that in contrast to our model, a dyadic compensatory model not only understates demand in a demand forecast for a new product, it also suggests an optimal price that is significantly lower. The primary reason for these differences is that unaccounted-for price screening in a compensatory model can bias the price sensitivity estimates upward. A dyad's willingness to pay for a specific feature is also found to be closely tied to its consideration set that a compensatory model fails to detect. Therefore, compared with the proposed dyadic consider-then-choose model, a dyadic compensatory model can suggest a suboptimal price, incorrectly predict demand, and result in less profitable decisions.</p><p>The remainder of this paper is organized as follows. We begin with a section that outlines our conceptual framework and dyadic noncompensatory model. This is followed by a detailed description of our study and data collection procedure. Section 4 contains our findings from the multiphase study, and in §5 we present model extensions. We conclude the paper with a discussion of our findings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Conceptual Framework and Model</head><p>Noncompensatory decision rules involve exclusion of certain attributes for consideration. Such screening rules are obtained directly via stated measures <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Yee et al. 2007)</ref> or are model based <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Gilbride and Allenby 2006)</ref>. Our approach does both: using stated data as prior information when estimating model-based screening parameters. An intersection of individual screening parameters at the dyad level gives rise to our decision framework that we explain next.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Dyadic Consider-Then-Choose</head><p>Model Specification We describe our modeling framework for a situation in which two individuals (say, husband h and Marketing Science 30(6), pp. 1028-1047, © 2011 INFORMS wife w) jointly make a decision to choose a product. Let us assume that the husband h evaluating K alternatives within a choice set chooses alternative k . Each alternative k (k = 1 K) has a design vector x k indicating the presence (x km = 1) or absence (x km = 0) of attribute levels m = 1 M. The deterministic part of utility V hk , linear in the predictor variables (x k h ), with an independent and identically distributed Type I extreme value error structure, yields a multinomial logit model of choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(McFadden 1974)</ref>. To capture the noncompensatory evaluation process, a parameter ( hm is included for each attribute level m, where hm = 1 if the attribute level is screened out and hm = 0 otherwise <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Gilbride and Allenby 2006</ref>). An indicator function I(x k h governs the inclusion of an alternative in the consideration set as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Pr h k = Pr V hk + hk &gt; V hk + hk ∀ k such that I x k h = 1 where I x k h =        0 if M m=1 hm × x km ≥ 1 1 otherwise (1)</formula><p>That is, alternative k is not considered if there exists an attribute level m in alternative k x km = 1) such that the attribute level is screened out ( hm = 1). Stated differently, an alternative k is considered if all attribute levels in the alternative pass screening. The indicator function I x k h ) partitions the error space and results in the following expression for choice probability:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Pr h y k = 1 = I x k h exp x k h K k=1 I x k h exp x k h (2)</formula><p>Analogous to { h h } for husband h, there exist parameters { w w } for wife w such that</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">Pr w y k = 1 = I x k w exp x k w K k=1 I x k w exp x k w (3)</formula><p>Similarly, the dyadic choices made by the husband and wife together could be written as</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">Pr d y k = 1 = I x k d exp x k d K k=1 I x k d exp x k d (4)</formula><p>where parameters { d d } capture attribute preference and screening for the dyad. The dyad's attribute preferences in the vector d are linked to the attribute influence vector h of husband h in the dyadic choice decision <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Arora and Allenby 1999)</ref> as</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">d = h h + 1 − h w (5)</formula><p>That is, dyadic preference is a linear function of individual member preferences. The parameter space of h could be constrained to lie between 0 and 1 if dyadic preference is a convex combination of individual preferences. However, the group polarization phenomenon <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Myers and</ref><ref type="bibr">Lamm 1976, Rao and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Steckel 1991)</ref> suggests that dyadic preference may be more extreme than the average of individual prediscussion preference. Therefore, we refrain from imposing a range constraint (0 ≤ h ≤ 1) on the influence parameter. Compensatory dyadic influence of this type has been examined in prior research, but how the dyadic decision process unfolds in the noncompensatory context has not. Next, we describe our framework for characterizing the noncompensatory dyadic decision process, which is the primary focus of this paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Attribute-Level Noncompensatory</head><p>Dyadic Decision Process For a given attribute level, the intersection of the binary realizations of individual screening parameters { h w } creates a two-by-two matrix of possible noncompensatory dyadic decision states. These states can be classified into two categories: concordance and discordance. Concordance refers to states in which both h and w exhibit similar screening behavior ( h = w ): both parties are of the same mind to either consider or not consider the attribute level. Discordance, in contrast, refers to h and w having opposing screening behaviors ( h = w ): either h screens out the given attribute level and w does not ( h = 1 w = 0), or vice versa ( h = 0 w = 1). In the presence of the individual screening parameters just described, a dyad could subsequently screen ( d = 1) or not screen ( d = 0) on a given attribute level.</p><p>Connecting the dyad's screening behavior to member-specific screens creates four distinct characterizations of the noncompensatory dyadic decision process that are of particular interest to us. To illustrate this framework, we use a husband-andwife automobile choice decision example. We begin by focusing on a single attribute level (the Toyota brand in our illustration) and subsequently expand the framework to account for the dyadic decision process across attributes. Although the term "dyadic decision process" (or "DDP") could refer to both the compensatory and noncompensatory dimensions of a joint decision, in this paper we restrict our use of the term DDP to encompass only the noncompensatory aspects of the model as expressed in the attributelevel screening parameters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.1.">Compensatory Concordant</head><formula xml:id="formula_5">h = w = 0 .</formula><p>For this DDP both h and w include alternatives with this attribute level in their consideration set. In our example, this implies that the husband and wife are of the same mind-as individuals, they are both willing to consider the Toyota brand in the trade-offs they make. At a later stage, as a dyad, they will mostly likely keep the Toyota brand in their consideration set ( d = 0).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.2.">Screening Concordant</head><formula xml:id="formula_6">h = w = 1 .</formula><p>Both h and w exclude alternatives with this attribute level. This suggests that Toyota, in our example, is an unacceptable alternative for both the husband and wife as individuals. At a later stage, as a dyad, they will mostly likely keep the Toyota brand out of their consideration set ( d = 1).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.3.">Expand</head><formula xml:id="formula_7">h = w d = 0 .</formula><p>There is discordance about the attribute level: one member excludes alternatives with this attribute level while the other member does not. The dyad resolves the difference by including alternatives with this attribute level, thus expanding their consideration set. Expansion as a DDP is equivalent to a union (or) rule for consideration sets. In our example, although Toyota is an unacceptable alternative for one individual and is acceptable to the other, upon deliberation, the dyad decides to include Toyota for consideration.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.4.">Restrict</head><p>h = w d = 1). There is also attribute discordance here: one member excludes alternatives with this attribute level, but the other member does not. The dyad resolves the difference by excluding alternatives with this attribute level, thus restricting their consideration set. Restriction is equivalent to an intersection (and) rule for consideration sets. In our example, although Toyota is an unacceptable alternative for one individual and acceptable to the other, upon deliberation, the dyad decides to exclude Toyota as an alternative for consideration.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Across-Attribute Dyadic Decision</head><p>Process Our conceptualization of the noncompensatory dyadic decision process has thus far focused on only one attribute level, but most choices involve multiple attributes. Next, we extend the concordance, discordance, expand, and restrict concepts to the multiattribute context. This results in a potential fifth DDP that we also describe. For simplicity, we continue to use the term "DDP" instead of "DDP across attributes" when referring to the dyadic decision process across attributes. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref> lists the five DDPs that emerge in a multiattribute setting. To exemplify each DDP type, we extend our husband-and-wife automobile choice decision illustration to include two attributes-brand and color-each with two levels. The brands in our example are Honda and Toyota, and the colors are black and white.</p><p>In a multiattribute setting, dyads that exhibit compensatory concordance across all levels of all attributes are classified as compensatory concordant DDP. That is, for such dyads, hm = wm = 0 for all attribute levels m = 1 M. In this paper, the compensatory concordant DDP is referred to in abbreviated notation as CC. In our automobile example in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref>, this is the first DDP. Notice that both the husband and wife are in agreement and do not engage in screening-they consider both brands and both colors. As a dyad, they follow the "all-in" strategy and trade off between brands and colors when making a choice. Moving to the next DDP, dyads that are concordant across all attributes and exhibit screening concordance for at least one attribute level are classified as screening concordant DDP. That is, hm = wm for all attribute levels m = 1 M, and for at least one m, hm = wm = 1. We refer to the screening concordant DDP as SC. In our example of an SC in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref>, both the husband and wife are in agreement and exclude white cars. As a dyad, they only consider black cars and trade off between the two brands when making a choice. Discordance in a multiattribute setting occurs when for at least one attribute level m, hm = wm . In such instances resolution of the differences can occur via expansion, restriction, or a combination of the two mechanisms. To be classified in the expand DDP, a dyad must decide to include for consideration all m * attribute levels on which there is screening discordance between individual dyad members-that is, for set expansion dm = 0 for all m, where hm = wm . In the example of an expand DDP in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref>, m * = 2 because there is screening discordance on two attribute levels: the husband excludes the Toyota brand and white cars from consideration, but the wife is willing to consider all brands and colors. Dyads using the expand DDP do not exclude any alternatives and trade off all brands and colors when making a choice.</p><p>The restrict DDP describes dyads that decide to exclude from consideration all m * attribute levels on which there is screening discordance between individual dyad members. This dyadic consideration set restriction is expressed as dm = 1 for all m, where hm = wm . For the example in the fourth block of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref>, notice that the consideration set for a restrict DDP is smaller-the husband and wife only consider black and white Hondas. Finally, in cases where there is screening discordance across multiple attributes, a dyad may choose to pursue a mixed strategyexpanding its consideration set for some attributes and restricting it for other attributes. The husband in our example of a mixed DDP excludes Toyota, and the wife excludes the color white. The dyad restricts its consideration set on one aspect of the decision (only black color) and expands on the other (both Honda and Toyota brands).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.">Parameter Heterogeneity</head><p>Whereas our model development until this point has focused on a given dyad, preference, influence, and   </p><formula xml:id="formula_8">= h2 = h3 = h4 = 0 w 1 = w 2 = w 3 = w 4 = 0 d1 = d2 = d3 = d4 = 0 Husband Wife Dyad Consideration set DDP Screening concordance m I hm = wm = 0 ∧ m I hm = wm = 1 ≥ 1 Screening parameters h1 = h2 = h3 = 0, h4 = 1 w 1 = w 2 = w 3 = 0, w 4 = 1 d1 = d2 = d3 = 0, d4 = 1 Husband Wife Dyad Consideration set DDP Expand m I hm = wm = m * ≥ 1 ∧ m∈ m hm = wm I dm = 0 = m * Screening parameters h1 = h3 = 0, h2 = h4 = 1 w 1 = w 2 = w 3 = w 4 = 0 d1 = d2 = d3 = d4 = 0 Husband Wife Dyad Consideration set DDP Restrict m I hm = wm = m * ≥ 1 ∧ m∈ m hm = wm I dm = 1 = m * Screening parameters h1 = h3 = h4 = 0, h2 = 1 w 1 = w 2 = w 3 = w 4 = 0 d1 = d3 = d4 = 0, d2 = 1 Husband Wife Dyad Consideration set DDP Mixed m I hm = wm = m * ≥ 1 ∧ m∈ m hm = wm I dm = 0 ≥ 1 ∧ m∈ m hm = wm I dm = 1 ≥ 1 Screening parameters h1 = h3 = h4 = 0, h2 = 1 w 1 = w 2 = w 3 = 0, w 4 = 1 d1 = d2 = d3 = 0, d4 = 1</formula><formula xml:id="formula_9">d ∼ Normal ¯ D<label>(6)</label></formula><p>In Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_9">6</ref>), d is a vector of individual (i.e., h and w) preference and influence parameters for the dth dyad. Specifically, d = dh dw d , and</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">= ¯ h ¯ w ¯ and D =   D hh D hw D hd D wh D ww D wd D dh D dw D dd   (7)</formula><p>The hyperparameter vector¯ captures the central tendency of (husband-and-wife) preferences and influence. The diagonal elements of D demonstrate the extent of heterogeneity among husbands' preference (D hh ), wives' preference (D ww ), and influence (D dd ), whereas the off-diagonal elements capture preference and influence covariance.</p><p>For each attribute level, there are eight (i.e., 2 3 ) potential realizations of the husband, wife, and dyad binary screening parameters [ dh , dw , d ]. We define d to be the (8 × 1) vector that identifies a particular realization of the binary screening parameters [ dh , dw , d ], and the heterogeneity of d is captured through the following alternative model specifications.</p><p>2.4.1. Model 1. We assume that for a given attribute level m, the screening vector dm follows a multinomial distribution with probabilities p 1m p 8m , where each probability indicates the proportion of the sample belonging to each one of the eight realizations of dm . Thus,</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">dm ∼ Multinomial p 1m p 8m (8)</formula><p>We specify a generalized Dirichlet distribution <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Wong 1998)</ref> as the prior of the multinomial probabilities to allow for a more general covariance structure. 1 That is, p 1m p 7m ∼ generalized Dirichlet 1m , 7m 1m 7m</p><p>and p 8m = 1 − p 1m − • • • − p 7m . As such, Model 1 is a multidimensional extension of the specification used in the conjunctive screening rule model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Gilbride and Allenby (2006)</ref>.</p><p>In addition to bringing noncompensatory research to the joint decision-making domain, a novel aspect of our paper is that we leverage stated data to better understand the noncompensatory decision process. The next model provides a method in which stated measures of attribute screening obtained from respondents are used to improve parameter estimate efficiency.</p><p>2.4.2. Model 2. Stated measures of individual and dyadic propensity to screen certain attribute levels are easy to elicit. For example, previous research <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Yee et al. 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">, Aribarg et al. 2010</ref> uses "must have" or "can't have" classification schemes to assess screenedout attributes. Similarly, self-explicated approaches <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Srinivasan and Park 1997)</ref> routinely rely on measures such as "most you will pay" or "lowest acceptable speed" to assess screening. In the presence of choice data, such stated data could be of significant value <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Horsky et al. 2006</ref>) because they help inform the screening probabilities in Equation ( <ref type="formula">8</ref>). This is particularly important in our context because the model includes individual-level parameters, so the total number of parameters is high.</p><p>It is reasonable to assume that the dyads' stated screening for each attribute level is indicative of actual screening behavior in the choices they make. For example, if a dyad states that it would consider all attribute levels across all attributes both as individuals and as a dyad, then it is reasonable to assume that it is quite likely that the dyad would do so during the choice task. Using the stated screening information that is often easy to collect, in Model 2 we translate stated data on screening into subjective probabilities. The multinomial dm bin membership probability is specific to each dyad based on the information from the dyad's stated screening, so</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">dm ∼ Multinomial p d1m p d8m<label>(9)</label></formula><p>We incorporate dyad-specific stated screening information through a generalized Dirichlet prior as follows. Let * dm = w b denote that the stated screening for dyad d falls in the bth bin of the eight possible realizations. Because the order of elements in a generalized Dirichlet distribution is not arbitrary, we first rearrange the multinomial probabilities based on the self-stated screening bin membership by mapping p d1m p d8m to p * d1m p * d8m so that p * d1m = p dbm and p * dbm = p d1m if * dm = w b . Then,</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">p * d1m p * d7m ∼ generalized Dirichlet * 1m * 7m * 1m * 7m (<label>10</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_14">)</formula><p>where * bm / * bm + * bm = b for b = 1 2 7, and p * d7m are provided in the appendix. Within this setup, dyads have a high expected probability of exhibiting the screening behavior they stated and a lower probability of falling into one of the other dm bins. 2</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">p * d8m = 1 − p * d1m − • • • − p * d7m .</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5.">Consequences of Dyadic Decision Processes</head><p>Next, we study decision quality implications for both concordant and discordant dyads. In particular, (i) when concordant, do compensatory concordant dyads make better decisions than screening concordant dyads? And (ii) when discordant, which one of the three DDPs (expand, restrict, or mixed) results in better decisions for the dyad? Literature on consumer expertise and the use of choice heuristics <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Alba and Hutchinson 1987)</ref> suggests that more knowledgeable dyads with well-formed preference structures will use screening to efficiently narrow the choice set and make high-quality decisions. Research also suggests that considering too many alternatives, as would be the case with compensatory dyads, leads to information overload, resulting in suboptimal outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Keller and Staelin 1987</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">, Gourville and Soman 2005</ref><ref type="bibr">, Kuksov and Villas-Boas 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">, Dhar 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">, Iyengar and Lepper 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">, Chernev 2003</ref>). Existing research therefore suggests that screening concordant dyads likely make better decisions than compensatory concordant dyads because these dyads focus on a smaller consideration set.</p><p>Unlike situations when preferences concord, previous research provides less conclusive guidance for situations when discord exists. From the standpoint of fairness and reciprocity, considering more alternatives, or an expand DDP, appears most equitable <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Deutsch 1975</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">, Albin 1993</ref>) and would likely have a Marketing Science 30(6), pp. 1028-1047, © 2011 INFORMS positive impact on decision quality. In contrast, the "overchoice" literature suggests that a restrict strategy might be better because it helps focus the dyads on a more manageable consideration set.</p><p>In the empirical section that follows, we examine the implications of different DDPs on decision quality using the following three specific measures: concession, choice inefficiency, and dyadic preference intensity, which can be thought of as proxies for dyadic welfare/happiness. 2.5.1. Concession. Concession for a given dyad measures the compromises that individual members of the dyad make during the joint choice decision process <ref type="bibr">Lehmann 1993, Aribarg et al. 2002)</ref>. Specifically, for a particular dyadic joint choice task, let ideal h (ideal w ) represent the alternative with maximal utility that the husband (wife) would have chosen based on his (her) individual preferences, and let chosen d represent the actual alternative chosen jointly by the dyad. We define dyadic concession as</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">Concession d = Pr h ideal h − Pr h chosen d + Pr w ideal w − Pr w chosen d (11) 2.5.2. Choice Inefficiency.</formula><p>Although a dyad is expected to maximize utility and choose the ideal alternative, this may not always occur. Therefore, we define the choice inefficiency measure as the deviation of the dyad's chosen alternative from the dyad's ideal alternative as</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">Choice inefficiency d = Pr d ideal d −Pr d chosen d (12)</formula><p>2.5.3. Dyadic Preference Intensity. The concepts of welfare <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Gupta and Kohli 1990)</ref> and regret <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Inman et al. 1997)</ref> suggest that dyads selecting an alternative with larger relative attractiveness are likely to be happier than those dyads that select an alternative with a smaller relative attractiveness. We define dyadic preference intensity as the relative attractiveness (choice probability) of the dyad's chosen alternative:</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">Dyadic preference intensity d = Pr d chosen d (13)</formula><p>Next, we describe a study we designed to (i) test the proposed dyadic noncompensatory choice model, (ii) empirically investigate the prevalence of alternative dyadic decision processes and their subsequent impact on decision efficiency and quality, and (iii) investigate the substantive implications of the dyadic noncompensatory model on managerial decisions involving product design and pricing. In our study design, we paid particular attention to how stated measures of individual and dyadic screening were obtained, because these measures lie at the heart of the dyadic decision processes we hope to uncover.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Empirical Study</head><p>The study was completed by 265 married couples in an online panel environment managed by C&amp;R Research and had several stages that involved individual and joint tasks, as summarized in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">2</ref>. Because of its multistage nature, in addition to the usual reward points for an opt-in panel, the respondents were given $15 for completing the survey and also had a chance to win a flat-panel television. The study involved three durable goods categories (laptop computers, digital cameras, and flat-panel televisions), and dyads qualified on the basis of likelihood to buy a flat-panel TV. Next, we explain each stage of the study in detail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Individual Preference Measurement</head><p>(Laptop Computer or Digital Camera) A subset of the full sample indicated that it was likely to buy a laptop computer or a digital camera over the next 12 months. For one of these two categories, we asked the qualifying dyads specific questions pertaining to their product attribute preferences. Laptop computer attributes included brand name (e.g., Apple, Gateway), features (e.g., Intel processor, quadcore architecture), and price. Similarly, digital camera attributes included brand (e.g., Nikon, Sony), features (e.g., 10-megapixel resolution, 5× zoom), and price. The respondents were provided a brief overview of each attribute and then asked to drag and drop each attribute level into one of the three attribute classification bins: "can't have this feature," "it depends," or "must have this feature." Taken as a proxy for screening, the "can't-have" category indicates that alternatives with this attribute would not be found in the respondent's consideration set. In addition to the attribute classification task, we asked individuals category-specific questions about product usage, experience, and knowledge.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Individual Preference Measurement</head><p>(Flat-Panel TV) Similar to the aforementioned categories, measures of stated preference, experience, knowledge, etc., were also obtained for the flat-panel TV category. The specific attributes we used are listed in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">3</ref>. In addition to these stated measures, respondents also completed a choice-based conjoint session with 14 choice tasks, each involving four alternatives, which were used to estimate his or her preferences. A blocked design involving four sets of 14 such quads using the attributes and levels in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">3</ref> was created using SAS OPTEX. When performing these choice tasks, members were instructed to make choice decisions based on their own preferences.</p><p>Following individual preference measurement, the first spouse then provided detailed data on measures such as personality traits and demographics.  Upon completion, we contacted the second spouse via e-mail and asked him or her to provide the exact same information-including the identical choice task-as the first spouse.</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">                                                           Individual</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Joint Preference Measurement (Flat-Panel</head><p>TV Only) After the second spouse finished the individual preference measurement task, he or she was instructed to complete the next section of the study jointly with the first spouse. If the first spouse was unavailable, the second spouse was asked to save the survey link and click it when they were both ready. First, the dyad was asked to drag and drop a series of TV attribute levels into one of three categories: must have this feature, it depends, or can't have this feature. Next, dyads completed a choice-based conjoint session with 14 choice tasks, each involving four alternatives, which were used in estimating the dyad's preferences. The 14 choice tasks were different from the set the spouses had individually completed. When performing these tasks, dyads were instructed to make choice decisions jointly. Specifically, they were told, Please feel free to discuss your likes and dislikes with each other. There is no right or wrong answer. We are simply interested in knowing which flat-panel TV the two of you would select together.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.">Joint Shopping Task (Flat-Panel TV Only)</head><p>In this section the dyads were asked to visualize shopping together for a flat-panel TV at a number of different online retailers. Their task was to select one flat-panel TV that the dyad would be most interested in buying. They were given the option to click on links to one of six highly rated retailer websites (Abt, Onecall, J&amp;R, TigerDirect, Crutchfield, or Vann's) and view an assortment of flat-panel televisions. Each retailer in our study carried six flat-panel TV models, so, in total, the dyads had 36 options from which to choose. Dyads could visit the retailers in our study as many times as they wanted. The dyadic part of the survey ended after a TV selection was made by the dyad. The first spouse was thanked at this stage,   and the survey continued with the second spouse to obtain the final set of measures.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5.">Post-Joint Choice Measures</head><p>The second spouse was asked about the extent of disagreement and the resolution process in the joint choice task. As a separate follow-up, the first spouse was asked the exact same questions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Results</head><p>A total of 265 dyads finished the study. The respondents were mostly white (83%), represented all regions of the United States (Northeast = 22%, Midwest = 32%, South = 34%, and West = 12% and came from a wide spectrum of household incomes (&lt;$35 000 = 14%, and &gt;$100 000 = 15%) and family sizes (≤1 child = 18%, and ≥4 children = 22%). By design, all 265 dyads provided data on the flatpanel television category-these dyads qualified for the study based on a purchase likelihood question. A subset of these dyads also provided data for either the laptop (n = 103, 39%) or the digital camera (n = 96, 36%) because these dyads indicated that they were likely to buy in that category as well. We begin by looking at results based on stated can't-have, itdepends, and must-have measures as outlined in §3.1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Inference Based on Stated Measures</head><p>(Laptop Computer and Digital Camera) Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">4</ref> reports the proportion of respondents that fall into one of the three stated can't-have, it-depends, and must-have attribute classification categories. The can't-have category indicates the attribute level would be screened out, whereas the must-have designation suggests that all attribute levels except this one would be screened out. To simplify exposition we discuss screening for three classes of attributes: brands, features, and price. Using the stated measures, we find that a sizable proportion of husbands would exclude either the Apple (33%) or the Gateway (29%) brands from consideration. On the opposite end of the spectrum, a small proportion of husbands (8%) would consider only the Apple brand. Screening based on product features is also prevalent-44.7% of husbands would exclude laptops without an Intel processor, and 33% would consider only quad-core laptops. We also see evidence of price screening in the market: 41.7% would exclude all laptops that exceed the $799 price point. In comparing the digital camera data in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">4</ref> with the laptop computer data, there is far less brand screening, higher levels of features-based screening, and a similar type of price break point.</p><p>Looking at the wife-stated data across both product categories, we find that husbands and wives have a similar aggregate pattern of brand, feature, and price screening, but the action at the dyad level might be different. Using the stated attribute screening data from the two product categories and the DDP descriptions outlined in §2, we next classify dyads into CC, SC, and discordant groups for the brand, feature, and price attribute classes. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> We examine the prevalence of the DDPs derived using these stated measures and link their existence to dyad characteristics, as is illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>.</p><p>Across product categories and attribute classes, we find that each of the three DDP groups has a sizable presence in our data. Recall that the DPP grouping is conditional on both category and attribute class; thus the six sets of DDP group proportions reported in Figure 1 each sum to 1. Looking at these numbers, the Consistent with existing research that suggests expertise is linked to the use of choice heuristics <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bettman and</ref><ref type="bibr">Park 1980, Johnson and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Russo 1984)</ref>, Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> shows that in both the laptop and digital camera categories, feature-and brand-based screening concordant dyads (i.e., the husband and wife both use screens) have higher product knowledge (p &lt; 0 05) when compared with feature-and brand-based compensatory concordant dyads (i.e., the husband and wife both say it depends). This result suggests that more knowledgeable dyads are more likely to have smaller consideration sets because both parties agree to rule out specific brands or features. The opposite relationship between knowledge and screening emerges when looking at the price attribute in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>-price-based screening concordant dyads have considerably lower product knowledge (p &lt; 0 05) when compared with other groups. This means that the least knowledgeable dyads are most likely to form consideration sets on the basis of a price threshold.</p><p>Closely related measures of product knowledge such as experience, ownership, and advanced decision stage mimic these findings; thus we observe a general pattern of results over two product categories and multiple measures: more knowledgeable dyads tend to screen on brands and features, whereas less knowledgeable dyads screen on price.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Model-Based Inference (Flat-Panel TV)</head><p>In the preceding section, we used easily collected stated measures to identify compensatory concordant, screening concordant, and discordant groups for brand, feature, and price attribute classes. We show that dyad characteristics such as knowledge are drivers of screening behavior. In this section we report our findings from model-based inference on the conjoint choice data for the flat-panel television category as described in §3.2. These data complement our earlier findings in two ways. First, because we obtained joint choice data for the TV category, we are able to empirically investigate expand and restrict DDPs not studied earlier. Second, because stated measures may exhibit an upward bias in reported screening, we now rely on model-based inference. We also test a model that treats the stated screening data as prior information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.1.">Model Comparison.</head><p>Four different models were fit to these data. In addition to Models 1 and 2 proposed in §2, we also fit a dyadic compensatory model (Arora and Allenby 1999) that does not account for screening (Model 0). An alternative model specification that uses dyadic likelihood aggregation rather than a dyadic utility aggregation (Model 3) was also fit. In Model 3 the basic idea is that across a series of choices, the dyad chooses what the husband likes some times and what the wife likes other times. That is, the probability of alternative k being chosen by a dyad d is a mixture of the husband h and the wife w choice probabilities. That is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">Pr d y k = 1 h w h w = d • Pr h y k = 1 h h + 1 − d • Pr y k = 1 w w (<label>14</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_21">)</formula><p>where d is the probability that the dyad's choice is consistent with the husband's preference, and (1 − d ) is the probability that the dyad's choice is consistent with the wife's preference.  Model fit statistics are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_11">5</ref>. These include deviance information criterion (DIC; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Spiegelhalter et al. 2002)</ref>, log marginal density (LMD; see Newton and Raftery 1994), hit rates, and mean absolute deviation (MAD). We begin with our findings reported in the top part of the table. For each model, for the full data set of 265 dyads we computed in-sample and out-of-sample fit statistics for each dyad. In-sample fit was based on 12 out of the total 14 choices, and the remaining 2 choices were used to obtain out-of-sample fit.</p><p>First, compared with Models 1 and 2, Model 3, which obtains dyadic choice probabilities via likelihood aggregation, does not perform well. This result is consistent with <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Arora and Allenby (1999)</ref> and suggests that the utility aggregation structure in Models 1 and 2 more flexibly accommodates polarization and attribute-specific compromise than does Model 3. Second, we find that noncompensatory consider-thenchoose Models 1 and 2 outperform a compensatory Model 0. Finally, between the two consider-thenchoose models, Model 2 (with stated data as priors) fits the data better than Model 1, thus highlighting the value of incorporating prior information in parameter estimation.</p><p>To assess the predictive power of the models, we also split the data into a calibration sample of 200 dyads and a holdout sample of 65 dyads. In the bottom part of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_11">5</ref>, we report the fit statistics for the 200-dyad calibration sample and then use the hyperparameters from the calibration sample and the stated measures from the 65 holdout dyads to predict the choices for the holdout dyads. Hit rate and MAD statistics for this holdout sample demonstrate that accounting for screening improves the predictive power of the model and that leveraging stated data significantly enhances the model's ability to predict dyadic choices.</p><p>We note that although there is substantial improvement in the likelihood-based measures (e.g., DIC and LMD) when comparing Model 2 with Model 0, the improvement in hit rates is smaller. This happens because a noncompensatory model yields sharper choice probabilities by eliminating unacceptable alternatives, thus resulting in better LMD and DIC measures than a compensatory model if indeed there is screening in the decision process. At the same time, a compensatory model is sufficiently flexible to approximate a noncompensatory process by allowing coefficients to get very large or very small to capture for extreme preferences. A compensatory model therefore performs fairly well in identifying the most preferred alternative and has comparable hit rates as a noncompensatory model. This pattern of significant improvement in likelihood-based measures but less dramatic improvement in hit rates is consistent with results from prior research <ref type="bibr">Allenby 2004, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Jedidi and Kohli 2005)</ref> that compare compensatory and noncompensatory models. It is, however, critical to recognize that beyond superior model fit, the bigger difference between the dyadic compensatory and noncompensatory models is that the latter allows us to uncover the DDP framework-the primary focus of this paper. A compensatory model fails to capture the richness of the DDP-based behavioral insights and their subsequent impact on managerial decisions.  0 000 (0.000) 0 004 (0.000) 0 000 (0.000)</p><p>Notes. Cells contain the posterior mean and standard deviation (in parentheses) of the hyperparameter. When the posterior mean is in bold, the 95% highest posterior density for that hyperparameter does not include 0 for preference and screening (¯ and¯ or does not include 0.5 for influence (¯ .</p><p>Section 4.4 shows that a careful recognition of these DDPs has substantive implications for pricing and product design decisions that a compensatory model fails to capture.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2.">Insights from Model Parameter Estimates.</head><p>The aggregate-level or hyperparameter estimates from Model 2 (reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_12">6</ref>) indicate that features and price play a more important role than brands in husbands' and wives' choices. In particular, attribute sensitivity (¯ ) is high for price, screen size, and resolution, but it is quite low for brand. Overall, wives (¯ wife ) show the same preference pattern as husbands, although wives appear to be slightly more sensitive to price and less sensitive to high-end product features. In interpreting the influence parameter (¯ ), recall that¯ = 0 5 suggests equal influence between husband and wife. For some features (e.g., 720p resolution) we find that husbands have a higher influence (¯ &gt; 0 5, probability &gt; 0 95) than wives. Wives, in contrast, have a higher aggregate influence (¯ &lt; 0 5, probability &gt; 0 95) than husbands on price.</p><p>Because this paper's emphasis is on the consideration aspect of the consider-then-choose model, we focus our attention on the screening parameter estimates for husbands, wives, and dyads. The aggregate results show that Vizio is a brand that would be excluded from a sizable proportion of husband (14.5%), wife (12.6%), and dyad (12.2%) consideration sets. Similar to the results from laptop computers and digital cameras, we also see evidence of price thresholds-a large proportion of dyads (41.3%) exclude alternatives offered at the highest ($1,599) price point. On average, the husbands screen out high-price televisions less than the wives, a pattern that is consistent with the price sensitivity (¯ ) differences between the two groups.</p><p>Although the overall proportion of attribute-level screening recovered by the model is modest, comparing these estimates with the stated can't-have data reveals that the latter are significantly exaggerated. For example, over half the dyads (52.5%) stated they would not consider alternatives with 720p resolution, yet when making choices in a trade-off environment, the model shows that 11.7% of dyads actually exclude 720p resolution alternatives from consideration. The stated and recovered consideration proportions displayed in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> illustrate that the problem of stated data screening exaggeration (upward bias) exists across most attributes in the study. Although stated measures may not be an accurate reflection of consideration alone, the comparison between Models 1 and 2 in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> shows the value of incorporating these stated measures as priors in a model. Incorporating stated data as priors in the dyadic consider-then-choose model therefore offers a reasonable in-between approach.</p><p>Next, we link the model-based screening parameters with the proposed DDP framework to empirically investigate their effect on decision quality and efficiency for buyers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">DDP Incidence and Implications for Buyers</head><p>We construct the DDPs as outlined in §2.3 for each of the three attribute classes using the dyad-level, model-based screening parameters from Model 2. The posterior incidence of these DDPs, as well as their relationship to stated and model-based measures, is reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_14">7</ref>. As reported in the first column of this table, the most prevalent DDP across the brand (69.3%), feature (57.1%), and price (44.7%) attribute classes is the compensatory concordant DDP. Screening concordant, expand, and restrict DDPs are also well represented in the data. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> For example, the  expand (25%) and screening concordant DDP groups (19.8%) for price are sizable. Next, we focus on two comparisons with decision quality implications for buyers: (i) When concordant, do compensatory concordant dyads make better decisions than screening concordant dyads? And (ii) when discordant, does an expand or restrict strategy result in better decisions? We also contrast decision efficiency of alternative DDPs.  <ref type="table" target="#tab_14">7</ref> also shows that across all three attribute classes, screening concordant dyads, with their smaller consideration sets, make quicker choice decisions than compensatory concordant dyads (probability &gt; 0 95). This decision speed result is differentially linked to dyad characteristics such as product experience. Dyads defined as screening concordant on the basis of the brand and feature attributes are more experienced than their counterpart compensatory concordant dyads (probability &gt; 0 95). The opposite is true of dyads defined as screening concordant for price-they have less experience than compensatory concordant dyads (probability &gt; 0 95). The consistent pattern is that less informed dyads tend to take decision-making shortcuts based on price. Regardless of the motivation for having smaller consideration sets, we find that screening concordant dyads make less choice concession, have lower choice inefficiency, and experience higher dyadic preference intensity. We therefore conclude that screening concordant dyads make quicker as well as better dyadic decisions when compared with compensatory concordant dyads.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2.">Restrict</head><p>Is Better Than Expand. The second DDP contrast of interest applies to discordant dyads: expand versus restrict. We have learned that dyads with smaller consideration sets have less information to process in making a decision. As such, in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_14">7</ref> we find that the restrict dyads (smaller consideration set) make quicker choice decisions compared with expand dyads (larger consideration set). To illustrate, discordant dyads on brand who restrict their consideration set complete the joint choice task over a minute earlier (3.720 minutes) than other brand discordant dyads who expand their consideration set (4.918 minutes, probability &gt; 0 95). The restrict DDP is related to product expertise-brand restrict dyads have more product experience (3.088) than brand expand dyads (2.774, probability &gt; 0 95). In addition, the restrict dyads exhibit lower concession, lower choice inefficiency, and higher dyadic preference intensity. We therefore conclude that restrict dyads make quicker as well as better dyadic decisions than expand dyads. 4.3.3. Mixed DDP Benefits from Smaller Consideration Sets. The key distinction between expand and restrict is the dyad's retention or abandonment of a particular dyad member's smaller consideration set. The mixed strategy has both expand and restrict DDP characteristics. To assess how well a mixed strategy works, we aggregate across the attributes in all three classes to form a single DDP classification that has a large enough proportion of the mixed DDP group (6%). Choice concession for the mixed DDP (0.497) is similar to the expand DDP (0.491) and different from the restrict DDP (0.384, probability &gt; 0 95). In contrast, inefficiency and preference intensity for the mixed DDP (0.034 and 0.886) are similar to the restrict DDP (0.037 and 0.877) and different from the expand DDP (0.063, probability &gt; 0 95; and 0.795, probability &gt; 0 95). These results suggest that the mixed DDP strategy also benefits from narrowing of alternatives.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.4.">Screening Concordant Dyads Have Lower</head><p>Regret. Overall, the pattern of results suggests that dyads with smaller consideration sets end up with better decisions. The data from the joint shopping task (see §3.4) provide the opportunity to assess the usefulness of the screening decision strategy in a context outside of the conjoint choice task. The results from that shopping task indicate that smaller consideration sets do lead to better dyadic decisions. Compared with compensatory concordant dyads, screening concordant dyads take fewer shopping task trips (4.330 versus 3.463, probability &gt; 0 95), exhibit higher shopping task dyadic preference intensity (0.534 versus 0.740, probability &gt; 0 95), perceive they compromised less (0.459 versus 0.255, probability &gt; 0 95), and indicate lower postshopping task regret 5 (0.340 versus −0 150, probability &gt; 0 95). The finding that fewer options leads to lower regret links nicely with existing overchoice research (e.g., Schwartz 2004).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.">Substantive Implications of a Dyadic</head><p>Consider-Then-Choose Model So far we have tested the dyadic noncompensatory choice model, and we empirically investigated the prevalence of alternative dyadic decision processes and their impact on decision efficiency and quality. Next, we investigate the substantive implications of the dyadic noncompensatory model on managerial decisions involving product design and pricing. We begin with the observation that unaccounted-for price thresholds in a compensatory model bias the aggregate price sensitivity estimates upward. That is, aggregate price coefficients in a compensatory model tend to be more negative to capture exclusion of high-price alternatives (e.g.,¯ price husband M2 = −4 190 versus¯ price husband M0 = −4 454). A similar argument also applies to nonprice attributes as preference estimates in a compensatory model attempt to account for attribute screening. Next, we illustrate substantive implications of such systematic differences in parameter estimates of dyadic noncompensatory and compensatory models. We conduct an optimal product profile and pricing exercise for flat-panel televisions and compare the managerial guidance from our dyadic consider-then-choose model relative to a compensatory model. The results show that the models yield starkly different substantive results.</p><p>We conduct a stylized market simulation at the dyad level starting with a baseline scenario with three alternatives as shown in  decision maker, under both the compensatory model (Model 0) and the dyadic consider-then-choose model (Model 2), we obtain the posterior distribution of choice probabilities and functions of the parameters such as market share and willingness to pay. The three alternatives in the baseline scenario each claim a roughly equal proportion of the simulated market.</p><p>Owing to preference structure disparities as previously shown in §4.2, there are differences between husbands and wives as to which product is most preferred-the husbands prefer a larger, more expensive TV relative to the wives. There are large discrepancies in market share predictions when using model parameters of either husbands or wives, strongly supporting the need for a dyadic choice model. The husband-wife differences are manifest for both compensatory and consider-then-choose models. Next, we contrast the findings from the two models by focusing on results corresponding to the dyad choices.</p><p>4.4.1. Because of Screening, the Market Is Not Cleared. One thing we learn from the considerthen-choose model that the standard compensatory model cannot tell us is that given the baseline set of offerings, the market does not clear. That is, husbands/wives/dyads who exclude all three alternatives from consideration exist. This is shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_15">8</ref> as the "No-buy" proportion. This means some dyads would not buy any of the three options because the alternatives do not fall in their consideration set. In this particular situation, there is a small proportion of dyads who must have a large 52" television and, as such, would not choose any of the existing offerings. Because the compensatory model does not account for the consideration stage of the decision, it would ascribe choice to the most attractive of the three smaller screen size alternatives rather than ruling them all out, thus overstating its demand.</p><p>Motivated by this unmet market need for large TVs that the consideration model uncovers, we construct a scenario that includes a fourth option with a 52" screen. To find this fourth option, we search the design space for the optimal combination of binary product attributes to accompany a 52" Samsung brand TV. To determine the optimal price for the new product, we search between $799 and $1,799 in $50 increments for the price level that maximizes new product revenue. This new product profile and the corresponding scenario of market shares are shown in the bottom panel of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_15">8</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.2.">The New Product Optimal Prices and</head><p>Demand Forecasts Are Different. The two models make very different predictions regarding the optimal price and market demand for the proposed new product. Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref> illustrates these differences by showing the posterior mean of simulated market share and revenue at each of the price points in the search space under the dyadic compensatory model (Model 0) and the consider-then-choose model (Model 2). The optimal price point for the new profile as determined under each model is denoted by an enlarged plotting symbol. These optima are not the same. The compensatory model predicts an optimal price of $949 (just higher than the existing products in the market), whereas the consider-then-choose model suggests an optimal profile price of $1,249-a price $300 higher. If a manager set prices according to the compensatory model optimum ($949) and ignored the additional information the consider-then-choose model provides, market share for the new product would be higher, but revenue would be 3.5% lower than if the new product were priced at the optimum ($1,249) indicated by the consideration-based model. Furthermore, even at the same price point (i.e., $1,249), the compensatory model underestimates demand relative to the forecast obtained from the consider-then-choose model. The higher aggregate price sensitivity of a compensatory model explains this pattern of results in our illustration. In general, we see that the ability of a noncompensatory model to pick up this behavioral richness has direct substantive implications that should not be ignored. Attribute-specific willingness to pay ( attribute / price ; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Meijer and Rouwendal 2006)</ref>, an interrelated dimension of product design and pricing, is also affected by the presence of screening. Once again, because price for the two models differs, so does the willingness-to-pay (WTP) measure. As an illustration, we examined each dyad's willingness to pay to move from a 32" screen size to a 52" screen size. For a dyadic compensatory model, the WTP 52" is $424 compared to $372 for a noncompensatory model. It is important to recognize that the latter WTP is an average for both screeners and nonscreeners in the sample. To dig a bit deeper, we find that WTP 52" for dyads who would screen high-priced alternatives is significantly lower (WTP 52" = $181) compared with dyads who would not screen high-priced alternatives (WTP 52" = $440, probability &gt; 0 95). Not surprisingly, the screening-WTP relationship works in the opposite direction when consideration is attribute based. For example, WTP for a 52" screen size is much higher among dyads who exclude a 32" screen size from consideration (WTP 52" = $556) compared with those who would not (WTP 52" = $315, probability &gt; 0 95). The lesson from this simple WTP illustration is an important one. Pricing decisions that ignore dyadic screens fail to accurately characterize how WTP varies in the marketplace. As shown earlier in this section, this can result in setting a suboptimal price and predicting a demand schedule that is inaccurate. As such, a meaningful advantage of a consider-then-choose model is its ability to capture discontinuities in the demand schedule that naturally arise because of price screening thresholds.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Model Extensions</head><p>This paper demonstrates that noncompensatory dyadic decision processes are conceptually rich and substantively important. Before we conclude, we outline some model extensions that suggest the logical next steps. In particular, we focus on two aspects for model extension: how the cost of thinking may factor into screening and the strategic use of consideration sets. The former attempts to explain differential dyadic screening in the marketplace because of thinking costs dyads are willing to incur, and the latter assumes that a member's screening behavior may be influenced by the others' in a systematic way. A key distinction between a dyadic application of an attribute screening consider-then-choose model and a cost-of-thinking approach is the implied mechanism for the dyadic decision process. A cost-of-thinking model would specify how the husband-and-wife cognitive cost parameters get aggregated rather than how the attribute-level screens and consideration sets are integrated. Furthermore, although our data collection Marketing Science 30(6), pp. 1028-1047, © 2011 INFORMS procedure ruled out the possibility of strategic consideration by explicitly directing individuals to choose for themselves at the individual stage, the issue of strategic consideration is an aspect of joint choice decision making that merits further investigation. We next outline a model that can be used to capture such strategic consideration building on a cost-of-thinking model. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> For a given person, an attribute level m is screened out ( m = 1) if the expected gain G m from including the attribute level is less than the cost-of-thinking <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Gilbride and Allenby 2006)</ref>. Let the subscripts h, w, and d represent husband, wife, and dyad, respectively. Then hm = 1 if G hm &lt; h , wm = 1 if G wm &lt; w , and dm = 1 if G dm &lt; d . To capture a husband's strategic consideration based on the knowledge of the other spouse's screening behavior, the expected gain for the husband is</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">G hm = E x E h max X h + hm I wm =1 + h − max X −m h + h (15)</formula><p>where X −m denotes the matrix that captures the choice alternatives without the attribute level m, hm captures the influence of the wife's decision on the husband's, and I • is an indicator function. If hm is positive, then the attribute level is more likely to be included for consideration by the husband based on the knowledge that it is excluded for consideration by the wife. On the other hand, if hm is negative, then the attribute is more likely to be excluded. A similar argument applies for the wife's gain function (G wm . The expected gain for the dyad is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">G dm = E x E d max X d + d −max X −m d + d (16)</formula><p>where the dyad's joint preference dm on attribute level m is linked to the individual preferences through the influence parameter hm as</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">dm = hm hm + hm I wm =1 + 1 − hm • wm + wm I hm =1 (17)</formula><p>Next, let G hm0 be the husband's expected gain from including attribute level m knowing that the wife is including it for consideration ( wm = 0), and let G hm1 be the expected gain knowing that the wife is screening it out ( wm = 1). Similarly, the wife's expected gains are G wm0 and G wm1 . The dyad's expected gains are G dm00 , G dm01 , G dm10 , and G dm11 , corresponding respectively to the individual members' screening behavior (0, 0), (0, 1), (1, 0), and (1, 1). There are a total <ref type="bibr">6</ref> We thank the associate editor for this suggestion. of eight possible solutions for the screening indicators ( hm wm dm ), and the equilibrium conditions are 0 0 0 if G hm0 &gt; h G wm0 &gt; w and G dm00 &gt; d 0 0 1 if G hm0 &gt; h G wm0 &gt; w and G dm00 &lt; d</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">0 1 0 if G hm1 &gt; h G wm0 &lt; w and G dm01 &gt; d 0 1 1 if G hm1 &gt; h G wm0 &lt; w and G dm01 &lt; d 1 0 0 if G hm0 &lt; h G wm1 &gt; w and G dm10 &gt; d 1 0 1 if G hm0 &lt; h G wm1 &gt; w and G dm10 &lt; d 1 1 0 if G hm1 &lt; h G wm1 &lt; w and G dm11 &gt; d 1 1 1 if G hm1 &lt; h G wm1 &lt; w and G dm11 &lt; d</formula><p>To address the problem of multiple equilibria that may exist in certain conditions (e.g., Hartmann 2010), we select the equilibrium that gives maximum total gain-that is, the one that maximizes G hm +G wm +G dm .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Discussion</head><p>Anecdotal evidence for choice decisions made by families (e.g., buying a house) and organizations (e.g., hiring decisions) suggests that groups often exclude alternatives from consideration based on a wide variety of factors. This paper fills a void in the literature by capturing the intersection of member-level consideration sets in a dyadic consider-then-choose model. The DDP framework we introduce facilitates the investigation of both the compensatory and noncompensatory dimensions of a joint choice decision. We investigate alternative ways in which consideration set differences between members are reconciled and the subsequent implications for decision efficiency and quality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.">What We Find</head><p>Across a variety of attribute classes (e.g., brands, features, and price), we find that there are sizable proportions of dyads who adopt a concordant (compensatory or noncompensatory) or a discordant (expand, restrict, or mixed) decision process. With regard to the consideration stage of the decision process, more knowledgeable dyads tend to screen on brands and features, whereas less knowledgeable dyads screen on price. We find that the stated measures of screening behavior are biased upward but serve an excellent role as prior information in a statistical model of dyadic choice. Model-based inference in our empirical investigation shows that compared with compensatory dyads, dyads with smaller consideration sets make quicker and better decisions. Specifically, when comparing compensatory concordant dyads to screening concordant dyads and expand dyads to restrict dyads, those that use screening not only make quicker decisions but are also better off.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.">Implications for Buyers</head><p>One message to a dyad or group making collective choice decisions is that knowledge is the critical first step of joint choice. Greater knowledge likely results in the exclusion of alternatives, thus setting the stage for quicker, better decisions. At the level of a dyad, agreeing on what to exclude from consideration helps make better decisions. If the members do not a priori agree on which alternatives to exclude, our empirical evidence suggests that consideration set restriction is a significantly better decision process than set expansion. Although the concept of dyadic fairness might prima facie implicate an expand strategy, restricting the consideration set by leveraging one group member's screening thresholds leads to improved welfare and decision efficiency.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3.">Implications for Sellers</head><p>Our findings speak to at least two marketing constituencies: sales and product design. Product returns attributable to buyer's remorse represent a significant cost to retailers and manufacturers ($3.7 billion for consumer electronics; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Lawton 2008)</ref>, but a seller's efforts to maximize buyer welfare can be challenging in a dyadic decision context. Our research suggests that there are some dyadic decision processesscreening when concordant or restrict when discordantthat help make quicker and better decisions. When carefully used in the selling process, these strategies can become an effective tool to maximize a dyad's overall happiness with the decision. Because we find that less knowledgeable dyads screen more on price, a price-restricted consideration set may signal an opportunity for a Best Buy salesperson, for example, to educate the dyad about the product and, in so doing, maximize dyadic welfare.</p><p>We find that preference differences between decision makers and careful recognition of dyadic screening behavior can substantially affect product design and pricing decisions. Product decisions that ignore attribute-level consideration will likely underestimate demand for a new functionally superior product and could possibly underprice the new offering, particularly if price-based screening thresholds are prevalent. Results from the optimal product profile and pricing exercise demonstrate that there might be a real cost to ignoring screening. In sum, our framework to capture the dyadic consideration dimension of the choice process yields insights that are conceptually novel and substantively relevant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4.">Directions for Future Research and</head><p>Limitations We conclude by noting some limitations of our data. First, although the decision to use only married couples is representative of a certain type of dyad in the marketplace, our data may underestimate the level of discord when compared to studies that use other types of dyads (e.g., organization buyers). Although collecting data from such dyads is time consuming and expensive, it would be instructive to expand this enquiry to business-to-business settings. As an example, although our sample size is large relative to other studies of group decision making, we were somewhat constrained by the sample size of some of the DDPs (i.e., mixed). Contexts that involve higher discord may help overcome this limitation. Second, although we find no systematic differences in responses from groups that completed one or two product categories, the overall length of our survey was long. This may have adversely affected data quality from the joint shopping task near the end of the survey, where dyads engaged in limited search and frequently bought from the first store they visited. This suggests that future research in this area should restrict data to fewer categories and limit the number of questions to the extent possible. Alternative methodologies that bypass the need to collect dyadic data (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Aribarg et al. 2010)</ref> should also be explored. Finally, the dyadic decision process framework we propose naturally extends to a group with greater than two members. For example, key conceptual ideas pertaining to concordant (noncompensatory or screening) and discordant (expand, restrict, or mixed) decision processes also apply to larger groups. Correspondingly, the model could be extended to a larger group by increasing the dimension of preference ( ), influence ( ), and screening ( ) parameters. Empirical testing of such a model, however, presents significant challenges because such data are not readily available. Future research should investigate such model extensions to larger groups. For a given dyad d, we follow <ref type="bibr">Allenby (2004, 2006)</ref> and use "Griddy Gibbs" to draw dm sequentially, given dm on all other attribute levels m . There are eight ( <ref type="formula">2</ref> where p dbm , b = 1 8 are the multinomial probabilities for the eight versions of the dm vector.</p><p>(3) Generate¯ from a multivariate Normal (MVN) distribution as</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">f ¯ d D ∝ n d=1 f d ¯ D × f ¯ ∝ exp n d=1 − 1 2 d −¯ D −1 d −¯ × exp − 1 2 ¯ − A −1 ¯ − ∼ MVN nD −1 + A −1 −1 n d=1 D −1 d +A −1 nD −1 + A −1 −1</formula><p>where the prior distribution of¯ is assumed to be multivariate Normal with mean and covariance matrix A. In our estimation, we use a diffuse prior, where = 0 and A = 100I.</p><p>(4) Generate D from an Inverted Wishart distribution as</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">f D d ¯ ∝ n d=1 f d ¯ D × f D ∝ D −n/2 exp n d=1 − 1 2 d −¯ D −1 d −¯ × D − v+q+1 /2 exp − 1 2 Trace D −1 V ∼ Inverted Wishart n + v n d=1 d −¯ d −¯ + V</formula><p>where q is the length of vector d . The prior distribution of D is assumed to be Inverted Wishart(v V ). In our estimation, we set v = q + 1, and V = identity matrix of size q.  <ref type="bibr">86, 41.67, 40, 37.5, 33.33, 25</ref> so that 1 = 80%, + = 50 and the expected standard deviation of p * dbm is equivalent across b (see p. 174 of Wong 1998 for more details).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2Comparison of Stated Screening with Model-Based Screening Estimates</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>3 ) possible realizations of the dm vector of 0s and 1s, which we denote by w b , b = 1 Pr dh k dh × Pr dw k dw × Pr d k d otherwise. "Contradiction" represents the scenario when the proposed w b contradicts observed choices, that is, when w b indicates that alternative k is screened out, but, in fact, it is chosen. Pr dh k dh Pr dw k dw and Pr d k d are obtained through Equations (2)-(4) by assuming dm = w b given all other dm s. Next, out of all eight possible w b s, select one w b * with probability</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>∼∼</head><label></label><figDesc>generalized Dirichlet m + m + and p 8m = 1 − p 1m − • • • − p 7m . For a given attribute level m, [p 1m p 7m ] is drawn from a generalized Dirichlet( m + m + ) distribution with a generalized Dirichlet( ) prior, where = 1 and = 7 6 5 4 3 2 1 and m = 1m 8m is a vector of counts where bm = n d=1 1 dm =w b is the count of the dyads that have used decision process strategy b for b = 1 8. (5b) Generate [p d1m p d7m ] for Model 2. Using the self-stated screening bin membership data, map p d1m p d8m to p * d1m p * d8m so that p * d1m = p dbm and p * dbm = p d1m if * dm = w b . Then, generalized Dirichlet * * such that * bm / * bm + * bm = b for b = 1 2 7, and p * d8m = 1 − p * d1m − • • • − p * d7m . We choose the values for * bm 40 7 14 8 33 10 12 5 16 67 25 and * bm 10 42.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Across-Attribute DDP Illustration DDP Compensatory concordance m I hm = wm = 0 ∧ m I hm = wm = 1 = 0 Screening parameters h1</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Study Flow</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Stage</cell><cell>First spouse</cell><cell>Second spouse</cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell>Screening questions</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Purchase likelihood of TV, laptop,</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>camera</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="5">Flat-Panel Television Choice-Based Conjoint Study Attributes</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">and Levels</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Brand</cell><cell>Sony</cell><cell>Panasonic</cell><cell>Vizio</cell><cell>Samsung</cell></row><row><cell>Screen size</cell><cell>32"</cell><cell>42"</cell><cell>52"</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Warranty</cell><cell>Standard</cell><cell>Extended</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Picture</cell><cell>LCD</cell><cell>Plasma</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>technology</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Resolution</cell><cell>720p</cell><cell>1080p</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Price ($)</cell><cell>699</cell><cell>999</cell><cell>1 299</cell><cell>1 599</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Laptop and Camera Stated Attribute Classification Proportions</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Husband-stated</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Wife-stated</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>attribute classification</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>attribute classification</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Proportion of sample</cell><cell>Can't</cell><cell>It</cell><cell>Must</cell><cell>Can't</cell><cell>It</cell><cell>Must</cell></row><row><cell>in each category by attribute</cell><cell>have</cell><cell>depends</cell><cell>have</cell><cell>have</cell><cell>depends</cell><cell>have</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Model Comparison</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Model 0</cell><cell>Model 1</cell><cell>Model 2</cell><cell>Model 3</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Dyadic consider-</cell><cell>Likelihood</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Dyadic</cell><cell>Dyadic consider-</cell><cell>then-choose with</cell><cell>aggregation with</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>compensatory</cell><cell>then-choose</cell><cell cols="2">stated data as priors stated data as priors</cell></row><row><cell>All dyads (n = 265)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>DIC</cell><cell>10 380 020</cell><cell>8 712 203</cell><cell>8 313 273</cell><cell>10 184 640</cell></row><row><cell>In-sample hit rate</cell><cell>0 883</cell><cell>0 886</cell><cell>0 899</cell><cell>0 883</cell></row><row><cell>In-sample MAD</cell><cell>0 199</cell><cell>0 184</cell><cell>0 167</cell><cell>0 201</cell></row><row><cell>LMD</cell><cell>−4 234 351</cell><cell>−3 740 127</cell><cell>−3 494 958</cell><cell>−4 157 582</cell></row><row><cell>Holdout choice sets' hit rate</cell><cell>0 789</cell><cell>0 781</cell><cell>0 789</cell><cell>0 789</cell></row><row><cell>Holdout choice sets' MAD</cell><cell>0 261</cell><cell>0 261</cell><cell>0 251</cell><cell>0 283</cell></row><row><cell>Sample dyads (n = 200)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>DIC</cell><cell>7 859 777</cell><cell>6 537 809</cell><cell>6 298 346</cell><cell>7 797 041</cell></row><row><cell>In-sample hit rate</cell><cell>0 883</cell><cell>0 893</cell><cell>0 904</cell><cell>0 883</cell></row><row><cell>In-sample MAD</cell><cell>0 195</cell><cell>0 177</cell><cell>0 168</cell><cell>0 205</cell></row><row><cell>LMD</cell><cell>−3 237 398</cell><cell>−2 802 254</cell><cell>−2 641 796</cell><cell>−3 192 334</cell></row><row><cell>Holdout choice sets' hit rate</cell><cell>0 790</cell><cell>0 780</cell><cell>0 808</cell><cell>0 795</cell></row><row><cell>Holdout choice sets' MAD</cell><cell>0 265</cell><cell>0 263</cell><cell>0 253</cell><cell>0 284</cell></row><row><cell>Holdout dyads (n = 65)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Hit rate</cell><cell>0 442</cell><cell>0 442</cell><cell>0 535</cell><cell>0 435</cell></row><row><cell>MAD</cell><cell>0 600</cell><cell>0 590</cell><cell>0 501</cell><cell>0 597</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12"><head>Table 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Noncompensatory Model (M2) Preference, Influence, and Screening Hyperparameters</figDesc><table><row><cell>husband¯ wife¯</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_14"><head>Table 7</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Incidence and Implications of Model-Based DDPs for Each Attribute Class</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Product</cell><cell>Joint task</cell><cell>Choice</cell><cell>Choice</cell><cell>Preference</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Proportion</cell><cell>experience</cell><cell>time (min)</cell><cell>concession</cell><cell>inefficiency</cell><cell>intensity</cell></row><row><cell>Brand</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Compensatory 0 693 (0.017)</cell><cell>3 012 (0.019)</cell><cell>5 547 (0.204)</cell><cell>0 375 (0.009)</cell><cell>0 049 (0.003)</cell><cell>0 837 (0.005)</cell></row><row><cell>concordant</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Screening</cell><cell>0 090 (0.007)</cell><cell>3 318 (0.082) a</cell><cell>4 280 (0.216) a</cell><cell>0 354 (0.031)</cell><cell>0 049 (0.009)</cell><cell>0 834 (0.017)</cell></row><row><cell>concordant</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Expand</cell><cell>0 130 (0.016)</cell><cell>2 774 (0.102)</cell><cell>4 918 (0.509)</cell><cell>575 (0.029)</cell><cell>0 070 (0.009)</cell><cell>0 781 (0.017)</cell></row><row><cell>Restrict</cell><cell>0 087 (0.008)</cell><cell>3 088 (0.090) b</cell><cell>3 720 (0.125) b</cell><cell>0 443 (0.029) b</cell><cell>0 041 (0.008) b</cell><cell>0 876 (0.015) b</cell></row><row><cell>Features</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Compensatory 0 571 (0.011)</cell><cell>2 949 (0.019)</cell><cell>5 555 (0.030)</cell><cell>0 421 (0.011)</cell><cell>0 058 (0.003)</cell><cell>0 814 (0.005)</cell></row><row><cell>concordant</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Screening</cell><cell>0 174 (0.006)</cell><cell>3 261 (0.030) a</cell><cell>4 628 (0.103) a</cell><cell>0 293 (0.016) a</cell><cell>0 041 (0.005) a</cell><cell>0 867 (0.008) a</cell></row><row><cell>concordant</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Expand</cell><cell>0 116 (0.010)</cell><cell>3 087 (0.094)</cell><cell>4 867 (0.211)</cell><cell>0 498 (0.025)</cell><cell>0 063 (0.008)</cell><cell>0 788 (0.014)</cell></row><row><cell>Restrict</cell><cell>0 140 (0.010)</cell><cell>2 925 (0.083)</cell><cell>4 691 (0.117)</cell><cell>0 401 (0.021) b</cell><cell>0 026 (0.005)</cell><cell>0 908 (0.010) b</cell></row><row><cell>Price</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Compensatory 0 447 (0.015)</cell><cell>3 237 (0.026)</cell><cell>5 378 (0.223)</cell><cell>0 390 (0.013)</cell><cell>0 053 (0.003)</cell><cell>0 822 (0.006)</cell></row><row><cell>concordant</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Screening</cell><cell>0 198 (0.015)</cell><cell>2 691 (0.068) a</cell><cell>4 617 (0.195) a</cell><cell>0 310 (0.022) a</cell><cell>0 041 (0.005)</cell><cell>0 868 (0.009) a</cell></row><row><cell>concordant</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Expand</cell><cell>0 250 (0.020)</cell><cell>2 960 (0.066)</cell><cell>5 475 (0.435)</cell><cell>0 498 (0.022)</cell><cell>0 056 (0.005)</cell><cell>0 820 (0.010)</cell></row><row><cell>Restrict</cell><cell>0 105 (0.015)</cell><cell>2 814 (0.127)</cell><cell>4 832 (0.388)</cell><cell>0 431 (0.035)</cell><cell>0 049 (0.009)</cell><cell>0 844 (0.017)</cell></row></table><note>Note. Cells contain posterior mean and standard deviation (in parentheses) of the measure by group. a Screening concordant significantly different (probability &gt; 0 95) from compensatory concordant. b Restrict significantly different (probability &gt; 0 95) from expand.4.3.1. Screening Concordance Is Better Than Compensatory Concordance. Table</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_15"><head>Table 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>For each</figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science 30(6), pp. 1028-1047, © 2011 INFORMS</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_16"><head>Table 8</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Simulated Product Profile Market Share in Two Scenarios</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Sony, 32", LCD, 1080p,</cell><cell cols="2">Panasonic, 42", plasma,</cell><cell>Vizio, 32", LCD, 1080p,</cell></row><row><cell>Baseline scenario</cell><cell></cell><cell>extended, $899</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">720p, standard, $899</cell><cell>standard, $699</cell><cell>No-buy</cell></row><row><cell>Market share</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Consider-then-choose</cell><cell>Husband</cell><cell>0.329</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 333</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 285</cell><cell>0 053 b</cell></row><row><cell>model (Model 2)</cell><cell>Wife</cell><cell>0.326</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0 283 a</cell><cell>0 340 a</cell><cell>0 051 b</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Dyad</cell><cell>0.275</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 334</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 322</cell><cell>0 069 b</cell></row><row><cell>Compensatory</cell><cell>Husband</cell><cell>0.340</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 350</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 310</cell><cell>0 000</cell></row><row><cell>model (Model 0)</cell><cell>Wife</cell><cell>0.333</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0 298 a</cell><cell>0 368 a</cell><cell>0 000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Dyad</cell><cell>0.317</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 330</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 353</cell><cell>0 000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Sony, 32",</cell><cell cols="2">Panasonic, 42",</cell><cell>Vizio, 32",</cell><cell>Samsung, 52",</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>LCD, 1080p,</cell><cell></cell><cell>plasma, 720p,</cell><cell>LCD, 1080p,</cell><cell>LCD, 1080p,</cell></row><row><cell>Introduce 52" profile</cell><cell></cell><cell>extended, $899</cell><cell cols="2">standard, $899</cell><cell>standard, $699</cell><cell>extended, $1,249</cell><cell>No-buy</cell></row><row><cell>Market share</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Consider-then-choose</cell><cell>Husband</cell><cell>0.137</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 201</cell><cell>0 206</cell><cell>0 457 b</cell><cell>0 000</cell></row><row><cell>model (Model 2)</cell><cell>Wife</cell><cell>0.172</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 151 a</cell><cell>0 267 a</cell><cell>0 410 a b</cell><cell>0 000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Dyad</cell><cell>0.113</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 191</cell><cell>0 242</cell><cell>0 454 b</cell><cell>0 000</cell></row><row><cell>Compensatory</cell><cell>Husband</cell><cell>0.150</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 229</cell><cell>0 235</cell><cell>0 386</cell><cell>0 000</cell></row><row><cell>Model (Model 0)</cell><cell>Wife</cell><cell>0.170</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 181 a</cell><cell>0 296 a</cell><cell>0 353</cell><cell>0 000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Dyad</cell><cell>0.136</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 203</cell><cell>0 268</cell><cell>0 392</cell><cell>0 000</cell></row><row><cell cols="6">a Difference between husband and wife does not include 0 over 90% highest probability density.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="6">b Difference between Model 0 and Model 2 does not include 0 over 90% highest probability density.</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_17"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3New Profile Market Share and Revenue at Various Prices Under Two Different Models</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>65</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>60</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>150,000</cell></row><row><cell>New profile market share (%)</cell><cell>35 40 45 50 55</cell><cell cols="3">Consider-then-choose model Compensatory model</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>120,000 130,000 140,000</cell><cell>($)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>30</cell><cell cols="2">Revenue (M2) Revenue (M0)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>25</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>110,000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>799</cell><cell>899</cell><cell>999</cell><cell>1,099</cell><cell>1,199</cell><cell>1,299</cell><cell>1,399</cell><cell>1,499</cell><cell>1,599</cell><cell>1,699</cell><cell>1,799</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>($)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_18"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Marketing Science 30(6), pp. 1028-1047, © 2011 INFORMS where Pr dh k dh Pr dw k dw and Pr d k d are obtained through Equations (2)-(4). A random-walk Metropolis-Hastings step is used to generate d separately for each dyad d. Let * d = d + s × N 0 I represent the proposed candidate new draw, and let d represent the current draw. Let LP( d ) denote the last expression in (18). Accept * d with probability = min LP * d /LP d 1 . (2) Generate d = dh dw d</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">This is in comparison to the standard Dirichlet distribution, which restricts the covariances of the multinomial probabilities to be negative. We thank the associate editor for raising this issue.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">An alternative approach to incorporate stated screening data would be to use them as a covariate for the hyperparameter vector in Equation (8). Fit statistics from this alternative model (available from the authors upon request) were inferior to the proposed Model 2 and are therefore excluded.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Because we do not collect stated screening measures from dyads for the laptop computer and digital camera categories, we cannot distinguish expand from restrict within the discordant group using these data. Data from the flat-panel TV category do not have this limitation.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Arora, Henderson, and  Liu: Noncompensatory Dyadic Choices Marketing Science 30(6), pp. 1028-1047, © 2011 INFORMS</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">Within an attribute class, the incidence of mixed DDP is too small to draw meaningful comparisons. Therefore we do not include it in this section. Across attributes, the mixed DDP bin is larger and is included in subsequent analyses.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">Regret was measured using individual postshopping task responses to statements such as "I regret our decision" and "I think we made a mistake" and was then aggregated to the dyad level as a dyadic regret factor score. Perceived compromise is also a stated measure of the shopping task decision process, where 0 indicates that both dyad members felt that "no compromise was needed."</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank Paul Metz and Jane Burch of C&amp;R Research, Chicago, for their generous support of this research. This research was supported in part by the McCombs Research Excellence Fund.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix. Estimation Algorithm</head><p>The following Markov chain Monte Carlo algorithm was used to obtain the posterior estimates of the model parameters.</p><p>(1) Generate d = dh dw d . For a given dyad d, let vector c d = k dh k dw k d denote the vector of the husband's, wife's, and the dyad's chosen alternatives; that is, y k dh = 1 y k dw = 1, and</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dimensions of consumer expertise</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Alba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Hutchinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="411" to="454" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of fairness in negotiation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Albin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Negotiation J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="244" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the role of preference revision and concession in group decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Aribarg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Bodur</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="336" to="349" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting joint choice using individual data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Aribarg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="157" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring the influence of individual preference structures in group decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="476" to="487" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An Information Processing Theory of Consumer Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bettman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Reading, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of prior knowledge and experience and phase of the choice process on consumer decision processes: A protocol analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bettman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="234" to="248" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When more is less and less is more: The role of ideal point availability and assortment in consumer choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Chernev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="170" to="183" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Models of cooperative group decision-making and relative influence: An experimental investigation of family purchase decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Corfman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The importance of others&apos; welfare in evaluating bargaining outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Corfman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124" to="137" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiattribute dyadic choice: Models and tests</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Curry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Menasco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Van Ark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="267" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dimensions of marital roles in consumer decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="168" to="177" />
			<date type="published" when="1970" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Equity, equality, and need: What determines which value will be used as the basis of distributive justice?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Deutsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Soc. Issues</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="149" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consumer preference for a no-choice option</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="231" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new integrated model of noncompensatory and compensatory decision strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Elrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organ. Behav. Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="19" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A choice model with conjunctive, disjunctive, and compensatory screening rules</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gilbride</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="391" to="406" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating heterogeneous EBA and economic screening rule choice models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gilbride</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="494" to="509" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overchoice and assortment type: When and why variety backfires</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Gourville</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Soman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="382" to="395" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing products and services for consumer welfare: Theoretical and empirical issues</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kohli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="230" to="246" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cardinal welfare, individualistic ethics, and interpersonal comparison of utility</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Harsanyi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="321" />
			<date type="published" when="1955" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Demand estimation with social interactions and the implications for targeted marketing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hartmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="601" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Observed and unobserved preference heterogeneity in brand-choice models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Horsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Misra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="322" to="335" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A generalized utility model of disappointment and regret effects on post-choice valuation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Inman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="111" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When choice is demotivating: Can one desire too much of a good thing?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Iyengar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lepper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Personality Soc. Psych</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="995" to="1006" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probabilistic subset-conjunctive models for heterogeneous consumers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Jedidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kohli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="483" to="494" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Product familiarity and learning new information</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Russo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="542" to="550" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of quality and quantity of information on decision effectiveness</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Keller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Staelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="200" to="213" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When more alternatives lead to less choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kuksov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="507" to="524" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Villas-Boas</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The war on returns</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lawton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wall Street Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">D1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008-05-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditional logit analysis of qualitative choice behaviour</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mcfadden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Econometrics</title>
		<editor>P. Zarembka</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="142" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring welfare effects in models with random coefficients</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Meijer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="244" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Utility and choice: An empirical study of wife/husband decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Menasco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Curry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="97" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The group polarization phenomenon</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lamm</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psych. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="602" to="627" />
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Approximate Bayesian inference with the weighted likelihood bootstrap</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Newton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Raftery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Royal Statist. Soc. Ser. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="48" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A polarization model for describing group preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Steckel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="108" to="118" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Paradox of Choice: Why More Is Less</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<publisher>Harper-Collins</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian measures of model complexity and fit</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Spiegelhalter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Best</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Carlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Van Der Linde</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Royal Statist. Soc. Ser. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="583" to="639" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surprising robustness of the selfexplicated approach to customer preference structure measurement</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="286" to="291" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized Dirichlet distribution in Bayesian analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Math. Comput</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">97</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="165" to="181" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Greedoid-based noncompensatory inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Yee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Dahan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Orlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="532" to="549" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
