<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Identifying Unmet Demand</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sandeep</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Chandukala</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Kelley School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Indiana University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>47405</postCode>
									<settlement>Bloomington</settlement>
									<region>Indiana</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yancy</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Edwards</surname></persName>
							<email>yancy.edwards@saintleo.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Saint Leo University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Saint Leo</addrLine>
									<postCode>33574</postCode>
									<settlement>Florida</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Greg</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
							<email>allenby.1@osu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Fisher College of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ohio State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>43210</postCode>
									<settlement>Columbus</settlement>
									<region>Ohio</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Identifying Unmet Demand</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1100.0589</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: December 10, 2009; accepted: April 26, 2010; Eric Bradlow served as the editor-in-chief and Michel Wedel served as associate editor for this article.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:27+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>unmet demand</term>
					<term>heterogeneous variable selection</term>
					<term>conjoint analysis</term>
					<term>Bayesian hierarchical model</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>B rand preferences and marketplace demand are a reflection of the importance of underlying needs of consumers and the efficacy of product attributes for delivering value. Dog owners, for example, may look to dog foods to provide specific benefits for their pets (e.g., shiny coats) that may not be available from current offerings. An analysis of consumer wants for these consumers would reveal weak demand for product attributes resulting from low efficacy, despite the presence of strong latent interest. The challenge in identifying such unmet demand is in distinguishing it from other reasons for weak preference, such as general noninterest in the category and heterogeneous tastes. We propose a model for separating out these effects within the context of conjoint analysis, and we demonstrate its value with data from a national survey of toothpaste preferences. Implications for product development and reformulation are explored.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Preference for a product offering is determined by the expected benefits that accrue from its use. These benefits are a function of both the importance of the underlying motivations that drives an individual to the marketplace looking for assistance and the efficacy of the product attributes in meeting the individual's needs <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Patrick 1997)</ref>. Despite the best attempts by firms to anticipate and respond to the motivating wants of consumers, the possibility always exists that some aspects are either poorly met or unmet by the current array of marketplace offerings. There is no guarantee that the supply of product offerings is best positioned to respond to the concerns and interests of individuals as they engage in the tasks of everyday life <ref type="bibr">Allenby 2002, cf. Kennedy and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Ehrenberg 2001)</ref>, despite marketing's best efforts to guide management to make what people will want to buy. Unmet demand results when the brands within the product category are perceived as ineffective at meeting consumers' needs.</p><p>A challenge in measuring unmet demand is distinguishing it from the many other reasons that can account for low sales, including the obvious reason that prices are too high, existing offerings do not have the right combination of attributes, or particular attributes are irrelevant to an individual. For these and other reasons, marketing researchers rely on conjoint analysis to assess potential demand for offerings <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Green and Srinivasan 1978</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">, Louviere and Woodworth 1983</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">, Haijer et al. 1998</ref>. Conjoint analysis facilitates the measurement of consumer value for the attributes and benefits of hypothetical offering so that their levels can be optimally set in anticipation of marketplace competition. The attributes and attribute levels are used by firms to emphasize their advertising (short-run) and product development (long-run) strategies <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Green and Krieger 1995)</ref>. In this paper, we develop a new model of heterogeneity that can be used in conjoint analysis, and in other models of choice, to identify unmet demand.</p><p>Our model of heterogeneity extends the conventional random-effects model through the combination of three features: (i) a normal component mixture model that allows for different response segments <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Allenby et al. 1998</ref>), (ii) heterogeneous variable selection that is sensitive to the possibility that only a few attributes are of any importance to a specific respondent (extending <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Gilbride et al. 2006)</ref>, and (iii) the presence of covariates whose relationship to the model parameters can be segment specific <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Lenk and DeSarbo 2000)</ref>. Our normal component variable selection model allows for the presence of distinct response segments characterized by a subset of model parameters being nonzero, each having a potentially unique relationship to the covariates. Thus, the response segments are more meaningfully and specifically defined than in a standard normal Marketing Science 30(1), pp. 61-73, © 2011 INFORMS component model, providing for a richer interpretation of heterogeneity. A unique feature of our model is that the covariate relationship in (iii) above is determined almost entirely by attribute levels that are of some importance to each respondent, not by levels that are unimportant. By removing the influence of unimportant or unattended attribute levels, we find a much stronger covariate relationship to model parameters. Moreover, we find that including their influence distorts estimated relationships.</p><p>We apply our model to conjoint data collected in a national study of toothpaste preferences and find large improvements in model fit from the three components. We relate part-worth coefficients to covariates describing discomfort in the use of the product (e.g., tastes too strong, scratches enamel, costs too much), and views of overall efficacy (e.g., does not work) of offerings in the category, and we find evidence of a large segment of respondents who appear to have minimal interest in toothpaste attributes and benefits. For those respondents who are more engaged, a strong relationship to the covariates is detected. Interestingly, we find that the components of our model account for many of the randomeffects covariances, implying that joint preferences for attribute levels in our conjoint analysis is due to nonzero part-worths, not the extent of preference. Finally, we find sizable and robust implications for responding to unmet demand.</p><p>The remainder of this paper is organized as follows. Section 2 presents our normal component variable selection for heterogeneity and discusses challenges in estimation. Section 3 describes the data used in the analysis, and §4 reports parameter estimates and model fit. Section 5 discusses implications for detecting and responding to unmet demand, and §6 offers concluding remarks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">A Model for Unmet Demand</head><p>We define unmet demand as the result of competing forces. We assume that there is a primary motivation or need that drives an individual to want a particular benefit that may or may not be realized though the available product attributes and their levels <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Allenby et al. 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">, Yang et al. 2002</ref>). An individual may be troubled by stains on his or her teeth as a result of items he or she recently ate or drank but may feel that the whitening powers of toothpastes are ineffective at offering a solution. Swimmers may have great need for repairing damaged hair but may feel that existing conditioners do not leave their hair feeling restored. Similarly, parents cooking dinner for a busy family may be unsatisfied with the currently available options for healthy and tasty meals that are easy and quick to prepare. The common theme in each of these scenarios is the presence of a motivational state in search of an effective instrument for change.</p><p>Our model for unmet demand is essentially a model of heterogeneity. It describes the variation of model coefficients across a population for those respondents who express some evidence of a primary motivation. The presence of the primary motivation manifests itself through nonzero coefficient values for product attributes moderated by the individual's belief about product efficacy. Thus, our model is different from other models of unmet demand <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Anupindi et al. 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">, Kalyanam et al. 2007</ref>) that focus on the effects of stockouts and product nonavailability, where consumers substitute to other goods. It also differs from models in which "demand" is measured through a marketplace transaction. We operationalize demand as a motivating force that may result in an actual purchase.</p><p>We include consumer beliefs about product efficacy in our analysis, as was originally suggested by <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Green and Rao (1971)</ref> and pursued by others who have introduced attitudinal <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Ashok et al. 2002)</ref> and subjective characteristics <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Luo et al. 2008</ref>) into models of choice. In these models, a factor structure is assumed that directly affects overall utility and purchase intention. Our model does not assume a factor structure but assumes that beliefs moderate the magnitude of nonzero model coefficients only. These coefficients correspond to preference for product attribute levels, not overall utility, and are therefore more diagnostic.</p><p>Our model for unmet demand begins with a random-effects specification for heterogeneity <ref type="bibr">(Lenk et al. 1996, Allenby and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Ginter 1995)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">h = z h + h (1)</formula><p>where h indexes the respondent, is a vector of model coefficients, z h is a vector of product beliefs, and h is a vector of random-effects reflecting unobserved heterogeneity. The matrix of coefficients describes the variation of the model coefficients associated with variation in product beliefs. We expect larger coefficient values for respondents who have positive beliefs about product efficacy and smaller coefficient values for respondents who do not believe that attributes are effective at addressing their needs. Our goal is to accurately estimate .</p><p>Beliefs have been used to explain a variety of aspects of consumer judgment and decision making. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Brucks (1985)</ref>, for example, relates product category beliefs to search behavior, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Bettman and Park (1980)</ref> view beliefs in terms of a person's prior knowledge of brand performance. Beliefs are propositions that link objects to attributes, and it is natural to incorporate them into models of heterogeneity as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Horsky et al. (2006)</ref>. However, a complication arises in the estimation of when consumers attend to only a subset of the elements of the model coefficients. In a conjoint analysis, it is common for the coefficient vector, , to be of high dimension, with a small subset of the model coefficients of any importance to a specific respondent. Thus, elements of the coefficient vector may be small because of an underlying need state rather than a belief of an attribute being ineffective.</p><p>Models of variable selection have been used extensively in statistics <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(George and McCulloch 1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">, Geweke 1996</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">, Clyde and George 2004</ref> and more recently in marketing <ref type="bibr">(Gilbride et al. 2006, Fong and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">DeSarbo 2007)</ref>. We incorporate variable selection into the model using a model of heterogeneous variable selection <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Gilbride et al. 2006</ref>) by defining a diagonal matrix C whose elements take on a value of either one or a small positive constant c:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">C h = diag h</formula><p>where</p><p>hj ∼ Binomial j taking on values 1 c (2)</p><p>Combining ( <ref type="formula">2</ref>) with (1), we obtain a model of heterogeneity that effectively nullifies specific elements of the coefficient vector:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">h = C h z h + C h h (3)</formula><p>The inclusion of the matrix C h in the model specification avoids a "regression to the mean," or "shrinkage" effect present in models of heterogeneity. When a particular element of h is measured imprecisely, typically because of the lack of individual-level data, posterior estimates in model (1) are shrunk toward the posterior mean of z h of the random-effects distribution. For model (3), they are shrunk toward the posterior mean of C h z h with elements equal to either a small constant or the corresponding element of z h , depending on the posterior distribution of the vector h . When there is too little respondent-specific information in the data about an element of h , its posterior distribution is near zero. When there is much information, the posterior distribution moves away from zero. Thus, in Equation (3), the default condition is that a coefficient is expected to be close to zero unless there is evidence of the coefficient's significance in the data. This aspect of the model is important for measuring unmet demand because it requires evidence of the existence of the primary motivation for a coefficient to be nonzero.</p><p>The advantage of using Equation (3) to estimate is that much greater weight is given to those respondents with nonzero coefficients. If posterior estimates of h are near zero, then so are the corresponding elements of h , resulting in little available information for estimating since (3) holds for any of its values. The information for estimating comes from the larger values of h , corresponding to h equal to one. Thus, the estimates of in Equation (3) describe the relationship between the coefficients h and the covariates z h for those instances where a respondent's behavior is affected by the variables, not when the variables play no role. In a conjoint analysis, these are the attribute levels that affect choice.</p><p>It is useful to write Equation (3) in an alternative form to more clearly see the effects of the variable selection matrix C h on the distribution of heterogeneity:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">* h = C −1 h h = z h + h (4)</formula><p>Here, the elements of the vector * h have been filled out by the matrix C −1 h . When there exists little information in the data about a specific element of * h , posterior estimates will be centered at z h with uncertainty determined by h . We employ a multivariate Normal distribution for the random effects and introduce a mixture component model to allow for possibly distinct response segments:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">* h = C −1 h h ∼ K k=1 k N k z h k (5)</formula><p>where k indexes the response segments of size k , with segment-specific coefficient matrix k and covariance matrix k . Equation ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>) extends the heterogeneous variable selection model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Gilbride et al. (2006)</ref> (we refer to the reference hereafter as GAB) by introducing covariates, z h , into the model specification and introducing a latent normal component structure. This structure is particularly useful for identifying unmet demand because the key parameters k , describing the variation of model coefficients with brand beliefs, are determined only by those variables playing a nontrivial role in describing behavior.</p><p>An intuitive understanding of the three model components is provided in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>. Equation ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>) is a standard model of heterogeneity in which the coefficient matrix describes the relationship between the model coefficient vector ( h ) and the covariates (z h ) for all values of the covariate. The variable selection portion of the model in Equations (2) and (3) allows the coefficient matrix to describe only on nonzero values of the coefficient vector. When h is near zero, the corresponding diagonal elements of C h are also near zero and Equation ( <ref type="formula">3</ref>) is true for nearly any value of . The coefficient matrix is therefore uninformed by the elements of h near zero. Finally, the mixture component portion of the model allows for distinct response segments. In our model, it is as if the zero coefficient elements are removed from the analysis for estimation of . This aspect of the model is important for measuring unmet demand where, by definition, we assume the presence of a primary force that is moderated by the covariate value. Including the zero-valued elements would distort the estimated relationship. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Variable selection</head><formula xml:id="formula_5">h = C h z h + C h h</formula><p>measures the relationship C h = diag h where between and z for nonzero</p><p>hj ∼ Binomial j coefficients. taking on values 1 c</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">Mixture components h = K k=1 k N C h k z h C h k C h</formula><p>k measures the relationship between and z for nonzero coefficients in each segment k .</p><p>Finally, it is important to note that we rely on the cross-sectional relationship between h and z h to identify unmet demand. At the disaggregate level, we can only infer about the single posterior distribution of a respondent, h , which is similar to having just one "observation" in an analysis. Hence, we cannot distinguish between low interest and unmet demand, and we must rely on cross-section covariation with z h to infer where demand is being poorly met. Our model implicitly assumes that the respondents provide exchangeable information about unmet demand for nonzero elements of their coefficient vector (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bernardo and Smith 1994)</ref>, an assumption typically made in random-effects models for all model coefficients.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Bayesian Estimation</head><p>Bayesian estimation of the model of heterogeneity is carried out using the method of data augmentation in which a latent variable, s h , is introduced, which points to respondent segment membership. When s h is known, estimation is greatly simplified and closely follows the GAB algorithm. Bayesian estimation requires the assumption of a prior distribution for all model parameters, including a prior for the segment-specific variable selection parameters:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">j k ∼ Beta a b (6)</formula><p>where j indexes the elements of the coefficient vector h . The posterior conditional distribution of the latent augmented variable s h is distributed multinomial with segment probabilities proportional to</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">s h = k h C h k k k k k ∝ Normal C −1 h k h k z h k × k × J j=1 Beta C j k j k (7)</formula><p>The factor on the far right of ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>) is due to incorporating heterogeneous variable selection within a normal component mixture model, distinguishing it from standard component mixture models (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Rossi et al. 2005</ref>). In addition, as discussed in GAB, the draw of , which determines whether an element of h is shrunk toward zero or not, is determined in part by the likelihood of each respondent's data. As near-zero values of h are more likely to explain a respondent's data, the greater the likelihood of hj taking on a small value, c. Details are provided in the appendix.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Empirical Application</head><p>Data are from a national sample of 757 respondents investigating the preferences for toothpaste. A portion of the survey involved a conjoint study of 30 toothpaste attributes and benefits (a/b) and their levels, which are displayed in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. The levels were originally identified through a series of focus group studies. Data were also collected on a scale from 1-5, reflecting agreement with statements about the product category, which are described below. Attributes and benefits (a/b) were described in a manner similar to brand claims found on toothpaste packaging and media advertising, and they include attributes related to the physical formation of the offering and psychological attributes constructed by marketing efforts and benefits sought from product use. Ten sets of stimuli (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">2</ref>) were presented, with each comprising four hypothetical product offerings described by three attribute levels, or benefits (a/b). Respondents were told that the a/b items not listed in the description were the same for the offerings (cf. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bradlow et al. 2004)</ref>. For a ranking conjoint task, the distributional assumptions lead to an exploded logit form of complete preference ordering <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Chapman and Staelin 1982)</ref>. The likelihood of the rank ordering for the four triplets in one of the sets is equal to</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">Pr U 1m &gt;U 2m &gt;U 3m &gt;U 4m h = 3 i=1 exp x im h 4 j=i exp x jm h (8)</formula><p>where U 1m is the utility of the hypothetical product offering with the highest rank in the mth set, x im is the dummy variable coding of the a/b for the ith ranked offering in set m, and h is the vector of a/b importance weights (part-worths) for respondent h. The likelihood for an individual's ranks is defined across all 10 triplets:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">L h Data = 10 m=1 Pr U 1m &gt; U 2m &gt; U 3m &gt; U 4m h = 10 m=1 3 i=1 exp x im h 4 j=i exp x jm h (9)</formula><p>Heterogeneity is incorporated into the model specification by assuming a random-effects distribution described in its most general form by Equation (5). Six product beliefs, displayed in Table <ref type="table">3</ref>, comprise the vector z h . Some belief statements concern specific attributes (e.g., taste, price), whereas others refer to toothpastes in general. Attribute-specific beliefs are worded to reflect discomfort in using the product. Category beliefs are worded to reflect frustration with the outcome from using toothpaste and were collected before the conjoint exercise and reflect prior knowledge. Respondents indicated their belief strength to the statements in Table <ref type="table">3</ref> by indicating whether the statement described them or their belief completely, very well, somewhat, slightly, or not at all. The numerical assignment for "not at all" is 0, "slightly" is 1, "somewhat" is 2, "very well" is 3, and "completely" is 4. We treat these variables as continuous in our analysis, and we leave for future research the investigation of their treatment as ordinal scores.</p><p>Table <ref type="table">3</ref> provides the responses and summary statistics to the product belief statements. Seventy-four percent responded that the statement "Toothpastes irritate my mouth" does not describe them, and less than 1% said the statement completely describes them. Just over 18% of the respondents marked that the statement "Toothpaste breath freshening doesn't last long enough" completely describes them, and less than 10% do not ascribe to that statement. The belief data indicate that there is heterogeneity in consumers' beliefs about toothpaste attributes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Parameter Estimates</head><p>Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) methods are used to estimate the model parameters (see <ref type="bibr">Rossi et al. 2005, Chib and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Greenberg 1995)</ref>. The chain was run for a total of 50,000 iterations, with parameter estimates based on the last 5,000 iterations. We investigate multiple start points and found the chain to converge to a common posterior distribution. The estimation algorithm for the best-fitting model is provided in the appendix. Product beliefs were entered in mean-centered form, so that the intercept term reflected part-worth importance for respondents with average beliefs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Alternative Models</head><p>We investigate eight variations of the distribution of heterogeneity whose most general form is expressed in Equation (5). Fit statistics, measured in terms of the marginal density of the data, are reported for all models in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">4</ref>. The first model is a standard random-effects model, and the second model adds product beliefs to this standard specification as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Rossi et al. (2005)</ref>. Model 3 is the heterogeneous variables selection model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Gilbride et al. (2006)</ref>. Model 4 adds covariates to the model 3 specification, and models 5 and 6 are based on a normal component mixture specification with unique component intercepts, k . Finally, models 7 and 8 combine covariates (product beliefs), normal components, and variable selection into one model. In model 7, the relationship of the covariates (z h ) is assumed constant across components, and in model 8 the relationship is allowed to be unique for each of the mixing components.  Think back to the last time you brushed your teeth. Let's assume you had to choose a specific toothpaste for this toothbrushing occasion. If you had to choose among the four toothpaste products described below, please indicate which would be your most preferred choice by writing a "4" in the box below that one. Then choose your next most preferred and write a "3" below that and so on, marking a "1" beneath your least preferred choice. Assume all features not listed are the same across the choices. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Model Fit Statistics</head><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">4</ref> provides the in-sample and out-of-sample fit statistics for all eight models. We find that model 7 has the best in-sample fit based on comparison of the log-marginal densities, as suggested by <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Newton and Raftery (1994)</ref>. Moreover, we find that just two components are sufficient for this model. When we specify a greater number of mixing components, the MCMC algorithm gives nonnegligible mass to only two components. The size of the mixing components is 0.70 for the first component (528 respondents) and 0.30 for the second component (229 respondents). We also find large changes in the marginal density across models, indicating that the data are informative for distinguishing among the models. We employ hit rate and hit probability to assess out-of-sample fit. Hit rate is defined as the posterior mean of correct predictions for the entire rank ordering for one holdout choice for each individual averaged across all respondents. Hit probability is defined as the posterior mean of the predicted probability for the most preferred alternative. We find that model 7 has the best predictive fit. As discussed in GAB we find that models with variable selection have a good predictive fit. We find that the best-fitting model (model 7) results in a 17% improvement over the baseline model (model 2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Parameter Estimates</head><p>Parameter estimates for the mean of the mixing distributions for model 7, the best-fitting model, are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">5</ref>. Reported is the posterior mean of the parameters when the covariates z h are at their average values. Also reported are posterior estimates of j 1 and j 2 which reflect the proportion of respondents who give nonzero weight to each of the attribute levels when providing their responses. We find that estimates (posterior means) for the first mixture component are almost always greater in magnitude than estimates for the second component. We also find that values of j 2 are much smaller than estimates of j 1 . Both findings indicate that the second component reflects responses that are less dependent on the attribute levels of the product description than responses and respondents assigned to the first component. This may be due to many factors, such as disengagement from the data collection exercise, cognitive errors and constraints, or possible noninterest in the product category that results in low estimates of j 2 across most of the attributes and benefits. Responses in the first mixing component are much more sensitive to toothpaste attributes and their levels.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> compares estimates of diagonal and offdiagonal elements of the covariance matrices for models 2 and 7. The plots in the left portion of the figure compare diagonal elements of the covariance matrix of random effects, with estimates from the first model plotted on the horizontal axis and estimates from the best-fitting model appearing on the vertical axis. A 45-degree line is added for interpretation. The top plots correspond to the covariance matrix for the first mixing component plotted on the vertical axis, and the bottom plots are for the second mixing component of less engaged respondents. The plots in the right portion of the figure compare off-diagonal elements of the covariance matrices of random effects.  </p><formula xml:id="formula_11">C −1 h h ∼ z h + K k=1 k N ¯ k k − 17</formula><formula xml:id="formula_12">C −1 h h ∼ K k=1 k N k z h k −17 987 63 0.36 0.49</formula><p>The plots indicate that the normal mixture model with variable selection (model 7) has much smaller diagonal elements and off-diagonal elements that are very close to zero. That is, the presence of covariances in a standard model of heterogeneity appear to be largely due to an attribute level being of any importance to a respondent versus not important, not the extent of importance. It also appears that a large amount of detected heterogeneity is due to "noise" from respondents who are disengaged from the decision process. The dominant presence of zero off-diagonal covariance elements in model 7, coupled with large improvements in model fit, indicates that the model is successfully explaining heterogeneity, reducing that which is commonly called "unobserved."</p><p>The presence of a common coefficient matrix is consistent with the small parameter estimates reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">5</ref> for the second mixing component. It indicates that the data cannot support the estimation of a distinct coefficient matrix. For the respondents who are responsive to the changing attributes and levels describing the product offerings, we find many large coefficient estimates relating attributelevel part-worth to the product beliefs about product cost and efficacy. Estimates of the coefficient matrix in model 6 are much different than that from model 2, with a correlations coefficient of only 0.16. Coefficient matrices for these and other models are available from the authors upon request.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Discussion</head><p>Unmet demand results when the brands within the product category are perceived as ineffective at meeting consumers' needs. We identify the presence of unmet demand with the coefficient matrix . In our conjoint study we have 11 product components (e.g., medical benefits, taste, abrasiveness, resulting appearance, resulting breath), each composed of 2 to 6  Note. Estimates in bold have more than 95% of their posterior mass away from zero.  Off-diag model 2 Off-diag comp 2 model 7 Off-diagonal elements for engaged respondents</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Diagonal elements for less engaged respondents</head><p>Off-diagonal elements for less engaged respondents Diagonal elements for engaged respondents attributes and benefits, totaling 30. As is common in conjoint analysis, we focus on the part-worths relative to a baseline condition. The medical benefits component, attribute b1, "Helps prevent cavities," is considered the base level all toothpastes possess within that component, and other benefits are viewed as enhancements. Similarly, the resulting appearance component, b15, "Helps clean teeth," is the base level all toothpastes possess in that component and so on. We study the contrast of the attribute and benefit to its associated base level within its component by differencing the rows of the matrix to measure the added value of product enhancements (e.g., b2 − b1) to the covariates z h .</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">6</ref> displays the covariate relationship for the medical benefit component. A negative coefficient indicates that increased agreement with the belief statement in Table <ref type="table">3</ref> is associated with a decline in the magnitude of the contrast; i.e., respondents see less value in product enhancements. Negative coefficients point to the condition of unmet demand for respondents in agreement with the belief statement. Respondents not in agreement with the belief statement are expected to have greater value for the enhanced level of a/b relative to the baseline condition. In contrast, positive coefficients indicate that demand is being met through the levels of an a/b. Respondents who are in agreement with belief statements value the levels of an a/b more. Positive coefficients point to where underlying latent demand is currently being met.</p><p>Unmet demand for medical benefits is associated with beliefs that toothpastes are too strong tasting (z 1 ), irritate one's mouth (z 3 ), cost too much (z 4 ), and generally do not work (z 6 ). Respondents  who agree with these beliefs tend to have smaller part-worths for enhanced levels of the medical benefits attributes. In contrast, concerns about tooth enamel (z 2 ) and breath freshening (z 5 ) are found to express themselves in heightened levels of demand for the medical benefits. Concerns about scratched tooth enamel are associated with demand for toothpastes that deliver protection in hard-to-reach places (b2), promote healthy gums (b4), and the strengthen teeth (b5). We note that the magnitude of the coefficient contrasts is large, given that the partworths are measured using a logit model, and the beliefs are collected on a five-point rating scale. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">7</ref> displays the covariate relationship for the taste component. We find evidence of unmet demand for the contrasted a/b of the taste component when toothpastes are believed to be too strong tasting (z 1 ), scratch one's enamel (z 2 ), irritate one's mouth (z 3 ), and generally do not work to prevent dental problems (z 6 ). However, demand is met by the contrasted a/b of taste when it is believed that breath freshening does not last long enough (z 5 ). That is, respondents are more likely to value the heightened level of the taste attributes (e.g., fresh tasting, gives your mouth a tingle) even though they believe that these benefits do not last long enough. This association suggests that even though demand is being met, it might be further met by tastes that last longer in addition to immediate taste sensations such as "fresh" or "gives your mouth a tingle."</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">a/b (z 1 ) (z 2 ) ( z 3 ) ( z 4 ) ( z 5 ) (<label>z</label></formula><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">8</ref> displays the covariate relationship for the abrasiveness component. Here, we do not find </p><formula xml:id="formula_14">a/b (z 1 ) (z 2 ) ( z 3 ) ( z 4 ) ( z 5 ) ( z 6 ) b8 −0 40 −0 75 −0 42 −0 19 0 18 −0 68 b9 −0 37 −0 54 −0 75 0 60 0 69 −0 37 b10 −0 62 0 26 −0 92 0 57 0 71 −0 82 b11 −0 21 −1 11 0 28 −0 37 0 28 −0 95</formula><p>Note. Estimates in bold have more than 95% of their posterior mass away from zero.  Note. Estimates in bold have more than 95% of their posterior mass away from zero.</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">a/b (z 1 ) (z 2 ) ( z 3 ) ( z 4 ) ( z 5 ) (<label>z 6</label></formula><p>evidence of unmet demand that corresponds to a negative coefficient. Instead, we find evidence of demand that is met through toothpastes for sensitive teeth (b13) when respondents believe that toothpastes scratch tooth enamel (z 2 ) and when toothpastes are believed not to work at all (z 6 ). Similarly, preference for the nonscratching tooth enamel benefit (b14) is sought by respondents who believe that toothpaste is too strong tasting (z 1 ) and by those who believe that toothpastes do not really work (z 6 ). Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_11">9</ref> displays the covariate relationship for the appearance component. We find evidence of met demand for heightened levels of this component for stain removal (b16), teeth whitening (b17), and the ability to make your teeth gleam like pearls (b18).  Note. Estimates in bold have more than 95% of their posterior mass away from zero. </p><formula xml:id="formula_16">a/b (z 1 ) (z 2 ) ( z 3 ) ( z 4 ) ( z 5 ) (<label>z 6</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_17">a/b (z 1 ) (z 2 ) ( z 3 ) ( z 4 ) ( z 5 ) ( z 6 ) b20 0 09 −0 31 −0 38 0 37 −0 23 −0 08 b21 −0 02 −0 19 −0 05 0 47 0 01 −0 06</formula><p>Note. Estimates in bold have more than 95% of their posterior mass away from zero.  Note. Estimates in bold have more than 95% of their posterior mass away from zero. Medical benefits, abrasiveness z 3 : Toothpastes irritate my mouth.</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">a/b (z 1 ) (z 2 ) ( z 3 ) ( z 4 ) ( z 5 ) (<label>z 6</label></formula><p>Medical benefits Resulting appearance z 4 : Toothpastes cost too much.</p><p>Resulting breath z 5 : Toothpaste breath freshening doesn't last long enough. Taste z 6 : Toothpastes don't really work to prevent dental problems.</p><p>Medical benefits, taste Abrasiveness, resulting appearance</p><p>Stain removal is the most preferred a/b for respondents who feel toothpastes are too strong tasting (z 1 ) or that toothpastes do not really work to prevent dental problems (z 6 ). Whitening is also preferred among these respondents, as is the pearly whitening benefit. These same respondents, who do not believe in the ability of toothpaste to prevent dental problems (z 6 ), were described in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">6</ref> as not valuing enhancements in the medical benefits of toothpaste. They appear to have given up on receiving medical benefits and taste, and they instead seek toothpastes that are nonabrasive and deliver enhanced levels of appearance.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">10</ref> displays the covariate relationship for the breath-freshening component. Levels of unmet demand are associated with beliefs about toothpaste scratching enamel (z 2 ), irritating one's mouth (z 3 ), and breath freshening not lasting long (z 5 ) for the enhanced a/b of 12-hour breath freshening (b20) and morning mouth (b21). Respondents who believe that toothpastes cost too much (z 4 ) prefer the morningmouth benefit (b21) and also prefer the 12-hour breath-freshening benefit (b20).</p><p>Finally, Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">11</ref> displays the covariate relationship for price, ingredients, and other components. Unmet demand is expressed as people being more price sensitive if they feel toothpastes do not work (z 6 ). Unmet demand for people who believe that ingredients are 100% natural (b23) exists in their lack of belief of long-lasting breath freshening (z 5 ). Similarly, we find unmet demand for packaging, social interests, and routine maintenance benefits (b24-b30).</p><p>A summary of the findings is presented in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">12</ref>. We find that beliefs about toothpastes being too strong tasting (z 1 ) are associated with depressed demand for medical benefits and taste, and with heightened demand for toothpastes that are less abrasive. The belief that toothpastes scratch tooth enamel (z 2 ) is held by respondents with heightened demand for medical benefits and less abrasion. Respondents who believe that toothpastes irritate the mouth (z 3 ) have depressed demand for medical benefits and heightened demand for appearance attributes. Respondents who believe that toothpastes cost too much (z 4 ) have heightened demand for breath freshening, and those who believe that toothpaste breath freshening does not last long enough (z 5 ) have heightened demand for taste attributes. Finally, respondents who feel that toothpastes do not work to prevent dental problems (z 6 ) have depressed demand for medical and taste benefits but have heightened demand for abrasiveness and appearance attributes.</p><p>The predicted effects of changing consumer beliefs are a function of the coefficient matrix and also the variable selection probabilities j k . As reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">5</ref>, the variable selection probabilities range from 0.73 for attribute b18 (makes your teeth gleam like pearls) to 0.12 for attribute b12 (doesn't irritate your mouth). These probabilities reflect the proportion of respondents in the responsive segment expected to experience change in demand as beliefs change. The identification of profitable campaigns to change respondents' beliefs of products in the product category requires knowledge of both parameters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Concluding Remarks</head><p>In this paper we propose a model of heterogeneity useful for detecting unmet demand, which is defined as the presence of an underlying need not being fulfilled by the array of marketplace offerings. We assume that consumer value for the attributes and benefits of product offerings reflects met demand, which may be depressed or dampened by beliefs that products are costly to use or are ineffective. Here, we interpret cost in a broad sense to include factors that give rise to displeasure in use, including prices. Our inference about unmet demand is made through a cross-sectional analysis relating part-worth estimates in a conjoint analysis to beliefs about the performance of offerings in a product category.</p><p>A challenge in detecting unmet demand is in separating out respondents who have no demand for the attributes and benefits of a product. It is not possible to make an inference about unmet demand unless there is some positive demand present; however, much of it may be depressed. We propose a new model of heterogeneity that combines the heterogeneous variable selection model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Gilbride et al. (2006)</ref> with a normal component mixture model (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Rossi et al. 2005)</ref>, which includes covariates, into the same model structure.</p><p>Our model of heterogeneity has two features useful for detecting unmet demand. First, the variable selection aspect of the model leads to a shrinkage value of zero rather than the mean of the mixing distribution. Unless there is information in the data likelihood that indicates otherwise, this distribution of heterogeneity assumes that demand for a product feature is zero. Second, the model allows for a potentially different covariate relationship to exist for each of the normal components. This offers the potential of identifying distinct response segments whose behavior is driven by different subsets of the model parameters, each with a unique relationship to the covariates. This could provide a richer description of heterogeneity that assumes a priori the existence of a common relationship.</p><p>In application to conjoint data of toothpaste, we find strong support for the proposed model. We detect the existence of a sizable response segment with very weak demand (i.e., part-worth estimates near zero) that negatively affects analysis relying on standard models of heterogeneity. We also find that only one additional response segment is required by the data and that the covariate relationship is homogeneous, not heterogeneous. Most surprisingly, we find that this best-fitting model explains the covariances detected with simpler models of heterogeneity. That is, covariances in the unobserved component of heterogeneity are nearly zero in the best-fitting model, indicating that our model is successful in explaining the structure of heterogeneity. Our analysis indicates that unobserved covariances are not due to a continuous preference relationship among respondents. Instead, they are driven by whether respondents have any nonzero preference for an attribute. This interpretation is confirmed by the large improvement in fit for the proposed model relative to simpler models (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">4</ref>).</p><p>We use the model to detect patterns of unmet demand using the coefficient matrix that relates part-worth estimates to the beliefs about product offerings. The elements of the coefficient matrix are estimated to be large, with coefficient negative values pointing to patterns of unmet demand and positive values indicating where demand is being met by the attributes and their levels. As technology changes and brands are repositioned, the coefficients provide insight into which product attributes will be in greater demand as beliefs change. It also provides guidance as to which beliefs need to be addressed to increase demand for particular levels of an attribute.</p><p>We believe that our model of heterogeneity has application to a wide class of problems in marketing, wherever it is important to characterize relationships on "what is" as opposed to "what is not." Marketing research studies make wide use of screening questions to qualify respondents in surveys, and our model structure can be thought of as qualifying evidence for the measurement of associations by screening out the nonrespondents. In a needs-based market segmentation study, respondents are grouped into segments for characterization and further analysis. The basis for segment inclusion should, we believe, be focused on the common needs of respondents, not the common non-needs or needs that they do not have. In an analysis of price responsiveness, it does not make conceptual sense to include respondents who are not prospects in the product category and have no interest in making a purchase. Similar arguments can be made for studying response to changes in advertising and channel and product formulation, as well as for removing respondents from an analysis that provides random responses. Our model structure offers a device for controlling for such nonresponse.</p><p>There are numerous avenues for extending the analysis in this paper. In addition to offering a new model of heterogeneity that can be applied in other contexts, our analysis challenges conventional thinking about the presence of distinct segments in a population of respondents having distinct needs. We do not find a need for more than two normal components in the mixing distribution, with one reflecting the behavior of respondents who are disengaged from the study. Just one coefficient matrix, , is found to be needed in our analysis. Moreover, the lack of heterogeneity covariances indicates a lack of response clusters in the distribution of heterogeneity. This challenges common notions of market segmentation where collections of need states give rise to distinct demand groupings. Additional research incorporating consumer needs into the analysis is desired, possibly using these variables to explain the process of variable selection.  </p><formula xml:id="formula_19">h = C −1 h h ∼ z h + K k=1 k N ¯ k k C h = diag h ,</formula><formula xml:id="formula_20">1 2. Generate¯ k ¯ k * h , hj k : Form * h ∼ C −1 h h , k ∼ Normal ˜ k /V −1 + 100I −1 −1 , = k /V −1 + 100I −1 −1 −1 k H h=1 * h − z h + 100I −1 3. Generate k k * h , hj ¯ k : k ∼ IW + V + H h=1 * h − z h −¯ k * h − z h −¯ k</formula><p>where IW is the inverted Wishart distribution with = J + 3 and = I. 4. Generate jk jk hj : If hj = 1, then q hj = 1; else, q hj = 0. = Normal 0 0 01I . 6. Generate latent indicator variable s h and segment weights k :</p><p>When making assignments of individuals to the components, we employ the standard procedure of augmenting the parameter space with a latent indicator variable s h , which aids in determining to which of the components a respondent is associated. The draw for the latent variable s h is done from</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">s h = k h C h k k k k k ∝ Normal C −1 h k h k z h k × k × J j=1 Beta C j k j k</formula><p>The last factor on the right-hand side is the product of the probabilities associated with a respondent's C h .</p><p>The segment weights k have Dirichlet distribution and are given by k s h k ∼ D 1 + n 1 2 + n 2 K + n K , where n k = # i s i = k is the number of subjects assigned to segment k. In our analysis, we set 1 = 1 = • • • = K = 3; given the large sample size for the data used, this prior specification results in a very mild influence on the posterior.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Model OverviewCovariate relationshiph = z h + h measures the relationship between and z.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2Comparison of Covariance Matrices for Engaged and Less Engaged Respondents</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Estimates in bold have more than 95% of their posterior mass away from zero.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>where hj ∼ Beta jk taking on values 1 c .The priors are specified ashj = 1 with probability jk and hj = c with probability 1 − jk ,k ∼ Normal 0 100I k ∼ IW ,jk ∼ Beta a b , with a = b = 5. Draws of the conditional distribution are obtained with the Metropolis-Hastings algorithm with a random walk chain. The notation of (n) and (o) correspond to new and old draws.(i) We set nhj = 1 with a probability of jk ; else,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>=</head><label></label><figDesc>Normal ˆ * ˆ * , wherê * = Z Z ⊗ −1 + 0 01 I −1 Z ⊗ −1 B * , B * = vec B where B = 1 2 • • • H , ˆ * = Z Z ⊗ −1 + 0 01 I −1, and (0.01I) is due to the prior on :</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Toothpaste Attributes and Benefits</figDesc><table><row><cell>Attribute/benefit</cell><cell>Description</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Medical benefits</cell></row><row><cell>b1</cell><cell>Helps prevent cavities</cell></row><row><cell>b2</cell><cell>Delivers protection in hard-to-reach places</cell></row><row><cell>b3</cell><cell>Helps remove tartar and plaque</cell></row><row><cell>b4</cell><cell>Helps promote healthy gums</cell></row><row><cell>b5</cell><cell>Penetrates to strengthen your teeth against cavities</cell></row><row><cell>b6</cell><cell>Helps fight germs and infections in your mouth</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Taste</cell></row><row><cell>b7</cell><cell>Mild tasting</cell></row><row><cell>b8</cell><cell>Fresh tasting</cell></row><row><cell>b9</cell><cell>Gives your mouth a tingle</cell></row><row><cell>b10</cell><cell>A taste kids love</cell></row><row><cell>b11</cell><cell>Great bubbling action</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Abrasiveness</cell></row><row><cell>b12</cell><cell>Doesn't irritate your mouth</cell></row><row><cell>b13</cell><cell>For sensitive teeth</cell></row><row><cell>b14</cell><cell>Safe for tooth enamel (nonscratching)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Resulting appearance</cell></row><row><cell>b15</cell><cell>Helps clean teeth</cell></row><row><cell>b16</cell><cell>Helps remove stains</cell></row><row><cell>b17</cell><cell>Whitens your teeth</cell></row><row><cell>b18</cell><cell>Makes your teeth gleam like pearls</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Resulting breath</cell></row><row><cell>b19</cell><cell>Fights bad breath</cell></row><row><cell>b20</cell><cell>Freshens breath for 12 hours</cell></row><row><cell>b21</cell><cell>Helps take away morning mouth</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Price</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Regular price a</cell></row><row><cell>b22</cell><cell>20% less</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Ingredients</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>80% natural/20% artificial ingredients a</cell></row><row><cell>b23</cell><cell>100% natural ingredients</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Packaging</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>80% recyclable packaging a</cell></row><row><cell>b24</cell><cell>100% recyclable packaging</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Interests</cell></row><row><cell>b25</cell><cell>An interesting way to clean your teeth</cell></row><row><cell>b26</cell><cell>Provides a change of pace</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Social</cell></row><row><cell>b27</cell><cell>Shows others you care about your teeth</cell></row><row><cell>b28</cell><cell>Helps you feel good about yourself for brushing regularly</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Maintenance</cell></row><row><cell>b29</cell><cell>For everyday brushing</cell></row><row><cell>b30</cell><cell>For routine maintenance</cell></row></table><note>a Null condition.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Example Stimuli for Measuring the Importance of Attribute Levels</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Model Fit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Out of sample</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Log-marginal</cell><cell>Hit</cell></row><row><cell>Model of heterogeneity</cell><cell cols="4">Description</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>density</cell><cell>Hit rate</cell><cell>probability</cell></row><row><cell>1 Intercept model</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">h = + h</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>−19 090 11</cell><cell>0.31</cell><cell>0.42</cell></row><row><cell>2 Covariate model</cell><cell cols="4">h = z h + h</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>−18 976 53</cell><cell>0.35</cell><cell>0.48</cell></row><row><cell>3 Intercept model with variable selection</cell><cell cols="5">h ∼ N C h¯ C h V C h</cell><cell></cell><cell>−18 342 52</cell><cell>0.33</cell><cell>0.46</cell></row><row><cell>4 Covariate model with variable selection</cell><cell cols="6">h ∼ N C h z h C h V C h</cell><cell>−18 146 64</cell><cell>0.36</cell><cell>0.49</cell></row><row><cell>5 Normal component mixture model</cell><cell>h ∼</cell><cell>K</cell><cell cols="2">k N ¯ k</cell><cell>k</cell><cell></cell><cell>−18 446 34</cell><cell>0.32</cell><cell>0.44</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>k=1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>6 Normal component mixture model with covariates</cell><cell cols="2">h ∼ z h +</cell><cell>K</cell><cell cols="2">k N ¯ k</cell><cell>k</cell><cell>−18 009 11</cell><cell>0.34</cell><cell>0.46</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>k=1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>7 Normal component mixture model with variable selection and</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>common covariate relationship</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 5 Posterior</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note>Estimates of the Mean of the Normal Components and Variable Selection Probability</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="4">Unmet Demand for Medical Benefits</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Breath</cell><cell>Don't really</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>freshening</cell><cell>work to</cell></row><row><cell>Strong Scratch</cell><cell>Irritate</cell><cell>Cost too</cell><cell>doesn't</cell><cell>prevent dental</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">tasting enamel my mouth</cell><cell>much</cell><cell>last long</cell><cell>problems</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table 7</head><label>7</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Unmet Demand for Taste</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Breath</cell><cell>Don't really</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>freshening</cell><cell>work to</cell></row><row><cell>Strong Scratch</cell><cell>Irritate</cell><cell>Cost too</cell><cell>doesn't</cell><cell>prevent dental</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">tasting enamel my mouth</cell><cell>much</cell><cell>last long</cell><cell>problems</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table 8</head><label>8</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Unmet Demand for Abrasiveness</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Breath</cell><cell>Don't really</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>freshening</cell><cell>work to</cell></row><row><cell>Strong Scratch</cell><cell>Irritate</cell><cell>Cost too</cell><cell>doesn't</cell><cell>prevent dental</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">tasting enamel my mouth</cell><cell>much</cell><cell>last long</cell><cell>problems</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>Table 9</head><label>9</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Unmet Demand for Appearance</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Breath</cell><cell>Don't really</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>freshening</cell><cell>work to</cell></row><row><cell>Strong Scratch</cell><cell>Irritate</cell><cell>Cost too</cell><cell>doesn't</cell><cell>prevent dental</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">tasting enamel my mouth</cell><cell>much</cell><cell>last long</cell><cell>problems</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12"><head>Table 10</head><label>10</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="4">Unmet Demand for Breath Freshening</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Breath</cell><cell>Don't really</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>freshening</cell><cell>work to</cell></row><row><cell>Strong Scratch</cell><cell>Irritate</cell><cell>Cost too</cell><cell>doesn't</cell><cell>prevent dental</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">tasting enamel my mouth</cell><cell>much</cell><cell>last long</cell><cell>problems</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_13"><head>Table 11</head><label>11</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="5">Unmet Demand Because of Price, Ingredients, Packaging,</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Interests, and Maintenance</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Breath</cell><cell>Don't really</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>freshening</cell><cell>work to</cell></row><row><cell>Strong Scratch</cell><cell>Irritate</cell><cell>Cost too</cell><cell>doesn't</cell><cell>prevent dental</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">tasting enamel my mouth</cell><cell>much</cell><cell>last long</cell><cell>problems</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_14"><head>Table 12</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Toothpastes scratch the enamel on my teeth.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Summary of Findings</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>have depressed demand for</cell><cell>and enhanced demand for</cell></row><row><cell>People who believe</cell><cell>(unmet demand)</cell><cell>(met demand)</cell></row><row><cell>z 1 : Toothpastes are too strong tasting.</cell><cell>Medical benefits, taste</cell><cell>Abrasiveness</cell></row><row><cell>z 2 :</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>1. Generate h , hj for h = 1 H respondents: The posterior for h is given byh data ∝ L h Data × h z h k ¯ k k (10)where the likelihood, i.e., the first component of (1), is given byL h Data = 10 m=1 Pr U 1m &gt; U 2m &gt; U 3m &gt; U 4m h</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>=</cell><cell>10 m=1</cell><cell>3 i=1</cell><cell>exp x im h 4 j=i exp x jm h</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">The second component of (1),</cell></row><row><cell>h</cell><cell cols="3">z h k ¯ k k</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">can be formulated as</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>*</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank Yankelovich Partners for providing access to data and helpful comments.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix. Markov Chain Monte Carlo Estimation</head><p>The empirical application discussed in this article consists of 757 respondents filling out a conjoint survey of 30 toothpaste attributes and their levels. Ten sets of stimuli were presented with each set comprising of four hypothetical product offerings described by three attribute levels with respondents rank ordering these offerings. Let h denote the index of the respondent, let j denote the product offering, let m denote different sets of stimuli, and let k denote the number of latent segments.</p><p>Estimation is carried out by sequentially generating draws from the following distributions.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using extremes to design products and segment markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Ginter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="392" to="403" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporating prior knowledge into the analysis of conjoint studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Ginter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="152" to="162" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Market segmentation research: Beyond within and across group differences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Fennell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bemmaor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Bhargava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Christen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dawley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dickson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="233" to="243" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimation of consumer demand with stock-out based substitution: An application to vending machine products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Anupindi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="406" to="423" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extending discrete choice models to incorporate attitudinal and other latent variables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ashok</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Dillon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bayesian Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bernardo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">F M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Chichester, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of prior knowledge and experience and phase of the choice process on consumer decision processes: A protocol analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bettman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="234" to="248" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A learning-based model for imputing missing levels in partial conjoint profiles</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Bradlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T.-H</forename><surname>Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="369" to="381" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of product class knowledge on information search behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brucks</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting rank ordered choice set data within the stochastic utility model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Staelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="288" to="301" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Edwards</forename><surname>Chandukala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Allenby</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>© 2011 INFORMS 73</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Identifying Unmet Demand Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="73" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the Metropolis-Hastings algorithm</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chib</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Greenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Statistician</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="327" to="335" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Clyde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>George</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Model uncertainty. Statist. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="94" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">No brand level segmentation? Let&apos;s not rush to judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Fennell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="18" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Bayesian methodology for simultaneously detecting and estimating regime change points and variable selection in multiple regression models for marketing research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K H</forename><surname>Fong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Desarbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="427" to="453" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Variable selection via Gibbs sampling</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>George</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Mcculloch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">423</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="881" to="889" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Variable selection and model comparison in regression</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Geweke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Bayesian Statistics 5: Proc. Fifth Valencia Internat. Meeting</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bernando</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Berger</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dawid</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">F M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="609" to="620" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Models for heterogeneous variable selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gilbride</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brazell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="420" to="430" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attribute importance weights modification in assessing a brand&apos;s competitive potential</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Krieger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="270" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conjoint measurement for quantifying judgmental data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="363" />
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conjoint analysis in consumer research: Issues and outlook</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Utility covariances and context effects in conjoint MNP models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Haijer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Virens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wansbeek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="236" to="252" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Observed and unobserved preference heterogeneity in brand-choice models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Horsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Misra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="322" to="335" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deconstructing each item&apos;s category contribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kalyanam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Borle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Boatwright</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="327" to="341" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">There is no brand segmentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kennedy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ehrenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian inference for finite mixtures of generalized linear models with random effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lenk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Desarbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychometrika</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="119" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hierarchical Bayes conjoint analysis: Recovery of partworth heterogeneity from reduced experimental designs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lenk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Desarbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="173" to="191" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design and analysis of simulated consumer choice or allocation experiments: An approach based on aggregate data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Louviere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Woodworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="350" to="367" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporating subjective characteristics in product design and evaluations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kannan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ratchford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="182" to="194" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Approximate Bayesian inference with the weighted likelihood bootstrap</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Newton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Raftery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Roy. Statist. Soc. Ser. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="48" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How to Develop Successful New Products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Patrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>American Marketing Association and NTC Business Books</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Chicago</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bayesian Statistics and Marketing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rossi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mcculloch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling variation in brand preference: The roles of objective environment and motivating conditions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Fennell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
