<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Effects of Information Transparency on Suppliers, Manufacturers, and Consumers in Online Markets</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Zach</forename><forename type="middle">Zhizhong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<email>zzhou@rady.ucsd.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Rady School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>San Diego</addrLine>
									<postCode>92093</postCode>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>California</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><forename type="middle">Xiaoguo</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
							<email>kxzhu@ucsd.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Rady School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>San Diego</addrLine>
									<postCode>92093</postCode>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>California</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Effects of Information Transparency on Suppliers, Manufacturers, and Consumers in Online Markets</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1100.0585</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: March 24, 2009; accepted: April 26, 2010; processed by Greg Shaffer.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:27+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>electronic markets</term>
					<term>competition</term>
					<term>uncertainty</term>
					<term>market microstructure</term>
					<term>information transparency</term>
					<term>B2B marketing</term>
					<term>game theory</term>
					<term>analytical modeling</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>T his paper looks into the effects of information transparency on market participants in an online trading environment. We study these effects in business-to-business electronic markets with firms competing in both upstream and downstream industries. The prior literature generally assumes that either the downstream firm (buyer) or the upstream firm (seller) is a monopoly. It is not clear whether information transparency would still create value if both buyers and sellers face oligopolistic competition, where the benefits of information transparency could be competed away. To answer this question, we first develop a simple two-echelon e-market model and then extend the model to more general settings. We find that information transparency can create value for the overall e-market, yet it affects buyers and sellers very differently: one side will be hurt, depending on the competition mode (Cournot or Bertrand) in the downstream. This suggests that a manufacturer-owned, a supplier-owned, and a neutral e-market will have different preferences for information transparency. Finally, we find that information transparency can hurt consumers when the downstream industry engages in Bertrand competition. This is a surprising result given the expectation that online markets create substantial value for consumers.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>After the burst of the dot-com bubble in 2000, many electronic markets went out of business, yet many surviving markets, which built brand awareness and market share, kept growing and evolving. Alibaba, the largest business-to-business (B2B) online e-market in the world, has witnessed a revenue growth of 58% from 1,364 million yuan in 2006 to 2,163 million yuan in 2007. Its gross profit increased by 67% in 2007, and its operating profit increased by nearly 200%. The number of registered buyers and sellers of its online trading platform grew to 28 million (as of <ref type="bibr">December 31, 2007)</ref>, representing a 40% annual growth in user base. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> In the United States, online transactions were still small as a percentage of total retail sales ($31,708 million, about 3.5% of total retail sales in the first quarter of 2009), but they kept increasing steadily. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> It was estimated that more than 94% of total online transactions were B2B trading. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The ups and downs of B2B e-markets motivate us to examine how a B2B market <ref type="bibr">1</ref> See <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Alibaba (2008)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> See U.S. Census <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Bureau (2009)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> See U.S. Census <ref type="bibr">Bureau.</ref> creates value for market participants. In this paper, we focus on an important feature of B2B: information transparency, which enables firms to share information online.</p><p>Information sharing has been shown to benefit trading partners. In reality, many industries are still in search of a platform that will facilitate information sharing while allowing firms to conduct transactions. B2B electronic markets (e-markets) have the promise of being one such transaction platform. B2B e-markets provide a digital environment with abundant data about products, prices, bids, quantities, and other transaction details. Hence, relative to traditional physical markets, e-markets offer a data-rich environment. Thus, information transparency, which is defined as the degree of visibility and accessibility of information, is a key feature of B2B e-markets <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Zhu 2004)</ref>.</p><p>Earlier studies show that information transparency benefits total supply chain (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Lee et al. 2000, Cachon and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Fisher 2000)</ref>, but the information transparency in these studies generally refers to vertical information sharing about demand between an upstream firm (e.g., a supplier) and a downstream firm (e.g., a manufacturer). This is different from horizontal information transparency between competitors. Evidence shows that horizontal information 1126 <ref type="bibr">Marketing Science 29(6), pp. 1125</ref><ref type="bibr">-1137</ref><ref type="bibr">, © 2010</ref> transparency in electronic markets enables firms to use transaction data to infer the cost structure of competitors <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Soh et al. 2006)</ref>. This new feature is partly enabled by the data-rich environment of online markets (relative to traditional markets).</p><p>Information transparency is deemed socially desirable because it may help improve efficiency in resource allocation <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bakos 1997</ref>). On the other hand, market participants may want to conceal transaction data to protect their privacy <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Kalvenes and Basu 2006)</ref>. Prior economics literature has analyzed the effects of information sharing in a one-level market (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Gal-Or 1985)</ref>; however, it is not clear whether information transparency about competitors' cost would benefit a two-level e-market with oligopolistic competition existing in both upstream and downstream industries. In this paper, we focus on the following research questions:</p><p>• In such a market, will information transparency benefit both sellers and buyers, or will there be a conflict of interest?</p><p>• If such conflict of interest exists, under what conditions would buyers (or sellers) be hurt?</p><p>• How does information transparency affect consumers?</p><p>The real world offers examples on both sides: B2B e-markets with high information transparency and with low information transparency. Before 2000, auto manufacturers each had their own private exchanges in which their prequalified suppliers could do transactions with the dedicated auto manufacturer. That is, each of the "big three" auto manufacturers ran their own separate marketing channels. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> In 2000, Covisint was created to provide a transparent shared platform on which bidding prices were visible to all participants, yet market participants were concerned about their privacy. Ariba, another B2B e-market, adopted a business model with lower information transparency than that of Covisint. WorldWide Retail Exchange (WWRE), another e-market, has two e-market structures with different levels of information transparency. First, WWRE's data pool service provides up-to-date and searchable information, with an objective to develop a "single platform that connects retailers, manufacturers and their business trading partners to more efficiently and effectively share information and manage work processes" (Logistics Today 2005, emphasis our own). Second, WWRE also provides private e-markets to those firms who want to customize their information exchange with selected suppliers, thus achieving better control over transaction data.</p><p>These real-world examples illustrate that neither the transparent e-market nor the opaque e-market is <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Exostar has a similar industry structure in the aerospace industry. an all-encompassing solution in practice. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> This can be related to multiform ownership structures of the B2B e-markets. <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Yoo et al. (2007)</ref> defined three ownership structures: (1) buyer-owned (manufacturerowned) marketplaces where manufacturers jointly own the marketplace, (2) seller-owned (supplierowned) marketplaces, and (3) neutral marketplaces that are owned by independent third parties. The ownership structure could affect the choice of transparency level of a B2B e-market. Intuitively, if the information transparency benefits manufacturers, then a manufacturer-owned marketplace would prefer a transparent market structure. The question is this: under what conditions will the information transparency be beneficial to a specific type of B2B e-market? The answer to such a question may generate useful insights about the role of information transparency in online markets and on the microstructure design of online markets. This in turn may be useful in understanding which structure worked and which structure failed.</p><p>To better understand these issues, we develop a two-level B2B e-market model. Buyers (manufacturers) in the downstream each have some prequalified suppliers in the upstream. Suppliers compete for the manufacturer's orders via bidding on the e-market platform; manufacturers in turn compete in the consumer market. Using this setting, we show that the information transparency affects manufacturers and suppliers very differently. We find that one side (either manufacturers or suppliers) is hurt by, whereas the other side benefits from, the information transparency enabled by the e-market. Interestingly, the competition mode of the downstream industry turns out to be a critical factor that determines which side is hurt. If manufacturers compete on quantity (i.e., Cournot competition), the information transparency helps them but hurts their upstream suppliers. That is, a manufacturer-owned B2B e-market may prefer a transparent e-market structure, whereas a supplier-owned B2B e-market may prefer an opaque market. Conversely, if manufacturers compete on price (i.e., Bertrand competition), they are hurt while suppliers benefit. These results show a conflict of interest regarding information transparency between manufacturers and suppliers.</p><p>Despite the conflict of interest, we find that information transparency always increases the overall welfare to all e-market participants regardless of the competition mode, implying that its benefit always dominates the loss. This suggests that a neutral B2B e-market may prefer a transparent e-market model.</p><p>We further examine the effect of information transparency on consumers. We find that the information transparency can hurt consumers under certain conditions. This is a surprising result given the expectation that online markets could create substantial values to consumers <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Hitt and Brynjolfsson 1996)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.">Related Literature</head><p>Our paper is related to the marketing literature on information economics in a distribution channel. Vertical information sharing was found to have two effects on an upstream manufacturer: (1) an efficiency effect, which helps the manufacturer to better manage its inventory; and (2) a strategic effect, which can hurt it by limiting its ability to extract profits from a downstream retailer <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Iyer et al. 2007</ref>). In examining information acquisition and sharing in a distribution channel, it was shown that information acquisition benefits a downstream retailer, whereas vertical information sharing hurts the retailer but benefits an upstream wholesaler <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Guo 2009)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">He et al. (2008)</ref> consider vertical information sharing in a channel setting where demand is highly volatile and firms engage in short-term trading relationships. Information asymmetry about demand can also be dealt with by using advertising and slotting allowances <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Desai 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">, Chu 1992</ref>). The literature of operations management also examined the vertical information sharing in various settings (see, for example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Lee et al. 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Lee et al. , 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Gavirneni et al. 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Cachon and Fisher 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Kulp et al. 2004)</ref>.</p><p>Most of this prior literature focuses on vertical information sharing and considers the case where there is one firm in an upstream industry or in a downstream industry. Our paper differs from the prior literature in that we consider the case where competition exists in both the upstream and the downstream industries, and information is transferred horizontally between competitors via a market mechanism. There is a stream of economics literature that focuses on horizontal information sharing among competitors in a one-level market, where sourcing from upstream is not explicitly modeled <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Vives 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">, Raith 1996</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">, Shapiro 1986</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">, Gal-Or 1985</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Zhu (2004)</ref> examines the incentives for firms to join a transparent e-market. Our paper differs from this literature in that we model a twolevel e-market, where both the upstream industry and downstream industry are explicitly modeled. Thus, our paper fills a gap in the literature and provides new business insight regarding the effects of information transparency on the upstream industry, the downstream industry, and the total e-market, respectively.</p><p>Our paper is also related to the marketing literature on vertical channel coordination (see, for example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Gerstner and Hess 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">, Iyer 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">, Coughlan 1985</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">, Shaffer and Zettelmeyer 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">, Jeuland and Shugan 1983</ref>. In this paper, information transparency in the e-market can help downstream buyers to coordinate their strategies when the downstream industry engages in Cournot competition. The coordination occurs between competitors instead of between business partners. In our model, this is done by using supplier cost information to achieve better outcomes in the final consumer market.</p><p>To illustrate the major result with mathematical simplicity, we present a simple base model, followed by an analysis of the overall effects on the total e-market and differential effects on suppliers and manufacturers, respectively. Then, we relax some of the assumptions and extend the base model to examine more general situations, incorporating (1) different competition modes (Cournot versus Bertrand), (2) overlapping suppliers, and (3) asymmetric procurement channels. We show that the major results in the base model also hold in more general settings. Most of the technical proofs are provided in the electronic companion, available as part of the online version that can be found at http://mktsci.pubs .informs.org/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">The Base Model</head><p>To illustrate the essence of the issue, we consider a simple two-level e-market with two manufacturers (M 1 and M 2 ) in the downstream industry. Each manufacturer has two prequalified upstream suppliers, where M i 's suppliers are labeled as S ia and S ib i = 1 2 , as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>. Built on related literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bakos and</ref><ref type="bibr">Brynjolfsson 1993, Pinker et al. 2003)</ref>, we make several assumptions to model such a market.</p><p>Assumption 1. A manufacturer procures from a limited number of prequalified suppliers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1</head><p>The Base Model</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">S 1a M 1</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Consumers S 1b</head><p>Bidding (A)</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">S 2a M 2 S 2b Bidding (B)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Suppliers</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Manufacturers B2B E-market</head><p>Marketing Science 29(6), pp. <ref type="bibr">1125</ref><ref type="bibr">-1137</ref><ref type="bibr">, © 2010</ref> This setting captures some key features of B2B e-markets that are different from those of businessto-consumer (B2C) e-markets and is motivated by several real-world exchanges, such as Exostar and Covisint. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> First, each manufacturer does business with a limited number of suppliers because business relation-specific investments in B2B e-markets are significantly higher than those in B2C e-markets. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bakos and Brynjolfsson (1993)</ref> argue that manufacturers often find it optimal to work with only a small number of suppliers. Second, transactions in B2B e-markets often involve mutual trust, integrating interorganizational information systems, quality requirements, product specification, and arrangements of shipments and payments. Before a manufacturer invites suppliers to bid on a contract, the manufacturer generally needs to prequalify suppliers who meet its requirements <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Pinker et al. 2003)</ref>. In a B2B e-market, it is often difficult or impractical to switch to a nonprequalified supplier in a short period of time. 7 These fundamental industry relationships remain important, even with the presence of an electronic market. We can think of the supplier selection problem as a two-stage process: first, manufacturers prequalify suppliers based on nonprice attributes (which we take as given in this model); second, prequalified suppliers bid for the manufacturers' business.</p><p>For mathematical simplicity, we assume that the prequalified suppliers of one manufacturer are different from those of the other manufacturer (i.e., manufacturers have different upstream suppliers). In §6, we will relax this assumption and allow overlapping suppliers (i.e., some suppliers can contract with both manufacturers).</p><p>Assumption 2. Upstream suppliers' marginal costs are private information and independently follow a uniform distribution U 0 1 .</p><p>The cost structure of manufacturers consists of procurement cost and other costs. To simplify exposition, we assume that the sum of all other costs for each manufacturer remains a constant and is further normalized to zero. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Examples of real-world B2B e-markets that partly resemble this feature (and the structure in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>) include Covisint in the auto industry, Exostar in aerospace industry, and the Global Healthcare Exchange in health-care industry. They have a small number of downstream firms to do business with some prequalified upstream firms. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> For example, evidence shows that it is useful for auto manufacturers to procure from prequalified suppliers who get involved in collaborative new product development <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Zirpoli and Caputo 2002)</ref>. Price is not the only consideration when choosing suppliers. A manufacturer could procure car components from a dedicated supplier who offers a higher price than other nonprequalified suppliers.</p><p>Suppliers compete for contracts via a Vickrey second-bid auction. We make this assumption for two reasons. First, English auction is currently the dominant mechanism on the Internet <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Pinker et al. 2003)</ref>. Second, the outcome of the English auction can be achieved by the Vickrey auction, and it is customary to model an English auction as a Vickrey auction <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Milgrom 1989)</ref>.</p><p>Regarding the information structure, there are two possible informational schemes: transparent and opaque. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> First, if the e-market is run as a transparent platform (i.e., bidding prices are revealed), suppliers' bids are visible to both manufacturers (see Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>), which means that both manufacturers can observe each other's procurement cost. Second, if the e-market is run as an opaque platform, suppliers' bids are visible only to the corresponding manufacturer, not to its competitor. That is, there are two separate auctions (similar to those private exchanges discussed in §1). In contrast to the transparent market, each manufacturer's procurement cost remains as private information. The following assumption summarizes the difference between the two information structures.</p><p>Assumption 3. The transparent market enables manufacturers to share their cost information. Assumption 4. A manufacturer-owned (or supplierowned) B2B e-market seeks to maximize expected gains of manufacturers (or suppliers), whereas a neutral B2B e-market seeks to maximize the total expected gain of suppliers and manufacturers.</p><p>Given the information structures defined above, the sequence of events is as follows. Prequalified upstream suppliers compete for downstream orders via bidding. After the bidding is closed, both manufacturers collect necessary information from the B2B e-market and then make decisions on their procurement quantities. After receiving purchased inputs from upstream suppliers, both manufacturers assemble final products and sell to consumers.</p><p>Manufacturers are engaged in Cournot competition with an inverse demand function from the consumer market,</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">p m1 = d − q m1 − q m2 p m2 = d − q m2 − q m1</formula><p>where q mi is the quantity sold by manufacturer i (i = 1 2), p mi is the price set by manufacturer i (i = 1 2), and d is the demand intercept. We further assume that 0 &lt; &lt; 1, which means that the impact of a unit change of q mi on p mi is greater than that of q mj on p mi (that is, p mi / q mi &gt; p mi / q mj , where i = j). To avoid degenerate solutions, we follow prior literature by assuming that the demand intercept is sufficiently large. Also, all firms are risk neutral. The notation used in this paper is given in the appendix.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">The Effects of Information Transparency</head><p>Based on the above model setup, we study the effects of information transparency on the manufacturers, the suppliers, and the total e-market, respectively. Denote the cost to manufacturer i by c mi (i = 1 2), which is the best price that it can get from its prequalified supplier. Let the lowest cost of its upstream suppliers be s l1 i and the second-lowest cost be s l2 i . The strategic variable for a supplier is its bidding price. In a Vickrey auction with endogenous quantity, a supplier's optimal bidding will reveal its true marginal cost, an equilibrium result established in standard auction theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Hansen 1988</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">, Milgrom 1989</ref>). 9 Thus, c mi = s l2 i i = 1 2 , manufacturer i's cost is equivalent to the second-lowest cost of its prequalified suppliers. According to the information structure of the e-market, c mi is revealed to manufacturer j (j = 1 2 j = i) in a transparent e-market but remains private in an opaque e-market.</p><p>First, we consider the transparent e-market. After c mj is revealed to manufacturer i, its problem is max</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">q mi T mi = d − q mi − q mj − c mi • q mi i = 1 2 i = j</formula><p>where T mi , c mi , and q mi are manufacturer i's profit, cost, and quantity, respectively. As discussed above, c mj is observable to manufacturer i through the e-market platform. Thus, manufacturer i may use c mj to compute q mj , indicating that q mj is known to i by computation. Solving the two manufacturers' problems, we get the following results (see the appendix for details):</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">p T mi = 1 4 − 2 d 2 − + 2 − 2 c mi + c mj q T mi = 1 4 − 2 d 2 − − 2c mi + c mj</formula><p>where the superscript T stands for a transparent market. It follows</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">E T mi = 1 36 1 2 − 2 + 17 + 12d 3d − 4 2 + 2 E T si = 6d 2 − + 4 − 9 18 4 − 2</formula><p>(1) <ref type="bibr">9</ref> Here, we borrow a result from established literature in which the bidders' decision problem has been analyzed via game-theoretic models. Although we do not repeat the analysis, suppliers are still strategic.</p><p>where E T mi is the expected profit of manufacturer i in the transparent B2B e-market, and E T si is the expected profit of manufacturer i's supplier who wins the auction. By symmetry, E T , the total expected profit of all participants, is</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">E T = 2E T mi +2E T si = 2d 3d + −2 3 2+ 2 + 2 9−2 −8 9 4− 2 2</formula><p>(2)</p><p>Now, considering the opaque e-market, we get the following results (see the appendix for details):</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">p O mi = 3d − − 2 3 2 + + 1 2 c mi + c mj q O mi = 1 2 2 + 2d + 2 3 − 2 + c mi E O mi = 1 2 + 2 d − 2 3 2 +</formula><p>1 72</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">E O si = 1 72 2 + 24d − 18 − (3) E O = 2E O mi + 2E O si = 2 3d − 2 3d + 9 2 + 2 (4)</formula><p>Comparing Equation (1) with Equation (3) and Equation (2) with Equation (4), we obtain the following result:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">E T mi − E O mi = 2 12 − 2 / 72 4 − 2 2 &gt; 0 E T si − E O si = − 2 / 72 4 − 2 &lt; 0 E T − E O = 2 2 / 9 4 − 2 2 &gt; 0</formula><p>This shows that manufacturers will benefit from, and suppliers will be hurt by, information transparency. The overall effect is still positive. The prior literature has shown that vertical information sharing about demand creates value to a supply chain (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Lee et al. 2000)</ref>. Here, we obtain a consistent result but in an expanded setting where the information transparency is about cost rather than demand, and there are competing firms in both upstream and downstream-none is a monopoly. Thus, our result, based on a B2B e-market that makes this feasible, brings additional insights into the value of information in a more realistic two-level e-market setting.</p><p>Marketing Science 29(6), pp. 1125-1137, © 2010 INFORMS</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>It is easy to verify that</head><formula xml:id="formula_10">E b mi = E q b mi 2 = E q b mi 2 +var q b mi , where b = T or O. Further, E q T m1 = E q O m1 = 3d − 2 3 2 + Then E T mi − E O mi = var q T mi − var q O mi .</formula><p>When the downstream firm's decision variable is quantity (that is, Cournot competition in the downstream industry), a transparent B2B e-market makes the quantity more responsive to market conditions and thus makes it more volatile compared with that in an opaque B2B e-market. Thus, we have var</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">q T m1 &gt; var q O m1 , which leads to E T mi &gt; E O mi .</formula><p>The intuition is that a transparent market helps manufacturers coordinate their quantity strategies, leading to more efficient production and thus greater expected profits for both.</p><p>It can be shown that</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">E b si = E q b mi s l2 i − s l1 i + cov q b mi s l2 i − s l1 i where b = T or O. Further, E q T mi s l2 i − s l1 i = E q O mi s l2 i − s l1 i Then E T si − E O si = cov q T mi s l2 i − s l1 i − cov q O mi s l2 i − s l1 i .</formula><p>Consider a supplier (say, S 1a ) who wins the bid. Supplier S 1a hopes that q m1 and s l2</p><p>1 − s l1</p><p>1 have a more positive correlation. That is, when S 1a 's profit margin s l2</p><p>1 − s l1</p><p>1 is large, q m1 is also large. However, s l2</p><p>1 − s l1 1 in a transparent e-market tends to be more negatively associated with q m1 than in an opaque market. This can be illustrated by</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">cov q T m1 s l2 1 −s l1 1 = −1/ 18 4− 2 &lt; cov q O m1 s l2 1 −s l1 1 = −1/72</formula><p>It means that a high-cost manufacturer is less likely to "incorrectly" order a large quantity in a transparent e-market than in an opaque market, but such a "mistake" is desirable to suppliers. In this sense, information transparency works against suppliers. Proposition 1 has important managerial implications to e-market operators. The first business implication is that the ownership structure of an e-market affects the choice between transparency and opaqueness. Second, regarding the information transparency, a conflict of interest between suppliers and manufacturers exists in a setting where both sides engage in competition, whereas the prior literature generally does not consider the competition within both levels.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Bertrand Competition in Downstream Industry</head><p>The above analysis assumes that manufacturers compete on quantity. In this section, we consider Bertrand competition where manufacturers compete on price. Manufacturer i's demand function is</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">q mi = d − p mi + p mj i = 1 2 i = j</formula><p>where p mi and p mj are prices charged by manufacturers i and j, respectively. Again, 0 &lt; &lt; 1, which means that the impact of M i 's price change on M i 's demand is greater than the impact of M j 's price change (that is, q mi / p mi &gt; q mi / p mj ). Using a similar process as that in the previous section, we derive the following results.</p><p>In a transparent e-market,</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">p T mi = 1 4 − 2 d 2 + + 2c mi + c mj q T mi = 1 4 − 2 d 2 + − 2 − 2 c mi + c mj E T mi = 1 6 2 − 2 6d 2 − 8d 1 − + 3 1 − 2 + 2 − 2 9 4 − 2 2</formula><p>(5)</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">E T si = 1 6 − 3 d − 1 36 4 − 2 18 − 8 + 9 (6) E T = 2E T mi + 2E T si = 2d 2 2 − 2 − 2d 2 − 3 3 2 − 2 + 3 2 8 + 3 − 32 18 4 − 2 2 (7)</formula><p>In an opaque e-market,</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">p O mi = 3d + 3 2 − + 1 2 c mi q O mi = 3d − 1 − 3 2 − − 1 2 c mi − c mj E O mi = d 2 2 − 2 − 4d 1 − 3 2 − 2 + 36 + 33 − 68 72 2 − 2 (8) E O si = d 3 2 − − 18 − 17 72 2 − (9) E O = 2E O mi + 2E O si = 2 3d + 3d + 2 − 2 9 2 − 2 (10)</formula><p>These equations represent the expected profits for the manufacturers, the suppliers, and the total e-market under transparent and opaque markets, respectively. Comparing Equation (5) with Equation ( <ref type="formula">8</ref>), Equation (6) with Equation ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>), and Equation (7) with Equation (10), we obtain the following result:</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">E T mi − E O mi = − 2 4 − 3 2 / 72 4 − 2 2 &lt; 0 E T si − E O si = 2 / 288 − 72 2 &gt; 0 E T − E O = 4 / 18 4 − 2 2 &gt; 0</formula><p>It shows that information transparency hurts manufacturers but benefits suppliers and the whole e-market. </p><formula xml:id="formula_19">c m1 =c + c m2 =c c m1 =c − c m2 =c p p m1 ↑ p m2 ↑ p m1 ↓ p m2 ↓ m1 ↑ m2 ↑ m1 ↓ m2 ↓</formula><p>Proposition 2. When the downstream industry engages in Bertrand competition, a supplier-owned and a neutral B2B e-market prefer a transparent e-market model, whereas a manufacturer-owned B2B e-market prefers an opaque e-market model.</p><p>Recall that information transparency benefits downstream manufacturers when they compete on quantity, but here it turns to be against them under Bertrand competition. Following a similar analysis as that for the Cournot competition, we can show that</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">E T mi − E O mi = var q T mi − var q O mi .</formula><p>Again, a transparent e-market makes the decision variable, which is price in Bertrand competition, more responsive to market conditions. However, price absorbs most of the market uncertainties, leading to a reduction of the variance of quantity and thus a reduction of the expected profits of manufacturers. Another way of illustrating the intuition is showing how prices and profits are affected by the information transparency under different scenarios.</p><p>In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, we fix M 2 's cost to be the expected costc and let M 1 's cost be slightly higher (or lower) thanc. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows that when M 1 's cost is slightly higher thanc, then the information transparency increases M 1 's price and profit. This is because when M 2 realizes that M 1 is a less competitive firm than expected (c m1 &gt;c), M 2 increases its price (p m2 ↑). Consequently, M 1 faces a softened price competition and thus is able to increase its price as well. In this case, the information transparency helps M 1 . However, when M 1 's cost is a little bit lower thanc, then the information transparency works against M 1 . The reason is that M 2 reduces its price when it realizes that it faces a more competitive firm than expected (c m1 &lt;c). Such reaction causes M 1 to reduce its price as well, resulting in an intensified price competition, which hurts both manufacturers. It can be verified that M 1 's gain from the first case is less than its loss from the second case:</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">m1 c m1 =c + c m2 =c + m1 c m1 =c − c m2 =c &lt; 0</formula><p>Thus, the information transparency reduces a manufacturer's expected profit. Following a similar analysis as that for the Cournot competition, we find that a winning supplier (say, S 1a ) hopes that q m1 and s l2 1 − s l1</p><p>1 have a more positive correlation, and it can be shown that cov</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">q T m1 s l2 1 − s l1 1 &gt; cov q O m1 s l2 1 − s l1 1 .</formula><p>That is, when S 1a 's profit margin s l2 1 − s l1 1 is large, q m1 in a transparent e-market tends to be larger than that in an opaque e-market. The intuition is that a transparent e-market enables a manufacturer to adjust its price according to its competitors' cost. In Bertrand competition, both manufacturers can raise their prices without losing too much demand, especially when is close to 1 (noting that the demand of M 1 is q 1 = d − p 1 + p 2 ). This suggests that when s l2 1 − s l1</p><p>1 is large in a transparent e-market, q T m1 still can be large as a result of price adjustments by manufacturers. Thus, a transparent e-market benefits suppliers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Conflict of Interest Regarding</head><p>Information Transparency As a quick summary of the analysis so far, we have found that the effect of information transparency on the upstream is always opposite to the effect on the downstream. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> summarizes these effects. It means that information transparency can benefit one side but at the cost of the other side, indicating an inherent conflict of interest regarding information transparency. The competition mode in the downstream industry determines which side will be hurt.</p><p>We have shown that a neutral e-market prefers a transparent e-market model. However, if manufacturers or suppliers have an alternative choice to establish an opaque e-market by themselves, then the operator of a neutral e-market could lose its customers. For example, when the downstream is Cournot competition, manufacturers could establish an opaque manufacturer-owned e-market when these manufacturers have more market power than suppliers. The conflict of interest between buyers and sellers in such an e-market has been conceptually addressed in the prior literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Sairamesh et al. 2002)</ref>. This paper uses an analytical model to illustrate such conflict of interest regarding information transparency in a neutral e-market. This result offers an important managerial insight to a neutral e-market operator. It suggests that the operator may need to reallocate the informational benefits between buyers and sellers (e.g., charging one side while compensating the other side) so that both sides have no incentives to establish their own private e-markets. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">The Effects on Consumers</head><p>Our above analysis focuses on the informational effects on business participants. Now we consider the broader effects on consumers (the lowest tier in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>). If the downstream industry engages in Cournot competition, the consumer surplus (CS) can be expressed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">CS = 2 i=1 q i 0 d − q i − q 3−i dq i − d − q i − q 3−i q i = 1 2 q 2 m1 + q 2 m2</formula><p>If the e-market is transparent, then CS</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">T = 1 2 q T m1 2 + q T m2 2 . If the e-market is opaque, then CS O = 1 2 q O m1 2 + q O m2 2 .</formula><p>Using the results established earlier, it can be shown that</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">E CS T − E CS O = 2 12 − 2 / 72 4 − 2 2 &gt; 0</formula><p>meaning that consumer surplus in the transparent e-market is higher than that in the opaque e-market.</p><p>The intuition is as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">E CS T − E CS O = E q T m1 2 − E q O m1 2 by symmetry. It can be shown that E q T m1 = E q O m1 = 3d − 2 / 3 2 + . Then E CS T − E CS O = E q T m1 2 + var q T m1 − E q O m1 2 − var q O m1 = var q T m1 − var q O m1 . This shows that E CS T &gt; E CS O because var q T m1 &gt; var q O m1 .</formula><p>As discussed earlier, when downstream firms engage in Cournot competition, their quantities are more responsive to market conditions than those in an opaque e-market. Thus, we have var q T m1 &gt; var q O m1 and E CS T &gt; E CS O . This shows that a higher variance of quantity makes consumers better off.</p><p>As shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref>, the information transparency benefits the e-market as a whole. It follows that the information transparency increases the social welfare (SW) when the downstream competition is Cournot competition. That is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">E SW T &gt; E SW O where SW T = T + CS T and SW O = O + CS O .</formula><p>Now, consider the Bertrand competition in the downstream industry. We follow a similar derivation process to arrive at</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">E CS T − E CS O = − 2 20 − 11 2 + 4 / 72 4 − 2 2 &lt; 0 E SW T − E SW O = − 2 20 − 15 2 + 4 / 72 4 − 2 2 &lt; 0 We find that E CS T &lt; E CS O because var q T m1 &lt; var q O m1 .</formula><p>As discussed earlier, when downstream firms engage in Bertrand competition, a transparent e-market increases the variance of the decision variable (that is, price). However, it reduces the variance of quantity because the decision variable has absorbed most of the market uncertainties. This explains var q T m1 &lt; var q O m1 in Bertrand competition, and this hurts consumers.</p><p>Proposition 3. When the downstream industry engages in Cournot competition, information transparency benefits end consumers and increases the total social welfare. When the downstream industry engages in Bertrand competition, information transparency hurts end consumers and reduces the total social welfare. Interestingly, when the downstream industry engages in Cournot competition, there is no conflict of interest between consumers and upstream firms. However, when the downstream industry engages in Bertrand competition, a conflict of interest between end consumers and upstream firms arises. This is summarized in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref>.</p><p>The finding that when the downstream competition is Bertrand-type, information transparency hurts consumers is a rather surprising, and perhaps unintended, consequence of electronic markets. The common belief about the Internet-enabled e-markets has been that they are largely positive for consumers <ref type="bibr">(Bakos 1997, Hitt and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Brynjolfsson 1996)</ref>. Our results indicate that this is not always the case.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Extensions</head><p>Our results thus far were obtained under certain assumptions, and we realize that some of them may seem restrictive. In this section, we attempt to relax some of the assumptions and extend the base model in several dimensions. We will see that the simple base model is in fact able to demonstrate the major result, whereas the extended model confirms its robustness.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.">Overlapping Suppliers in Upstream Channel</head><p>The base model assumes that each downstream manufacturer has its own dedicated supplier base in the upstream. Now we relax this assumption by allowing manufacturers to have common suppliers; i.e., a supplier may trade with both manufacturers, who in turn compete on quantity in the consumer market. Thus, it becomes possible that both manufacturers may procure from the same supplier (as illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>). In fact, this is becoming increasingly common as the outsourcing trend continues. </p><formula xml:id="formula_29">M 1 M 2 c m1 c m2 Consumers q m1 q m2 p mi = d -q mi -q mj Bidding (B) k s Common suppliers</formula><p>We assume that each manufacturer has k prequalified suppliers, among which k s suppliers are commonly shared by both manufacturers (k ≥ k s ≥ 0, k ≥ 2, k k s ∈ N ). Sharing common suppliers may have two effects on manufacturers. First, it increases the cost correlation between manufacturers as they tend to get similar prices from the upstream industry. That is, cov c m1 c m2 is no longer zero. Second, information spillover may arise even in an opaque e-market when k s ≥ 1. This is because M i may observe the bidding prices of common suppliers. This information may be used to infer M j 's cost, even in an opaque market structure. These two effects introduce new complexities. Albeit a tedious process, it can be shown that</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">mi = E T mi − E O mi ≥ 0 si = E T si − E O si ≤ 0 = E T − E O ≥ 0</formula><p>This is consistent with what we have established in Proposition 1. Moreover,</p><formula xml:id="formula_31">mi k s + 1 − mi k s &lt; 0 si k s + 1 − si k s &gt; 0 k s + 1 − k s &lt; 0</formula><p>This establishes the following result.</p><p>Proposition 4. If upstream suppliers are allowed to trade with both manufacturers who engage in Cournot competition, the value of information transparency to the total e-market ( ) and to a manufacturer ( mi ) and a supplier's loss caused by information transparency ( si ) decrease as the number of overlapping suppliers increases.</p><p>This proposition shows that the benefits of information transparency go down when the number of overlapping suppliers goes up. The key reason is that information spillover via overlapping suppliers partly substitutes the value of information transparency. To see why, suppose that both manufacturers share a completely overlapping set of suppliers (k = k s ); then it no longer matters whether the B2B e-market is opaque or transparent because a manufacturer would know the competitor's cost in both types of information structures. In this extreme case, the informational value of the transparent e-market would be neutralized.</p><p>As shown in §3, information transparency benefits the manufacturers and the total e-market. This section shows that information transparency can be achieved in two ways: (1) adopting a transparent e-market structure, and (2) sharing common suppliers. A natural question then arises: Which way would be more beneficial (a) to manufacturers, (b) to suppliers, and (c) to consumers? The following proposition provides an answer.</p><p>Proposition 5. Compared to adopting a transparent e-market, sharing common suppliers hurts manufacturers and end consumers, but it benefits suppliers.</p><p>It can be shown that</p><formula xml:id="formula_32">E T mi ≥ E O mi k s = k E T si ≤ E O si k s = k</formula><p>which indicates that sharing common suppliers is suboptimal to achieve information transparency.</p><p>Using common suppliers increases the information transparency on the one hand, but it has an unintended consequence on the other hand: increasing manufacturer cost correlation cov c mi c mj . The first effect benefits manufacturers and the second hurts them because manufacturers would be more likely to have the same cost (or less differentiated), which may intensify head-to-head competition between them. Proposition 5 suggests that the net effect is negative to manufacturers. It also shows that upstream suppliers can take advantage of the intensified competition between downstream manufacturers. This result warns managers to be mindful about the mechanism of information transparency. The increasing reliance on common contract suppliers may have unintentional consequences of information spillover despite the growing trend of outsourcing.</p><p>Last, but important to note, consumers are hurt by this kind of information transparency because sharing suppliers reduces the variance of quantity (when both manufacturers have the same suppliers, then their quantities are the same). Following a similar analysis as that shown in §5, we show that</p><formula xml:id="formula_33">E CS T − E CS O k s = k = var q T m1 − var q O m1 k s = k = var q T m1 &gt; 0</formula><p>Marketing Science 29(6), pp. 1125-1137, © 2010 INFORMS Thus, a reduction in quantity variance reduces consumer surplus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.">Asymmetric Upstream Channels</head><p>The base model assumes that each of the two manufacturers has two prequalified upstream suppliers.</p><p>This assumption can be relaxed by allowing each manufacturer, M i , to have an arbitrary number, k i , of suppliers, and without losing generality, let k 2 ≥ k 1 ≥ 2, k i ∈ N . Manufacturers could have an asymmetric number of prequalified suppliers. We derive the expected manufacturer profit and supplier profit as in the appendix. It follows that ). The expected loss of that manufacturer's winning supplier is more than that of the other manufacturer's winning supplier ( s1 ≥ s2 ). As discussed earlier, information transparency tends to help Cournot manufacturers coordinate their quantity strategies. Because k 2 ≥ k 1 ≥ 2, M 2 is more likely to obtain a lower procurement price than that obtained by M 1 and thus is more competitive than M 1 . Information transparency reduces M 1 's cost uncertainty in M 2 's eyes and makes M 2 less aggressive than otherwise in an opaque e-market. This is the source of informational benefits to M 1 . Given the fact that M 2 is more competitive than M 1 in terms of cost advantage, a decrease in the agressiveness of M 2 is certainly more valuable to M 1 than a decrease in the aggressiveness of M 1 to M 2 , all else being equal.</p><formula xml:id="formula_34">mi = E T mi − E O mi &gt; 0 si = E T si − E O si &lt; 0 = E T − E O &gt;</formula><p>On the other hand, information transparency makes suppliers worse off because a high-cost manufacturer in a transparent e-market is less likely to "incorrectly" order a large quantity than in an opaque market. Note that M 1 is more likely to be a higher-cost manufacturer than M 2 . This suggests that the negative effect of information transparency would have a stronger impact on M 1 's winning supplier than on M 2 's winning supplier.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">Discussion and Conclusions</head><p>This paper studies marketing channels and associated information transparency in an e-market where suppliers compete for orders from downstream manufacturers in a B2B e-market and then manufacturers compete for consumers in a B2C market. Based on a model different from the literature, our study sheds light on several important questions about the effects of information transparency on market participants. Along the way, it makes several contributions to the literature.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1.">Major Findings and Contributions</head><p>First, we find that the information transparency enabled by online trading benefits the overall marketing channel. Prior literature has shown that information sharing about demand benefits the total supply chain. In this paper, our result is obtained in an expanded setting in which we take competition into account (where the informational benefits would have to be divided among market participants). Also, information transparency in this paper refers to transparency about a competitor's cost rather than market demand. Thus this paper takes another step further toward understanding the important but subtle effects of information transparency in an online environment.</p><p>Second, although the information transparency benefits the total marketing channel, the effect on one side is always in conflict with the other side. The competition mode in the downstream e-market determines which side is benefited (or hurt) by the information transparency. Prior literature has shown that the key difference between Cournot and Bertrand competition critically depends on production capacity <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Kreps and</ref><ref type="bibr">Scheinkman 1983, Haskel and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Martin 1994)</ref>. The Cournot model is appropriate when firms are capacity constrained, whereas the Bertrand model fits the case where firms have the capacity to serve the market gained. The auto industry in the United States can be considered a Cournot industry. We find that when the downstream firms engage in Cournot competition, a manufacturer-owned B2B e-market prefers a transparent structure. This finding seems to be consistent with Covisint, which was a transparent B2B platform owned by the big three auto manufacturers. In contrast, the retailing industry in the United States can be considered a Bertrand industry. We find that when the downstream firms engage in Bertrand competition, then an opaque structure is preferred by downstream firms. This finding seems to be consistent with the fact that major U.S. retailers tend to use their own private exchanges to source goods from their suppliers.</p><p>It is commonly believed in the post-bubble era that a lack of overall value creation may kill a neutral B2B e-market. However, this paper suggests information transparency can actually create overall value for a neutral e-market's participants. However, its market operator may need to reallocate informational benefits between sellers and buyers so as to resolve their conflict of interest regarding information transparency. A mismanagement of value reallocation may also cause a problem. Our theoretical model seems to be supported by empirical evidence presented in <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Soh et al. (2006)</ref>, which shows that buyers and sellers have conflicting interests regarding price transparency.</p><p>Finally, we consider the effects on consumers and the total social welfare. It was believed that the Internet-enabled e-markets have been largely positive for consumers. We show that this is not always the case. When the downstream firms engage in Bertrand competition, the consumers are worse off with information transparency. Another surprising result is that information transparency can reduce the total social welfare under certain conditions (that is, when downstream competition is Bertrand-type). These findings suggest that a more transparent e-market is not necessarily socially desirable. Even when it is socially desirable, it may come at a cost to end consumers.</p><p>More broadly, the results of this paper can be applied to other settings where the downstream firms source inputs from upstream suppliers via open bidding and then sell the products to consumers. Also, there may be uncertainty about the costs of the procurement. The transaction platform is not necessarily a B2B e-market. It can be an electronic data integration (EDI), a teleconference bidding system, or a quote via phone or fax, for example.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2.">Future Research</head><p>This paper leaves several issues open for further research. First, our results are obtained under several assumptions about costs, demand, and market structure. We have relaxed some of these assumptions (and the results seem robust). Other assumptions can also be relaxed. For example, one could use more general demand functions and cost distribution and test if our results still hold in more general settings. Second, one could introduce uncertainty in demand functions (e.g., the intercept d is not a constant) and then examine the effects of information transparency. Third, our e-market model can be used to study not only information transparency but also other interesting issues such as the consequences of the increased use of common contract suppliers due to outsourcing. These questions are left for further analysis. We hope that the initial results reported herein will motivate more research in this area.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.">Electronic Companion</head><p>An electronic companion to this paper is available as part of the online version that can be found at http:// mktsci.pubs.informs.org/.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Proposition 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>When the downstream industry engages in Cournot competition, a manufacturer-owned and a neutral B2B e-market prefer a transparent e-market model, whereas a supplier-owned B2B e-market prefers an opaque e-market model.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2Expanded Model with Overlapping Upstream Suppliers</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Impact of Information Transparency on Price, Quantity, and Profit</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="4">The Effects of Information Transparency in B2B E-market</cell></row><row><cell>Downstream</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>competition</cell><cell>Manufacturers</cell><cell>Suppliers</cell><cell>Overall effect</cell></row><row><cell>Cournot</cell><cell>+</cell><cell>−</cell><cell>+</cell></row><row><cell>Bertrand</cell><cell>−</cell><cell>+</cell><cell>+</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>The Effects of Information Transparency</figDesc><table><row><cell>Downstream</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>competition</cell><cell>Consumers</cell><cell>E-market</cell><cell>Social welfare</cell></row><row><cell>Cournot</cell><cell>+</cell><cell>+</cell><cell>+</cell></row><row><cell>Bertrand</cell><cell>−</cell><cell>+</cell><cell>−</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">Defined more precisely in the next section, a transparent e-market refers to an information structure in which a manufacturer is able to see the bids (prices) to other manufacturers in the online market, whereas an opaque e-market refers to an information structure in which a manufacturer is unable to see the bids to other manufacturers.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8">Given that we focus on comparing these two e-market structures, we do not consider the case that firms may trade off-line.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors are listed alphabetically. The authors are grateful to the senior editor, the area editor, and two anonymous reviewers for their valuable comments and suggestions during the revision of this paper. The authors acknowledge the feedback from seminar presentations at Stanford University and the University of California, San Diego, as well as conference participants of International Conference on Information Systems 2007 and the INFORMS Annual Conference 2006. The second author acknowledges the financial support of the CAREER Award from the U.S. National Science Foundation (Grant 0654400) and the financial support from the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grant 70728002).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Transparent E-market. Manufacturer i's problem is max</p><p>Solving the first-order condition and noting that the secondorder condition is satisfied, we have</p><p>where the superscript "T " stands for transparent market. We will substitute this back to the profit function to get E T mi , the expected profit for manufacturer i. Before computing E T mi , we need to obtain the expected value of c mi , E c mi , and its variance, var c mi .</p><p>Noting that c mi = s l2 i , we get the cumulative distribution function (CDF) of c mi as follows:</p><p>The last equality holds because manufacturer i has two prequalified suppliers, and thus the probability that the second-lowest supplier cost is lower than x is equivalent to the probability that the costs of both suppliers are lower than x. It follows that f x = 2x, E c mi = 2/3, and var c mi = 1/18. Because the two manufacturers procure from different suppliers, and the suppliers' marginal costs are independent of each other, we have cov c m1 c m2 = 0. The manufacturer's expected profit can be computed as</p><p>. By symmetry, we have</p><p>It follows that</p><p>Next, we derive the expected profit of the suppliers. It is apparent that, the supplier who loses the bidding obtains zero profit. Now consider the supplier who wins the order from M i . The cost of this supplier is s l1 i , and the price paid to it by M i is s l2 i , where</p><p>si , we need to derive the following results. First, cov s l1 i c mj = cov s l2 i c mj = 0 because s l1 i and s l2 i are independent of c mj . Second, the CDF of</p><p>, and the CDF of</p><p>Using these results, we have</p><p>Inserting Equation ( <ref type="formula">11</ref>) in E T si and noting that c mi = s l2 i , we have</p><p>Using the results obtained above, we have</p><p>By symmetry, the total expected profit of all participants E T in a transparent e-market is</p><p>Opaque E-market. Now, we turn to the opaque B2B e-market in which firms have less information relative to the transparent market design. Manufacturer i's problem is max</p><p>where the superscript O stands for opaque market, and E q mj represents manufacturer i's expectation about manufacturer j's quantity (not directly observable to manufacturer i). Following prior literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Vives 1984</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Vives , 2002</ref>, we derive the Bayesian Nash equilibrium <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Harsanyi 1967)</ref>, which is defined by a pair of strategies and a pair of conjectures such that (a) each firm's strategy is a best response to its conjecture about the behavior of the rival, and (b) the conjectures are unbiased.</p><p>Solving the first-order condition, we have</p><p>This satisfies the first requirement of the Bayesian Nash equilibrium. The second requirement implies that E</p><p>Substituting it back to the profit function yields the expected profit for the manufacturer: Following a similar process as above, we can derive the expected profit for the winning supplier:</p><p>Then, the total profit of all participants, E O , in an opaque e-market is</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Alibaba.com announces full year 2007 results</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alibaba</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.alibaba.com/aboutalibaba/releases_080318.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-03-18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Press release</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reducing buyer search costs: Implications for electronic marketplaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Bakos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1676" to="1692" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information technology, incentives, and the optimal number of suppliers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Bakos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Brynjolfsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Management Inform. Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supply chain inventory management and the value of shared information</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Cachon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1032" to="1048" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competition and cooperation in marketing channel choice: Theory and application</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Coughlan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="110" to="129" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Demand signalling and screening in channels of distribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="327" to="347" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiple messages to retain retailers: Signaling new product demand</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Desai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="381" to="389" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information sharing in oligopoly</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gal-Or</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="329" to="343" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Value of information in capacitated supply chains</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gavirneni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kapuscinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tayur</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pull promotions and channel coordination</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hess</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The benefits of downstream information acquisition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="457" to="471" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Auctions with endogenous quantity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Hansen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">RAND J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="58" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Games with incomplete information played by &quot;Bayesian&quot; players, I-III. Part I. The basic model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Harsanyi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="182" />
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Capacity and competition: Empirical evidence on UK panel data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Haskel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Indust. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="44" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vertical information sharing in a volatile market</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Marklund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Vossen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="513" to="530" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Productivity, business profitability, and consumer surplus: Three different measures of information technology value</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Brynjolfsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">MIS Quart</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="142" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coordinating channels under price and nonprice competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Iyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="338" to="355" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information and inventory in distribution channels</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Iyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Narasimhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Niraj</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1551" to="1561" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing channel profits</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Jeuland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="272" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design of robust business-to-business electronic marketplaces with guaranteed privacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kalvenes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Basu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1721" to="1736" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interview: Covisint&apos;s last chance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.cio.com/archive/120102/ecomm.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">CIO</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002-12-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantity precommitment and Bertrand competition yield Cournot outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kreps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Scheinkman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bell J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="326" to="337" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manufacturer benefits from information integration with retail customers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Kulp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ofek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="431" to="444" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information distortion in a supply chain: The bullwhip effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Padmanabhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Whang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="546" to="558" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The value of information sharing in a two-level supply chain</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>So</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="626" to="643" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Retail exchanges GNX and WWRE agree to merger</title>
		<ptr target="http://logisticstoday.com/global_markets/outlog_story_7127/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-05-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Logistics Today</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Auctions and bidding: A primer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Milgrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Perspect</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing online auctions: Current business and research issues</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Pinker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Seidmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Vakrat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1457" to="1484" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A general model of information sharing in oligopoly</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Raith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="288" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A platform for business-to-business sell-side, private exchanges and marketplaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sairamesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mohan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hasson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bender</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IBM Systems J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="242" to="252" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advertising in a distribution channel</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Shaffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Zettelmeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="619" to="628" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exchange of cost information in oligopoly</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="433" to="446" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electronic marketplaces and price transparency: Strategy, information technology and success</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Soh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Markus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Goh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">MIS Quart</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="705" to="723" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">E-stats-Measuring the electronic economy: Frequently asked questions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bureau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.census.gov/eos/www/faq.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quarterly retail e-commerce sales: 2nd quarter</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bureau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.census.gov/retail/mrts/www/data/html/09Q2.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-08-17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Duopoly information equilibrium: Cournot and Bertrand</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Vives</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="94" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Private information, strategic behavior, and efficiency in Cournot markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Vives</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">RAND J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="361" to="376" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electronic B2B marketplaces with different ownership structures</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Yoo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Choudhary</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mukhopadhyay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="952" to="961" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information transparency of business-to-business electronic markets: A game-theoretic analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="670" to="685" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The nature of the buyer-supplier relationships in co-design activities: The Italian auto industry case</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Zirpoli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Caputo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Oper. Production Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1389" to="1410" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
