<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Modeling the Underreporting Bias in Panel Survey Data</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2009-12-02">December 2, 2009.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sha</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
							<email>shayang@stern.nyu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yi</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Ravi</forename><surname>Dhar</surname></persName>
							<email>ravi.dhar@yale.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Mack</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Leonard N. Stern School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">New York University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>10012</postCode>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>New York</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Economics and Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Southwest Jiaotong University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>610031</postCode>
									<settlement>Chengdu</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">College of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Georgia State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>30302</postCode>
									<settlement>Atlanta</settlement>
									<region>Georgia</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Yale School of Management</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>06520</postCode>
									<settlement>New Haven, Connecticut</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Modeling the Underreporting Bias in Panel Survey Data</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2009-12-02">December 2, 2009.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1090.0536</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: March 4, 2008; accepted: September 2, 2009; processed by Michel Wedel.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:27+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>panel survey data analysis</term>
					<term>measurement error</term>
					<term>underreporting</term>
					<term>Bayesian analysis</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Survey is a popular marketing research tool for collecting information on consumer attitudes and behaviors. When it is difficult to directly observe consumer actions, marketers often rely on surveys to have respondents report their behaviors over time and collect longitudinal panel survey data. With the advent of new digital technology, the use of diary data is increasing. For example, advertising research companies repeatedly collect media usage information from the same respondent for every hour in an entire week. Beverage companies recruit participants to record their beverage consumption on any drinking occasion in a given time period.</p><p>Panel survey data have two primary benefits compared with cross-sectional survey data. First, panel survey data allow marketers to collect microlevel information such as when consumption occurs and what type of product is consumed in every consumption occasion. Such microlevel information helps marketers gain more insights on consumer behavior. Second, panel survey data make it convenient to study consumer behavioral dynamics. For example, diary data allow marketers to study how past behaviors affect current behavior, which can be useful in many marketing research contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Guadagni and</ref><ref type="bibr">Little 1983, Erdem and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Keane 1996)</ref>.</p><p>At the same time, collecting multiday data creates the problem of underreporting if a respondent's ability and willingness to keep accurate recording declines over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Kitamura and Bovy 1987)</ref>, making it difficult to estimate econometric models. Underreporting has been documented <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Turner 1961</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">, Waksberg and Neter 1965</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">, Lee et al. 2000</ref> and modeled <ref type="bibr">(Bailar 1975, Marketing</ref>   <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bollinger and David 1997)</ref> in the literature. Imagine the following scenario where marketing researchers have respondents make a record and answer a few consumption-related questions whenever consumption of a product occurs for a two-week period. In such context especially when the survey involves a frequently consumed product, underreporting is especially likely to occur because the data recording mechanism is tedious, complex, and effortful. Moreover, this underreporting probability is likely to increase in the later stage of the longitudinal survey because respondents may feel less involved in the task. Finally, this underreporting probability is likely to vary across respondents because of the heterogeneity in their ability or willingness to accurately report consumption patterns.</p><p>If underreporting occurs, it would be difficult to study respondents' true behavior based on reported panel survey data. For example, if we find women tend to drink soft drinks less often than men, it could be due to the gender difference in consumption propensity, or because women are more likely to underreport than men when participating in the longitudinal survey, or both. What becomes more problematic is when estimating the state-dependence effect in the consumption, i.e., the effect of last period consumption incidence on the current period consumption utility. Because last period consumption incidence is measured with error, the state-dependence effect is likely to be biased if such omission error is not accounted for.</p><p>In this paper, we address these aforementioned challenges by proposing a model to simultaneously study reported behavioral incidences and partially observed true behavioral incidences. Given the complexity of the proposed model, we propose a Bayesian estimation approach. The essence of the proposed estimation method is to treat the actual behavioral incidences as latent variables, and the Gibbs sampler makes it convenient to impute these nonreported consumption incidences along with making inferences on other model parameters. The proposed model and estimation approach are tested on both synthetic data and actual panel survey data on consumer reported beverage consumption behavior. Our analysis suggests that underreporting can significantly mask respondents' true behavior.</p><p>Our proposed model has two important managerial implications. First, it offers a model-based approach to remove the underreporting bias in panel survey data and therefore allows marketing researchers to make accurate inferences about consumer behavior. Our empirical analysis with both simulated and actual data suggests that it is important to control for the underreporting to avoid biased inferences. Second, our model offers a natural way to study the factors that influence a respondent's propensity to underreport. Because we treat those underreported behavioral incidences as nonmissing at random (NMAR), this underreporting propensity varies across respondents and over time. This understanding can help marketing researchers design the right strategy to intervene and incentivize respondents to accurately report and therefore improve the quality of panel survey data.</p><p>The remainder of this paper is organized as follows. We will next review the relevant literature on data measurement in panel survey data. We then propose a model and a Bayesian estimation approach to study the underreporting behavior. We then apply the proposed model to a panel survey data set collected by a large beverage manufacturer on consumer beverage consumption behavior and discuss the empirical findings. We conclude the paper with a brief summary and potential extensions of our study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Literature Review</head><p>Studies describing response error with consumer survey data in marketing can be dated back to the 1960s. <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Sudman (1964)</ref> documented the accuracy of consumer panel data and studied the determining factors. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Mandell and Lundsten (1978)</ref> provided evidence of underreporting of financial data by survey respondents because high-asset households may consistently underestimate their asset holdings. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Hawkins and Coney (1981)</ref> documented the uninformed response error in survey research and examined factors that influence respondents' tendency to make an uninformed response. There has been abundant evidence in the literature suggesting biases in survey results of behavioral frequency, and marketing researchers have examined factors attributing to these biases and ways to reduce biases with improved questions <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Menon 1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Menon , 1997</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Lee et al. (2000)</ref> investigated how actual behavioral frequency and duration systematically affect the direction of errors in consumer survey responses. They demonstrate that high-frequency groups underreported their behavioral frequencies, whereas low-frequency groups overreported them. Although actual usage data are accessible in those aforementioned studies, they are not readily available in many other cases such as consumption incidence, creating a challenge to determine the magnitude of the response error. Our paper extends this line of literature by proposing a modeling framework to study the actual behavioral incidence and the underreporting mechanism simultaneously.</p><p>Our research is methodologically related to some work in statistics on modeling discrete choice or quantity with response error in cross-sectional survey data. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bradlow and Zaslavsky (1999)</ref> modeled the "no answer" responses in customer satisfaction survey. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bollinger and David (1997)</ref> studied the omission and commission error in the reported food stamp participation. Several other papers have modeled underreported counted data such as purchase quantity <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Schmittlein et al. 1985</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">, Winkelmann 1996</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">, Fader and Hardie 2000</ref>. Our study differs and extends this line of work in the following two ways. First, unlike these prior studies that focused on crosssectional self-reported data, we study panel study data with the state-dependence effect. The impact of last period behavioral incidence on the current period utility, i.e., the state-dependence effect, is an important element to include when modeling panel data. As we show later, estimating state-dependence effect adds additional complexity in the analysis of panel survey data with response error, and it is difficult to estimate such a model with traditional estimation approaches. To the best of our knowledge, we are the first to incorporate state-dependence effect in analyzing longitudinal panel survey data while correcting for the underreporting bias. Second, in our proposed framework, we simultaneously model the factors that drive true behavioral incidence and the underreporting likelihood. Consequently, such a model allows researchers to disentangle the effect of the same covariate on respondents' true behavior and their likelihood of underreporting.</p><p>In the statistics literature, researchers have modeled the phenomenon that the likelihood of underreporting is likely to increase over time as the respondent loses interest and incentive in longitudinal panel surveys. The common approach to statistically control for such effect is to model the dependent variable (continuous or discrete) as a function of explanatory covariates and a time trend (see <ref type="bibr">Fuller 1995 for a discussion)</ref>. This approach has several limitations. First, this approach assumes that there is no underreporting in the first period, which is a strong assumption. Second, the time trend specification does not allow researchers to disentangle the dynamics from the reporting behavior and the dynamics from the actual behavior. For example, the observation that reported consumption frequency decreases over the survey period can be driven by that respondents are underreporting towards the later stage or respondents are indeed drinking less because of the seasonal variation. Third, because the underlying process of underreporting is not modeled in this standard approach, researchers are not able to disentangle the effect of the same covariate on the respondent's true consumption behavior and on the respondent's underreporting tendency. Finally, it will be very difficult, if at all possible, to model the state dependence in true consumption behavior, with this standard approach. This is because lagged reported consumption incidence is measured with error and this measurement error needs to be statistically controlled. The goal of this paper is to propose a model to address these aforementioned limitations.</p><p>Finally, our research is related to marketing studies on response style. Ter <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Hofstede et al. (1999)</ref> modeled the response scale usage in their market segmentation research. <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Rossi et al. (2001)</ref> addressed the issue that respondents vary in their scale usage when answering survey questions and proposed a statistical model with individual scale and location effects to capture scale usage differences. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bradlow et al. (2004)</ref> developed a learning-based imputation model to study how respondents infer missing levels of product attributes in conjoint studies with partial conjoint profiles. <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Gilbride et al. (2005)</ref> proposed a modeling approach and empirically showed how brand usage and attribute perception responses are jointly determined by justification, order, and brand halo effects. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Baumgartner and Steenkamp (2001)</ref> examined five forms of stylistic responding (acquiescence and disacquiescence response styles, extreme response style and response range, midpoint responding, and noncontingent responding) and discussed their biasing effects on scale scores and correlations between scales. de <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Jong et al. (2008)</ref> studied the extreme response style in marketing research using item response theory. Marketing researchers have examined how fatigue can affect respondent's choice behavior in conjoint studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Otter et al. 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">, Liechty et al. 2005</ref> and attrition biases in dairy panel <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Toh and Hu 1996)</ref>. Researchers have also studied social desirability response style and how to control for social desirability bias in survey research <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Ganster et al. 1983</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">, Fisher 1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">, Jo et al. 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">, de Jong et al. 2010</ref>. Our study complements this line of research by modeling one type of response style, underreporting, in the context of longitudinal panel survey research. In the following section, we lay out the model, describe how to estimate the proposed model using Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) with data augmentation, and test the proposed model and estimation approach with synthetic data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Model</head><p>Let R it stand for the reported incidence of a behavior and Y it stand for the actual incidence of a behavior (such as consumption of a product) by respondent i at time t in the survey period. When underreporting happens, some actual behavioral incidences are not reported. The econometrician only observes R it . When a behavior occurs (Y it = 1), we model the respondent's decision on whether or not to report as in a standard binary probit setting; that is, </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">R it = 1 if U * it &gt; 0 R it = 0 if U * it ≤ 0 given Y it = 1 (1a)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_1">R it = 0 given Y it = 0 (1b) U * it = z it i + it (1c) i ∼ MVN D (1d)</formula><p>In the above equations, U * it is the latent utility of reporting, z it is the vector of covariates, i is the vector of coefficients correspondent to z it , and it is the error term. We adopt the random coefficient specification on i to capture the unobserved consumer heterogeneity, where is the mean-level estimate and D is the variance-covariance matrix.</p><p>Similarly, we model the respondent's true behavioral incidence as a binary probit; that is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">Y it = 1 if Y * it &gt; 0 Y it = 0 if Y * it ≤ 0 (2a) Y * it = x it i + it (2b) i ∼ MVN D (2c)</formula><p>In the above equations, Y * it is the latent utility for consumption, x it is the vector of covariates, i is the vector of coefficients correspondent to x it , and it is the error term. We adopt the random coefficient specification on i to capture the unobserved consumer heterogeneity, where is the mean-level estimate and D is the variance-covariance matrix.</p><p>To capture any unobserved correlation between the reporting utility and the consumption utility, we allow the two error terms to be correlated and distributed as bivariate normal with mean of zero and correlation of ; that is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">it it ∼ MVN 0 0 1 1 (3)</formula><p>Note that our model can be viewed as a restricted version of the hidden Markov model. When there is no behavioral occurrence reported (R = 0), we model two latent states, one being the state in which consumption indeed occurs (Y = 1) and the other being the state in which consumption does not occur (Y = 0). We used the probit link to parameterize the switching probabilities between the two states. Hidden Markov models have been widely used in many marketing studies to model unobserved consumer behavioral dynamics <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Montgomery et al. 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">, Du and Kamakura 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">, Montoya et al. 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">, Netzer et al. 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">, van der Lans et al. 2010</ref>.</p><p>We introduce a Bayesian approach to estimate the model using data augmentation. The critical step in this MCMC algorithm is to draw the true behavioral incidence Y it conditional on data (reported behavioral incidence and covariates) and model parameters.</p><p>The above model specification suggests the following probabilities to be associated with each one of the three events:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">Pr R it = 1 Y it = 1 = 2 z it i x it i (4a) Pr R it = 0 Y it = 1 = 2 −z it x it i − (4b) Pr R it = 0 Y it = 0 = −x it i (4c)</formula><p>where 2 a b stands for the cumulative density function for a standard bivariate normal distribution with mean as zero and correlation as . Then conditional on R it = 0, based on the Bayes theorem, we can derive the conditional distribution of Y it :</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">Pr Y it = 1 R it = 0 = 2 −z it x it i − 2 −z it x it i − + −x it i (5a) Pr Y it = 0 R it = 0 = −x it i 2 −z it x it i − + −x it i (5b)</formula><p>In many situations, marketing researchers are interested in the state-dependence effect, that is, the effect of last period behavioral incidence on the current period choice utility. There has been a long history of incorporating the state-dependence effect when studying consumer product choices using supermarket scanner panel data <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Guadagni and</ref><ref type="bibr">Little 1983, Seetharaman et al. 1999)</ref>. State dependence has been shown to be an important factor to capture consumer dynamic preferences, leading to important implications to firms' pricing decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Che et al. 2007</ref>). Incorporating the state-dependence effect is especially important when analyzing longitudinal panel survey data, because a key advantage of panel survey data compared with cross-sectional survey data is that they allow researchers to examine consumer dynamic preferences. To incorporate the state-dependence effect, 1 we need to revise the consumption utility in Equations (2b) and (2c) as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">Y * it = x it i + i Y i t−1 + it (6a) i = i i ∼ MVN ¯ D (6b)</formula><p>Incorporating the state-dependence effect is standard when there is no measurement error on last-period behavioral incidence. However, when last-period behavioral incidence is measured with error, we need to account for this measurement error. Now, to draw Y it with the state-dependence effect incorporated, we need to derive the probability of each of the nine possible combinations of outcomes conditional on</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">Y i t−1 . Pr R it = 0 Y it = 1 R i t+1 = 1 Y i t+1 = 1 = 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − • 2 z i t+1 i x i t+1 i + i (7a) Pr R it = 0 Y it = 1 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 1 = 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − • 2 −z i t+1 i x i t+1 i + i − (7b) Pr R it = 0 Y it = 1 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 0 = 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − • 1 − x i t+1 i + i (7c) Pr R it = 0 Y it = 0 R i t+1 = 1 Y i t+1 = 1 = 1 − x it i + i Y i t−1 • 2 z i t+1 i x i t+1 i (7d) Pr R it = 0 Y it = 0 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 1 = 1 − x it i + i Y i t−1 • 2 −z i t+1 i x i t+1 i − (7e) Pr R it = 0 Y it = 0 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 0 = 1 − x it i + i Y i t−1 • 1 − x i t+1 i (7f) Pr R it = 1 Y it = 1 R i t+1 = 1 Y i t+1 = 1 = 2 z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 • 2 z i t+1 i x i t+1 i + i (7g) Pr R it = 1 Y it = 1 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 1 = 2 z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 • 2 −z i t+1 i x i t+1 i + i − (7h) Pr R it = 1 Y it = 1 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 0 = 2 z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 • 1 − x i t+1 i + i (7i)</formula><p>Note that we only need to generate Y it when</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">R it = 0, because Y it = R it when R it = 1. Thus condi- tional on R it = 0, R i t+1 = 1 R i t+1 = 0 and Y i t+1 = 1 Y i t+1 = 0 , we can derive the posterior distribution of Y it : Pr Y it = 1 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 1 Y i t+1 = 1 = 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − • 2 z i t+1 i x i t+1 i + i • 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − • 2 z i t+1 i x i t+1 i + i + 1− x it i + i Y i t−1 • 2 z i t+1 i x i t+1 i −1 (8a) Pr Y it = 0 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 1 Y i t+1 = 1 = 1−Pr Y it = 1 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 1 Y i t+1 = 1 (8b) Pr Y it = 1 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 1 = 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − • 2 −z i t+1 i x i t+1 i + i − • 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − • 2 −z i t+1 i x i t+1 i + i − + 1− x it i + i Y i t−1 • 2 −z i t+1 i x i t+1 i − −1 (8c) Pr Y it = 0 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 1 = 1−Pr Y it = 1 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 1 (8d) Pr Y it = 1 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 0 = 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − • 1− x i t+1 i + i • 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − • 1− x i t+1 i + i + 1− x it i + i Y i t−1 1− x i t+1 i −1 (8e) Pr Y it = 0 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 0 = 1−Pr Y it = 1 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 0 (8f)</formula><p>With the true behavioral incidence Y it generated, we can estimate i and i as in a bivariate probit model with sample selection. We provide details of the MCMC algorithm in Appendix A. This concludes the model description and estimation.</p><p>It is important to note that it is difficult to estimate the proposed model with state-dependence effect using classical estimation methods. For example, in the maximum likelihood estimation approach, we need to write down the likelihood of the observed data from respondent i according to the specified model; that is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">L i = P R i1 P R i2 R i1 P R i3 R i2 R i1 • • • P R iT R i T −1 R i T −2 R 1 (9)</formula><p>However, in our research context, the conditional probability P R it R i t−1 R i t−2 R i1 is difficult to write down. To see this more clearly, we provide an example below. For the convenience of illustration, we assume zero correlation between the two error terms associated with the reporting utility and consumption utility. If we observe the reported incidence R it = 1, Marketing Science 29(3), pp. 525-539, © 2010 INFORMS then the probability of this observation can be written as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">P R it = 1 R i t−1 R i t−2 R i1 = P Y it = 1 U it = 1 = Z it i P Y it = 1 = Z it i P Y i t−1 = 1 •P Y * it &gt; 0 Y i t−1 = 1 +P Y i t−1 = 0 •P Y * it &gt; 0 Y i t−1 = 0 (10)</formula><p>If a behavioral incidence is reported at time t − 1that is, R i t−1 = 1-then Y i t−1 = 1 with probability 1 by assumption. In this case, it is straightforward to compute P R it = 1 , where</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">P R it = 1 = P Y it = 1 U it = 1 = Z it i P Y * it &gt; 0 Y i t−1 = 1 (11)</formula><p>However, when a behavioral incidence is not reported at time t −1-that is, R it−1 = 0-then we need to calculate P Y it−1 = 1 and this probability depends on Y it−2 ; that is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">P Y i t−1 = 1 = Z i t−1 i P Y i t−2 = 1 •P Y * i t−1 &gt; 0 Y i t−2 = 1 +P Y i t−2 = 0 •P Y * i t−1 &gt; 0 Y i t−2 = 0 (12)</formula><p>Following the same logic, P Y i t−1 = 1 needs to be computed differently depending on whether R i t−2 = 0 or R i t−2 = 1, and this algorithm continues till time t − k, where R i t−k = 1. As we see in the aforementioned example, the conditional probability of a reported behavioral incidence at time t is extremely difficult to compute because the model involves dynamics (i.e., current-period true behavioral incidence is dependent on lag true behavioral incidence), and the lag true behavioral incidence is not fully observed. In summary, what makes the Bayesian estimation approach especially effective and efficient in this context is that our proposed model involves a large number of latent discrete variables. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> It is important to note that our proposed model has an identification condition. The standard "exclusion" condition needs to hold here in order to empirically identify the proposed model. This identification requires that the two vectors x and z do not contain the exact same covariates. We illustrate why this empirical identification constraint needs to be imposed here using a simpler version of our proposed mode by assuming = 0. In that case, the probability of observing a reported behavioral incidence (R it = 1) is z it i x it i , and the probability of not observing a reported behavioral incidence (R it = 0) is 1 − z it i</p><p>x it i . If z it = x it , then different combinations of i and i can lead to the same likelihood of the data. There are two suggestions on how to impose the exclusion identification constraint. First, we can include a set of covariates in the consumption utility function but include only an intercept in the reporting utility function. This specification usually serves the purpose of testing whether underreporting exists in the data. Second, behavioral theory and previous findings can help us find variables that only predict one but not the other. For example, some psychographic variables such as consumer general attitudes towards survey participation can predict the authentic reporting probability but not necessarily the true consumption incidence.</p><p>To test the proposed model, we have conducted simulation analysis. We have simulated data according to the proposed model with prespecified parameter values and then estimated these parameters using the proposed method. Our results suggest that our estimation approach can recover the true parameter values of the proposed model. In addition, our simulations fulfill other two important goals. First, it helps us determine whether the model is statistically identified. Second, it helps us quantify the direction and size of the biases on model parameters caused by the underreporting response style. Overall, our simulation results show that the proposed model is identified, the proposed estimation method works well on recovering true parameter values, and ignoring the underreporting phenomenon leads to biased inferences. For details of the simulation, please refer to Appendix B.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">An Empirical Application</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Data and Variable Specification</head><p>The data were provided to us by one of the world's leading marketers of nonalcoholic beverages, who collect these data as part of an extensive and ongoing market research exercise lasting several years. Each respondent was provided with a handheld personal digital assistant. In each weekday over a two-week period, a respondent was asked to make a record and answer a few consumption-related questions whenever he or she consumed a beverage at that moment. Underreporting is likely to occur in such context. Because the data recording mechanism is tedious, complex, and effortful, it is possible that consumption occurs but a respondent does not record the behavioral incidence. On the other hand, overreporting is less likely to occur in such context based on the same intuition.</p><p>We randomly sampled 1,000 respondents surveyed in the three months of June, July, and August in 2003 for our empirical analysis. For each respondent, and   for each of the 6 parts of the day (morning, lunch, afternoon, dinner, night, late night) on each of the 10 days, we created a dummy variable indicating whether the person reports any beverage consumption. Figures <ref type="figure">1(a</ref>), 1(b), and 1(c) plot the total daily consumption frequency from the 1,000 respondents over 10 days of the survey period for overall beverage and two specific types of beverage: water and soft drinks. Regression analysis on the 10 data points suggests a negative and significant time trend for all three categories. This provides evidence of underreporting because consumer consumption frequency on these product categories is unlikely to be changing significantly during a two-week period.</p><p>Next, we discuss the details of the model specification. In the consumption utility, we include eight variables that capture a respondent's demographics, psychographics, and time effect: AGE, GENDER, EDUCATION, INCOME, LOOKGOOD, INDULGE, HEALTHY, and LOG_WEEK. The coefficients of these variables are modeled with fixed effects. AGE is measured as a respondent's actual age. GENDER = 0 for males, and GENDER = 1 for females. EDUCATION is measured on the following 6-point scale: 1 = grade school or less, 2 = some high school, 3 = high school graduate, 4 = some college or trade school, 5 = college graduate, and 6 = postgraduate work. INCOME was measured on the following 7point scale: 1 = under $15 000; 2 = $15 000-$25 000; 3 = $25 000-$35 000; 4 = $35 000-$50 000; 5 = $50 000-$75 000; 6 = $75 000-$100 000; and 7 = $100 000 or greater. Respondents also reported the level of the motivation for looking good (LOOK-GOOD), which is measured on a 3-point scale (1 = least, 2 = average, 3 = most), the likelihood of being motivated by indulging oneself (INDULGE), and the likelihood of being motivated to be healthy (HEALTHY). The likelihood measure ranges from 0 to 1. Because the 1,000 randomly sampled respondents were surveyed for a two-week period at different time points during the three months, we include a LOG_WEEK variable that is measured by the natural log of the week (from 1 to 12 because we have data from 12 consecutive weeks in those three months) of a respondent's reported consumption incidences. This potentially captures the beverage consumption dynamics because of change of weather (becoming hotter in our context). In the consumption utility, we also include seven variables that are modeled with random coefficients or unobserved heterogeneity across respondents: the six day parts (MORNING, LUNCH, AFTERNOON, DINNER, NIGHT, and LATE NIGHT) and lagged actual consumption incidence to capture the state-dependence effect. Note that the "exclusion" identification constraint is imposed by including the 10 day dummies in the reporting utility while including LOG_WEEK in the consumption utility.</p><p>We estimated fixed effects for all the covariates included in the utility of reporting conditional on a consumption incidence. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> These covariates include the seven demographic and psychographic variables as Marketing Science 29(3), pp. 525-539, © 2010 INFORMS mentioned above, 10 dummies to indicate the consumption in any of the 10 days of the survey period, and the 6 day parts as mentioned above where LATE NIGHT is treated as the baseline.</p><p>To ensure the convergence of the MCMC chain, we adopted three different techniques to test the convergence. First, we did the time-series inspection on trace plots, which has been often used in the marketing literature. Second, we computed the Geweke (1992) convergence diagnostic, which takes two nonoverlapping parts of the Markov chain and compares the means of both parts, using a difference of means test to assess if the two parts of the chain are from the same distribution (null hypothesis). Last, we used three sets of starting values for the model parameters, and the moments of the posterior distributions remain unchanged across all sets. All three of these tests indicated that model estimation is convergent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Estimation Results</head><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">1</ref> reports the estimation results on consumption incidence of any beverage from both the proposed model accounting for underreporting and the naïve model not accounting for underreporting. We first discuss results from the proposed model. With regard to consumption utility, we find that the consumption incidence varies from the lowest to the highest over the six day parts in the following order: late night, night, morning, afternoon, dinner, and lunch. The state-dependence parameter at the mean level is significantly negative (−0 209). The variance (heterogeneity) of the state-dependence parameter is 0.368, or its standard deviation is 0.607. This suggests that some respondents have a positive statedependence coefficient, whereas some respondents have a negative state-dependence coefficient. We also find significant unobserved heterogeneity in consumer beverage consumption incidence over the six day parts. On the effect of demographics, we find that females drink any beverage more often than males. On the effect of psychographics, we find people who are more motivated by INDULGE and HEALTHY drink beverages more frequently. Finally, the effect of LOG_WEEK is insignificant.</p><p>On respondents' reporting behavior conditional on consumption, our analysis reveals some interesting findings. First, on the effects of demographic variables, we find that older respondents are more likely to report and females are less likely to report than males when consumption occurs. Second, on the effects of psychographic variables, we find that people who are more motivated by INDULGE are less likely to report when consumption occurs. Third, the estimates on DAY1 through DAY10 show that the reporting tendency is much lower in the last eight days than in the first two days, which may be because of a decreased interest in expending the effort required. Fourth, the reporting tendency varies over the six day parts from the lowest to the highest in the following order: morning, afternoon, lunch, late night, and night. This order is not consistent with that of the predicted consumption incidence, which suggests that low (high) probability of a consumption incidence does not necessarily mean low (high) reporting probability. The analysis on respondents' authentic reporting behavior allows marketing researchers to better understand who at what time are more likely to omit reporting of their actual behavioral incidence. Finally, we find that there is a significant negative correlation between the consumption utility and the reporting utility because of the unobserved variables in these two equations.</p><p>Next, we estimated a model where we treat the reported consumption incidence as the actual consumption incidence without accounting for the possibility of omission. Estimates from such naïve model are reported in the last two columns of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">1</ref>. We find that failure of accounting for underreporting leads to substantial biases in the coefficient estimates on the day parts such as morning, afternoon, night, and late night. In addition, we find that the statedependence estimate is attenuated towards zero (40% less negative in our case), consistent with our findings in the simulation.</p><p>We have also estimated the same proposed model on soft drink consumption and water consumption, respectively. The estimates from both the proposed model and the naïve model on soft drink consumption are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">2</ref>. Similarly, we find biases in estimates if not accounting for underreporting. For example, our proposed model suggests that EDUCA-TION does not predict soft drink consumption incidence, but according to the naïve model without accounting for the underreporting bias, EDUCATION has a significant and positive effect. In the proposed model, INCOME is found to have a significant and negative effect on soft drink consumption, but the naïve model found the income effect to be insignificant. Interestingly, we find a significant and positive effect of LOG_WEEK in the proposed model, suggesting that consumers consume soft drinks more frequently as the weather turns hotter. However, the naïve model fails to detect this relationship. Finally, apart from those estimates that suffer from a directional bias, we also find substantial biases on other model parameters. For example, the effect of AGE on soft drink consumption utility is -0.261 (-0.089) in the proposed (naïve) model. The effect of INDULGE on soft drink consumption utility is 0.700 (0.345) in the proposed (naïve) model. The mean-level estimates on some of the six day parts are substantially biased. The variance (unobserved heterogeneity) estimates of the six day-part random coefficients and the statedependence effect are underestimated in general.</p><p>The estimates from both the proposed model and the naïve model on water consumption are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref>. As shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref>, the estimates on DAY1 through DAY10 in the report utility from the proposed model are larger than those found in the      In summary, as empirically demonstrated in the above three examples, it is important to model the underreporting bias when respondents have a tendency to omit reporting but a behavior of interest indeed occurs. Ignoring such underreporting bias can lead to wrong or inaccurate estimates of model parameters. In this regard, our proposed model presents a modeling framework to correct such bias. To gain more managerial insights, we compare the effect of  same variables on consumption and reporting of soft drinks and water in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">4</ref>, estimated from the proposed model. On the consumption utility, we find the following different and similar effects on the two beverage categories: (1) Effect of demographics: Age has a negative effect for both soft drink (−0 199) and water (−0 074). Females are predicted to drink soft drinks (water) less (more) frequently than males. INCOME has a signif-icant and negative effect on soft drink consumption but an insignificant effect on water consumption incidence. (2) Effect of psychographics: Specifically, we find that people who are more motivated by LOOKGOOD and HEALTHY tend to consume soft drinks less frequently and water more frequently, and vice versa for those who are more motivated by INDULGE.</p><p>(3) Effect of consumption dynamics: Interestingly, we find a positive (negative) consumption dynamic in soft drink (water), suggesting that consumers tend to drink soft drink (water) more (less) often as the weather turns hotter. The magnitude of state dependence is about the same for these two types of beverages. (4) Mean-level effect of day parts: The predicted mean-level consumption probability of soft drink and water varies over the six day parts in different patterns. For example, soft drinks are consumed most in lunchtime, whereas water is consumed most in afternoon. (5) Unobserved heterogeneity: In general, we find that the variance of the random coefficients of day parts and state dependence is larger in consumption of soft drinks than in consumption of water.</p><p>More importantly, our proposed model presents a modeling framework to allow marketing researchers to better understand who are more likely to underreport and when underreporting is more likely to occur. On the reporting utility, we find the following different and similar effects on the two beverage categories: (1) Effect of demographics: For both categories of beverage, we find AGE has a positive effect on the utility of reporting with the effect size being significantly larger for water. For water, we find that females are less likely to report than males. For soft drinks, we find that respondents with higher income are more likely to report than respondents with lower income. (2) Effect of psychographics: We find that people with stronger consumption motivation of INDULGE are more likely to underreport actual consumption incidence of both categories of beverage. (3) Effect of reporting dynamics: For both categories, we find the probability of reporting decreases over the 10-day survey period. This pattern is consistent with the plots of consumption frequency observed in the data shown in Figures <ref type="figure">1(a)</ref>-1(c), suggesting that the observed consumption dynamics from the data are likely driven by the dynamics in the probability of reporting and underreporting. (4) Effect of day parts: The probability of reporting is fairly constant across the six day parts for both categories. (5) Unobserved correlation: The correlation of the consumption utility and the reporting utility caused by the unobservable is negative for both soft drinks and water.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Model Validation</head><p>We next do model validation. Model validation is especially important in our context because respondents' true consumption behavior is not observed.  To gain confidence in our proposed model and the importance of correcting for the underreporting bias, we provide both internal and external validations.</p><p>For the internal validation, we conducted two sets of analysis. First, we compared our proposed model with a naïve model that ignores underreporting, in predicting the reported consumption incidence. The naïve model is a nested version or special case of our proposed model by assuming the underreporting probability is zero. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">5</ref>(a) reports the mean absolute deviation (MAD) between the predicted probability of a reported consumption incidence and the actual reported consumption incidence on any beverage, soft drink, and water, respectively. We found that our proposed model predicts better for both insample and out-sample on all three categories.</p><p>Second, we ran correlation analysis between the predicted consumption incidence and the actual consumption incidence. In our context, the company also collected an overall measure of how frequently each respondent consumes each type of beverage overall ("FREQ"), which is measured on a 5-point scale where "1" means least frequently and "5" means most frequently. This overall measure is collected only once for each respondent and therefore is less prone to a systematic underreporting bias. We use this measure to approximate a respondent's actual consumption frequency. We found that the correlation between FREQ and the predicted consumption incidence based on our proposed model is 30% larger than the correlation between FREQ and the predicted consumption incidence based on the naïve model. Collectively, these results suggest that our proposed model more accurately predicts the reported consumption incidence and the actual consumption frequency. For the external validation, we collected new data (cross-sectional data) on consumer beverage consumption frequency in various day parts, from a different source based on a representative sample of 200 consumers. In this new survey, we ask each respondent to report his or her likelihood of consuming any beverage on each of the five day parts: morning, lunch, afternoon, dinner, and night. The last row in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">5</ref>(b) reports the average beverage consumption probability on each of the five day parts based on this new sample. We use these average probabilities to approximate the true level of beverage consumption incidence over the five day parts. In the first three rows of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">5</ref>(b), we report the predicted consumption probabilities over the five day parts from three models based on the longitudinal panel data we analyzed earlier: (1) data on reported consumption incidences, (2) naïve model assuming the underreporting probability is zero, and (3) our proposed model. As shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">5</ref>(b), our proposed model significantly outperforms the other two models in predicting the true consumption probability on morning, lunch, afternoon, and dinner.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.">Managerial Implications</head><p>Surveys are extensively used for collecting information about consumers. However, if there is a systematic tendency to underreport, the model estimates will be biased if such underreporting phenomenon is not accounted for. An important managerial implication of our study is to provide a modeling approach to extract unbiased estimates when the survey data might suffer from underreporting. As shown in our analysis, underreporting can significantly mask respondents' true behavior.  Another important managerial implication of our study is to help survey researchers identify who at what time are more likely to underreport and incentivize these people to authentically report. In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">6</ref>(a), we report the predicted reporting probabilities of two types of respondents and the sample average predicted reporting probabilities for any beverage consumption in the six-day parts. We find that the reporting probability of Respondent A is higher than the sample average, whereas the reporting probability of Respondent B is lower than the sample average. In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">6</ref>(b), we report the average predicted reporting probabilities of any beverage consumption over the 10 day survey period. As shown, the reporting probabilities in the first two days are significantly higher than those in the remaining eight days.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusion</head><p>Panel survey data have been gaining importance in marketing for their benefit of allowing marketing researchers to dynamically track changes in consumer behavior. However, one challenge of estimating econometric models based on panel survey data is how to account for the underreporting bias. There is evidence suggesting that respondents may underreport their true behavioral incidence over the duration of the survey period when the data recording mechanism is tedious, complex, and effortful. Such underreporting bias can significantly mask respondents' true behavior and its dynamics. Therefore, it is important to account for such measure error when estimating models based on panel survey data.</p><p>In this paper, we developed a model and Bayesian estimation approach for estimating the proposed model to address an important marketing research issue: the underreporting bias in panel survey data. We view this as an important methodological contribution. In the proposed modeling framework, we simultaneously study reported behavioral incidences and partially observed actual behavioral incidences. We treat those unobserved actual behavioral incidences as latent variables, and the Gibbs sampler makes it convenient to impute these nonreported consumption incidences along with making inferences on other model parameters. The proposed Bayesian estimation approach adds additional value when estimating the state dependence effect in panel survey data with underreporting bias. In such context, it is extremely difficult to estimate the model using classical estimation methods.</p><p>The proposed model is then applied to a unique data set on consumer beverage consumption incidence collected by a large manufacturer of nonalcohol beverage producer. The empirical study revealed many important findings and managerial insights that would not have been obtained without modeling the underreporting bias. On one hand, our empirical analysis shows that ignoring the underreporting bias leads to biased estimates on the consumption utility and such biases can be substantial. In this regard, our proposed model is useful to marketing researchers and firms to make accurate inference on consumer behavior with panel survey data. On the other hand, the proposed model allows one to examine factors affecting the underreporting likelihood. Once we know what factors are explaining the underreporting, we can design procedures to intervene and provide incentives to the right respondents at the right time and hence reduce the size of the underreporting measurement error and increase the quality of panel survey data.</p><p>Finally, our study can be extended in several ways. First, the incidence model can be extended to a choice model with more than two alternatives. In this study, the incidence model is adopted for ease of demonstration. Second, it will be interesting to incorporate the cross-category state-dependence effect; that is, the last period of consumption incidence on product A influences the current period consumption utility of product B. This requires additional derivation on the posterior distribution of the true consumption incidence for both products. Such an extension may add more complexity to the proposed model but can be valuable to researchers and practitioners who find the cross-category state-dependence effects important. Third, even though our interest in this paper is to model underreporting (behavior occurs but is not recorded), the proposed framework can be extended to modeling overreporting (behavior does not occur but is recorded). In our empirical context, the overreporting is unlikely to occur because of the complicated data-recording mechanism and the product of interest being largely viewed as necessity goods. However, when asked to report usage behavior on some luxury or social status goods, respondents might have an incentive to overreport. Finally, the model can be extended to incorporate and test behavioral theories on sources of measurement error. We hope this paper will generate some further interest in this important marketing research area.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix A. The MCMC Algorithm</head><p>Below, we describe the MCMC algorithm for the proposed model presented in the model section with both statedependence effect and consumer heterogeneity. Other models presented in the paper can be viewed as special cases.</p><p>1. Draw Y it : If R it = 1, then Y it = 1 with probability 1. If R it = 0, we need to discuss the full condition distribution for y it across different situations:</p><p>(a) When R it = 0, R i t+1 = 1 and</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">Y i t+1 = 1, the proba- bility of Y it = 1 is Pr Y it = 1 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 1 Y i t+1 = 1 = 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − • 2 z i t+1 i x i t+1 i + i • 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − • 2 z i t+1 i x i t+1 i + i + 1− x it i + i Y i t−1 2 z i t+1 i x i t+1 i −1</formula><p>We then draw u ∼ uniform 0 1 .</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">If u &lt; Pr Y it = 1 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 1 Y i t+1 = 1 , set Y it = 1; otherwise set Y it = 0. (b) When R it = 0, R i t+1 = 0 and Y i t+1 = 1, the proba- bility of Y it = 1 is Pr Y it = 1 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 1 = 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − • 2 −z i t+1 i x i t+1 i + i − • 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − • 2 −z i t+1 i x i t+1 i + i − + 1− x it i + i Y i t−1 2 −z i t+1 i x i t+1 i − −1</formula><p>We then draw u ∼ uniform 0 1 .</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">If u &lt; Pr Y it = 1 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 1 , set Y it = 1; otherwise, set Y it = 0. (c) When R it = 0, R i t+1 = 0 and Y i t+1 = 0, the proba- bility of Y it = 1 is Pr Y it = 1 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 0 = 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − 1− x i t+1 i + i • 2 −z it i x it i + i Y i t−1 − 1− x i t+1 i + i + 1− x it i + i Y i t−1 1− x i t+1 i −1 We then draw u ∼ uniform 0 1 . If u &lt; Pr Y it = 1 R it = 0 R i t+1 = 0 Y i t+1 = 0 , set Y it = 1; otherwise, set Y it = 0. 2. Draw Y * it : If Y it = 1, then draw Y * it truncated by Y * it &gt; 0 from N x it i + Y i t−1 i + U * it − z it i 1 − 2 . If Y it = 0, then draw Y * it truncated by Y * it &lt; 0 from N x it i + Y i t−1 i 1 .</formula><p>3. Draw i : </p><formula xml:id="formula_16">Define Y * it = Y * it − U * it − z it i / 1 − 2 if Y it = 1 Y * it otherwise and X it = x it Y i t−1 / 1 − 2 if Y it = 1 x it Y i t−</formula><formula xml:id="formula_17">Y i =      Y * i1 Y * iT      and X i =      X i1 X iT     </formula><p>Based on our assumption i = i i ∼ MVN ¯ D , we can derive the posterior distribution of i :</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">i Y i X i ∼ MVN b S</formula><p>where b = S X i Y i + D −1 ¯ and S = X i X i + D −1 −1 . 4. Draw¯ : Assume¯ has a diffuse prior distribution ∼ N 0 S 0 , where 0 = 0 and S 0 = 100I. Given all i and D , we can derive the posterior distribution as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">i i= 1 n ∼ N b S</formula><p>where b = S S −1 0 0 + n D −1 ˜ , S = S −1 0 + n D −1 −1 and˜ = 1/n n i=1 i . 5. Draw D : For convenience of the estimation, we assume the heterogeneity matrix is diagonal; that is, D = Diag D 1 1 D K K . Assume the prior of D k k follow inverted-gamma distribution as below:</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">D k k ∼ IG v 0 V 0</formula><p>then the posterior can be given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">D k k i i= 1 n ∼ IG v 0 + n 2 V 0 + 1 2 n i=1 i −¯ 2</formula><p>where v 0 = 0 01 and V 0 = 0 01. 6. Draw U * it : As mentioned in the paper, we consider underreporting a problem only when behavior incidence Y it = 1. We first define = i t Y it = 1 and let U it = R it when i t ∈ ; then similar to Step 2, we draw U * it based on U it for i t ∈ .</p><p>7. Draw i similar to Step 3; draw i based on U * it and z it when {i,t} ∈ . 8. Draw similar to Step 4. 9. Draw D similar to Step 5. 10. Draw . Similar to Step 6, define = i t Y it = 1 and N = # i t Y it = 1 . Then set the prior distribution of as uniform between -1 and 1. We use Metropolis-Hastings algorithm with a random walk chain to generate draws. Let denote p the previous draw, and then the next draw n is given by n = p + with the accepting probability as follows: </p><formula xml:id="formula_22">min    1− n 2 −N /2 exp − 1/2 i t</formula><formula xml:id="formula_23">p = 1 p p 1 −1 n = 1 n n 1 −1</formula><p>and is a draw from the density Normal 0 0 05 . We also constrained candidate draws to lie between -1 and 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix B. Simulation Analysis</head><p>Our simulation study is based on synthetic panel data of 1,000 people with 100 observations per person generated from a random coefficients binary probit model with underreporting. We include an intercept and three randomly generated covariates in the utility that drives the true behavioral incidence and in the utility that drives the likelihood of authentic reporting.</p><p>In addition, we include the lagged true behavioral incidence (z 4 to capture the state-dependence effect in predicting the true behavior incidence in the current time period. We simulated two separate data sets. In the first data set, we assumed a negative state-dependence effect (¯ 4 = −0 5 . In the second data set, we assumed a positive state-dependence effect (¯ 4 = 0 5 . Tables B.1 and B.2 report the estimates of¯ (the mean response) and D (the heterogeneity) under positive state    dependence and under negative state dependence, respectively. As shown, the proposed method works well and we can accurately recover all the model parameters. Ignoring the underreporting behavior leads to biased inferences on model parameters. In particular, the state-dependence estimate is biased up (less negative) when there is positive state dependence. The state-dependence parameter is biased down (less positive) when there is negative state dependence.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1(a)The Total Beverage Consumption Frequency Over 10 Days from 1,000 Respondents</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1(b)The Total Soft Drink Consumption Frequency Over 10 Days from 1,000 Respondents</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1(c)The Total Water Consumption Frequency Over 10 Days from 1,000 Respondents</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Marketing</head><label></label><figDesc>Science 29(3), pp. 525-539, © 2010 INFORMS</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, and Dhar: Modeling the Underreporting Bias in Panel Survey Data Marketing Science 29(3), pp. 525-539, © 2010 INFORMS 539</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Science 29(3), pp. 525-539, © 2010 INFORMS</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Estimates on Beverage Consumption Incidence: Posterior Mean (Std. Dev.)</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Proposed model</cell><cell cols="2">Naïve model</cell></row><row><cell>Consumption</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>AGE</cell><cell>−0 039 (0.026)</cell><cell cols="2">0 013 (0.012)</cell></row><row><cell>GENDER</cell><cell>0 129 (0.044)</cell><cell cols="2">−0 038 (0.028)</cell></row><row><cell>EDUCATION</cell><cell>0 009 (0.019)</cell><cell cols="2">0 008 (0.010)</cell></row><row><cell>INCOME</cell><cell>0 015 (0.013)</cell><cell cols="2">0 005 (0.007)</cell></row><row><cell>LOOKGOOD</cell><cell>0 021 (0.024)</cell><cell cols="2">0 032 (0.014)</cell></row><row><cell>INDULGE</cell><cell>0 709 (0.071)</cell><cell cols="2">0 748 (0.045)</cell></row><row><cell>HEALTHY</cell><cell>0 120 (0.061)</cell><cell cols="2">0 199 (0.042)</cell></row><row><cell>LOG_WEEK</cell><cell>0 014 (0.029)</cell><cell cols="2">−0 036 (0.021)</cell></row><row><cell>MEAN_MORNING</cell><cell>0 743 (0.122)</cell><cell cols="2">0 125 (0.030)</cell></row><row><cell>MEAN_LUNCH</cell><cell>1 199 (0.099)</cell><cell cols="2">0 768 (0.031)</cell></row><row><cell>MEAN_AFTERNOON</cell><cell>0 886 (0.064)</cell><cell cols="2">0 517 (0.027)</cell></row><row><cell>MEAN_DINNER</cell><cell>1 080 (0.061)</cell><cell cols="2">0 864 (0.031)</cell></row><row><cell>MEAN_NIGHT</cell><cell>0 231 (0.055)</cell><cell cols="2">0 051 (0.027)</cell></row><row><cell>MEAN_LATE NIGHT</cell><cell>0 194 (0.096)</cell><cell cols="2">−0 545 (0.037)</cell></row><row><cell>MEAN_STATE DEPENDENCE</cell><cell>−0 209 (0.035)</cell><cell cols="2">−0 126 (0.021)</cell></row><row><cell>VAR_MORNING</cell><cell>1 135 (0.163)</cell><cell cols="2">0 677 (0.046)</cell></row><row><cell>VAR_LUNCH</cell><cell>0 983 (0.125)</cell><cell cols="2">0 624 (0.046)</cell></row><row><cell>VAR_AFTERNOON</cell><cell>0 438 (0.044)</cell><cell cols="2">0 377 (0.031)</cell></row><row><cell>VAR_DINNER</cell><cell>0 565 (0.054)</cell><cell cols="2">0 533 (0.041)</cell></row><row><cell>VAR_NIGHT</cell><cell>0 366 (0.035)</cell><cell cols="2">0 433 (0.036)</cell></row><row><cell>VAR_LATE NIGHT</cell><cell>1 278 (0.127)</cell><cell cols="2">0 959 (0.066)</cell></row><row><cell>VAR_STATE DEPENDENCE</cell><cell>0 368 (0.034)</cell><cell cols="2">0 198 (0.015)</cell></row><row><cell>Report</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>AGE</cell><cell>0 101 (0.036)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>GENDER</cell><cell>−0 287 (0.053)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>EDUCATION</cell><cell>0 007 (0.022)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>INCOME</cell><cell>−0 011 (0.016)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>LOOKGOOD</cell><cell>0 033 (0.027)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>INDULGE</cell><cell>−0 379 (0.083)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>HEALTHY</cell><cell>0 145 (0.075)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>DAY1</cell><cell>1 062 (0.139)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>DAY2</cell><cell>1 007 (0.128)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>DAY3</cell><cell>0 781 (0.100)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>DAY4</cell><cell>0 746 (0.102)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>DAY5</cell><cell>0 653 (0.094)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>DAY6</cell><cell>0 707 (0.094)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>DAY7</cell><cell>0 724 (0.094)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>DAY8</cell><cell>0 696 (0.096)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>DAY9</cell><cell>0 611 (0.089)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>DAY10</cell><cell>0 746 (0.095)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>MORNING</cell><cell>0 354 (0.111)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>LUNCH</cell><cell>0 851 (0.086)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>AFTERNOON</cell><cell>0 692 (0.099)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>DINNER</cell><cell>1 180 (0.107)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>NIGHT</cell><cell>1 041 (0.206)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>LATE NIGHT</cell><cell>Fixed to be 0</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>Corr</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Corr</cell><cell>−0 838 (0.007)</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Notes. Significant estimates at 95% are in bolded in Tables 1-4. NA, not</cell></row><row><cell>applicable.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Estimates on Soft Drink Consumption Incidence: Posterior Mean (Std. Dev.)</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Estimates On Water Consumption Incidence: Posterior Mean (Std. Dev.)</figDesc><table><row><cell>Proposed model</cell><cell>Naïve model</cell></row><row><cell>Consumption</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Comparison of Estimates from Soft Drink and Water from the Proposed Model</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>(a)</cell><cell cols="6">Mean Absolute Deviation of Prediction on the Reported</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Consumption Probability</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Beverage</cell><cell cols="2">Soft drink</cell><cell>Water</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="6">In-sample Out-sample In-sample Out-sample In-sample Out-sample</cell></row><row><cell>Proposed</cell><cell>0.151</cell><cell>0.166</cell><cell>0.092</cell><cell>0.097</cell><cell>0.111</cell><cell>0.108</cell></row><row><cell>model</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Naïve model 0.264</cell><cell>0.266</cell><cell>0.119</cell><cell>0.133</cell><cell>0.146</cell><cell>0.142</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>(b)</cell><cell cols="5">Predicting the Actual Beverage Consumption</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Probability-External Validation</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Morning</cell><cell>Lunch</cell><cell>Afternoon</cell><cell>Dinner</cell><cell>Night</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(%)</cell><cell>(%)</cell><cell>(%)</cell><cell>(%)</cell><cell>(%)</cell></row><row><cell>Observed</cell><cell></cell><cell>52.87</cell><cell>71.50</cell><cell>64.70</cell><cell>74.11</cell><cell>75.99</cell></row><row><cell>report data</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Naïve model</cell><cell></cell><cell>53.05</cell><cell>72.70</cell><cell>65.47</cell><cell>75.37</cell><cell>75.49</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Proposed model</cell><cell>68.25</cell><cell>79.56</cell><cell>73.54</cell><cell>78.65</cell><cell>77.61</cell></row><row><cell>The true</cell><cell></cell><cell>73.64</cell><cell>83.99</cell><cell>74.68</cell><cell>86.47</cell><cell>72.57</cell></row><row><cell>probability</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>(a)</cell><cell cols="5">Predicted Reporting Probabilities on Any Beverage</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Consumption Across Respondents</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="5">Morning Lunch Afternoon Dinner Night Late night</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Respondent A Age = 4, Gender = 1, Education = 9, Income = 2,</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="5">LOOKGOOD = 3, INDULGE = 0 82, HEALTHY = 0 82</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="5">94 51% 98 60% 97 46% 99 36% 98 62% 85 69%</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Respondent B Age = 1, Gender = 2, Education = 4, Income = 9,</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="5">LOOKGOOD = 1, INDULGE = 0 14, HEALTHY = 0 06</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="5">59 24% 81 88% 74 46% 89 36% 79 04% 27 81%</cell></row><row><cell>Sample</cell><cell>81 98</cell><cell>93 16</cell><cell>91 03</cell><cell>96 64 93 51</cell><cell>59 20</cell></row><row><cell>average (%)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>Table 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>(b)</cell><cell cols="8">Predicted Reporting Probabilities on Any Beverage Consumption Over Time</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>DAY1</cell><cell>DAY2</cell><cell>DAY3</cell><cell>DAY4</cell><cell>DAY5</cell><cell>DAY6</cell><cell>DAY7</cell><cell>DAY8</cell><cell>DAY9</cell><cell>DAY10</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Reported incidence</cell><cell>3,781</cell><cell>3,635</cell><cell>3,495</cell><cell>3,431</cell><cell>3,342</cell><cell>3,425</cell><cell>3,436</cell><cell>3,413</cell><cell>3,327</cell><cell>3,431</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Actual incidence</cell><cell>4,088</cell><cell>4,072</cell><cell>4,075</cell><cell>4,075</cell><cell>4,078</cell><cell>4,075</cell><cell>4,074</cell><cell>4,083</cell><cell>4,076</cell><cell>4,076</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Report probability</cell><cell>0.925</cell><cell>0.893</cell><cell>0.858</cell><cell>0.842</cell><cell>0.820</cell><cell>0.840</cell><cell>0.843</cell><cell>0.836</cell><cell>0.816</cell><cell>0.842</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_14"><head>Table B</head><label>B</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>.1</cell><cell cols="3">Simulation Results with Negative State Dependence</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Accounting for</cell><cell>Not accounting for</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>underreporting</cell><cell>underreporting</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Posterior mean</cell><cell>Posterior mean</cell></row><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell>True value</cell><cell>(std. dev.)</cell><cell>(std. dev.)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_15"><head>Table B</head><label>B</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>.2</cell><cell cols="3">Simulation Results with Positive State Dependence</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Accounting for</cell><cell>Not accounting for</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>underreporting</cell><cell>underreporting</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Posterior mean</cell><cell>Posterior mean</cell></row><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell>True value</cell><cell>(std. dev.)</cell><cell>(std. dev.)</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">Multiperiod state dependence can be incorporated but with extra complication.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">An alternative classical approach to estimate our proposed model is by using the expectation-maximization algorithm.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Yang, Zhao, and Dhar: Modeling the Underreporting Bias in Panel Survey Data Marketing Science 29(3), pp. 525-539, © 2010 INFORMS</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">The fixed-effects specification leads to a better out-sample fit than the random coefficients specification for the reporting equation in our empirical application.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of rotation group bias on estimates from panel surveys</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bailar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">349</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="30" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response styles in marketing research: A cross-national investigation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Baumgartner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-B</forename><forename type="middle">E M</forename><surname>Steenkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="156" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling discrete choice with response error: Food stamp participation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bollinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="827" to="835" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A hierarchical latent variable model for ordinal data from a customer satisfaction survey with &quot;no answer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Bradlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Zaslavsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">responses. J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">445</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="52" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A learning-based model for imputing missing levels in partial conjoint profiles</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bradlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T.-H</forename><surname>Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="369" to="381" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bounded rationality in pricing under state-dependent demand: Do firms look ahead? How far ahead?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Che</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sudhir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Seetharaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="434" to="449" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reducing social desirability bias via item randomized response: An application to measure underreported desires</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>De Jong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Pieters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-P</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using item response theory to measure extreme response style in marketing research: A global investigation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>De Jong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B E M</forename><surname>Steenkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-P</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Baumgarter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="104" to="115" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Household life cycles and lifestyles in the United States</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Du</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Kamakura</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="132" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision-making under uncertainty: Capturing dynamic choice processes in turbulent consumer goods markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Erdem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A note on modeling underreported Poisson counts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Stat</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="953" to="964" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social desirability bias and the validity of indirect questioning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="303" to="315" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimation in the presence of measurement error</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fuller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. Statist. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="141" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social desirability response effects: Three alternative models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ganster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Hennessey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Luthans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acad. Management J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="331" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating the accuracy of sampling-based approaches to the calculation of posterior moments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Geweke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bayesian Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="193" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling simultaneity in survey data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gilbride</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="311" to="315" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A logit model of brand choice calibrated on scanner data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Guadagni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D C</forename><surname>Little</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="238" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Uninformed response error in survey research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Coney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="370" to="374" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model for controlling social desirability bias by direct and indirect questioning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M.-S</forename><surname>Jo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kiecker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="429" to="437" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analysis of attribution biases and trip reporting errors for panel data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kitamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">H L</forename><surname>Bovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transportation Res. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4/5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="287" to="302" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Are consumer survey results distorted? Systematic impact of behavioral frequency and duration on survey response errors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Toh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="133" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic models incorporating individual heterogeneity: Utility evolution in conjoint analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Liechty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K H</forename><surname>Fong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Desarbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="293" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Some insights into the underreporting of financial data by sample survey respondents</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mandell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lundsten</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="294" to="299" />
			<date type="published" when="1978-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of accessibility of information in memory on judgments of behavioral frequencies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Menon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="431" to="440" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Are the parts better than the whole? The effects of decompositional questions on judgments of frequency behaviors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Menon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="335" to="346" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling online browsing and path analysis using clickstream data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Montgomery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Liechty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="579" to="595" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dynamic marketing mix allocation for long-term profitability. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Montoya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Netzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Jedidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Columbia University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A hidden Markov model of customer relationship dynamics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Netzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lattin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="185" to="204" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Unobserved preference changes in conjoint analysis. Working paper, Fisher College of Business</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Otter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Frühwirth-Schnatter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Tüchler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<pubPlace>Columbus</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Ohio State University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overcoming scale usage heterogeneity: A Bayesian hierarchical approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rossi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Gilula</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">96</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why does the NBD model work? Robustness in representing product purchases, brand purchases and imperfectly recorded purchases</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Schmittlein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Bemmaor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="266" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating household state dependence effects across categories</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Seetharaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ainslie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="488" to="500" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the accuracy of recording of consumer panels: Impact of some demographic factors and behavioral characteristics on systematic attrition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sudman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="1964-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">International market segmentation based on consumer-product relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ter</forename><surname>Hofstede</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-B</forename><forename type="middle">E M</forename><surname>Steenkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="1999-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural mortality and participation fatigue as potential biases in diary panels: Impact of some demographic factors and behavioral characteristics on systematic attrition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Toh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="138" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inter-week variations in expenditure recorded during a two-week survey of family expenditure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="136" to="146" />
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A viral branching model for predicting the spread of electronic word of mouth</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Van Der Lans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Van Bruggen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Eliashberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Wierenga</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="348" to="365" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response errors in collection of expenditures data by household interviews: An experimental study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Waksberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Neter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Government Printing Office</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>U.S; Washington, DC</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1965" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Technical Paper 11, U.S. Bureau of the Census</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Markov chain Monte Carlo analysis of underreported counted data with an application to worker absenteeism</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Winkelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Empirical Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="575" to="587" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
