<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Generalized Multinomial Logit Model: Accounting for Scale and Coefficient Heterogeneity</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2009-07-23">July 23, 2009</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Denzil</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Fiebig</surname></persName>
							<email>d.fiebig@unsw.edu.au</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
							<email>michael.keane@uts.edu.au</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><surname>Louviere</surname></persName>
							<email>jordan.louviere@uts.edu.au</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Nada</forename><surname>Wasi</surname></persName>
							<email>nada.wasi@uts.edu.au</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Economics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of New South Wales</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>2052</postCode>
									<settlement>Sydney</settlement>
									<region>New South Wales</region>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Technology Sydney</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>2007</postCode>
									<settlement>Sydney</settlement>
									<region>New South Wales</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Arizona State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>85287</postCode>
									<settlement>Tempe</settlement>
									<region>Arizona</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">School of Marketing, Centre for the Study of Choice</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Technology Sydney</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>2007</postCode>
									<settlement>Sydney</settlement>
									<region>New South Wales</region>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">School of Finance and Economics, Centre for the Study of Choice</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Technology Sydney</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>2007</postCode>
									<settlement>Sydney</settlement>
									<region>New South Wales</region>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Generalized Multinomial Logit Model: Accounting for Scale and Coefficient Heterogeneity</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2009-07-23">July 23, 2009</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1090.0508</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: December 5, 2007; accepted: March 27, 2009; processed by Peter Fader.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:27+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>T he mixed or heterogeneous multinomial logit (MIXL) model has become popular in a number of fields, especially marketing, health economics, and industrial organization. In most applications of the model, the vector of consumer utility weights on product attributes is assumed to have a multivariate normal (MVN) distribution in the population. Thus, some consumers care more about some attributes than others, and the IIA property of multinomial logit (MNL) is avoided (i.e., segments of consumers will tend to switch among the subset of brands that possess their most valued attributes). The MIXL model is also appealing because it is relatively easy to estimate. Recently, however, some researchers have argued that the MVN is a poor choice for modelling taste heterogeneity. They argue that much of the heterogeneity in attribute weights is accounted for by a pure scale effect (i.e., across consumers, all attribute weights are scaled up or down in tandem). This implies that choice behaviour is simply more random for some consumers than others (i.e., holding attribute coefficients fixed, the scale of their error term is greater). This leads to a "scale heterogeneity" MNL model (S-MNL). Here, we develop a generalized multinomial logit model (G-MNL) that nests S-MNL and MIXL. By estimating the S-MNL, MIXL, and G-MNL models on 10 data sets, we provide evidence on their relative performance. We find that models that account for scale heterogeneity (i.e., G-MNL or S-MNL) are preferred to MIXL by the Bayes and consistent Akaike information criteria in all 10 data sets. Accounting for scale heterogeneity enables one to account for "extreme" consumers who exhibit nearly lexicographic preferences, as well as consumers who exhibit very "random" behaviour (in a sense we formalize below).</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>It is well known that consumer choice behaviour exhibits substantial heterogeneity. In choice modelling, adequate modelling of heterogeneity is important for many reasons. Most obviously, estimates of own-and cross-price elasticities of demand may be severely biased if one does not properly account for taste heterogeneity. More subtle and interesting, perhaps, are issues that arise with respect to new product development (NPD), product positioning and advertising, optimal price discrimination strategies, the development of menus of product offerings, and considerations of product image or brand equity, or both.</p><p>For example, in NPD, the estimation of only average preferences, as in a simple multinomial logit model-or misspecification of the taste distribution more generally-may lead one to miss that a product with particular attributes would have great appeal for a subset of the population. Similarly, welfare analysis requires correct modelling of taste distributions. Failure to understand the nature of taste heterogeneity may result in failure to optimally target advertising that stresses certain product features to groups that favour those features. Also, in many instances, one cares at least as much about the composition of buyers by type as about market share (e.g., any insurance or usage fee-based product where profits/revenues <ref type="bibr">Fiebig et al.: The Generalized Multinomial</ref>  Many more examples could be provided.</p><note type="other">Logit Model</note><p>For over 25 years there has been a major research program in marketing on alternative ways to model consumer heterogeneity. As <ref type="bibr">Keane (1997a, b)</ref> discusses, the traditional multinomial logit (MNL) of <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">McFadden (1974)</ref> and multinomial probit (MNP) of <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Thurstone (1927)</ref> have an asymmetric heterogeneity structure, because they can be motivated by assuming consumers have heterogeneous tastes for unobserved (or unmeasured/intangible) attributes of products but common tastes for observed attributes. Much recent work focuses on extending these models to also allow for heterogeneous tastes over observed attributes as well.</p><p>For example, the mixed or heterogeneous logit (MIXL) model is currently quite popular (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Ben-Akiva et al. 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">, McFadden and Train 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">, Dubé et al. 2002</ref>. MIXL extends MNL to allow random coefficients on observed attributes while continuing to assume the idiosyncratic error is independent and identically distributed (i.i.d.) extreme value. A researcher has great latitude in specifying distributions for the attribute coefficients, but the multivariate normal is used in most applications. (An exception is the price coefficient, which is often modelled as lognormal to impose the constraint that it be negative.) Indeed, it is common to call MNL with normal heterogeneity the mixed logit (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr">Dubé et al. 2002, p. 210</ref>). <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Of course, one can also estimate multinomial probit (MNP) models with normally distributed attribute weights using the Gewecke Hajivassiliou Keane (GHK) simulator to evaluate the choice probabilities (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Keane 1994</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Keane , 1997b</ref>. However, the popularity of the MIXL stems from its greater ease of use (i.e., GHK is harder to program, and MIXL procedures are now available in standard estimation software packages). Thus, the use of MNP has been mostly limited to more sophisticated academic users, whereas various logit models are widely used by practitioners.</p><p>One may also specify a discrete distribution for heterogeneity in either the MNL or MNP. This leads to what is known as the "latent class" (LC) model (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Kamakura and Russell 1989)</ref>. Most applications of LC have used MNL as the base model, again based on ease of use. LC models typically generate a few discrete types of consumers. Part of the appeal of this approach is that one can "name" the types (e.g., couch potatoes, trend setters) leading to easier interpretation of market segments (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Wedel and Kamakura 1998)</ref>. On the other hand, work by Elrod and Keane <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Even when other distributions have been considered, computational problems have often led researchers to revert back to a normality assumption (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bartels et al. 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">, Small et al. 2005</ref>).</p><p>(1995) and <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Allenby and Rossi (1998)</ref> suggests that latent class models understate the extent of heterogeneity in choice data.</p><p>Other ways of capturing heterogeneity have been proposed, such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Harris and Keane (1999)</ref>, who extended MIXL to allow the means of the random coefficients to depend on observed characteristics of consumers-in particular, attitudinal questions about how much they value each attribute. This led to dramatic improvements in model fit (i.e., doubling of pseudo R-squared). In general, however, choice modellers have favored models that rely largely or exclusively on unobserved heterogeneity, largely abandoning attempts to explain heterogeneous tastes using observables. To be fair, this is partly due to the rather limited set of consumer characteristics recorded in most data sets used in choice modelling.</p><p>Recently, <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Louviere et al. (1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Louviere et al. ( , 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Louviere et al. ( , 2008b</ref>), <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Louviere and Eagle (2006)</ref>, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Louviere and Meyer (2007)</ref> have argued that the normal mixing distribution commonly used in the MIXL model is seriously misspecified. They argue that much of the taste heterogeneity in most choice contexts can be better described as "scale" heterogeneity-meaning that for some consumers, the scale of the idiosyncratic error term is greater than for others. However, the scale or standard deviation of the idiosyncratic error is not identified in discrete choice data-a problem that is typically resolved by normalizing it to a constant. Thus, the statement that all heterogeneity is in the scale of the error term is observationally equivalent to the statement that heterogeneity takes the form of the vector of utility weights being scaled up or down proportionately as one "looks" across consumers.</p><p>It is important to note that the scale heterogeneity model is not nested within the heterogeneous logit with normal mixing. It might appear that the scale model is a limiting case of MIXL in which the attribute weights are perfectly correlated. However, the scale parameter must be positive for all consumers, so although attribute weights may vary in the population, for all consumers they must have the same sign. A normal mixture model with perfectly correlated errors does not impose this constraint. What is clear is that MIXL with independent normal mixing is likely to be a poor approximation to the data-generating process if scale heterogeneity is important. MIXL with correlated random coefficients may or may not provide a better approximation-an empirical question we address below.</p><p>Consider then the more general case with both scale heterogeneity and normally distributed taste heterogeneity (independent of the variation induced by scale). In that case, MIXL with normal mixing is clearly misspecified. For example, suppose the utility weight on attribute k, k = 1 K, for person n, n = 1 N , 395 is given by nk = n k + nk , where k is the population mean utility weight on attribute k; n is the person n-specific scaling parameter, which for illustration we assume is log-normal; and nk is what we will call "residual" heterogeneity not explained by scale heterogeneity. Assume nk is distributed normally. Then, writing nk = k + nk as in the conventional MIXL model, the error term nk = k n − 1 + nk is a complex mixture of normal and log-normal errorsthe nature of the mixing depending on the unknown parameter vector k . Thus, the normal mixing model is misspecified. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> There are a number of possible responses to this problem. Some argue for estimation of individuallevel models, which circumvent the need to specify a heterogeneity distribution (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Louviere et al. 2008b</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">, Louviere and Eagle 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">, Louviere and Meyer 2007</ref>. However, revealed preference data rarely provide enough observations per individual to make this approach feasible. However, as shown by <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Louviere et al. (2008b)</ref>, it is possible to estimate individuallevel models from stated preference data obtained using efficient experimental designs. Their results suggest that distributions of preference weights generally depart substantially from normality. Nevertheless, models are by definition only approximations to "reality," so if the estimation of individual models is not feasible, it remains an empirical matter whether assuming normal preference weights is a good modelling choice.</p><p>The hierarchical Bayes (HB) approach has also become popular recently, in part because advances in simulation methods (Markov chain Monte Carlo) made it computationally practical (see <ref type="bibr">Rossi 1998, Geweke and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Keane 2001)</ref>. In HB, the ease of use advantage of MIXL vanishes, so both MNP and MIXL are widely used. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> An appeal of HB is that by specifying weak priors that individual level parameters are normally distributed, one can allow considerable flexibility in their posterior distribution. However, as Allenby and Rossi (1998) note, HB procedures shrink individual level estimates toward the prior. Furthermore, as <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Rossi et al. (2005, p.</ref> 142) note, "the thin tails of the normal model tend to shrink outlying units greatly toward the center of the data." Thus, if one shrinks toward a normal prior, when the true heterogeneity distribution is highly nonnormal, it may result in unreliable inferences. A large amount of data per person may be necessary before the data "overwhelms" the prior.</p><p>In response to this problem, a literature has emerged on using mixtures of normal distributions to generate flexible priors that can easily accommodate a wide range of nonnormal posteriors. This approach, known as "Bayesian nonparametrics," originated with <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Ferguson (1973)</ref> for density estimation. It has been extended to probit by <ref type="bibr">Keane (1999, 2001)</ref>, and to MIXL by <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Rossi et al. (2005)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Burda et al. (2008)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>.7 in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Rossi et al. (2005)</ref> provides a nice illustration of how flexible the distribution of household posterior means can be in a mixture of normals model. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Of course, one can also adopt a mixture-ofnormals specification for the heterogeneity distribution within the classical framework.</p><p>Here, we propose an alternative approach to modelling heterogeneity that stays within the classical framework and retains the simplicity of use of MIXL while extending it to accommodate both scale and residual taste heterogeneity. We show how to nest the MIXL model and the MNL model with scale heterogeneity (S-MNL) within a single framework. We refer to this new model as the "generalized multinomial logit model," or G-MNL. Estimating the G-MNL model allows one to assess whether including scale heterogeneity leads to a significant improvement in fit over the conventional MIXL model in any given data set. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> In mixture of normals models, there is probability of drawing from each class in the mixture, and one must put a prior on that probability vector. Some authors adopt the Dirichlet process prior (DPP), which says there may be a countably infinite number of classes, but that is typically specified to put more prior mass on models with fewer classes. This is the approach of <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Ferguson (1973)</ref> recently extended to MIXL models by <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Burda et al. (2008)</ref>. A second approach is to assume a fixed number of classes and put a Dirichlet (i.e., multivariate Beta) distribution on the vector of type probabilities. This approach is adopted in <ref type="bibr">Keane (1999, 2001)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Rossi et al. (2005)</ref>. In practice there is no fundamental difference between the approaches. This is because (1) in the second method one can consider models with different numbers of classes and compare them based on the marginal likelihood, and (2) in the first approach, inference invariably puts essentially all mass on a fairly small number of types anyway. Thus, in practice, the two kinds of prior on the hyperparameters of the Dirichlet distribution produce essentially identical results, and the real point of this literature is the mixture of normals specification. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Recently, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Geweke and Keane (2007)</ref> introduced the "smoothly mixing regression" (SMR) model in which the class probabilities in a mixture of normals model are determined by a multinomial probit. The key advantage of SMR is that it allows class probabilities to depend on covariates, which is critical for modelling nonstationary processes. SMR is closely related to what are known as "mixture of experts" models in statistics (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Jiang and</ref><ref type="bibr">Tanner 1999, Villani et al. 2007)</ref>.</p><p>Marketing <ref type="bibr">Science 29(3), pp. 393-421, © 2010 INFORMS</ref> Although it is not immediately obvious, G-MNL is closely related to mixture of normals models. The relation becomes clear if we adopt an approximate Bayesian perspective and use our estimated model to calculate person-specific parameters a posteriori (see <ref type="bibr">Train 2003, Chapter 11)</ref>. Then the estimated heterogeneity distribution plays the same role as the prior in the Bayesian framework. One can interpret our model as allowing a more flexible prior on the distribution of individual-level parameters than does a normal model but via a different means than the standard discrete mixtures of normals approach. Specifically, G-MNL implies the attribute coefficients are a continuous mixture of scaled normals.</p><p>We apply G-MNL to data from 10 stated preference choice experiments that cover several different types of choices: choices about medical procedures, mobile phones, food delivery services, holiday packages, and charge cards. We also estimate MIXL and S-MNL on each data set and compare the performance of the models using three information criteria: the Akaike (AIC), Bayes (BIC), and consistent Akaike (CAIC) criteria.</p><p>Our main finding is that models that include scale heterogeneity are preferred over MIXL by both BIC and CAIC in all 10 data sets: G-MNL in 7 and S-MNL in 3. The MIXL model is only (very slightly) preferred by the AIC for the two charge card data sets. However, our Monte Carlo results indicate that BIC and CAIC are more reliable measures for determining if scale heterogeneity is present. Interestingly, among practitioners the MIXL model with uncorrelated errors is very widely used (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Train 2007)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> However, we find this model is dominated by either G-MNL or S-MNL in all 10 data sets, and in some cases by both.</p><p>Of course, it is also important to assess why the scale heterogeneity models fit better, in terms of what behavioural patterns they capture better than MIXL. We show that G-MNL can account for "extreme" consumers who exhibit nearly lexicographic preferences, whereas MIXL does not. We also show that G-MNL is better able to explain consumers who exhibit very "random" behaviour (in a sense we formalize below). Both of these advantages follow directly from the fact that the G-MNL model allows for much greater flexibility in the shape of posterior distribution of personspecific parameters than does MIXL.</p><p>A comparison of our results across data sets revealed two other interesting patterns. First, we can assess the importance of heterogeneity in general <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Presumably, a key reason is the ready availability of Ken Train's program for MIXL. The classical version of his program imposes uncorrelated errors (although the Bayesian version has an option to allow correlation).</p><p>(both scale and residual) by looking at the percentage log-likelihood improvement in going from the simple MNL to the G-MNL model. By this metric, heterogeneity is roughly twice as important in the data sets that involve medical decisions as in those that involve product choices. We speculate that this may be because medical decisions involve more complex emotions, greater involvement, higher brain functions, or all three, than do consumer purchase decisions. But regardless of the reason, the result has important implications for the study of medical decision making.</p><p>Second, we look at the fraction of the overall likelihood improvement (from including all forms of heterogeneity) that is attained by including scale heterogeneity alone. This fraction is far greater in the four data sets involving medical decisions or cell phones than in the six involving food delivery, holiday packages, or charge cards. Similarly, the pseudo-R 2 improvements from including scale heterogeneity are greatest in the medical and cell phone data sets. These findings are consistent with a hypothesis that scale heterogeneity is more important in contexts involving more complex choice objects (medical tests or high-tech goods versus consumer goods). However, research on sources of heterogeneity is in its infancy (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Louviere et al. 2002</ref> so this hypothesis is only preliminary.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">The Generalized Multinomial Logit Model</head><p>In the simple MNL model, the utility to person n from choosing alternative j on purchase occasion (or in choice scenario) t is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">U njt = x njt + njt n = 1 N j = 1 J t = 1 T (1)</formula><p>where x njt is a K-vector of observed attributes of alternative j, is a vector of utility weights (homogenous across consumers), and njt ∼ i.i.d. extreme value is the "idiosyncratic" error. As emphasized by <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Keane (1997b)</ref>, this error can be motivated as consumer heterogeneity in tastes for unobserved (or intangible or <ref type="bibr">7</ref> This previous work has examined complexity as a source of scale heterogeneity, defining complexity to be the amount of information subjects must process to make choices. Factors examined as contributors to complexity include the number of attributes, number of alternatives, number of attributes that differ among alternatives, and number of scenarios. However, complexity may also derive from the nature of attributes themselves (i.e., attributes of hightech goods may be intrinsically harder to evaluate than those of simple consumer goods). There may also be individual differences in ability to deal with complexity, arising because of literacy differences, age differences, etc. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Fang et al. (2006)</ref> find that the ability to choose among insurance plans differs by level of cognitive ability. latent) product attributes. The x njt for j = 1 J may include alternative specific constants (ASCs), which capture persistence in the unobserved attributes (for each option j) over choice occasions. If the average consumer views option j as having desirable unmeasured attributes, it will have a positive ASC.</p><p>Of course, the great popularity of MNL stems from the fact that it generates simple closed-form expressions for the choice probabilities</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">P j X nt = exp x njt J k=1 exp x nkt (2)</formula><p>where X nt is the vector of attributes of all alternatives j = 1 J . However, because of the restrictive assumptions that (1) the njt are i.i.d. extreme value and (2) tastes for observed attributes are homogenous, MNL imposes a very special structure on how changes in elements of x njt can affect choice probabilities. For instance, from (2) we see the restrictive IIA property P j X nt /P k X nt = exp x njt − x nkt which says the ratio of choice probabilities for alternatives j and k depends only on the attributes of j and k. Thus, changes in the attributes of any product l, or the introduction of a new product into the choice set, cannot alter the relative probabilities of j and k. This is obviously unrealistic in cases where product l is much more similar to j than to k.</p><p>One model that avoids IIA is the MIXL model. In MIXL the utility to person n from choosing alternative j on purchase occasion (or in choice scenario) t is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">U njt = + n x njt + njt n = 1 N j = 1 J t = 1 T (3)</formula><p>Here, is the vector of mean attribute utility weights in the population, whereas n is the vector of person n-specific deviations from the mean. The idiosyncratic error njt is still assumed to be i.i.d. extreme value. The investigator may specify any distribution for the n vector, but in most applications it is assumed to be multivariate normal, MVN 0 . However, the price coefficient is sometimes assumed to be log-normal to impose the proper sign restriction.</p><p>Many MIXL applications have assumed is diagonal. This rules out that consumers who like a certain attribute will also tend to like (dislike) some other attribute. That is, it rules out correlation in tastes across attributes but not correlation in tastes across alternatives. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> A major appeal of MIXL is ease of use. It relaxes IIA yet it is still simple to program. 9 This is clear from the expression for how choice probabilities are simulated</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">P j X nt = 1 D D d=1 exp + d x njt J k=1 exp + d x nkt (4)</formula><p>Thus, given D draws d d=1 D from the multivariate normal MVN 0 , one obtains simulated choice probabilities just by averaging simple logit expressions over these draws. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> The scale heterogeneity model (S-MNL) can be understood by recognizing that the idiosyncratic error in both ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>) and (3) has a scale or variance that has been implicitly normalized (to that of the standard extreme value distribution) to achieve identification. To proceed, let us write out the simple logit model with the scale of the error made explicit:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">U njt = x njt + njt / n = 1 N j = 1 J t = 1 T (5)</formula><p>Here, is the scale of the error term. Obviously, it is not possible to identify both and , so it is standard practice to normalize to 1, which is equivalent to multiplying (5) through by . Now, suppose that is heterogeneous in the population, and denote its value <ref type="bibr">8</ref> It is important to emphasize that the assumption that is diagonal does not rule out correlation across alternatives or within alternatives over time. Note that (3) can be rewritten as</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">U njt = x njt + n x njt + njt = x njt + v njt</formula><p>The composite error term v njt = n x njt + njt will be positively (negatively) correlated across alternatives j that have similar (dissimilar) attributes, which is indeed the essential idea of the MIXL model. Thus, MIXL with diagonal avoids IIA. It also allows for correlation over time, as a person who places high utility weights on certain attributes will persist in preferring brands with high levels of those attributes over time. </p><formula xml:id="formula_6">U njt = n x njt + njt n = 1 N j = 1 J t = 1 T (6)</formula><p>Notice that heterogeneity in scale is observationally equivalent to a particular type of heterogeneity in the utility weights. That is, Equation (6) implies that the vector of utility weights is scaled up or down proportionately across consumers n by the scaling factor n . <ref type="bibr">11</ref> If valid, S-MNL provides a much far parsimonious description of the data than MIXL, because n is a much simpler object than ( + n ). For example, say there are 10 attributes. Then n is a 10-vector of normals, with a 10 × 10 covariance matrix containing 55 unique elements to be estimated. In contrast, n is a scalar random variable, so its distribution will typically have far fewer parameters. For example, if n is log-normal, we need only estimate its variancea single parameter-because the mean must be constrained for identification (see below).</p><p>Recently, <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Louviere et al. (2008b)</ref> have criticized the MIXL model in (3). Based on the distributions of utility weights obtained from individual-level estimations, they have argued that (1) distributions do not appear very close to being normal, as assumed in most MIXL applications; and (2) when comparing coefficient vectors across consumers, something close to the scaling property implied by (6) seems to hold. Thus, they have argued that much of the heterogeneity in discrete models would be better captured by S-MNL than by MIXL.</p><p>In an attempt to shed light on this issue, <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Keane (2006)</ref> noted that MIXL and S-MNL could be nested, to obtain a "generalized multinomial logit" model (G-MNL). Estimation of G-MNL would shed light on whether heterogeneity is better described by scale heterogeneity, normal mixing, or some combination of the two. In the G-MNL model, the utility to person n from choosing alternative j on purchase occasion (or in choice scenario) t is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">U njt = n + n + 1 − n n x njt + njt (7)</formula><p>where is a parameter between 0 and 1. Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> describes how G-MNL nests MIXL, S-MNL, and MNL, as well as two other models we call G-MNL-I and G-MNL-II. To obtain MIXL one sets the scale parameter n = = 1. To obtain the S-MNL model one sets Var n = 0, meaning the variance-covariance matrix of n , denoted , is degenerate. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> A common misconception is that random coefficient and scale heterogeneity models are fundamentally different. In fact, they are just different ways of specifying the distribution of coefficient heterogeneity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1</head><p>The G-MNL Model and Its Special Cases</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>G-MNL G-MNL-I G-MNL-II</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>S-MNL MIXL MNL</head><formula xml:id="formula_8">n = n + n + 1 − n n = 1 = 0 n = n + n n = n + n var n = 0 n = = 1 n = n n = + n n = = 1 var n = 0 n =</formula><p>The parameter does not arise in either the MIXL or S-MNL special cases. It is only present in the G-MNL model, and its interpretation is more subtle than either n or . The parameter governs how the variance of residual taste heterogeneity varies with scale in a model that includes both. To see this, note that there are two equally sensible ways to nest MIXL and S-MNL. One might simply combine (3) and ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>) to obtain what we call G-MNL-I:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">U njt = n + n x njt + njt n = 1 N j = 1 J t = 1 T (8)</formula><p>Alternatively, one might start with (3) and make the scale parameter explicit:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">U njt = + n x njt + njt / n n = 1 N j = 1 J t = 1 T</formula><p>Then, multiplying through by n we obtain G-MNL-II:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">U njt = n + n x njt + njt n = 1 N j = 1 J t = 1 T (9)</formula><p>Note that, in either model (8) or (9), we can write the vector of utility weights as</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">n = n + * n</formula><p>In our terminology, the random variable n captures scale heterogeneity and * n captures residual taste heterogeneity. The difference between G-MNL-I and G-MNL-II is that in G-MNL-I, the standard deviation of * n is independent of the scaling of , whereas in G-MNL-II, it is proportional to n . As noted in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>, G-MNL approaches G-MNL-I as → 1, and it approaches G-MNL-II as → 0. In the full G-MNL model, ∈ 0 1 .</p><p>To enhance intuition, it is useful to consider using an estimated G-MNL model to calculate the posterior means of individual-level parameters. G-MNL-I adopts the prior they are a mixture of normals with different means but equal variances. G-MNL-II adopts the prior they are a mixture of normals with proportionally different means and standard deviations. The full G-MNL model allows for differential scaling of and * n . To impose that ∈ 0 1 in estimation, we use a logistic transform = exp * / 1 + exp * and estimate the parameter * . Thus, G-MNL approaches G-MNL-I as * → and approaches G-MNL-II as * → − . Finally, we must choose a distribution for n . Because n represents the (person-specific) scale of the idiosyncratic error, it should be positive. Thus, we assume it is log-normal with mean 1 and standard deviation , or LN(1 2 ). Thus, is the key parameter that captures scale heterogeneity. As → 0, G-MNL approaches MIXL. If &gt; 0, then G-MNL approaches S-MNL as the diagonal elements of approach 0. As both and go to 0 we approach MNL.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Computation and Estimation</head><p>Here, we discuss the details of computation and estimation for the G-MNL model. To constrain the scale parameter n to be positive, we use an exponential transformation</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">n = exp + 0n</formula><p>where 0n ∼ N 0 1 Thus, as the parameter increases, the degree of scale heterogeneity increases. Obviously, as n and only enter the model as a product n , some normalization on n is necessary to identify . The natural normalization is to set the mean of n equal to 1 so that is the mean vector of utility weights. To achieve this must be a decreasing function of . Note that E n = exp + 2 /2 . Thus, to set E n = 1 we should set = − 2 /2.</p><p>Then, the simulated choice probabilities in the G-MNL model take the form</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">P j X nt = 1 D D d=1 exp d + d + 1− d d X njt J k=1 exp d + d + 1− d d X nkt (<label>10</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_15">)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">d = exp + d 0 . Note that d is a K-vector distributed MVN 0</formula><p>, whereas d 0 is a N 0 1 scalar. The simulation involves drawing the d and d 0 for</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">d = 1 D.</formula><p>Note that the computation in ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_14">10</ref>) is no more difficult than for the MIXL model in (4). Now suppose we have either panel data or multiple-choice tasks per subject. 12 Let y njt = 1 if person n chooses option j at time t, and 0 otherwise. Then, the simulated probability of observing person n choosing a sequence of choices y njt T t=1 is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">P n = 1 D D d=1 t j P j X nt d d y njt = 1 D D d=1 t j exp d + d + 1− d d X njt J k=1 exp d + d + 1− d d X nkt y njt</formula><p>which strings together period-specific probabilities like that inside the summation in (10).</p><p>In practice, we found the numerical performance of the algorithm is substantially improved by adopting two slight modifications to the above specification. First, we set the mean of n equal to 1 in the simulated data, not merely in expectation. This means setting</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">= − ln 1 N N n=1 exp d n 0</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">d n 0</formula><p>denotes the dth draw for the nth person. Second, if is too large, it causes numerical problems (i.e., overflows and underflows in exponentiation) for extreme draws of 0 . To avoid this, we draw 0 from a truncated normal with truncation at ±2. We also discovered that the S-MNL model performs poorly when ASCs are scaled. That is, (1) the estimates often "blow up," with taking on very large values and the standard errors of the elements of becoming very large; and (2) the model produces a substantially worse fit than one where only the coefficients on observed attributes are scaled, whereas ASCs are assumed homogenous in the population. Mechanically, these problems arise because data sets typically contain a set of individuals who always (or almost always) chose the same option, regardless of the elements of X nt . If ASCs are scaled, the model can explain this phenomenon by making very large so that ASCs can vary substantially across individuals. The estimation algorithm usually decides to take this route.</p><p>12 Applications of MIXL, S-MNL, and G-MNL typically involve multiple observations per subject. Although the MIXL model is formally identified given only one observation per subject (as a mixture of normal and extreme value errors may provide a slightly better fit to the data than extreme value alone), <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Harris and Keane (1999)</ref> showed the likelihood surface is extremely flat without repeated observations. We cannot expect to identify parameters that characterize heterogeneity in choice behaviour if we only see each person once. On a more conceptual level, ASCs are fundamentally different from most observed attributes. For instance, for attributes like price or quality, it makes sense that all consumers have utility weights of the same sign, but these weights are scaled up or down across consumers (e.g., all consumers value quality, but some value it more than others). In contrast, ASCs tend to measure intangible aspects of products, which some consumers may like and others dislike. Thus, a model where all consumers have ASCs of the same sign, and where these are merely scaled, is unlikely to explain key patterns in choice behaviour, such as the strong persistence in choices (i.e., the loyalty consumers often exhibit for specific brands).</p><p>Thus, in models with ASCs, we specify S-MNL in one of two ways: In version one we assume the ASCs are homogenous in the population and do not scale them. In version two we treat the ASCs as random effects with a MVN distribution. We treat the ASCs in the G-MNL model in exactly the same way. Thus, we can rewrite (7) as</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">U njt = 0j + 0nj + n + n + 1 − n n x njt + njt (11)</formula><p>where x njt is now interpreted to include only observed attributes and not ASCs, and 0j + 0nj is the ASC for alternative j. This consists of the component 0j , which is constant across people, and the component 0nj , which is heterogeneous across people. Thus, we have that ( 0 + 0n ) is a vector of ASCs, with 0 being the mean vector and 0n being the stochastic component. We assume that the entire vector 0n n has a MVN distribution. Finally, to explain why scale differs across people, or across choice occasions, we can let n be a function of characteristics of people or choice occasions. That is, we could write</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">nt = exp + z nt + 0 (12)</formula><p>where z nt is a vector of attributes of person n and choice occasion t. One might let z nt contain demographics, or some measure of the entropy of the choice occasion (e.g., how similar or dissimilar the choices are; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Swait and</ref><ref type="bibr">Adamowicz 2001, DeShazo and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Fermo 2002)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Monte Carlo Results</head><p>In this section we present two Monte Carlo experiments to evaluate the properties of G-MNL model estimates. Of particular interest is whether the model can accurately assess the extent of scale heterogeneity (captured by ) versus residual taste heterogeneity captured by . To make the Monte Carlo experiments realistic, we constructed simulated data sets based on two of the empirical data sets that we will analyse in §5. The first is a data set where women choose whether to have a Pap smear exam, and the second is a data set where people choose between holiday locations (the "Holiday A" data set).</p><p>In each experiment, we use the actual Xs from the empirical data sets. The "true" parameters are obtained by estimating the G-MNL model on the empirical data sets. We generate 20 artificial data sets based on each empirical data set. We then estimate the G-MNL model on these 20 Monte Carlo data sets. In these estimations, as in our empirical work in §5, we use D = 500 draws to simulate the likelihood.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">1</ref> presents results of estimating G-MNL on 20 data sets based on the Pap smear data. There are five attributes, including cost, doctor attributes, and contextual variables (i.e., if the test is recommended), and an ASC for the "Yes" option. There are 79 hypothetical respondents and 32 choice occasions per respondent. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">1</ref> reports the true parameter values, the mean estimates across the 20 replications, the empirical standard deviation of the estimates across data sets, and the mean of the asymptotic standard errors. An asterisk indicates that the bias in an estimated parameter is significant at the 5% level.</p><p>The results in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">1</ref> show evidence of significant bias for only a handful of parameters. Of the six elements of the vector, only 5 exhibits significant bias. However, the magnitude of the bias is less than 2/3 of an empirical standard deviation. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> The standard deviations of residual taste heterogeneity are also rather precisely estimated, except for that on attribute 6, where it is upward biased. 14 Most importantly, the scale heterogeneity parameter is estimated quite precisely: its true value is 0.890 and the mean estimate is 0.891.</p><p>In these data sets the true value of the parameter is almost 0, but our mean estimate is 0.156. This is significantly greater than zero but still quantitatively small. In addition, the median estimate of is 0.08 (it exceeds 0.50 in only one out of 20 data sets). Thus, the model does a reasonable job of uncovering the fact that the true is small. For the most part, the empirical standard errors and mean asymptotic standard errors are close, suggesting the asymptotic theory is a good guide to the variability of the estimates.  m=1 ASE m , where m and ASE m denote parameter estimates and asymptotic standard errors, respectively, from each data set. An asterisk indicates the t-statistic for the estimated bias greater than the critical value at the 5% level; i.e., t &gt; 2 09 where t = √ 20 ¯ − true Std. dev. −1 . The true values are from Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">11</ref>.   <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">10</ref>, except is reduced from 1.51 to 1.00 to make detection of scale heterogeneity more challenging. In addition, is increased from 0 to 0.20 so to contrast with Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">1</ref>, where = 0.  <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">2</ref>. These data sets contain eight attributes, as described later. There are 331 hypothetical respondents and 16 choice occasions per respondent.</p><p>Of the eight elements of the vector, only 1 exhibits significant bias. However, the magnitude of the bias is only 1/2 of an empirical standard deviation. The scale heterogeneity parameter is again estimated quite precisely: its true value is 1.0 and the mean estimate is 0.968. However, the standard deviations of residual taste heterogeneity show a tendency to be upward biased, and this bias is significant for six out of eight parameters.</p><p>We would argue that this upward bias in the error variances is not a great cause for concern. The largest bias, which is for 8 , is only 80% of an empirical standard deviation, and other significant biases are about 2/3 of a standard deviation. Biases of this magnitude are not surprising, in light of prior work showing it is often difficult to pin down error variance-covariance parameters in discrete-choice models (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Geweke et al. 1994</ref>).</p><p>The true is 0.20 and the mean estimate is 0.137. This downward bias is significant, but the model does a reasonable job of uncovering the fact that is small. The greatest cause for concern in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">2</ref> is that asymptotic standard errors are systematically smaller than empirical standard errors. This was not the case in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">1</ref>. The difference may arise because here we attempt to estimate a larger number of variancecovariance parameters (36 versus 21).</p><p>In §5 we use AIC, BIC, and CAIC to choose between the G-MNL, MIXL, and S-MNL models; it is important to consider if these criteria are reliable. To address this issue, we perform a 3 × 6 factorial experiment where we (1) simulate data where the true model is S-MNL, MIXL, or G-MNL (both with correlated errors); and (2) estimate the MNL, S-MNL, MIXL, and G-MNL models (both with and without correlated errors) on those data sets. As in Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">1 and 2</ref>, this was done using data sets constructed to look like the Pap smear and Holiday A data. <ref type="bibr">15</ref> We then counted the number of times that AIC, BIC, and CAIC preferred each model in each case. The results are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref>.</p><p>Consider first the case where G-MNL with correlated errors is the true model. In the Pap smear data   The respondents in the two credit card data sets are the same. They first complete four tasks with three options and then answer four tasks with four options. Some data sets were used in previous research (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Hall et al. 2006</ref> for data sets 1 and 2; Fiebig and Hall 2005 for data set 6; <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Louviere et al. 2008a</ref> for data sets 4, 5, 7, and 8).</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">0 0 0 0 BIC 0 20 0 0 0 0 CAIC 0 20 0 0 0 0 (b) Holiday A data configuration True DGP is G-MNL AIC 0 0 0 20 0 0 BIC 0 0 0 1 5 14 CAIC 0 0 0 0 6 14 True DGP is MIXL AIC 0 0 13 7 0 0 BIC 0 0 0 0 16 4 CAIC 0 0 0 0 17 3 True DGP is S-MNL AIC 0 20 0 0 0 0 BIC 0 20 0 0 0 0 CAIC 0 20 0 0 0 0 G-MNL</formula><p>Finally, when S-MNL is the true model it is correctly identified by all three information criteria in all 40 cases. The reason for this success is that MIXL and G-MNL both involve a large increase in the number of parameters over S-MNL. In summary, although the results for the case when S-MNL is the true model are clear-cut, those for the cases where MIXL or G-MNL is the true model appear more ambiguous.</p><p>How can we make sense of these results? The bottom panel of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">3</ref> provides a useful summary. Here, we look only at the cases where MIXL or G-MNL is the true model, ignore the distinction between correlated and uncorrelated errors, and combine the results from the two data generating processes. We simply ask how reliably the three information criteria determine if the true model contains scale heterogeneity. Note that BIC makes the correct determination in 68/80 cases. It wrongly concludes that the true model is MIXL in 7/80 cases, and it only gives a false positive for scale heterogeneity in 5/80 cases. The results for CAIC are similar. In contrast, AIC has a bias towards accepting scale heterogeneity when it is not present (19/80 cases). This is not surprising, because the AIC has a smaller penalty for adding parameters, and G-MNL has only two more parameters than MIXL.</p><p>Given these results, we conclude that both BIC and CAIC provide accurate guides for whether scale heterogeneity is present-i.e., for distinguishing between MIXL and G-MNL. However, they are biased toward rejecting the presence of error correlations. This is not surprising as error correlations add many parameters, which these criteria penalize heavily. On the other hand, AIC correctly picks models where errors are correlated in 69/80 cases. Thus, we would recommend using the information criteria in conjunction: using BIC and/or CAIC as reliable measures of whether scale heterogeneity is present (i.e., MIXL versus G-MNL or S-MNL) and then using AIC to evaluate whether error correlations are important.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Empirical Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Estimation Results</head><p>Our empirical results are based on data from 10 stated preference choice experiments described in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">4</ref>. The data sets differ widely along several dimensions, including the object of choice (i.e., medical tests, mobile phones, pizza delivery services, holiday packages, and charge cards), the number of attributes (6 to 18), the number of choices (2 to 4), and the number of choice occasions (or choice sets) that each person faced in the experiment (4 to 32). All data sets are fairly large, but the number of observations also varies substantially (from 2,528 to 21,856). Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">5</ref> lists all attributes and how they are coded in each data set.</p><p>Tables 6-15 present estimation results for the 10 data sets. We only discuss the results for data set 1 in detail, giving an overview of results for the other data sets in § §5.2 and 5.4. In data set 1, participants were asked whether they would chose to receive diagnostic tests for Tay Sachs disease, cystic fibrosis, both, or neither, giving four alternatives. The attributes that vary across choice scenarios are the cost of the tests, whether the person's doctor recommends the tests, the chance that the test is inaccurate, how the results of the tests will be communicated, and what the person is told about the probability that they are a carrier  Attributes and Levels</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attributes Levels</head><p>Tay Sachs disease (TS) and cystic fibrosis (CF) test: Jewish and general population ASC for TS test 0, 1 ASC for CF test 0, 1 ASC for both tests 0, 1 Your cost of being tested for TS 0 150 300 600 /1 000 Your cost of being tested for CF 0 375 750 1 500 /1 000 Your cost of being tested both TS and CF 0 150 1 800 2 100 /1 000 Whether your doctor recommends you have a test −1 (no), 1 (yes) The chance that you are a carrier even if the test is negative 15 30 45 60 /10 Whether you are told your carrier status as an individual or as a couple −1 (individual), 1 (couple) Risk of being a carrier for TS log base 10 of 0 004 0 04 0 4 4 × 10 ∧ 3 Risk of being a carrier for CF log base 10 of 0 004 0 04 0 4 4 × 10 ∧ 3</p><p>Mobile phone ASC for purchase (phone 1, phone 2, or phone 3) 0, 1 Voice commands (omitted text to voice or voice to text converter)</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">(1) No −1, 0, 1 (2) Voice dialling by number or name −1, 0, 1 (3) Voice operating commands −1, 0, 1 Push to communicate (omitted to share video) (1) No −1, 0, 1 (2) To talk −1, 0, 1 (3) To share pictures or video −1, 0, 1 E-mail access (omitted e-mail with attachments) (1) Personal e-mails −1, 0, 1 (2) Corporate e-mails (VPN, RIM)</formula><p>−1, 0, 1 (3) Both personal and corporate e-mails on multiple accounts −1, 0, 1 WiFi −1 (no), 1 (yes) USB cable or cradle connection −1 (no), 1 (yes) Thermometer −1 (no), 1 (yes) Flashlight −1 (no), 1 (yes) Price 0 11 7 19 5 497 25 563 55 /100 (36 unique values) Pap smear test ASC for test 0 (no), 1 (yes) Whether you know doctor 0 (no), 1 (yes) Whether doctor is male 0 (no), 1 (yes) Whether test is due 0 (no), 1 (yes) Whether doctor recommends 0 (no), 1 (yes) Test cost 0 10 20 30 /10</p><p>Pizza A: Attributes 1-8; Pizza B: Attributes 1-16 (no ASC) Gourmet −1 (traditional), 1 (gourmet) Price −1 ($13), 1 ($17) Ingredient freshness −1 (some canned), 1 (all fresh ingredients) Delivery time −1 (45 mins), 1 (30 min) Crust −1 (thin), 1 (thick) Sizes −1 (single size), 1 (3 sizes) Steaming hot −1 (warm), 1 (steaming hot) Late open hours −1 (till 10 p.m.), 1 (till 1 a.m.) Free delivery charge −1 ($2), 1 (free) Local store −1 (chain), 1 (local) Baking method −1 (traditional), 1 (woodfire) Manners −1 (friendly), 1 (polite and friendly) Vegetarian availability −1 (no), 1 (yes) Delivery time guaranteed −1 (no), 1 (yes) Distance to the outlet −1 (in other suburb), 1 (in own suburb) Range/variety availability −1 (restricted menu), 1 (large menu)  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attributes Levels</head><p>Holiday A: Attributes 1-8; Holiday B: Attributes 1-16 (no ASC) Length of stay −1 (7), 1 (12) 5 Meal inclusion −1 (no), 1 (yes) 6 Local tours availability −1 (no), 1 (yes) 7 Peak season −1 (off-peak), 1 (peak) 8 Four-star accommodation −1 (2-star), 1 (4-star) 9 Length of trip −1 (3 hours), 1 (5 hours) 10 Cultural activities −1 (historical sites), 1 (museum) 11 Distance from hotel to attractions −1 (200 m), 1 (5 km) 12 Swimming pool availability −1 (no), 1 (yes) 13 Helpfulness −1 (helpful), 1 (very helpful) 14 Individual tour −1 (organized tour), 1 (individual) 15 Beach availability −1 (no), 1 (yes) 16 Brand −1 (jetset), 1 (creative holidays)</p><p>Charge card A and B (no transaction option for card A) 1 ASC for credit card 0, 1 2 ASC for debit card 0, 1 3 ASC for transaction card for each disease. <ref type="bibr">16</ref> The members of the sample in data set 1 are Ashkenazi Jews, who are a population of <ref type="bibr">16</ref> Note that the four alternative choice set in this experiment is of the form A B AB 0 , where A and B are the options to get one or the other medical test, AB is the option to get both tests, and 0 is the option to get neither test. In applying the multinomial choice framework in such a context, it is important to be careful in specifying the utility of the AB option. An early reference in this regard is <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Keane and Moffitt (1998)</ref>, who modelled the decision to participate in combinations of available public welfare programs. They noted that the costs and benefits of jointly participating in two programs may be a complex function of the costs and benefits of participating in each program individually (e.g., one program may tax part of another program's benefits). In the present case, the interaction between the two tests is rather simple. First, the cost of getting both tests may be less than the sum of the costs getting each test separately. Thus the cost variable in the AB utility function is the joint cost of getting both tests together. Second, there may be savings on time, discomfort, or both in getting the two tests jointly rather than separately (e.g., it may require just one interest as they have a relatively high probability of carrying Tay Sachs.</p><p>The estimation results are presented in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_11">6</ref>. The first column presents results for a simple MNL model. All attribute coefficients are significant with expected signs (except for how the result is communicated, which is not significant). Cost has a negative effect, doctor recommendation and risk factors have positive effects, and inaccuracy has a negative effect.</p><p>The second column contains results for the S-MNL model with homogeneous ASCs. The scale parameter is 1.14 with a standard error of 0.09, implying office visit, one blood sample, etc.). Because we do not measure such attributes directly, they are captured by the AB option having its own intercept. As Keane and Moffitt (1998) noted, estimation of separate models for options A and B cannot adequately capture such synergies between the two alternatives (even if the errors in the separate models are allowed to be correlated).    substantial scale heterogeneity in the data. Including scale heterogeneity leads to a dramatic improvement in the likelihood over MNL, from −3 717 to −3 223 (i.e., 494 points, or 13%). S-MNL adds only one parameter, so it leads to substantial improvements in all three information criteria (AIC, BIC, and CAIC).</p><p>In the third column we report results of the S-MNL model with heterogeneity in the ASCs. Allowing for such heterogeneity leads to a further substantial improvement in fit (e.g., 408 points in the likelihood, or 11%). Note that the scale heterogeneity parameter falls from 1.22 to 0.64 but remains highly significant with a standard error of 0.06.</p><p>The next two columns of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_11">6</ref> present results from MIXL and the G-MNL model that nests MIXL and S-MNL. Two aspects of the results are notable. First, although the S-MNL model provides a great improvement in fit compared to simple MNL, the improvement achieved by MIXL is, at least in this data set, considerably greater. MIXL achieves a loglikelihood of −2 500 versus −3 717 for MNL. This is a 33% improvement compared to the 24% improvement achieved by S-MNL (with random ASCs). Of course, this is not too surprising, because MIXL adds 66 parameters, whereas S-MNL (with random ASCs) adds only 7.</p><p>Second, G-MNL provides a better fit than either MIXL or S-MNL alone. By adding two parameters, it achieves a log-likelihood improvement of 20 points over MIXL, and it beats MIXL on all three information criteria (AIC, BIC, and CAIC).</p><p>Note that the G-MNL estimate of the scale parameter is 0.45 with a standard error of 0.08. Thus, the estimates imply a substantial degree of scale heterogeneity in the data, even after allowing for correlated normal random coefficients. As n = exp − 2 /2 + 0n , the estimates imply a person at the 90th percentile of the scale parameter would have his or her vector of utility weights scaled up by 57%, whereas a person at the 10th percentile would have his or her vector of utility weights scaled down by 46%.</p><p>The estimate of is 0.11, which implies the data is closer to the G-MNL-II model (see Equation ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>)), where the variance of residual taste heterogeneity increases with scale, than the G-MNL-I model (see Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_25">8</ref>)), where it is invariant to scale.</p><p>Finally, the last two columns of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_11">6</ref> report estimates of MIXL and G-MNL with uncorrelated residual taste heterogeneity. These are of interest in part because MIXL with uncorrelated coefficients is popular among practitioners. Restricting residual heterogeneity to be independent across attributes leads to a sharp deterioration of the log-likelihood-by over 250 points for both MIXL and G-MNL. 17 AIC, BIC, and   CAIC all prefer the G-MNL model with correlated taste heterogeneity. This is a bit surprising, in light of our Monte Carlo result that BIC and CAIC tend to prefer the uncorrelated model even if correlation is present.</p><p>With the above discussion as a guide, the interested reader should be able to follow the empirical results in Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">7-15</ref>. Rather than describe each of these in   detail, we turn to a discussion of general patterns that emerge across data sets.    indicated that BIC and CAIC were the most reliable criteria for determining whether scale heterogeneity is present. According to BIC and CAIC, G-MNL is the preferred model in 7 out of 10 data sets. S-MNL (with random intercepts) is preferred in the remaining three data sets (mobile phones and charge cards A and B). Thus, models that include scale heterogeneity are preferred over MIXL in all cases. That S-MNL is preferred in three cases is striking, given the great simplicity of this model relative to its competitors. For example, in the mobile phone data set, S-MNL (with a random intercept) beats MIXL by 176 points on BIC and beats G-MNL by 160 points. However, it has only 17 parameters, compared to 45 for MIXL and 47 for G-MNL. Similarly, in the charge card A and B data sets, S-MNL beats MIXL by 176 and 159 points on BIC, respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Comparing Model Fit Across Data Sets</head><p>Among the seven data sets where G-MNL is preferred by BIC and CAIC, the G-MNL model with correlated errors is preferred only in the two Tay Sachs data sets. The G-MNL model with uncorrelated residual taste heterogeneity is preferred in five data sets (Pap smear, Pizzas A and B, and Holidays A and B), but this result should be interpreted with caution in light of our Monte Carlo results in §4, showing that BIC and CAIC tend to prefer simpler models without correlation even when error correlations are present.</p><p>In the seven cases where BIC and AIC prefer G-MNL, the AIC, which imposes a smaller penalty for additional parameters, always prefers the full version of G-MNL with correlated errors. This is not too surprising, because our Monte Carlo results suggest that AIC is more likely to prefer models with correlated errors when correlation is in fact present.</p><p>The AIC results regarding the preferred model contradict BIC and CAIC in only three data sets. For mobile phones, AIC prefers G-MNL with correlated errors, whereas BIC and CAIC both prefer S-MNL. Also, in the two credit card data sets, AIC slightly prefers MIXL with correlated errors, although the advantage over G-MNL and S-MNL is very small.</p><p>In summary, models with scale heterogeneity (G-MNL or S-MNL) are preferred by all three information criteria in 8 out of 10 cases. In the other two cases, AIC picks MIXL, whereas BIC and CAIC pick S-MNL. Thus, there is clear evidence that scale heterogeneity is important in eight data sets and substantial evidence it is important in the other two. <ref type="bibr">18</ref> A final notable result is that MIXL with uncorrelated errors, which is very widely used (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Train 2007)</ref>, is never preferred. According to BIC and CAIC, it is beaten by G-MNL with uncorrelated errors in every data set except mobile phones. It is beaten by S-MNL in mobile phones, as well as the Tay Sachs general population data, and the two charge card data sets. It is beaten by MIXL with correlated errors in the Tay Sachs and charge card data. According to BIC and CAIC, it is beaten by G-MNL with correlated errors in those four data sets plus Pizza B and Holiday B, <ref type="bibr">18</ref> Among the 10 data sets, ran off to 0-and had to be pegged near 0-in five cases, and it ran off to one in another. Only in four cases (the Tay Sachs data sets, mobile phones, and charge card A) do we find intermediate values of . Usually was small, implying the G-MNL-II model is often a reasonable description of the data. In practice, we would advise users of G-MNL who experience the problem of running off to 0 or 1 to simply peg the parameter (at 0 or 1) and estimate either G-MNL-I or G-MNL-II, whichever is appropriate.   and under AIC it is beaten by G-MNL with correlated errors in every data set. The only case where it comes even close to being the preferred model is the Pap smear data. Thus, the data offer no empirical support for MIXL with uncorrelated errors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.">Why Do Models with Scale Heterogeneity Fit</head><p>Better than MIXL? We have shown that models with scale heterogeneity (either G-MNL or S-MNL) are preferred by BIC and CAIC in all 10 data sets, and preferred by AIC in 8 out of 10. Thus, we have strong evidence that models with scale heterogeneity provide a better fit to a wide range of data sets than do models like MIXL that rely on residual taste heterogeneity alone. In this section we ask, why do models with scale heterogeneity fit better? That is, what behavioural patterns can they explain better than the MIXL model? Moreover, what substantive behavioural predictions differ between the G-MNL model and simpler, nested models like MIXL?</p><p>These key questions are addressed in Figures 2 to 5 and looking specifically at the Pizza B data, although we could have shown similar figures for other data sets. In Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>, we order the 328 individuals from the one with the least negative log-likelihood contribution in the MIXL model (i.e., the person the model fits best) to the one with the most negative contribution (i.e., the person the model fits worst). We then plot these people from left to right (the dark circles). We also plot each person's log-likelihood contribution according to the G-MNL model (the light crosses). The horizontal line is the log-likelihood of the naïve model that assumes equal choice probabilities for both alternatives. We also divide the sample into thirds: the type I people on the left that MIXL fits best, the type II people in the middle, and the type III people on the right (for whom the fit is often worse than the naïve model).</p><p>The key result of Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> is that G-MNL generally fits types I and type III better than MIXL, whereas the fit for type II is about the same. What does this mean? It turns out the type I people are "extreme" and have preferences close to lexicographic. For instance, of these 109 people, 22 always choose the pizza with fresher ingredients on all choice occasions, regardless of other attributes, 18 always choose the pizza with the lower price, etc. <ref type="bibr">19</ref> The G-MNL model is better able to explain such extreme behaviour by saying that (1) some people have a very small scale for the error term (or, conversely, very large attribute weights), so there is little randomness in their behaviour; and</p><p>(2) because attribute weights are random, for some people one or a few attributes are much more important than others, so that one or few attributes almost entirely drive choices.</p><p>Type III people present behaviour that is highly random. That is, their behaviour is largely driven by the idiosyncratic error term njt and is little affected by attributes. Indeed, the naïve model that assumes equal choice probabilities regardless of attribute settings generally fits their behaviour better than MIXL. G-MNL still has trouble fitting the behaviour of such          Note. Bold estimates are statistically significant at the 1% level.     </p><p>Note. Bold estimates are statistically significant at the 1% level. people, but it gives a clear improvement over MIXL. G-MNL is better able to explain "random" people because it can say that some people have a very large scale of the error term (or, conversely, very small attribute weights). 20 Some further insight is gained by looking at the bottom panel of Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>. Here, we fit simple MNL models to the type I, II, and III groups separately. Note that for the type III people we obtain very small attribute weights. Thus, choices made by type III people are largely driven by the error terms. In this sense they are highly random. In contrast, for type I people we estimate very large attribute weights. This makes their choices very sensitive to attribute settings. The type II people are in the middle. One can clearly see a general scaling up of the attribute weights as one moves from type III to type II to type I.</p><p>Having isolated why G-MNL fits better than MIXL, we turn to the question of how its substantive predictions differ. In Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref>, the four graphs correspond to MNL, S-MNL, MIXL, and G-MNL, respectively. Each graph shows the distribution of people in terms of their probability of choosing between the two pizza delivery services. <ref type="bibr">21</ref> The distribution is shown under two scenarios: a baseline where services A and B have identical attributes, and a scenario where service A improves ingredient quality (to all fresh) while also raising the price by $4.</p><p>Of course, under the baseline, each model says that 100% of the people have a 50% probability of choosing A. After the policy change, MNL (which assumes homogeneous preferences) predicts that all people have a 52% chance of choosing A. In contrast, S-MNL predicts heterogeneity in consumer responses. Forty-one percent of consumers continue to have a roughly 50% chance of choosing A, whereas for 43% the probability of choosing A increases to about 55%, <ref type="bibr">20</ref> Note that, in principle, the MIXL model can also generate some people for whom all attribute weights are small. However, in a model with several attributes, this would be a very unlikely event. This would still be a problem if MIXL used an alternative heterogeneity distribution, such as multivariate t. <ref type="bibr">21</ref> Note that here we adopt the mathematical psychology view that choice is random for an individual across choice occasions. In the economist's view, the randomness in choice exists solely from the point of view of the analyst, who does not observe a consumer's preference type or all the relevant product attributes. In this view, a consumer faced with the same choice situation on two occasions should make the same choice. However, this view is hard to reconcile with behaviour in choice experiments where consumers make repeated choices (e.g., 32 in the Pizza B data set). Inevitably one sees cases where, when presented with A versus B, a person chooses A, and then later, in a situation that is identical except that an attribute of A is improved, the person chooses B. Randomness across choice occasions at the individual level is necessary to explain this. Such randomness is present in choice models applied to experimental data whenever one lets the stochastic terms differ across choice occasions. and for 17% of the probability of choosing A increases into the 60%-75% range.</p><p>The more interesting comparison is between MIXL and G-MNL. G-MNL predicts that after the policy change 14% of consumers still have a 50% chance of choosing A. Strikingly, 8% of consumers would have essentially a 100% chance of choosing A (these are the types who put great weight on fresh ingredients), whereas 5% would have essentially a 0% chance of choosing A (these are the types who care primarily about price). As we would expect based on the Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> results, MIXL predicts that fewer people stay indifferent and also that fewer people have extreme reactions. Specifically, MIXL predicts that only 8% of consumers stay at roughly a 50% chance of choosing A, whereas essentially no consumers have their choice probabilities move all the way to 100% or 0%.</p><p>In the actual Pizza B data, there are 24/328 = 7 3% of subjects who choose the fresh ingredient pizza on all choice occasions regardless of other attribute settings, and there are 27/328 = 8 2% who always choose the less expensive pizza. The Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref> results show that G-MNL can generate such extreme (or lexicographic) behaviour, whereas MIXL cannot.</p><p>To gain additional insight into why the behavioural predictions of G-MNL and MIXL differ, we report for each model the posterior means of the person-level coefficients on fresh ingredients and price. To do this we condition on the estimated model parameters and the 32 observed choices of each person, using the algorithm in <ref type="bibr">Train (2003, p. 266)</ref>. Distributions of the posterior means of the person-specific parameters are reported in Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref>. <ref type="bibr">22</ref> The difference in posteriors generated from MIXL and G-MNL is striking. Although the MIXL posteriors depart modestly from normality, the strong influence of the normal prior, and its tendency to pull in tail observations, is evident. In contrast, the G-MNL posteriors are multimodal, with considerable tail mass. For instance, the G-MNL posterior for the price coefficient has a substantial mass of people in the left tail who care greatly about price. In addition, the G-MNL posterior for the coefficient on fresh ingredients has a substantial mass of people in the right tail who greatly value freshness. This illustrates the flexibility of the continuous mixture of scaled normals prior for individual-level coefficients in the G-MNL model.</p><p>Finally, Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref> shows that the pattern shown in Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref> emerges not just for fresh ingredients but <ref type="bibr">22</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Allenby and Rossi (1998)</ref> call this an "approximate Bayesian" approach. We tried integrating over uncertainty in the estimated model parameters, as well as uncertainty in calculating the posterior means. This made little difference, presumably because (1) the model coefficients are estimated quite precisely, and (2) with 32 observations per person, the posterior means are also estimated rather precisely.   for other attributes as well. Each panel plots the distribution of consumer choice probabilities under an experiment where one attribute of pizza delivery service A is improved, and price is also increased by $4. The first panel repeats the fresh ingredients experiment from Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref>. However, now the probability distributions of the G-MNL and MIXL models are plotted side by side, making the differences easier to see. Clearly, the G-MNL model puts more mass near the center of the distribution of choice probabilities (i.e., close to 50%) and more mass in the tails (close to 0% or 100%). The same basic pattern holds in experiments where firm A offers gourmet pizza, steaming hot pizza, or a vegetarian option. What are the managerial implications of these results? Unlike the situation in the Pizza B choice experiment, in the real world, pizza delivery firms do not offer a single type of pizza (or a small range of options) at a single price. They offer a wide range of pizzas with different attributes at different prices. To determine the optimal menu of offerings, a firm needs to know the entire distribution of demand. It is beyond the scope of this paper to design optimal menus. However, it is clear that optimal price discrimination strategies would differ between a market where a significant fraction of consumers have essentially lexicographic preferences versus a market where attribute weights differs less markedly across consumers.</p><p>In summary, these results make clear why models with scale heterogeneity (G-MNL or S-MNL) fit better than MIXL in every data set we examine. The models with scale heterogeneity are able to generate the sort of extreme (or lexicographic) behaviour that is common in choice experiments, whereas MIXL cannot. They are also able to capture random choice behaviour (i.e., low responsiveness to attribute settings) better than MIXL. The reason for both advantages is transparent. Models that include scale can generate random behaviour by setting the scale large and can generate lexicographic behaviour by setting the scale small (while also letting one attribute have a large idiosyncratic component of its preference weight).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4.">Comparing the Importance of Heterogeneity</head><p>Across Data Sets Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">17</ref> summarizes results across the 10 data sets. <ref type="bibr">23</ref> One interesting pattern is the extent to which including heterogeneity of all types leads to improvement in model fit. That is, what is the percentage improvement in the log-likelihood when we go from the simple MNL model to the full-fledged G-MNL model? Strikingly, this differs greatly by data set, ranging from only 12% to 16% in the mobile phone, Pizza B, and Holiday B data sets to as much as 33% to 40% in the Tay Sachs and Pap smear data sets. Another metric (not reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">17</ref>) is the improvement in pseudo-R 2 when heterogeneity is included. This ranges from 0.27 to 0.35 in the three medical data sets, but from only 0.10 to 0.17 in the other data sets. <ref type="bibr">24</ref> Thus, the extent of preference heterogeneity in the three data sets involving medical decisions is roughly twice as great as in those for consumption goods (phones, pizza delivery, holidays, charge cards). There are a number of possible explanations for this pattern. People may have stronger feelings about medical procedures than the more mundane attributes of consumer products. People may have very different attitudes towards risk. Perhaps medical decision making is a more complex or higher involvement task, and taste heterogeneity in general (and perhaps scale heterogeneity in particular) increases with task complexity. <ref type="bibr">25 26</ref> A second interesting pattern is how the importance of scale heterogeneity differs across data sets. We cannot calculate the fraction of heterogeneity that the G-MNL model assigns to residual versus scale, because the improvement in the likelihood when these are included is not additive. However, we can get a sense of the importance of scale heterogeneity by asking, Of the total improvement in the likelihood achieved by adding all forms of heterogeneity, what fraction is attained by adding scale heterogeneity alone? 27 Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">17</ref> reports this figure for the S-MNL models with and without random ASCs. The more 24 Pseudo-R 2 for a discrete-choice model is defined as 1−LL(m)/ LL(0), where LL(m) is the log-likelihood of the model, and LL(0) is that of a "null" model that assigns equal probability to each choice. <ref type="bibr">25</ref> Medical decisions are also relatively "unfamiliar" tasks compared to choice among common consumer goods. It is plausible that choice in such unfamiliar contexts is more difficult. relevant figure is that for models with fixed ASCs, because the likelihood improvement from adding random intercepts is more appropriately ascribed to residual taste heterogeneity.</p><p>Differences in results across data sets are striking. For mobile phones, 71% of the log-likelihood improvement that can be achieved by introducing all heterogeneity is achieved by introducing scale heterogeneity alone. For the three medical tests (Pap smear, Tay Sachs Jewish sample, Tay Sachs general population sample) the values range from 40% to 66%, but in the other data sets scale heterogeneity appears to be less important. In the pizza delivery and holiday destination data sets the fraction of the total loglikelihood improvement that can be achieved just by introducing scale is only 13% to 23%, and in the two charge card data sets, the values are only 21% to 22%.</p><p>Another way to gauge the importance of scale heterogeneity is by the improvement in pseudo-R 2 when it is added to the model. This ranges from 0.07 to 0.23 in the medical and mobile phone data sets 28 but from only 0.02 to 0.05 in the other data sets.</p><p>Thus, by both metrics, scale heterogeneity appears to be much more important in the medical and mobile phone data sets than for pizza, holidays, and charge cards. What accounts for this contrast? One hypothesis is that scale heterogeneity increases with task complexity. It is intuitive that choices about medical tests are complex, because they involve making decisions about risks and probabilities, which humans have difficultly understanding. Similarly, mobile phones are high-tech goods with attributes like WiFi connectivity, voice commands, USB connections, etc., which consumers may also find difficult to assess. In contrast, attributes of simple consumer goods like pizza and holidays (e.g., thick crust, quality of hotels) may be easier to evaluate. Thus, the results appear consistent with a view that scale heterogeneity is more important in more complex choice contexts.</p><p>In summary, we find that two hypotheses seem at least consistent with the observed patterns across data sets. First, heterogeneity (in general) is more important in data sets that involve high-involvement decisions (e.g., medical tests). Second, scale heterogeneity is more important in data sets that involve more complex choice objects (i.e., objects with more complex attributes). Of course, we view both of these hypotheses as merely preliminary, but they suggest interesting avenues for future work. ment in going to the most general model may be decomposed into parts because of residual versus scale heterogeneity.</p><p>Marketing Science 29(3), pp. 393-421, © 2010 INFORMS Finally, we tried using observed covariates to explain differences in scale across subjects, as in Equation ( <ref type="formula">12</ref>), but we had little success and hence do not report the results. Our limited data on subject characteristics did not help to explain scale, nor did our measures of task complexity (number of attributes, number of alternatives, number of attributes that differ among alternatives, number of scenarios). Clearly, more work is needed on this topic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.5.">Comparing Willingness to Pay Calculations in</head><p>the MIXL and G-MNL Models An important issue that arises in choice modelling is the calculation of consumer willingness to pay (WTP) for changes in product attributes. How best to do this in random coefficient models has recently been an active area of research (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Sonnier et al. 2007</ref>). To understand the issue, consider a general model with heterogeneity in (1) the attribute weights, (2) the price coefficient, and (3) the scale parameter: In the model in Utility space, WTP for an additional unit of attribute k is nk / n , and for the model in WTP space it is simply * n . <ref type="bibr">29</ref> These two models will give identical fits to the data, and identical estimates of WTP, provided the specification and estimation methods maintain the restrictions that * n = n / n and n = n . Practitioners have reported, however, that the two models give very different estimates of WTP, and in particular that estimates obtained in utility space are often unreasonably large. The source of these differences is that, in practice, it is difficult (or inconvenient) to specify the utility space and WTP space models in such a way that they are equivalent. <ref type="bibr">30</ref> This does not mean, however, that the two models are not equivalent if properly specified.</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">U njt = n x njt − n p njt + njt / n n = 1 N j = 1 J t = 1 T (</formula><p>It is interesting to examine the issue of estimating WTP in the context of the G-MNL and S-MNL models. Rewriting (7) so the price coefficient is explicit, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">U njt = n + n + 1 − n n x njt − n + n + 1 − n n p njt + njt (14)</formula><p>where denotes the mean price coefficient in the population. If only scale heterogeneity matters, WTP for a unit of attribute k reduces to just k / , where k denotes the kth element of the vector. This illustrates a strong property of the S-MNL model-there is heterogeneity in coefficients but not in WTP. <ref type="bibr">31</ref> However, this does not mean there is no heterogeneity in price sensitivity. For example, in the pure S-MNL model the derivative of the choice probability with respect to price is P n j X nt / p njt = −P n j X nt 1 − P n j X nt • n • . Thus, as n → 0, only unobserved attributes matter for choice, and price sensitivity goes to zero.</p><p>This illustrates an odd aspect of the "willingness to pay" concept in choice models. A consumer's WTP for an attribute increase is defined as the price increase which, combined with the attribute increase, leaves the deterministic part of his utility for a brand unchanged-and hence the choice probability unchanged. However, consider the same unit increase in the attribute holding price fixed. Given heterogeneity, consumers with the same WTP for the attribute will not in general have the same increase in their choice probability for the brand (even given the same initial probability). Consumers with larger n in the WTP space model, or larger n = * n n in the utility space model, will have a larger increase in demand. In other words, it is perfectly compatible that some consumers have a large WTP for an attribute but that introducing it leads to little increase in their probability of choosing the brand. positive). Regardless, the distribution of WTP for attribute k is the ratio nk / n , where the numerator is normal and the denominator normal or log-normal. In contrast, in the WTP space model, the WTP distribution is simply that of * nk , which is typically specified as normal (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Sonnier et al. 2007</ref>). Hence, it is not surprising that the two models-as typically specified-give very different answers, because there is no reason to expect nk / n to be approximately normal. Furthermore, it is not surprising that, in a utility space model, WTP sometimes takes on extreme values; we are taking the ratio of two random variables, where the denominator is normal or log-normal, and the ratio can "explode" because the denominator is close to zero. In general, WTP in the G-MNL model is given by the ratio</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">n k + kn + 1− n kn / n + n + 1− n n</formula><p>Although seemingly complicated, this is no more difficult to simulate than nk / n in the MIXL model. To guarantee "reasonable" WTP estimates one must choose distributions for n and n so that the price coefficient</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">n + n + 1 − n n</formula><p>is bounded away from zero. However, in light of our previous comments, we argue that WTP calculations are overemphasized and that more emphasis should be placed on simulating demand. This will become clear below.</p><p>In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">18</ref>, we compare demand and WTP predictions of the G-MNL and MIXL models, again focusing on the Pizza B data set. The top and bottom panels report results for MIXL and G-MNL, respectively. In the first row we consider an experiment where delivery service A switches from traditional to gourmet pizza while raising the price by $4 (holding other attributes equal between the two services). Both MIXL and G-MNL predict that roughly 39% of consumers would choose service A under this experiment (as opposed to 50% under the baseline where all attributes are equal). Thus, the demand curves generated by both models imply that roughly 39% of consumers are willing to pay $4 extra for gourmet pizza.</p><p>A similar pattern holds when we look (see the next three rows of each panel) at the demand predictions for fresh ingredients, guaranteed hot pizza, and vegetarian pizza. In each case, the demand predictions from G-MNL and MIXL are almost identical. This pattern holds across all data sets and a wide range of prediction scenarios: aggregate demand predictions from G-MNL and MIXL are almost identical. Recall that the key difference between the two models arises not from their predictions about aggregate demand but in their predictions about the distribution of demand across individual types of people (see §5.3).</p><p>We turn next to the distribution of WTP implied by each model. For both G-MNL and MIXL this is simulated in the conventional way, as described above. At the 50th percentile, the WTP for gourmet pizza is close to zero according to both models. At the 75th percentile it is about $3 according to MIXL and $2.40 according to G-MNL. Thus, given the simulated WTP distributions, both models imply less than 25% of consumers are willing to pay $4 extra for gourmet pizza. Here, we see immediately how WTP distributions generated by both models (calculated in the conventional way) seriously contradict the demand predictions, as we have already seen that both models predict that roughly 39% of consumers would be willing to pay $4 extra for the gourmet pizza. Indeed, based on the overall WTP distribution, the MIXL model implies that only 23% of consumers would buy the gourmet pizza at a $4 price premium, and the G-MNL model implies that only 20% of consumers would do so.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusion</head><p>Consumer taste heterogeneity is of central importance for many issues in marketing and economics. For at least 25 years there has been a large ongoing research program on how best to model heterogeneity. This research program has produced a large number of alternative modelling approaches. One of the most popular is the MIXL model. In most applications of MIXL, the vector of consumer utility weights is assumed to have a multivariate normal distribution in the population. However, <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Louviere et al. (1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Louviere et al. ( , 2008b</ref> have recently argued, based on estimation of individual-level models, that much of the heterogeneity in attribute weights is better described as a pure scale effect (i.e., across consumers, weights on all attributes are scaled up or down in tandem). This implies that choice behaviour is simply more random for some consumers than others (i.e., holding attribute coefficients fixed, the scale of their error term In this paper we have developed a G-MNL that nests S-MNL and MIXL. By estimating the G-MNL model on 10 data sets, we provide empirical evidence on the importance of scale heterogeneity and on the relative ability of the MIXL, S-MNL, and G-MNL models to fit the data. Our main results show that, based on BIC and CAIC, the G-MNL model is preferred in seven data sets, whereas the S-MNL model is preferred in the other three. This is striking evidence of the importance of scale heterogeneity-and of the ability of models that include scale heterogeneity to outperform MIXL.</p><p>We also show why G-MNL fits better than MIXL. Specifically, it can better explain the behaviour of extreme consumers who exhibit near lexicographic preferences (i.e., consumers who nearly always choose the option with a particular attribute, such as lowest price or highest quality, regardless of the attributes of other alternatives). G-MNL is also better able to explain highly random consumers whose choices are relatively insensitive to product attributes (i.e., consumer with a large scale of the idiosyncratic error terms).</p><p>We went on to show that the G-MNL model allows more flexibility in the posterior distribution of individual-level parameters than does MIXL. From an "approximate Bayesian" perspective, the MIXL model with a normal heterogeneity distribution imposes a normal prior on the distribution of individuallevel parameters. However, G-MNL imposes a much more flexible continuous mixture of scaled normals prior. Thus, even given a large amount of data per person, MIXL posteriors depart only modestly from normality, but G-MNL posteriors exhibit sharp departures. These include both multimodality with spikes in the tails (people who care greatly about particular attributes) and excess kurtosis (people who have small attribute weights or, conversely, a large scale of the error term).</p><p>An important avenue for future research is to compare G-MNL with alternative models that also allow a more flexible distribution of individual-level parameters, such as mixture of normals logit and probit models. The potential advantage of G-MNL is that it achieves a flexible distribution while adding only two parameters to the normal model.</p><p>Our analysis also yielded two interesting empirical findings. First, taste heterogeneity in general was far more important for medical decisions than for consumer goods. Second, scale heterogeneity was more important in data sets that involve more complex choice objects. Of course, these empirical findings are quite preliminary because they involve only 10 data sets.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>394</head><label></label><figDesc>Marketing Science 29(3), pp. 393-421, © 2010 INFORMS depend on subsequent usage, not just on purchase).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The attributes and true values are constructed from the Pap smear data set (X 1 is ASC). The number of draws used in simulated maximum likelihood estimation is 500. We construct 20 artificial data sets (indexed by m = 1 20) and compare the estimates to the true values.¯ = 1/20 20 m=1 m ; Std. dev. = 1/19 20 m=1 m −¯ 2 ; ASE = 1/20 20</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The attributes and true values are constructed from the Holiday A data set. The number of draws used in simulated maximum likelihood estimation is 500. We construct 20 artificial data sets (indexed by m = 1 20) and compare the estimates to the true values.¯ = 1/20 20 m=1 m ; Std. dev. = 1/19 20 m=1 m −¯ 2 ; ASE = 1/20 20 m=1 ASE m , where m and ASE m denote parameter estimates and asymptotic standard errors, respectively, from each data set. An asterisk indicates the t-statistic for the estimated bias greater than the critical value at the 5% level; i.e., t &gt; 2 09, where t = √ 20 ¯ − true Std. dev. −1 . The true values are from Table</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Marketing</head><label></label><figDesc>Science 29(3), pp. 393-421, © 2010 INFORMS The results of estimating the G-MNL model on the 20 artificial data sets based on the Holiday A data set are reported in Table</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Marketing</head><label></label><figDesc>Science 29(3), pp. 393-421, © 2010 INFORMS</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>available), 1 (not available) 7 Overdraft interest free days (up to) −30 5 15 30 /10 8 Interest charged on outstanding credit/overdraft −0 075 −0 035 0 015 075 * 100 9 Interest earned on positive balance Credit: access (omitted EFTPOS + telephone + Internet + mail, use worldwide) 11 (1) Nowhere else, use Australia-wide −1, 0, 1 12 (2) EFTPOS + telephone + Internet + mail, use Australia-wide −1, 0, 1 13 (3) Nowhere else, use worldwide −1, 0, 1 14 Loyalty scheme 0 (none), 1 (frequent flyer/fly buys and other rewards) 15 Loyalty scheme annual fees −40 40 /10 if loyalty scheme = 1; 0 if loyalty scheme = 0 16 Loyalty scheme points earning −1 (points on outstanding balance interest paid on), 1 (points on purchases only) 17 Merchant surcharge for using card −0 03 −0 01 0 01 03 * 100 18 Surcharge for transactions at other banks ATM Credit:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Fiebig</head><label></label><figDesc>et al.: The Generalized Multinomial Logit Model 406 Marketing Science 29(3), pp. 393-421, © 2010 INFORMS</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head>Marketing</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2Individuals' Log-Likelihood from Pizza B Data Set (N = 328; T = 32; Binary Choice)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head>Fiebig</head><label></label><figDesc>et al.: The Generalized Multinomial Logit Model 416 Marketing Science 29(3), pp. 393-421, © 2010 INFORMS</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fiebig et al.: The Generalized Multinomial Logit Model    </figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science 29(3), pp. 393-421, © 2010 INFORMS</cell><cell>397</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Monte Carlo Simulation Results-Pap Smear Test Configuration</figDesc><table><row><cell>True¯</cell><cell>Std. dev.</cell><cell>ASE</cell><cell>True¯</cell><cell>Std. dev.</cell><cell>ASE</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="4">Monte Carlo Simulation Results-Holiday A Configuration</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>True¯</cell><cell>Std. dev.</cell><cell>ASE</cell><cell>True¯</cell><cell>Std. dev.</cell><cell>ASE</cell><cell>True¯</cell><cell>Std. dev.</cell><cell>ASE</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Monte Carlo Simulation Results</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Correlated error</cell><cell cols="2">Uncorrelated error</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>MNL</cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell>G-MNL</cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell>G-MNL</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">(a) Pap smear test data configuration</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">True DGP is G-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>AIC</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>11</cell></row><row><cell>BIC</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>18</cell></row><row><cell>CAIC</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>16</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">True DGP is MIXL</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>AIC</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>BIC</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>19</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>CAIC</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>19</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">True DGP is S-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>AIC</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>20</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>MNL with uncorrelated errors. In contrast, for the Holiday A data sets, AIC correctly picks G-MNL with correlated errors in all 20 cases. Now consider BIC and CAIC (which have larger penalties for adding parameters). In both data sets, these criteria tend to pick the more parsimonious G-MNL with uncorrelated errors, even though errors are correlated. Indeed, they occasionally even pick MIXL with uncorrelated errors.Next consider the case where MIXL with correlated errors is the true model. In this case BIC and CAIC correctly pick MIXL as the true model in the large majority of cases, but they always choose the more parsimonious version with uncorrelated errors. The performance of AIC in this case is poor, because it incorrectly chooses G-MNL in 12/20 cases in the Pap smear data sets, and 7/20 cases in the Holiday A data sets.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>or MIXL</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Wrong</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Right</cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell>G-MNL</cell></row><row><cell>BIC</cell><cell>68</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>5</cell></row><row><cell>CAIC</cell><cell>66</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>4</cell></row><row><cell>AIC</cell><cell>61</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>19</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">sets, AIC correctly picks it in 9/20 cases. However,</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">in 11/20 cases AIC chooses instead the more par-</cell></row><row><cell>simonious G-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Empirical Data Sets</cell></row><row><cell>No. of</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table 5 (</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Cont'd.)    </figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>Table 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Tay Sachs Disease (TS) and Cystic Fibrosis (CF) Test: Jewish Sample (Three ASCs)</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Scale</cell><cell cols="2">Random</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Correlated errors</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Uncorrelated errors</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">heterogeneity</cell><cell></cell><cell>effects</cell><cell cols="2">Mixed logit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Mixed logit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell></row><row><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_13"><head>Table 7</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Tay Sachs Disease (TS) and Cystic Fibrosis (CF) Test: General Population Sample (Three ASCs)</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Scale</cell><cell cols="2">Random</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Correlated errors</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Uncorrelated errors</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">heterogeneity</cell><cell></cell><cell>effects</cell><cell cols="2">Mixed logit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Mixed logit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell></row><row><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_15"><head>Table 8</head><label>8</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Mobile Phones (One ASC)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Scale</cell><cell cols="2">Random</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Correlated errors</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Uncorrelated errors</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">heterogeneity</cell><cell></cell><cell>effects</cell><cell cols="2">One-factor</cell><cell cols="2">One-factor</cell><cell cols="2">Mixed logit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell></row><row><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_17"><head>Table 16</head><label>16</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>compares the fit of our seven alternative</cell></row><row><cell>models (MNL, S-MNL, MIXL, G-MNL, and the latter</cell></row><row><cell>two with uncorrelated taste heterogeneity) across the</cell></row><row><cell>10 data sets. Recall that our Monte Carlo results in  §4</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_18"><head>Table 9</head><label>9</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Pizza A (No ASC)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Scale</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Correlated errors</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Uncorrelated errors</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">heterogeneity</cell><cell cols="2">Mixed logit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Mixed logit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell></row><row><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_20"><head>Table 10</head><label>10</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Holiday A (No ASC)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Scale</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Correlated errors</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Uncorrelated errors</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">heterogeneity</cell><cell cols="2">Mixed logit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Mixed logit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell></row><row><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_23"><head>Table 11</head><label>11</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Pap Smear Test (One ASC)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Correlated errors</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Uncorrelated errors</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Scale</cell><cell cols="2">Random</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">heterogeneity</cell><cell></cell><cell>effects</cell><cell>Mixed logit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Mixed logit</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>MNL</cell><cell cols="2">S-MNL</cell><cell cols="2">S-MNL</cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell>G-MNL</cell></row><row><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell cols="2">Std. err. Est. Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell cols="2">Std. err. Est. Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_25"><head>Table 12</head><label>12</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Pizza B (No ASC)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Correlated errors</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Uncorrelated errors</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Scale</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">heterogeneity</cell><cell cols="2">One-factor</cell><cell cols="2">One-factor</cell><cell cols="2">Mixed logit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell></row><row><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_27"><head>Table 13</head><label>13</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Holiday B (No ASC)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Scale</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Correlated errors</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Uncorrelated errors</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">heterogeneity</cell><cell cols="2">One-factor</cell><cell cols="2">One-factor</cell><cell cols="2">Mixed logit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>MNL</cell><cell cols="2">S-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell></row><row><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_29"><head>Table 14</head><label>14</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Charge Card A (Two ASCs)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Scale</cell><cell>Random</cell><cell cols="2">Correlated errors</cell><cell cols="2">Uncorrelated errors</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">heterogeneity</cell><cell>effects</cell><cell>One-factor</cell><cell>One-factor</cell><cell>Mixed logit</cell></row><row><cell>MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell>G-MNL</cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell>G-MNL</cell></row><row><cell>Est. Std. err.</cell><cell>Est</cell><cell cols="2">Std. err. Est. Std. err.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>Est Std. err. Est. Std. err. Est. Std. err. Est. Std. err.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_30"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Note. Bold estimates are statistically significant at the 1% level.</figDesc><table><row><cell>412</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Fiebig et al.: The Generalized Multinomial Logit Model Marketing Science 29(3), pp. 393-421, © 2010 INFORMS</cell></row><row><cell>No. of parameters</cell><cell>17</cell><cell>18</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>51</cell><cell>53</cell><cell>35</cell><cell>37</cell></row><row><cell>LL</cell><cell>−3,354</cell><cell>−3,217</cell><cell>−2,768</cell><cell>−2,735</cell><cell>−2,734</cell><cell>−2,868</cell><cell>−2,820</cell></row><row><cell>AIC</cell><cell>6,742</cell><cell>6,470</cell><cell>5,579</cell><cell>5,572</cell><cell>5,574</cell><cell>5,806</cell><cell>5,714</cell></row><row><cell>BIC</cell><cell>6,846</cell><cell>6,580</cell><cell>5,707</cell><cell>5,883</cell><cell>5,898</cell><cell>6,020</cell><cell>5,940</cell></row><row><cell>CAIC</cell><cell>6,863</cell><cell>6,598</cell><cell>5,728</cell><cell>5,934</cell><cell>5,951</cell><cell>6,055</cell><cell>5,977</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_31"><head>Table 15</head><label>15</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Charge Card B (Three ASCs)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Scale</cell><cell cols="2">Random</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Correlated errors</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Uncorrelated errors</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">heterogeneity</cell><cell></cell><cell>effects</cell><cell cols="2">One-factor</cell><cell cols="2">One-factor</cell><cell cols="2">Mixed logit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell><cell></cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell cols="2">G-MNL</cell></row><row><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell><cell>Est.</cell><cell>Std. err.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_32"><head>Table 16</head><label>16</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Comparing Model Fit Across Data Sets</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Scale</cell><cell>Random</cell><cell cols="2">Correlated errors</cell><cell cols="2">Uncorrelated errors</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>heterogeneity</cell><cell>effects</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Criteria</cell><cell>MNL</cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell>S-MNL</cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell>G-MNL</cell><cell>MIXL</cell><cell>G-MNL</cell></row><row><cell>Tay Sachs disease and cystic fibrosis test-</cell><cell>AIC</cell><cell>7 455</cell><cell>6 469</cell><cell>5 666</cell><cell>5 154</cell><cell>5 118</cell><cell>5 550</cell><cell>5 535</cell></row><row><cell>Jewish sample (3 ASCs)</cell><cell>BIC</cell><cell>7 523</cell><cell>6 543</cell><cell>5 777</cell><cell>5 626</cell><cell>5 601</cell><cell>5 684</cell><cell>5 682</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CAIC</cell><cell>7 534</cell><cell>6 555</cell><cell>5 795</cell><cell>5 703</cell><cell>5 680</cell><cell>5 706</cell><cell>5 706</cell></row><row><cell>Tay Sachs disease and cystic fibrosis test-</cell><cell>AIC</cell><cell>9 320</cell><cell>7 158</cell><cell>6 477</cell><cell>6 047</cell><cell>5 986</cell><cell>6 507</cell><cell>6 446</cell></row><row><cell>general population (3 ASCs)</cell><cell>BIC</cell><cell>9 390</cell><cell>7 234</cell><cell>6 591</cell><cell>6 535</cell><cell>6 487</cell><cell>6 646</cell><cell>6 598</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CAIC</cell><cell>9 401</cell><cell>7 246</cell><cell>6 610</cell><cell>6 612</cell><cell>6 566</cell><cell>6 668</cell><cell>6 622</cell></row><row><cell>Mobile phone (1 ASC)</cell><cell>AIC</cell><cell>8 980</cell><cell>8 236</cell><cell>8 014</cell><cell>8 014</cell><cell>7 986</cell><cell>8 002</cell><cell>7 996</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>BIC</cell><cell>9 074</cell><cell>8 336</cell><cell>8 121</cell><cell>8 297</cell><cell>8 281</cell><cell>8 190</cell><cell>8 197</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CAIC</cell><cell>9 089</cell><cell>8 352</cell><cell>8 138</cell><cell>8 342</cell><cell>8 328</cell><cell>8 220</cell><cell>8 229</cell></row><row><cell>Pizza A (no ASC)</cell><cell>AIC</cell><cell>3 330</cell><cell>3 179</cell><cell></cell><cell>2 847</cell><cell>2 741</cell><cell>2 838</cell><cell>2 782</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>BIC</cell><cell>3 378</cell><cell>3 233</cell><cell></cell><cell>3 109</cell><cell>3 015</cell><cell>2 933</cell><cell>2 889</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CAIC</cell><cell>3 386</cell><cell>3 242</cell><cell></cell><cell>3 153</cell><cell>3 061</cell><cell>2 949</cell><cell>2 907</cell></row><row><cell>Holiday A (no ASC)</cell><cell>AIC</cell><cell>6 149</cell><cell>5 952</cell><cell></cell><cell>5 097</cell><cell>5 031</cell><cell>5 139</cell><cell>5 074</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>BIC</cell><cell>6 201</cell><cell>6 011</cell><cell></cell><cell>5 386</cell><cell>5 333</cell><cell>5 244</cell><cell>5 192</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CAIC</cell><cell>6 209</cell><cell>6 020</cell><cell></cell><cell>5 430</cell><cell>5 379</cell><cell>5 260</cell><cell>5 210</cell></row><row><cell>Pap smear test (1 ASC)</cell><cell>AIC</cell><cell>3 069</cell><cell>2 262</cell><cell>2 143</cell><cell>1 899</cell><cell>1 887</cell><cell>1 914</cell><cell>1 897</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>BIC</cell><cell>3 104</cell><cell>2 303</cell><cell>2 189</cell><cell>2 057</cell><cell>2 056</cell><cell>1 984</cell><cell>1 979</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CAIC</cell><cell>3 110</cell><cell>2 310</cell><cell>2 197</cell><cell>2 084</cell><cell>2 085</cell><cell>1 996</cell><cell>1 993</cell></row><row><cell>Pizza B (no ASC)</cell><cell>AIC</cell><cell>13 525</cell><cell>13 249</cell><cell></cell><cell>11 810</cell><cell>11 436</cell><cell>11 849</cell><cell>11 446</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>BIC</cell><cell>13 641</cell><cell>13 372</cell><cell></cell><cell>12 159</cell><cell>11 799</cell><cell>12 081</cell><cell>11 693</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CAIC</cell><cell>13 657</cell><cell>13 389</cell><cell></cell><cell>12 207</cell><cell>11 849</cell><cell>12 113</cell><cell>11 727</cell></row><row><cell>Holiday B (no ASC)</cell><cell>AIC</cell><cell>26 988</cell><cell>26 088</cell><cell></cell><cell>23 236</cell><cell>22 992</cell><cell>23 263</cell><cell>23 019</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>BIC</cell><cell>27 116</cell><cell>26 224</cell><cell></cell><cell>23 619</cell><cell>23 391</cell><cell>23 519</cell><cell>23 291</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CAIC</cell><cell>27 132</cell><cell>26 241</cell><cell></cell><cell>23 667</cell><cell>23 441</cell><cell>23 551</cell><cell>23 325</cell></row><row><cell>Charge card A (2 ASCs)</cell><cell>AIC</cell><cell>6 742</cell><cell>6 470</cell><cell>5 579</cell><cell>5 572</cell><cell>5 574</cell><cell>5 806</cell><cell>5 714</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>BIC</cell><cell>6 846</cell><cell>6 580</cell><cell>5 707</cell><cell>5 883</cell><cell>5 898</cell><cell>6 020</cell><cell>5 940</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CAIC</cell><cell>6 863</cell><cell>6 598</cell><cell>5 728</cell><cell>5 934</cell><cell>5 951</cell><cell>6 055</cell><cell>5 977</cell></row><row><cell>Charge card B (3 ASCs)</cell><cell>AIC</cell><cell>8 236</cell><cell>7 932</cell><cell>6 854</cell><cell>6 836</cell><cell>6 840</cell><cell>7 128</cell><cell>6 970</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>BIC</cell><cell>8 346</cell><cell>8 048</cell><cell>7 007</cell><cell>7 166</cell><cell>7 182</cell><cell>7 348</cell><cell>7 202</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CAIC</cell><cell>8 364</cell><cell>8 067</cell><cell>7 032</cell><cell>7 220</cell><cell>7 238</cell><cell>7 384</cell><cell>7 240</cell></row></table><note>Note. Bold estimates indicate the preferred model in each row.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_33"><head>Table 17</head><label>17</label><figDesc>Comparing the Importance of Heterogeneity Across Data Sets</figDesc><table><row><cell>Percent improvement</cell></row></table><note>a S-MNL with fixed ASCs. b S-MNL with random ASCs. c Imposing one-factor model restriction on variance-covariance matrix.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_34"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>This model is not identified, and the most common normalization is, of course, to set the scale parameter n = 1 for all n. This gives what is called a model in "utility space." However, an alternative is to normalize the price coefficient n = 1 for all n. This gives what is called a model in "WTP space." It is useful to write out the two models explicitly.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>13)</cell></row><row><cell>U njt = n x njt − n p njt + njt</cell><cell>"Utility space"</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">U  *  njt =  *  n x njt − p njt + njt / n "WTP space"</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_35"><head>Table 18</head><label>18</label><figDesc>Willingness to Pay Estimates vs. Aggregate Choice Probabilities</figDesc><table><row><cell>WTP distribution</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_36"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Marketing Science 29(3), pp. 393-421, © 2010 INFORMS is greater). This leads to what we have called an S-MNL model.</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2"><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">McFadden and Train (2000)</ref> show MIXL can approximate any random utility model arbitrarily well. However, this result relies on the investigator using the correct mixing distribution-which must be specified a priori. Unfortunately, their result seems to be widely misinterpreted among practitioners to mean MIXL with normal mixing can approximate any random utility model, which is certainly not true. Indeed, the correct mixing distribution is normal only in the case of the MNP model.3  Indeed, as noted inTrain (2003, p. 316), MNP is actually somewhat computationally easier, because it has the same distribution (normal) for both the attribute weights and the idiosyncratic errors.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">The MNP model, which assumes the idiosyncratic errors have a multivariate normal distribution, also avoids IIA. It can be extended to allow the whole vector to be normally distributed. MNP generates choice probabilities that are J − 1 dimensional integrals with no closed form. Thus, estimation beyond the J = 2 case was precluded for many years by computational limits. The development of the GHK algorithm in the late 1980s (see<ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Keane 1994</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Keane , 1997b</ref> made MNP estimation feasible. MNP algorithms are now available in popular packages like SAS and STATA, but these packaged programs only allow correlation across alternatives, not choice occasions.<ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Geweke et al. (1997)</ref> discuss the MNP with correlation across alternatives and over choice occasions. As they make clear, the programming required in this general case is much more involved.10 Furthermore, with panel data or multiple-choice occasions per subject, the simulated choice probabilities are obtained simply by taking the products of period-by-period logit expressions and averaging them over draws d.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="13">Bear in mind that ML estimates are only consistent-not unbiased in finite samples. This is why in Monte Carlo work it is generally argued that modest biases are to be expected and are not a major concern. Only quantitatively large biases that would substantially alter the interpretation of results would be a major concern.14  The estimates of the correlations among the errors (i.e., the residual taste heterogeneity) fall reasonably well in line with the true values, although significant biases show up in 6 out of 15 cases.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="15">For example, we fit the S-MNL model to the Pap smear data set, and use those estimates to generate the data where S-MNL is the true model. We fit MIXL with correlated errors to the Pap smear data set, and use those estimates to generate the data where MIXL is the true model. Finally, we fit G-MNL with correlated errors to the Pap smear data set and use those estimates to generate the data where G-MNL is the true model.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Marketing Science 29(3), pp.393-421, © 2010 INFORMS   </note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="17">A priori, one might have expected the deterioration in the likelihood to be less in the model with scale heterogeneity, because scale heterogeneity could "sop up" much of the positive correlation among the attribute weights. However, when we look at the estimated correlation matrix (not reported but available on request), we find that at least half of the correlations among attribute weights in this data set are negative.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="19">There are 32 choice occasions, but each attribute only differs between the two options on 16 occasions.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="23">The mobile phone, Pizza B, Holiday B, and charge card data sets contained very many attributes (16 to 18), so it was not feasible to estimate a full variance-covariance matrix in these cases. Instead, we restricted them to have a one-factor structure. Such an approach may be worth pursuing as a compromise between the two extreme options commonly applied in practice: imposing no correlation or estimating full variance-covariance matrix.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="26">It may simply be that taste heterogeneity is more important in data sets with ASCs, but this is contradicted by the mobile phone and credit card data, which contain ASCs but exhibit a relatively low degree of heterogeneity.27  Obviously this is not the same as decomposing the overall likelihood improvement in going from MNL to G-MNL into fractions because of residual versus scale heterogeneity, because the log-likelihood improvements from including them are not additive. However, examining incremental likelihood improvements in going from simple to more complex models is in the same spirit as information criteria like BIC. Intuitively, if the large majority of the likelihood improvement that can be obtained from adding both residual and scale heterogeneity to MNL can be achieved by adding scale heterogeneity alone, then BIC will tend to prefer the more parsimonious S-MNL model. In making this determination, BIC does not even consider how the overall likelihood improve-</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="28">The low end of this range (0.07) comes from the mobile phone data set, but this improvement appears more substantial when one considers that heterogeneity in general only improves pseudo-R 2 by 0.10 for mobile phones.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="29"> Analogously, in contingent valuation data, Hanemann (1984)  estimated WTP as the ratio of the intercept (representing the hypothetical program) to the price coefficient, whereas<ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Cameron (1988)</ref> uses the expenditure function to estimate WTP directly.30  In the utility space model it is common to assume n is normal and that the price coefficient n is normal or log-normal (to keep it</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="31">This is because people with larger attribute weights have a proportionately larger price coefficient.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The second author's work on this project was supported by Australian Research Council Grant FF0561843 and the first author's by National Health and Medical Research Council Program Grant 25402.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Marketing models of consumer heterogeneity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rossi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="2" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consumers and experts: An econometric analysis of the demand for water heaters</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bartels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Fiebig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Van Soest</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Empirical Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="369" to="391" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modelling methods for discrete choice analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ben-Akiva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mcfadden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Abe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Böckenholt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bolduc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gopinath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Morikawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="286" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Bayesian mixed logitprobit model for multinomial choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Burda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Harding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hausman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="232" to="246" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new paradigm for valuing non-market goods using referendum data: Maximum likelihood estimation by censored logistic regression</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cameron</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Environ. Econom. Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="335" to="379" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alternative non-market value-elicitation methods: Are the underlying preferences the same?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cameron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Poe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Ethier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Schulze</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Environ. Econom. Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="391" to="425" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing choice sets for stated preference methods: The effects of complexity on choice consistency</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Deshazo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Fermo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Environ. Econom. Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="123" to="143" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structural applications of the discrete choice model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-P</forename><surname>Dubé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Petrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bronnenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Goettler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Seetharaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sudhir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thomadsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="220" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A factor-analytic probit model for representing the market structure in panel data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Elrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advantageous selection in the Medigap insurance market</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Silverman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="303" to="350" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Bayesian analysis of some nonparametric problems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="230" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discrete choice experiments in the analysis of health policy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Fiebig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Tools for Microeconomic Policy Anal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="136" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Productivity Commission Conf.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mixture of normals probit models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Geweke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Analysis of Panels and Limited Dependent Variable Models</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hsiao</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lahiri</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">L.-F</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Pesaran</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="78" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Computationally intensive methods for integration in econometrics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Geweke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>J. J. Heckman, E. E</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Leamer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Econometrics</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier Science B.V</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3463" to="3568" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Smoothly mixing regressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Geweke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">138</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="291" to="311" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alternative computational approaches to statistical inference in the multinomial probit model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Geweke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Runkle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="609" to="632" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical inference in the multinomial multiperiod probit model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Geweke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Runkle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="165" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What influences participation in genetic carrier testing? Results from a discrete choice experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Fiebig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Hossain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Louviere</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Health Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="520" to="537" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Welfare evaluations in contingent valuation experiments with discrete responses</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hanemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. J. Agricultural Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="332" to="341" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Fiebig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>© 2010 INFORMS 421</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Generalized Multinomial Logit Model Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="393" to="421" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model of health plan choice: Inferring preferences and perceptions from a combination of revealed preference and attitudinal data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="157" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hierarchical mixtures-of-experts for exponential family regression models: Approximation and maximum likelihood estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tanner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="987" to="1011" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A probabilistic choice model for market segmentation and elasticity structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kamakura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="390" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A computationally practical simulation estimator for panel data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="116" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Current issues in discrete choice modelling</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="307" to="322" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling heterogeneity and state dependence in consumer choice behaviour</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Econom. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="310" to="327" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The generalized logit model: Preliminary ideas on a research program. Presentation, Motorola-CenSoC Hong Kong Meeting</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Motorola, Hung Hom, Kowloon, Hong Kong</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-10-22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A structural model of multiple welfare program participation and labor supply</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Moffitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="553" to="589" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confound it! That pesky little scale constant messes up our convenient assumptions! Proc</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Louviere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Eagle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Sawtooth Software Conf. Sawtooth Software</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Sequem, WA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="228" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Formal choice models of informal choices: What choice modeling research can (and can&apos;t) learn from behavioral theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Louviere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>N. K. Malhotra</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<publisher>M. E. Sharpe</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="32" />
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing discrete choice experiments: Do optimal designs come at a price?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Louviere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Islam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Wasi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Street</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Burgess</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="360" to="375" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modelling the choices of individuals decision makers by combining efficient choice experiment designs with extra preference information</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Louviere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Street</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Burgess</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Wasi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Islam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A J</forename><surname>Marley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Choice Model</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="128" to="163" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combining sources of preference data for modelling complex decision processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Louviere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bunch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Carson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Dellaert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hanemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hensher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Irwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="205" to="217" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dissecting the random component of utility</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Louviere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Street</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Carson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ainslie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Deshazo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cameron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hensher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Marley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="193" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditional logit analysis of qualitative choice behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mcfadden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Econometrics</title>
		<editor>P. Zarembka</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="142" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mixed MNL models for discrete response</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mcfadden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Train</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="447" to="470" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bayesian Statistics and Marketing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rossi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mcculloch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Hoboken, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Uncovering the distribution of motorists&apos; preferences for travel time and reliability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Small</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Winston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1367" to="1382" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heterogeneity distributions of willingness-to-pay in choice models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sonnier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ainslie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Otter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="331" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporating the effect of choice environment and complexity into random utility models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Swait</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Adamowicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organ. Behav. Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="167" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A law of comparative judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Thurstone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psych. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="286" />
			<date type="published" when="1927" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Train</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Discrete Choice Methods with Simulation</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A recursive estimator for random coefficient models. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Train</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<pubPlace>Berkeley</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of California Berkeley</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonparametric regression density estimation using smoothly varying normal mixtures</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Villani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Giordani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sveriges Riksbank Research Paper Series</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">211</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Market Segmentation: Concepts and Methodological Foundations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Kamakura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Boston</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
