<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Rejoinder-Response to Comments on &quot;Website Morphing&quot;</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2009-02-24">February 24, 2009.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
							<email>hauser@mit.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Glen</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Urban</surname></persName>
							<email>glurban@mit.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Guilherme</forename><surname>Liberali</surname></persName>
							<email>liberali@unisinos.br</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
							<email>braunm@mit.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">MIT Sloan School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02142</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>Massachusetts</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">MIT Sloan School of Management, Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">and Universidade do Vale do Rio dos Sinos</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02142, 90450</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge, Sao Leopoldo, Brazil</settlement>
									<region>Massachusetts, RS</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">MIT Sloan School of Management, Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02142</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>Massachusetts</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Rejoinder-Response to Comments on &quot;Website Morphing&quot;</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 09 2802 0227</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2009-02-24">February 24, 2009.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1080.0485</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: December 15, 2008; accepted: December 15, 2008.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:25+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Internet marketing</term>
					<term>cognitive styles</term>
					<term>dynamic programming</term>
					<term>Bayesian methods</term>
					<term>clickstream analysis</term>
					<term>automated marketing</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We are honored to receive excellent constructive suggestions from luminaries such as Andrew Gelman, John Gittins, and Hal Varian. Our research has built on seminal contributions by each of these authors. We hope we have contributed modestly to the use of "bandit" problems to select a website's look and feel, to the use of Bayesian inference to identify a website visitor's cognitive-state-dependent preferences, and to the interesting issues of experimentation, optimization, and personalization in the customization of websites. Each of these authors provides unique insights.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Expected Gittins Indices</head><p>Multiarm bandit problems were once considered too difficult to solve until Dr. Gittins proved that index strategies would work. Indeed, in an address to the Royal Statistical Society <ref type="bibr">(February 14, 1979)</ref>, the great statistician Peter Whittle opened:</p><p>[The bandit problem] was formulated during World War II, and efforts to solve it so sapped the energies and minds of Allied analysts that the suggestion was made that the problem be dropped over Germany, as the ultimate instrument of intellectual sabotage.</p><p>When cognitive states are known, the Gittins strategy provides an optimal strategy for assigning morphs to visitors. This optimality balances exploration and exploitation, and takes all opportunity costs into account, including potential misassignments. When cognitive states are known only probabilistically, the expected Gittins heuristic strategy is no longer guaranteed to be optimal. However, past results suggest that any deviations from optimality are small. Dr. Gittins is correct that our statement about testing relative to a no-morph strategy refers to the expected Gittins index (close to optimality), not the Gittins index (always optimal).</p><p>Optimality might also suffer for reasons outside our model. For example, visitors might be confused if they receive too many morph changes. 1 When such "switching costs" are incurred, the optimization is no longer indexable but can be solved with a multipleindex strategy. We find this new direction exciting.</p><p>We also thank John Gittins for highlighting that website applications require discount factors a that are much closer to 1.0 than typical bandit problems. Dr. Gittins' suggestions for computational efficiency suggest important improvements. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical Design of Experiments</head><p>Dr. Gelman suggests synergies between (partially observable) bandit problems and the statistical design of experiments. We agree. Expected Gittins indices enable experimenters to select experimental treatments optimally and to do so on the fly. Such algorithms have the potential to lead to new adaptive measurement methods in conjoint analysis experiments and/or the optimal assignment of pedagogical lessons in adaptive learning.</p><p>We also agree with Dr. Gelman's suggestions for posterior predictive checks (PPCs). In our analysis we use Markov chain Monte Carlo methods to infer a posterior distribution for the preference weights . These weights relate visitors' preferences for clickalternative characteristics to their clickstreams. When feasible, we have used PPCs in our other work. PPCs are likely to be valuable here to examine whether the logit model is consistent with the clickstreams that are observed in the priming study. Although PPCs are computationally intensive for our data set, they represent a valuable research direction. Extending Dr. Gelman's suggestion further, it might also be useful to study the sensitivity of the optimal morph assignment to the posterior distribution of .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Morphing Beyond Cognitive Styles, and Beyond a Website's Look and Feel</head><p>We are pleased that Dr. Varian suggests other applications and suggests other constructs besides cognitive styles that could be used for morphing applications. There are many instances in which website characteristics, product offerings, or software menus respond to users' choices. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Adomavičious and Tuzhilin (2005)</ref> review the next generation of recommendation systems such as those used by TiVo and by Amazon.com. Cookies within an URL and across URLs enable websites to provide customized content that is designed to increase customer satisfaction and/or sales. We are happy to contribute to this literature.</p><p>The Gittins engine provides a rigorous (and optimal) way to assign content, style, or other characteristics while balancing exploration and exploitation. For example, Google Analytics' Website Optimizer relies on experimental designs to identify website characteristics. The Gittins engine can improve the efficiency of such experimentation, and as Dr. Varian points out, the Gittins/Bayesian engines can condition a website's characteristics on partially observable user descriptions.</p><p>We thank Dr. Varian for suggesting other user descriptions. The Bayesian engine provides a practical means to identify many unobserved visitor descriptions whether they be cognitive styles (the BT application) or gender (Dr. Varian's example). We are experimenting with persistent user descriptions such as demographics and cultural styles (e.g., hierarchical versus egalitarian cultures, or individualistic versus collective cultures). We hope with experience to determine rules by which the best and most parsimonious descriptions can be matched to applications.</p><p>Dr. Varian raises the interesting technical challenge of dealing with the risk of misclassification. In the BT application, we assumed at most one morph per visit. Many morph changes might provide a cognitive penalty. If the website changes too often, the "switching-cost" penalty might overwhelm the advantage to morph-by-cognitive-style matching. Multiple-index strategies provide a means to explore solutions when such switching costs are substantial <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Dusonchet and</ref><ref type="bibr">Hongler 2006, Niño-Mora 2008)</ref>.</p><p>Finally, we are excited about opportunities to use information that is available from advertising networks such as DoubleClick. We are actively involved in a project to morph advertising across sessions (allowing for "opt in" or "opt out"). The study will include cognitive styles and other latent customer characteristics. We might also envision morphing across mobile devices (e.g., using customer location for a morph) and social media (e.g., using the customers place in the social network). We are excited by these and other applications.</p></div>			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">This is one practical reason why we limit morphing to at most one change per visitor.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward the next generation of recommender systems: A survey of the state-of-the-art and possible extensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Adomavičious</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tuzhilin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Knowledge Data Engrg</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="734" to="749" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Priority index heuristic for multiarmed bandit problems with set-up costs and/or set-up time delays</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Dusonchet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M.-O</forename><surname>Hongler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Comput. Integrated Manufacturing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="210" to="219" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A faster index algorithm and a computational study for bandits with switching costs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Niño-Mora</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">INFORMS J. Comput</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="269" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
