<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org A Theory of Combative Advertising</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yuxin</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<email>ychen@stern.nyu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yogesh</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
							<email>yjoshi@rhsmith.umd.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jagmohan</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Raju</surname></persName>
							<email>rajuj@wharton.upenn.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">John</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<email>zjzhang@wharton.upenn.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">The Leonard N. Stern School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Cheung Kong Graduate School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">New York University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>10012, 100738</postCode>
									<settlement>New York, Beijing</settlement>
									<region>New York</region>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">The Robert H. Smith School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Maryland</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>20742</postCode>
									<settlement>College Park, Maryland</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">The Wharton School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>19104</postCode>
									<settlement>Philadelphia</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org A Theory of Combative Advertising</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 09 2801 0001</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1080.0385</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: November 14, 2006; accepted: December 5, 2007; processed by James Hess.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:27+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>advertising</term>
					<term>persuasion</term>
					<term>game theory</term>
					<term>competitive strategy</term>
					<term>prisoner&apos;s dilemma</term>
					<term>preference shifts</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>In some of the earliest writings on the role of advertising in influencing firm prices and profitability, the renowned economist Alfred <ref type="bibr">Marshall (1919, p. 304</ref>) noted the following: …the nation <ref type="bibr">[America]</ref>, which excels all others in the energy and inventive ability devoted to developing the efficiency of retail trade, is also the nation that pays the most dearly for the services of that trade.</p><p>He believed that part of the reason why one observed high prices in many markets was the advertising efforts of firms; and the fact that much of this advertising spending was not constructive, but combative. He defined constructive advertising as all advertising designed to draw the attention of people to the opportunities of buying or selling of which they may be willing to avail themselves; and combative advertising as the iterative claims made by a firm in an effort to identify itself with consumers without expanding the market. His contention was that combative advertising helped a firm increase its market power and support a high price.</p><p>Over the past century, researchers have proposed many theories on how advertising may affect a firm's market power. Three main views have emerged: the informative, complementary, and persuasive views of advertising <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bagwell 2005)</ref>. According to informative view, advertising works by increasing consumer awareness and reducing search costs. This results in an increase in price sensitivity and reduction in market power (the Stigler-Telser-Nelson school of thought: <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Stigler 1961</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">, Telser 1964</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">, Nelson 1975</ref>. Of course, informative advertising can also enhance a firm's market power if it merely informs consumers of product differences and hence increases product differentiation <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Meurer and Stahl 1994)</ref>. The complementary view recognizes the importance of advertising in the consumption process by providing additional utility to consumers-such as creating a feeling of greater social prestige when the product is appropriately advertised, or by signalling high quality. Therefore, advertising is good or bad complementary to consumption. According to this view, advertising can increase a firm's market power if it 2 Marketing Science 28(1), pp. 1-19, © 2009 INFORMS enhances consumption utility, but need not always do so <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Becker and Murphy 1993)</ref>.</p><p>The view that is closest to capturing combative advertising described by Marshall is the persuasive view of advertising (the Kaldor-Bain-Comanor-Wilson school of thought: <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Kaldor 1950</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">, Bain 1956</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">, Comanor and Wilson 1967</ref>. This view supports Marshall's thesis that advertising can alter consumer tastes to create mostly spurious product differentiation. Ultimately, such advertising decreases consumer price sensitivity making demand less elastic, thus supporting higher prices and profits <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Gasmi et al. 1992</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">, Tremblay and Polasky 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">, Tremblay and Martins-Filho 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">, Bagwell 2005</ref>.</p><p>As combative advertising is often observed in mature markets for consumer goods such as detergents and soft drinks, according to this view, one would expect that as a firm increases its advertising expenditure, demand will shift in its favor. However, research in marketing does not always corroborate this view. Past research has shown that advertising can indeed have an impact on consumer's price sensitivity in the long term <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Mela et al. 1997)</ref>. While there is quite a bit of agreement that advertising in its various forms (rational, emotional, creative) helps shift consumer preferences towards the advertising firm <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Batra et al. 1996)</ref>, there is skepticism about advertising being of much help to firms in increasing short-term sales or profitability. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Erickson (1985</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Erickson ( , 2003</ref> suggests that when competing firms are equally matched (symmetric), combative advertising is harmful (albeit necessary) for firms as it does not provide any additional increase in market share or profits. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Studying disaggregate scanner data on detergents, <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Tellis and Weiss (1995)</ref> further the skepticism of advertising's positive sales impact by showing empirically that the effect of advertising on current sales is either weak or nonsignificant and appears to be present only when data are aggregated across consumers or over time. This implies that any sales effect of advertising or any gain in market power may be spurious, most likely due to data aggregation. Other researchers have presented a more mixed view. <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Kaul and Wittink (1995)</ref> reviewed 14 empirical studies on the effects of nonprice advertising 2 and concluded, based on the majority results (9 out of 14 studies), that nonprice advertising reduces consumer price sensitivity (mostly for frequently purchased consumer goods). They cite studies that suggest nonprice advertising could increase price sensitivity particularly in the airline industry <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Gatignon 1984)</ref> as well as for some categories of consumer goods such as aluminum foil and dog food <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Kanetkar et al. 1992</ref>). <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Albion and Farris (1981)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Lodish et al. (1995)</ref> also have reported mixed evidence about the effect of advertising on sales, thus calling into question the prevalent belief that nonprice (combative) advertising is primarily anticompetitive in nature. Recent research by <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Pauwels and Hanssens (2007)</ref> reports that advertising can lead to an increase or decrease in market share in mature markets depending on the brand's current performance regime. We believe this raises two questions currently unaddressed in the literature:</p><p>• Is it possible that combative advertising, while altering consumer preferences to favor competing firms, could also lead to procompetitive effects?</p><p>• If the answer to the previous question is yes, then through what mechanism does combative advertising lead to both pro-and anticompetitive effects?</p><p>The answers to these two related questions have important implications for our understanding of the role that advertising plays in competition, and therefore for advertising research and practice. If combative advertising can only lead to higher prices, then firms can legitimately consider advertising as an investment and a firm's advertising decision is a matter of weighing the costs and benefits of additional advertising expenditures. However, if combative advertising can also intensify price competition, the decision becomes more complex as now a firm must decide whether or how much to advertise in a product category in order to benefit from advertising and advertising professionals must decide how to implement an advertising campaign to benefit their clients. Therefore, marketing researchers will face a new line of inquiry: how different consumers may respond to different advertising messages such that either procompetitive or anticompetitive effects may result in the marketplace for different types of products.</p><p>In this paper, we seek to provide some answers to these two questions by developing a game theoretical model. Past empirical research on reaction functions has looked at how a competing firm would react to advertising and pricing decisions of the other firms in the same market, and has uncovered a high degree of competitive interaction depending on the product category <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Lambin et al. 1975</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">, Steenkamp et al. 2005</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, Horvath et al. 2005</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">, Bass et al. 2007</ref>). We examine the interactions of competing firms in advertising and pricing decisions by building a model that 3 incorporates the preference-changing effects of combative advertising. In our model, advertising does not directly enhance a consumer's willingness to pay for the advertised product, and it does not alter the advertising firm's positioning in the product space. Rather, the advertising we model is purely persuasive in nature: "each firm tries to convince consumers that what they really want is its particular variety" <ref type="bibr">(von der Fehr and Stevik 1998, p. 115)</ref>. In other words, advertising changes the distribution of consumer ideal points.</p><p>Two previous studies, von der Fehr and Stevik (1998) and <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bloch and Manceau (1999)</ref>, have investigated this preference-transforming effect of advertising in a competitive context. von der Fehr and Stevik (1998) anchor their study in a Hotelling model where advertising by a firm moves consumers located along the Hotelling line uniformly toward the advertising firm. They conclude that in any competitive equilibrium, such advertising will not change the distribution of consumer ideal points and hence should not have any price or sales effect. They came to this conclusion by assuming that all consumers along the Hotelling line are unaffected by advertising whenever competing firms advertise at the same level. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bloch and Manceau (1999)</ref>, however, suggest that persuasive advertisements may alter consumer preferences in a way that reduces or intensifies price competition. Their study is also anchored in a Hotelling model. According to this study, a firm's advertising can trigger more aggressive pricing by the competing (nonadvertising) firm to the detriment of the advertising firm, if consumers already prefer the product of the advertising firm. In other words, persuasive advertising intensifies price competition only under two conditions. First, when consumer preferences are biased in favor of one of the two competing firms' products, the favored firm is the one that advertises. Second, the firm in consumers' disfavor cannot advertise and can only respond to the rival's advertising with price. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> Similar to von der Fehr and Stevik (1998) and <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bloch and Manceau (1999)</ref>, our analysis is anchored in the Hotelling model of a horizontally differentiated duopoly. Compared to von der Fehr and Stevik (1998), we offer a more general specification for the preference distribution and model combative advertising as causing a shift in consumer preference towards the advertising firm in a more heterogenous way, consistent with empirical and experimental findings from the existing literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Zajonc 1968</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">, Hoch and Ha 1986</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">, Carpenter and Nakamoto 1989</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">, D'Souza and Rao 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">, Tellis 2004</ref>. We also incorporate the commonly observed diminishing returns to advertising in the sales response function. Compared to <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bloch and Manceau (1999)</ref>, we conduct an equilibrium analysis with competing firms setting both prices and advertising levels simultaneously. This analysis allows us to identify the mechanism through which combative advertising may reduce or intensify price competition when all competing firms can advertise. Such a mechanism is absent in both studies.</p><p>In our model, advertising always exerts a force pulling consumers closer to that firm. It turns out that the effect of such a force can be anticompetitive (all competing firms charge higher prices) or procompetitive (all competing firms charge lower prices). We discuss how these pro-and anticompetitive effects of combative advertising come about and what mediates these different outcomes first in a parsimonious discrete model in §2. In § §3 and 4 we extend this to a more general model to study how firms' advertising intensities and consumer responsiveness to advertising in a market jointly determine the effect of combative advertising. Because of the procompetitive effect we have identified, we can shed some new light on the effects of ever escalating advertising costs in §5: the rising costs of advertising might be a blessing in disguise. We demonstrate the possibility that with higher unit costs of advertising, the equilibrium levels of advertising could be lower, resulting in higher profits for competing firms. As all our conclusions hinge on the procompetitive effect, we experimentally test the external validity of this procompetitive effect in §6. Before we present the general model, in the next section, we start with a simple discrete model to illustrate the forces at work when firms compete in advertising. 4</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Basic Mechanics of Combative Advertising</head><p>In the absence of advertising, assume that consumers are uniformly distributed along a Hotelling line of unit length 0 1 , with Firm 1 located at 0 and Firm 2 at 1. This means that the density of consumer distribution is 1 everywhere along the line in the absence of any advertising in this market. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Each consumer buys at most one unit of the product, and incurs a linear Marketing Science 28(1), pp. 1-19, © 2009 INFORMS transportation cost. This transportation cost measures the disutility that a consumer suffers by consuming a nonideal product. We denote the unit transportation cost by t The reservation price of each consumer, V , is assumed to be sufficiently large compared to t so that the market is always covered in equilibrium, with or without advertising. This allows us to assume away any possible market expansion effect due to advertising in this market. Let the price for firm i's product be p i . Thus, the utility for Firm 1's product for a consumer located at x will be V − p 1 − tx. Similarly, the utility for Firm 2's product for the same consumer would be V − p 2 − t 1 − x .</p><p>In the past, the effect of persuasive advertising in a Hotelling model has been modeled as increasing either the reservation price V or the differentiation parameter t or as shifting the distribution of consumer ideal points <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(von der Fehr and</ref><ref type="bibr">Stevik 1998, Tremblay and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Polasky 2002)</ref>. We take the latter modeling approach to better capture combative advertising "as a tug-of-war in which each firm attempts to attract consumers by molding their preferences to fit the characteristics of its product" (von der <ref type="bibr">Fehr and Stevik 1998, p. 115)</ref>. This means that the distribution of consumers along the Hotelling line depends on both firms' choices of advertising levels. For now, we assume that a firm can choose to advertise in this market with a fixed intensity k to shift consumers's ideal points closer to its location.</p><p>To incorporate heterogeneity in consumer responsiveness to advertising, we divide consumers in this market into three segments based on their preadvertising ideal points: consumers located in 0 1 3 who prefer Firm 1, those in 2 3 1 who favor Firm 2, and those in 1 3 2 3 who are ambivalent in terms of which firm they favor.</p><p>We distinguish two possible mechanisms through which advertising affects the distribution of consumer ideal points. In the first case, consumers are very responsive to advertising so that all consumers in the market except those who already prefer a firm's product are susceptible to the influence of advertising and may change their ideal points. Past research suggests that advertising is not particularly effective in changing the preference for consumers who have a strong preference to start with, as they are already convinced of buying from the preferred firm and it is harder to reinforce their preferences further in favor of the preferred firm <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Winter 1973)</ref>. Specifically, when only Firm 1 advertises, any consumer in 1 3 2 3 and 2 3 1 relocates their ideal points uniformly to 0 1 3 with probability vk such that the density of consumer distribution in 1 3 2 3 and 2 3 1 each reduces by vk and that in 0 1 3 increases correspondingly by 2vk, where v is a constant and k is the level of advertising. Symmetrically, when only Firm 2 advertises, any 3 relocates uniformly to 2 3 1 with probability vk and corresponding density changes. Thus, whenever a firm advertises alone, it succeeds in persuading more consumers to like its products.</p><p>In the second case, consumers are not very responsive to advertising and only those who like a firm's product the least are affected by the firm's advertising. Thus, when only Firm 1 advertises, any consumer in 2 3 1 relocates their ideal points uniformly to 0 1 3 and 1 3 2 3 with probability uk such that the density in 2 3 1 reduces by uk and that in 0 1 3 and 1 3 2 3 each increases by <ref type="bibr">1</ref> 2 uk (u is also a constant). Symmetrically, when only Firm 2 advertises, any consumer in 0 1 3 relocates uniformly to 1 3 2 3 and 2 3 1 with probability uk and corresponding density changes. The effects of unilateral advertising are illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> for both cases. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> What happens if both firms choose to advertise? At a given level of consumer responsiveness to advertising, the effect of combative advertising on each of the three segments of the market will, of course, depend on how many consumers are attracted into the segment and how many are pulled out of it. For instance, when consumers are very responsive to advertising, at the same level of advertising intensity k for both firms, Firm 1's advertising will increase consumer distribution density in 0 1 3 by 2vk, but Firm 2's advertising will reduce the density in that segment by vk so that the net density increase in that segment is vk. This is also the case in 2 3 1 . In the middle region 1 3 2 3 , each firm's advertising will reduce the density by vk so that combative advertising will reduce the density in 1 3 2 3 by 2vk. Thus, combative advertising will reshape the distribution of consumer ideal points Similarly, for the case where consumers are not very responsive to advertising, we have a different density function as illustrated on the right in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>.</p><p>As readers might have already realized, depending on how responsive consumers are to advertising, combative advertising can have quite different competitive implications depending on its impact on the distribution of consumer ideal points. In the first case, consumers are very responsive and combative advertising generates more partisan customers, the customers who strongly prefer a firm's product, and reduces the number of indifferent customers, the customers who do not have a strong preference for either firm's product. In that case, when firms compete on price, they will each set a higher price, relative to the case of a uniform consumer distribution, to capitalize on stronger consumer preferences or less elastic demand. In this case, combative advertising supports a higher price, consistent with what Marshall and other economists have pointed out.</p><p>In the second case, consumers are not very responsive to advertising and combative advertising actually pulls more consumers to the middle-a region also referred to as the combat zone <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Syam et al. 2005)</ref>. This reduces the number of partisan customers and increases the number of indifferent customers. In this case, combative advertising results in higher price elasticity. Therefore, firms will price lower than what they would in the absence of advertising as they compete for a more sizable body of indifferent customers. It is this case that previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Gasmi et al. 1992</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">, Tremblay and Polasky 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">, Tremblay and Martins-Filho 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">, Bagwell 2005</ref>) have overlooked.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">A Model for Combative Advertising</head><p>What the previous simple model establishes is the fact that depending on consumer responsiveness to advertising, it is possible for combative advertising to cause more intense price competition in a market by increasing the number of indifferent customers and reducing the number of partisan customers. It thus raises two critical questions. First, could combative advertising intensify price competition when firms choose their advertising intensity simultaneously? Second, is the phenomenon an artifact of the discrete segments of consumers that we have specified as a way to model heterogeneity in consumer responsiveness to advertising? We now address these questions by developing a more general model of combative advertising. This more general model allows us to develop a better understanding of combative advertising and provides more insights about its competitive implications. We make two modifications to the illustrative model in the previous section. First, we abandon the discrete segmentation of consumers and specify a continuous density function f for this market. This general specification allows all consumers along the Hotelling line to respond to combative advertising. Second, we formally specify the game that two competing firms play and allow firms to set their respective advertising intensity simultaneously. Firms in our model play a two-stage game. In the first stage, firms simultaneously decide advertising levels, k i . We normalize k i to be within 0 1 , where k i = 0 denotes no advertising and k i = 1 denotes maximum advertising. We assume that advertising costs are quadratic, 1 2 ck 2 i <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Tirole 1988</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">, Bagwell 2005</ref>, where c is a constant. In the second stage, after observing the other firm's advertising level, each firm simultaneously decides its price p i and then consumers optimally make their purchases. For simplicity, we assume that both firms' marginal costs of production are zero.</p><p>Various factors, such as brand loyalty, product attributes, brand perceptions, etc., can potentially influence consumer preferences for products in a given market. In this paper, we focus the effects of combative advertising on shaping consumer preferences, given a baseline distribution of consumer preferences. We illustrate these effects for the case when baseline preferences are distributed uniformly.</p><p>We formulate the density function f k 1 k 2 x starting from a general specification. With the density function pinned down, we derive the advertising response functions. With these response functions, we show that combative advertising can generate anticompetitive effects in equilibrium. However, the same forces that give rise to the anticompetitive effects of advertising can, under other conditions, generate procompetitive effects.</p><p>In Appendix 1, we show that we can parameterize the density function f k 1 k 2 x relying only on the regularity conditions and the known effects of advertising to generate a tractable but still fairly general model that lends itself to game-theoretic analysis. This modeling approach differs from von der Fehr and Stevik (1998) and <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bloch and Manceau (1999)</ref> in that we do not parameterize the density function in Marketing Science 28(1), pp. 1-19, © 2009 INFORMS an ad hoc fashion. In von der Fehr and Stevik (1998), the distribution function of consumer ideal points is uniform and if competing firms advertise at the same level, none of the consumers along the Hotelling line are affected so that the distribution function does not change. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bloch and Manceau (1999)</ref> allow for more general density functions, however, allow only one firm to advertise, and their model is not sufficiently parameterized. Our parameterized density function is given by 7</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">f k 1 k 2 x = v 1 k 1 x + v 2 k 2 x</formula><p>(1)</p><p>such that we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">v 1 k 1 x = 1 2 + k 1 12a − 1 − 6 8a − 1 x + 6 6a − 1 x 2 − 12bk 2 1 1 − 4x + 3x 2 (2) v 2 k 2 x = 1 2 + k 2 12a − 1 − 6 8a − 1 1 − x + 6 6a − 1 1 − x 2 − 12bk 2 2 1 − 4 1 − x + 3 1 − x 2 (3)</formula><p>where 1 8 &lt; a &lt; 5 12 and max 0 a − 1</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">4 &lt; b &lt; min a − 1 8 a/2 − 1 24 .</formula><p>Intuitively, v i captures the effects of firm i's advertising. We thus view the density at any given x, i.e., f k 1 k 2 x , as resulting from two opposing advertising forces: consumers at x may be pulled away from x and at the same time consumers at other locations may be pulled to x when subject to combative advertising. This derived density function has only two parameters, a and b.</p><p>To understand what they represent, we first derive the mean location of consumers:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">m k 1 k 2 = 1 0 xf k 1 k 2 x dx = 1 2 − a k 1 − k 2 + b k 1 − k 2 k 1 + k 2 (4)</formula><p>It is straightforward to show that the density function satisfies the following conditions:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">m k 1 k 2 k 1 &lt; 0 2 m k 1 k 2 k 2 1 &gt; 0 and m k 1 k 2 k 2 &gt; 0 2 m k 1 k 2 k 2 2 &lt; 0 (5)</formula><p>This implies that, given the rival's advertising level, the average consumer location moves toward a firm as the firm increases its advertising intensity, but the rate of such movements diminishes as the firm's advertising level increases. In other words, a firm's increased advertising should, on average, make the firm's product closer to being the ideal product for the consumers in the market (the first-order effect),</p><p>given any level of the rival's advertising, but such preference-shifting effect diminishes with higher levels of advertising (the second-order effect). Therefore, holding the prices to be the same in the market, the sales response function for a firm's advertising is increasing and concave-an attractive feature of our parameterized density function. Many studies have shown that advertising exposure has a favorable effect on consumer preferences toward the advertised product, and that the consumer response to advertising is concave <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Winter 1973</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">, Simon and Arndt 1980</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">, Vakratsas and Ambler 1999</ref>. This concave nature of advertising response functions has been reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Little (1979)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Albion and Farris (1981)</ref>, and also endorsed by <ref type="bibr">Lilien et al. (1992, p. 267)</ref>, who note that "while a good deal of discussion and modeling concerns S-shaped response, most of the empirical evidence supports concavity." Even when advertising response is S-shaped, typically, the equilibrium advertising levels belong to the upper concave part of the S-curve, making the assumption of concavity more reasonable (also see <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Chen and Xie 2007)</ref>.</p><p>In Equation ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>), we see how these two effects come about. The term (k 1 − k 2 ) captures the relative advertising intensity, while (k 1 + k 2 ) captures the aggregate advertising intensity in the market. As a firm (say Firm 1) increases its advertising intensity, consumers prefer Firm 1's product so that the mean consumer location shifts toward Firm 1 by the distance of a per unit of advertising intensity. This is the firstorder effect of advertising in shifting consumer preference. However, this mean shift is tempered by the second-order effect of diminishing returns to advertising, captured in the term b k 1 + k 2 . This second-order effect depends on the aggregate advertising intensity in the marketplace, as expected. Thus, larger a means that the consumers are, on average, more responsive to advertising and larger b means that the consumers are more easily satiated with advertising appeals. If one firm has an advantage in terms of relative advertising intensity, it stands to gain more when the aggregate advertising intensity is low rather than high. If two competing firms have the same advertising level, then the mean location of consumers, or the mean consumer preference, does not change and is fixed at 1 2 . This is rather expected in the context of combative advertising when two competing firms are equally matched.</p><p>To understand how the density function may shift with advertising, we compute its variance:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">2 k 1 k 2 = 1 12 + k 1 + k 2 6a − 1 30 − b 10 k 1 + k 2 − k 1 − k 2 2 b 10 + a − b k 1 + k 2 2</formula><p>It is important to point out that compared to the variance of a uniform distribution of consumers</p><p>( 2 uniform = 1 12 ), the variance of this density function f can increase as well as decrease, depending on the relative levels of a, b, and k i . We shall return to the particular conditions under which this may happen later in the analysis.</p><p>In this market, the two competing firms engage in a tug-of-war in advertising. If only one firm has the ability to advertise, that firm will pull consumers over, gaining market share <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Bloch and Manceau 1999)</ref>. If both firms advertise to the same extent and yet the distribution of consumer preferences is not altered as a result, the tug-of-war is at a dead draw everywhere along the Hotelling line. In that case, as pointed out by von der Fehr and Stevik (1998), combative advertising does not generate any price effect. Of course, when consumers in the market are all subject to two opposing forces, it is perhaps unrealistic to expect that the distribution of consumer preferences does not change at all. With this more general and empirically grounded consumer preference distribution function, we can conduct an explicit equilibrium analysis next to investigate how the consumer distribution and hence price competition may change due to combative advertising.</p><p>Let d be the location of the marginal consumer who is indifferent between the two firms:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">d = t − p 1 + p 2 /2t.</formula><p>The demand functions for the two firms are <ref type="bibr">8</ref> the profit functions for the two firms are 1 = p 1 D 1 − 1 2 ck 2 1 and 2 = p 2 D 2 − 1 2 ck 2 2 . We now proceed to derive the equilibrium using backwards induction.</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">D 1 = d 0 f dx = F d ; and D 2 = 1 d f dx = 1 − F d . Given demand,</formula><p>In the second stage, both firms simultaneously set their prices for any given pair of advertising levels (k 1 k 2 ) chosen in the previous stage. In equilibrium, both firms' prices must satisfy the following two firstorder conditions:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">1 p 1 p 2 k 1 k 2 p 1 = 0 2 p 1 p 2 k 1 k 2 p 2 = 0 (6)</formula><p>As we show in Appendix 2, although the equilibrium prices p * 1 k 1 k 2 and p * 2 k 1 k 2 cannot be solved explicitly without any further simplifying assumptions, they exist and are unique. In other words, the second-stage equilibrium always exists and is unique for any pair of (k 1 k 2 ). When k 1 = k 2 , we can write out the second-stage price equilibrium explicitly below: 9</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">p * k 1 =k 2 =k = t 1 + k − 6ak + 6bk 2 * k 1 =k 2 =k = t 2 1 + k − 6ak + 6bk 2 − 1 2 ck 2 (7)</formula><p>8 One can easily verify that the sales response to advertising in this market is concave for both firms. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> We assume symmetry to allow for the derivation of closed form solutions for the pricing subgame and, subsequently, the advertising game. Future research could investigate alternative models that would permit a relaxation of this assumption. The above expressions reveal the impact of two equally matched firms on price competition. When k = 0, the above equations reduce to the familiar <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Hotelling (1929)</ref> results. Surprisingly, however, the relationship between advertising and price is not monotonic. Even more surprisingly, the market price may be lower because of combative advertising. In Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref>, we illustrate the optimal price in the second stage as a function of advertising. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_12">10</ref>Proposition 1. When competing firms are equally matched in advertising, equilibrium prices can be increasing or decreasing with the level of advertising in the market, dependent on the level of advertising p * / k &gt; 0 when k &lt; 6a − 1 /12b . More importantly, combative advertising can intensify or moderate price competition in a market, relative to the case of no advertising.</p><p>Given that empirical evidence in the literature largely suggests that manufacturer prices are increasing in advertising <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Steiner 1973</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">, Farris and Reibstein 1979</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">, Tellis 2004</ref>, the anticompetitive effect of advertising in Proposition 1 is perhaps not so surprising. However, the procompetitive effect in Proposition 1 is. At high levels of advertising (k &gt; 6a − 1 /12b, which corresponds to 2 / k k 1 =k 2 =k &lt; 0), an increase in advertising can lead to a decrease, rather than an increase, in equilibrium prices. Indeed, if the advertising level is sufficiently high (k &gt; 6a − 1 /6b, which also corresponds to 2 k 1 =k 2 =k &lt; 1 12 ), the market price with advertising falls below the price without any advertising.</p><p>How does this procompetitive effect come about? Equation ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>) offers some clues. We can see that the equilibrium price increases as the advertising response becomes steeper (a increases) and decreases as the rate of diminishing returns becomes stronger (b increases), in addition to responding to the level of advertising. Further clues are offered by changes Marketing Science 28(1), pp. <ref type="bibr">1-19, © 2009 INFORMS</ref> in the variance of the consumer density function. Observe that 2 / k k 1 =k 2 =k &gt; 0 when k &lt; 6a − 1 /12b. Thus, advertising affects prices via changes in the distribution of consumers in the market. When advertising levels are low (high), as advertising increases (decreases), the variance of the consumer density function increases (decreases). In other words, the shape of the advertising response function can have significant competitive implications. This does not come as a surprise, of course, given the illustrative model we have discussed previously.</p><p>Before we discuss how higher levels of advertising may lead to lower prices, we first show that competing firms may indeed optimally choose a level of advertising that would lead to a lower market price. We can do this by solving for the first-stage equilibrium.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Competitive Effects of Combative Advertising</head><p>In the first stage, both firms set their advertising level, anticipating how their choice may affect their subsequent pricing decisions. Then, in the first-stage equilibrium, the following two first-order conditions must be satisfied:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">1 p * 1 k 1 k 2 p * 2 k 1 k 2 k 1 k 2 k 1 = 1 k 1 + 1 p 1 p * 1 k 1 + 1 p 2 p * 2 k 1 = 0 2 p * 1 k 1 k 2 p * 2 k 1 k 2 k 1 k 2 k 2 = 2 k 2 + 2 p 1 p * 1 k 2 + 2 p 2 p * 2 k 2 = 0 (8)</formula><p>Note that i / p i p * i / k i = 0, by the envelope theorem. It is fairly tricky to solve for the equilibrium advertising levels based on the implicit expressions of p * 1 k 1 k 2 and p * 2 k 1 k 2 as defined by Equation (6). We first note that in the second-stage equilibrium, we must have for any</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">k i ∈ 0 1 , where i = 1, 2: 1 p * 1 p * 2 k 1 k 2 p 1 = 0 2 p * 1 p * 2 k 1 k 2 p 2 = 0 (9)</formula><p>By differentiating these two identities, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">2 1 p 1 k 1 + 2 1 p 2 1 p * 1 k 1 + 2 1 p 1 p 2 p * 2 k 1 = 0 2 1 p 1 k 2 + 2 1 p 2 1 p * 1 k 2 + 2 1 p 1 p 2 p * 2 k 2 = 0 2 2 p 2 k 1 + 2 2 p 1 p 2 p * 1 k 1 + 2 2 p 2 2 p * 2 k 1 = 0 2 2 p 2 k 2 + 2 2 p 1 p 2 p * 1 k 2 + 2 2 p 2 2 p * 2 k 2 = 0 (<label>10</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_13">)</formula><p>To obtain the symmetric equilibrium, we note that all second-order derivatives in the above system of equations, i.e., 2 i / p i k i , 2 i / p i k j , 2 i / p 2 i , and 2 i / p i p j , as well as the first-order derivatives in Equation ( <ref type="formula">8</ref>), i.e., i / p i and i / p j , can be obtained directly from differentiating the profit expressions and then substituting in p * k 1 =k 2 =k from Equation ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>). This means that we can solve p * i / k i and p * i / k j from Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_12">10</ref>) and substitute them into Equation (8). By imposing the symmetry condition k 1 = k 2 = k in the first stage, the two independent first-order conditions in Equation ( <ref type="formula">8</ref>) will be reduced to one, leading to a unique symmetric solution for k * , the candidate equilibrium we are looking for. In the case of c = 0, we obtain a closed-form solution, which is given in Appendix 2. In Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref>, we illustrate the parameter space where we have k * ∈ 0 1 for the case of c = 0. In the case of c &gt; 0, we solve numerically for the equilibrium for all feasible parameters. In both cases, we numerically verify that the proposed equilibrium is indeed the equilibrium of the game, as neither firm has any incentive to deviate. For now, we will focus on the first case, as this is the simpler case that would give us all the qualitative conclusions. We will pick up the second case in §5.</p><p>Our analysis shows, as expected, that a firm's optimal advertising level k * is increasing in a. This suggests that as consumers are more responsive to firms' advertising, firms will optimally choose to increase their advertising level. Also as expected, k * is decreasing in b, suggesting that if the advertising response exhibits higher diminishing returns, firms will optimally choose to do less advertising. With this equilibrium value of k * , we now assess the consequences of combative advertising on equilibrium pricing and profitability. The comparison of profits and prices with and without combative advertising is indicated in Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref>. Firms' prices and profits fall in the vertically shaded region (Region 1), and they rise in the horizontally shaded region (Region 2). In equilibrium, the variance of the consumer density function depends on the responsiveness parameters a, b, and k * is given by 11 * 2 =</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">1 12 + 6a − 1 15 k * − 2 5 bk * 2</formula><p>Proposition 2. Under combative advertising, competing firms' prices and profits are higher as compared to the case of no advertising if consumers in the market are sufficiently responsive to advertising * 2 &gt; 1 12 , in Region 2 . However, prices and profits are lower when consumers are not sufficiently responsive * 2 &lt; 1 12 , in Region 1 . Proposition 2, based on the first-order effect, suggests that whether or not a firm can benefit from combative advertising will depend on whether consumers in the market are sufficiently impressionable. The conclusions in the proposition are expected in light of the simple model we have discussed in §2. The driving force behind Proposition 2 is similar to that in the discrete model. Combative advertising determines the equilibrium distribution of consumers along the Hotelling line. As illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>, when consumers are sufficiently responsive to advertising, the variance of the consumer density function increases. <ref type="bibr">12</ref> Thus, combative advertising creates more partisan customers, with more consumers located toward the two ends as compared to a market without advertising, and thus increases product differentiation in the minds of consumers. Increased product differentiation, in turn, leads to higher prices and profits. When consumers are not sufficiently responsive, the variance of the consumer density function decreases. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> Thus, combative advertising creates more indifferent customers, manifested by a net accumulation of consumers in the middle and fewer consumers located closer to firms, reducing product differentiation. Reduced differentiation encourages more price competition and lowers the price and profit for competing firms. The main difference between the current model and the discrete model is that we do not need to restrict the pattern of consumer responses to advertising along the Hotelling line, except for imposing some mild conditions at the level of aggregate advertising response functions, which are supported by past empirical research. We now have in equilibrium a continuous, endogenous distribution density function f , which is convex in the former case and concave in the latter case.</p><p>While the profit implications of Proposition 2 follow directly from price implications, the price implications themselves are new and thought provoking. 11 k * , in turn, depends on a and b, as shown in Appendix 2.</p><p>12 For instance, a = 0 3, b = 0 1 ⇒ * 2 = 0 0978 &gt; 1/12. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> For instance, a = 0 2, b = 0 055 ⇒ * 2 = 0 0763 &lt; 1/12. Most importantly, Proposition 2 seems consistent with what we frequently observe in the marketplace. As competing firms combat, engaging in extensive advertising campaigns touting the virtues of their own product, one of two things can happen. In the first instance, consumers are bombarded with so much advertising that they become partisan customers. In that case, it would take a lot of convincing for these consumers to consider purchasing a product from a rival firm. <ref type="bibr">14</ref> In the second instance, consumers receive a good dose of advertising from both firms, see merits in both firms' products, and therefore feel more indifferent about buying from either firm. It is this latter possibility-the creation of indifferent customersthat the previous literature on advertising overlooks.</p><p>Our model shows that the critical moderating factor for these two outcomes is how responsive consumers are to advertising in a market.</p><p>It is important to note here that the concave distribution function of consumer preferences in Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref> is an endogenous outcome of the equilibrium strategies and is not assumed a priori. Given a = 0 2 and b = 0 055, the distribution function is concave only when the advertising intensity in the market is larger than 0.606061, as can be inferred from Equation (7). When the advertising intensity is less than that cutoff point, the distribution of consumer preferences in the market is convex, as shown in Figure <ref type="figure">6</ref>. However, competing firms are incentivized in this market to escalate their advertising intensities above and beyond that cutoff point and the equilibrium level of advertising intensity for both firms is 0.946128, resulting in the concave distribution function in Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>. What this means is that even in advertising, competing firms can be caught in a prisoner's dilemma situation where firms escalate their own level of advertising intensity, motivated by self-interest, and end up becoming worse off collectively because advertising competition leads to price competition. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">The Role of Advertising Costs</head><p>In their study of informative advertising, <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Grossman and Shapiro (1984)</ref> found that an increase in advertising costs could have two effects: a direct increase in total advertising costs resulting in a reduction in profits; and also a reduction in the degree of competition as measured by demand elasticities, which results in higher profits. Their explanation was that advertising improves information available to consumers and reduces profits. With increased costs, the amount of advertising decreases, resulting in a reduction in the information available to consumers, as a consequence allowing firms to charge higher prices.</p><p>In our analysis of combative advertising, an increase or decrease in advertising does not have any effect on the amount of information available to consumers. Hence, the above reasoning is not applicable to markets where consumers are already informed about the available products. Do the same relationships between costs and firms' prices and profits hold in the context of combative advertising?</p><p>To answer this question, we note that for any c &gt; 0, we can no longer write down an explicit expression for k * as a function of c; however, we can numerically analyze this case. We find, as expected, that the equilibrium level of advertising decreases as the unit cost of advertising increases ( k * / c &lt; 0). But what does this mean in terms of equilibrium profit levels? Note that a firm's equilibrium profit can be written as * = k * c c . Therefore, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">d * dc = k * c c k * k * c c + k * c c c (<label>11</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_16">)</formula><p>The second term in Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_15">11</ref>) is the direct effect of the advertising cost on a firm's profitability, which is always negative. The first term captures the indirect effect of advertising cost on a firm's profitability through advertising. As mentioned before, k * c / c in the first term is negative. Furthermore, it can be shown that k * c c / k * is also negative. This is because firms always advertise too much to maximize their profits, a feature of combative advertising. Thus, the first term, or the indirect effect, is always positive. This implies that a firm's profitability must decrease (increase) with the costs of advertising c, i.e., d * /dc &lt; 0 (d * /dc &gt; 0), if the direct effect is larger (smaller) than the indirect effect. The relative sizes of these two effects depend, in turn, on consumer responsiveness to advertising. The direct effect is larger (smaller) than the indirect effect, as we show in Figure <ref type="figure">7</ref>, when consumers in the market are sufficiently responsive (unresponsive) so that firms are already (not) engaging in a high level of advertising.</p><p>Proposition 3. With combative advertising, as the unit cost of advertising increases, equilibrium profit decreases when consumers are sufficiently responsive to advertising, and equilibrium profit increases when consumers are not sufficiently responsive to advertising.</p><p>Proposition 3 thus suggests that the intuition we have gained about the effects of advertising costs in the context of informative advertising does not necessarily carry over to combative advertising. Higher advertising costs can indeed hurt the bottom line of competing firms, as much anecdotal evidence seems to suggest. In fact, as shown in Figure <ref type="figure">7</ref>, firms that tend to get hurt by higher advertising cost are the firms in markets where the consumers are sufficiently responsive to advertising, and the firms that tend to benefit from higher advertising costs are the firms in markets where consumers are sufficiently unresponsive to advertising. This implication of our model is testable with suitable data. 15</p><p>15 Understanding how the variation in profits with costs relates to variation in prices with costs could further facilitate conducting an empirical test. Since our modeling assumptions imply a fixed-size market and symmetric market share, expected variation in profits would be positively correlated with the expected variation in prices. Thus, we expect that as the unit cost of advertising increases, equilibrium prices would decrease if consumers are sufficiently responsive to advertising, and equilibrium prices would increase</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Experimental Analysis</head><p>Past experimental research on consumer reactions to advertising messages suggests that advertising can have a dramatic effect on consumer perceptions of a product, especially when the product experience is of an ambiguous nature <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Hoch and Ha 1986)</ref>. In our modeling context, this change in perception could correspond to one of three things: a change in reservation price, or in travel costs, or in the distance of the consumer's ideal point from the product. These claims are further supported by the work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Carpenter and Nakamoto (1989)</ref>, who show that a firm can gain pioneering advantage by shifting consumer preferences toward itself-either by shifting the taste distribution towards the firm's position, and/or by influencing attribute weights used by consumers to evaluate products. Additional support is found in D' <ref type="bibr">Souza and Rao (1995)</ref> who show that in the context of mature product categories, advertising repetition can have a positive effect on relative brand preference. <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Tellis (2004)</ref> reports that loyals respond to advertising for their preferred brand more quickly at low levels of advertising than nonloyals, whereas high levels of advertising is likely to gain the attention of and positively influence nonloyals more so than loyal consumers of the brand. The shift in ideal points that we propose as a basic premise of our model is also consistent with the widely documented mere exposure effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Zajonc 1968</ref>), which suggests that the mere act of repetitive exposure of a stimulus can lead to a preference for it, even if consumers do not remember the exposure.</p><p>Our analysis so far has demonstrated that if combative advertising results in more indifferent consumers, it can result in lower prices and profits. While it is well documented that combative advertising can influence consumer preferences in favor of the firm, to the best of our knowledge, there are no studies that examine whether combative advertising can indeed result in more indifferent consumers. Therefore, we conducted experiments to investigate the effects of combative advertising on consumer preferences. Our objective in this study is not to test the validity of our model's predictions but to demonstrate that combative advertising can result in more indifferent consumers, a key driver behind our pricing implications.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.">Description of the Study</head><p>We limited our attention to a few product categories with two equally matched competitors actively if consumers were not sufficiently responsive to advertising. Since changes in prices and costs are relatively easier to monitor in a market than changes in profits and costs, these pricing implications of our cost analysis would be amenable to empirical testing in future research.</p><p>engaged in combative advertising to sway consumer preferences and with a high likelihood for us to observe the phenomenon of advertising generating more indifferent customers. Although many product categories can fit this description, our choice was further limited by the availability of current TV commercials, and also whether these product categories were relevant to our experimental subjectsundergraduate students at a major East Coast business school. The product categories and the brands chosen were as follows: Credit cards (Visa and MasterCard), Courier services (FedEx and UPS), Batteries (Duracell and Energizer), Toothpastes (Colgate and Aquafresh), and Cars (BMW and Audi). <ref type="bibr">16</ref> The study was conducted in a state-of-the-art behavioral lab. Two hundred seventy-two subjects participated in the study. The subject entered the lab, was greeted by the lab administrator, and was asked to fill out a questionnaire to report preferences for each of the two brands in five product categories by allocating 100 points between each brand pairs. The responses were collected. Then, subjects (164) were exposed to advertising stimuli (nonprice commercials) of the two brands in each of the five categories. The order in which the advertisements were shown was rotated across categories and also within each category. <ref type="bibr">17</ref> After viewing the TV commercials for a product category, the subjects in the exposure group were asked to report their preferences for the two brands again by allocating 100 points to the two brands-more to the one they preferred. The process was repeated for all five product categories. The subjects in the control group (108) were asked to perform the same task, but we replaced the commercials shown to subjects in the treatment condition with the same number of commercials not related to any of the product categories under study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.">Analysis and Results</head><p>The summary statistics are reported in Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1 and 2</ref>.</p><p>To analyze the effect of combative advertising on consumer preferences, we first placed all subjects on a Hotelling line, bounded by 0 100 , on the basis of their reported preferences prior to being exposed to the stimuli by (arbitrarily) locating the two competing firms at the two ends of the line. For example, we located FedEx at 0 and UPS at 100. If a subject assigned 60 points to FedEx and 40 points to UPS prior to the advertising exposure, we located the subject on the Hotelling line at 40, indicating that the subject prefers FedEx to UPS. Once all subjects were thus located on the Hotelling line, we grouped both  experimental and control group subjects into two subgroups: those who preferred one firm and those the other. The subjects assigning exactly 50 points were randomly assigned to these two subgroups. <ref type="bibr">18</ref> We then computed the pre-and postadvertising preferences for each of these two subgroups.</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">[0 = Fdx, 100 = UPS] [0 = Aqua, 100 = Colg] [0 = MC, 100 = Visa] [0 = Audi, 100 = BMW] [0 = Dura, 100 = Energ]</formula><p>If advertising generates more indifferent consumers, we would expect the conditional means of both these subgroups in the treatment condition to move closer to 50 and such movements should be statistically significant relative to the movements displayed by the corresponding subjects in the control group. If advertising generates more partisan consumers, we expect that the conditional means to move away from 50 in a statistically significant way relative to the control group. The results are reported in Table <ref type="table">3</ref>.</p><p>Results in Table <ref type="table">3</ref> suggest that for three of the five product categories (courier services, toothpaste, and cars), the conditional means move closer to 50, and this change is significant at the 5% level relative to the change in the control group. For credit cards, it is also in the same direction, but the results are statistically significant at the 10% level (p = 0 066). For the fifth product category (batteries), the conditional means move toward Duracell, implying a more effective Duracell advertising. These results do not depend on whether the two groups were formed based on mean or median.</p><p>We further analyze the data by focusing only on the within-subject information from the exposure group. In this case, we need to rule out the regression-to-the-mean bias (RTM). As we show in Appendix 3, if experimental subjects tend to give a small number after giving a large number or vice versa, the conditional means as we have calculated will move closer to the indifference point, regardless of whether advertising has any effect. To rule this out as a possible explanation, we conducted two additional statistical tests.</p><p>The first test we conduct is an F -test on the variance of pre-and postadvertising data. The basic idea is as follows: the variance in the data consists of two parts-the true variance in the data ( B or A ) and the error variance ( 0 ) that causes the RTM drift <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Morrison 1973)</ref>. As the latter variance should be the same for both the pre-and postadvertising data, it is easy to see that any significant difference in the measured total variance between pre-( B + 0 ) and postadvertising data series ( A + 0 ) must imply that B and A are significantly different. The difference must be due to advertising exposures, not due to any RTM effect. However, when the difference between ( B + 0 ) and ( A + 0 ) is not significant by the F -test, the difference between B and A can still be significant. In other words, the F -test here is an overly restrictive test for our purposes. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">4</ref> shows that in the categories of cars and credit cards, subjects become significantly more indifferent due to advertising exposures, as the postadvertising variance is significantly smaller than the preadvertising variance (at the 5% level). In the toothpaste category, subjects become more indifferent at the 10% significance level. In the battery category, the variance increases to indicate more partisan customers; however, the difference is not statistically significant.</p><p>Another test that incorporates a clearer indifference point is the distance dispersion test. With this test, we can also statistically eliminate the preference bias in favor of a brand and control for the possible differences in the commercials' potency. To conduct this test, we first compute the mean for both the pre-and postadvertising preferences. Then, we subtract the respective mean from each pre-and postadvertising observations to de-mean the two data sets. In other words, we statistically center both the preand postadvertising preference distributions at zero.  Then, for each subject i, we compute the distance of his or her preference from zero in absolute value, respectively, for both pre-and postadvertising cases.</p><p>The difference in the pre-and the postadvertising distances then measures the change in a subject's preference: the subject's preference moves closer to the center when the difference is positive and further away from the center when the difference is negative. We compute such a difference measure for all experimental subjects and find the mean difference for the population. As we show in Appendix 4, this procedure helps mitigate the RTM effect. We expect that the mean difference for the population is not zero due to the effect of the advertisements. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">5</ref> reports the results of this analysis.</p><p>Consistent with the analysis contained in Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3  and 4</ref>, Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">5</ref> shows that the dispersion in preferences for the two product categories of credit cards and cars shrinks even after controlling for any mean shift. The shrinkage is strongly significant statistically, implying that subjects become more indifferent between two brands in those two product categories after the ad exposure. For toothpaste, the change in subjects' preferences is in the same direction of indifference, but it is statistically significant only at the 10% level as in the F -test. However, with this test, the dispersion of subjects' preferences increases for the battery category with a strong statistical significance. Overall, this test suggests that combative advertisements can produce indifferent customers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3.">Pricing Implications</head><p>Although preferences may change due to advertisements in a statistically significant way, one may still question whether the change is economically significant so as to modify a brand's pricing behavior as predicted by our model. We address this question in the context of our experiment by fitting continuous cumulative distribution functions to the preference data within a product category. We estimate two such functions for each category, using the pre-and postadvertising data, respectively. Of course, we expect these functions to be highly nonlinear. To accommodate nonlinearity, we specify each function as a Taylor series to the fifth power to achieve the proper good-Marketing Science 28(1), pp. 1-19, © 2009 INFORMS ness of fit. <ref type="bibr">19</ref> We subsequently assume a common reservation price as in the Hotelling model and set the unit transportation cost t (a scaling factor) to one and marginal costs for both brands to zero. This allows us to numerically solve for the equilibrium in the pre-and postadvertising pricing games and see if the postadvertising price competition intensifies in a product category, as predicted by our model.</p><p>As illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure">8</ref>, the preadvertising price equilibrium for the category of cars is 0.68 for BMW and 0.48 for Audi and the postadvertising equilibrium prices are 0.52 and 0.41, respectively. In other words, price competition intensifies in the postadvertising market, because combative advertisements have generated more indifferent customers. Correspondingly, the equilibrium profit for BMW decreases from 0.3956 to 0.2924 and for Audi from 0.2007 to 0.1795. In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">6</ref>, we report the equilibrium analysis for the rest of the product categories. Note that the postadvertising equilibrium prices go down for two additional categories-credit cards and toothpastes, and they increase for the batteries category, consistent with the preference shifts in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">4</ref>. Interestingly, even if equilibrium prices decrease (increase) for both competing brands, not every brand is worse off (better off), as shown in the case of MasterCard (Energizer), because of preference-induced market share changes. <ref type="bibr">20</ref> Overall, our experimental analysis demonstrates that combative advertisements can indeed generate indifferent customers and lead to intensified price competition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">Conclusions and Future Research</head><p>Our analysis suggests that although from an individual firm's perspective combative advertising can change consumer preferences in its favor, through competitive interactions in the marketplace, such advertising may not favor the firm. We show that combative advertising can generate either more partisan customers or more indifferent customers. In the former case, more consumers will have a stronger preference for a particular firm's product and hence reduce price competition. In the latter case, more consumers feel indifferent about buying from either firm so as to intensify price competition through reduced product differentiation. Therefore, with advertising, as with pricing, firms can be caught in a prisoner's dilemma where all firms become worse off because of their independent decisions to advertise in order to gain advantages over competition. Our analysis shows that what ultimately mediates the two different outcomes is how responsive consumers are to advertising. In markets where consumers are sufficiently responsive, heavy combative advertising will create more partisan customers to the benefit of competing firms. In contrast, in markets where consumers are not sufficiently responsive, combative advertising might simply create more indifferent customers. As a result, price competition in the market could intensify.</p><p>Looking at it from a slightly different perspective, consumers in the market are subject to opposing  forces when firms engage in combative advertising.</p><p>Our analysis reveals that depending on the strengths of these opposing forces, consumers are either pulled away from the middle (more partisan customers) or pulled towards the middle (more indifferent customers). To the best of our knowledge, our model is the first in the literature that studies the mechanics of combative advertising, analyzing the full range of competitive implications of the preference-changing effects of advertising. The conclusion about indifferent customers is surprising but plausible. Indeed, our experimental analysis shows that the outcome we have uncovered is not just a theoretical curiosity-it can happen with real people watching real commercials and evaluating real products. Our analysis, informed by empirical research on advertising, also provides a number of insights that may guide practice and future research on advertising. First, if combative advertising can have anticompetitive effects in one case, but procompetitive effects in another, it implies that advertising decisions are more complex. While making these decisions, it is important for us to ascertain the mediators for these two kinds of effects. Our model suggests that the mediators are most likely related to the consumer responsiveness to advertising, which in turn is related perhaps to consumer characteristics, product characteristics, and message effectiveness. Future research, most suitably experimental research, can further explore those mediators. Second, by recognizing the phenomenon of combative advertising generating partisan and indifferent customers, we find an intuitive, measurable way of gauging its competitive effects in practice. As the creation of partisan or indifferent consumers is a phenomenon that could be observed even in the presence of more than two firms in the market, we are inclined to believe that the findings from our model are easily generalizable to product categories where oligopolistic competition is more prevalent as compared to duopolistic competition. Third, the competitive implications of advertising may differ in different markets depending on how responsive consumers are to advertising. For instance, lumping different product categories together to measure competitive effects may not be advisable, as it may lead to cancelling out of opposing effects. Additional research investigating the movement of each individual utility maximizing consumer may be able to shed more light on this issue. Fourth, in the context of combative advertising, lower advertising costs may or may not be a blessing for a firm. In markets where advertising creates indifferent customers, firms may want to embrace, rather than fight, the increase in advertising costs. Finally, advertising is not always wasteful at the expense of consumers, as it can encourage more intense price competition.</p><p>Our model can be extended in many ways. For instance, it may be worthwhile to allow for other marketing decision variables. 21 Also, it might be desirable to have a more detailed model at the micro-level. Another possibility is to introduce dynamic advertising competition between firms over time. In addition, future empirical or experimental research can further look into the magnitude of effects of advertising in shifting consumer preferences. While in our experiment the effects are quite pronounced, in real-life settings, they may not be. We hope that the first step we have taken here shows the fruitfulness of research on combative advertising.</p><p>Marketing Science 28(1), pp. <ref type="bibr">1-19, © 2009 INFORMS</ref> Consumers in this market are fully informed about the existence of the two firms, their locations, and prices; hence the effect of a firm's advertising is not to inform consumers about its existence, location, or price, but to engage in a combat with the competitor in shifting consumer preferences towards itself. Thus, under combative advertising, some consumers at location x may move towards firm i due to its advertising k i . In other words, they consider the firm's product closer to their ideal product. Consequently, the distribution of consumers along the unit line will change from the uniform distribution to f k 1 k 2 x , with the mean location of consumers in this market being given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">m k 1 k 2 = 1 0 xf k 1 k 2 x dx (13)</formula><p>As a probability density function, f k 1 k 2 x must satisfy the following regularity condition, for all k 1 and k 2 :</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">1 0 f k 1 k 2 x dx = 1 (14)</formula><p>We further impose symmetry on the density function to assume away any firm-specific factors and to focus on the competitive effect of combative advertising. Algebraically, this means the following condition must hold:</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">f k 1 k 2 x = f k 2 k 1 1 − x (15)</formula><p>This condition rules out the mechanism identified in <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bloch and Manceau (1999)</ref> as the driving force for competitive effects. To introduce the preference-shifting effect of a firm's advertising, we assume</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">f k 1 k 2 0 k 1 &gt; 0 f k 1 k 2 1 k 2 &gt; 0 (16)</formula><p>Equation ( <ref type="formula">16</ref>) shows the boundary conditions that ensure that at any given level of advertising by its rival, a firm can, through more of its own advertising, increase the number of customers who would consider its product as the ideal. Hence the density of consumers at x = 0 (x = 1) increases as Firm 1 (Firm 2) unilaterally increases its advertising intensity. We further impose a boundary condition below to help us to parameterize the density function:</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">f k 1 0 1 k 1 &lt; 0 f 0 k 2 0 k 2 &lt; 0 f 2 k 1 0 1 2 k 1 = f 2 0 k 2 0 2 k 2 = 0 (17)</formula><p>The conditions imposed in Equation ( <ref type="formula">17</ref>) are essentially technical in nature and they ensure that the density of consumers at the extreme location (x = 0 or x = 1) who consider the respective firm's product as ideal will decrease with the rival's advertising level, and do so at a constant rate if the rival firm does not do any advertising at all. To scale such preference-shifting effects, we assume</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">f 1 0 1 = 0 f 0 1 0 = 0 (18)</formula><p>Equation ( <ref type="formula">18</ref>) implies that the effect of a firm's maximum advertising is so strong that it can shift the preference of all consumers farthest away from it toward itself, if the other firm does not advertise at all. <ref type="bibr">22</ref> Finally, we assume</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">f k 1 0 x x ≤ 0 f 0 k 2 x x ≥ 0 (19)</formula><p>These two conditions simply state that if the rival firm does not advertise, a firm's advertising should skew the consumer distribution in its favor or should have favorable effects on consumer preferences. Together with ( <ref type="formula">18</ref>), ( <ref type="formula">19</ref>) ensures that the density of consumer distribution can never become negative.</p><p>To determine a specific density function that satisfies all conditions ( <ref type="formula">12</ref>)-( <ref type="formula">19</ref>), let us assume that</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">f k 1 k 2 x = v 1 k 1 x + v 2 k 2 x (20)</formula><p>i.e., f k 1 k 2 x is of an additive form in terms of the impact of k 1 and k 2 on the shifts in the distribution of preferences. <ref type="bibr">23</ref> Intuitively, v i captures the effects of firm i's advertising. We thus view the density at any given x, i.e., f k 1 k 2 x , as resulting from two opposing advertising forces: consumers at x may be pulled away from x and at the same time consumers at other locations may be pulled to x when subject to combative advertising. We let v 1 take on the following, general quadratic form 24 with respect to both x and k 1 :</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">v 1 k 1 x = a 0 + a 1 k 1 + a 2 k 2 1 + a 3 x + a 4 k 1 x + a 5 k 2 1 x + a 6 x 2 + a 7 k 1 x 2 + a 8 k 2 1 x 2 (21)</formula><p>We can analogously specify v 2 k 2 x . Now it is straightforward to use conditions ( <ref type="formula">12</ref>)-( <ref type="formula">19</ref>) to derive the following parameterized functions:</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">25 v 1 k 1 x = 1 2 + k 1 12a − 1 − 6 8a − 1 x + 6 6a − 1 x 2 − 12bk 2 1 1 − 4x + 3x 2 v 2 k 2 x = 1 2 + k 2 12a − 1 − 6 8a − 1 1 − x + 6 6a − 1 1 − x 2 − 12bk 2 2 1 − 4 1 − x + 3 1 − x 2</formula><p>The mean and variance for f are</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">Mean = 1 2 − a k 1 − k 2 + b k 1 − k 2 k 1 + k 2 Variance = 1 12 + k 1 + k 2 6a − 1 30 − b 10 k 1 + k 2 − k 1 − k 2 2 b 10 + a − b k 1 + k 2 2</formula><p>22 Note that as this assumption is only one of the many possible ways to scale the effect of advertising, we can easily relax this assumption by using any 0 ≤ f k 1 0 1 = f 0 k 2 0 &lt; 1 without changing our main results. <ref type="bibr">23</ref> We expect our qualitative conclusions to remain unchanged when f is nonseparable in advertising. If 2 f / k 1 k 2 &lt; 0, the equilibrium advertising level would be lower than the case when 2 f / k 1 k 2 = 0. This is because the marginal benefit from advertising becomes smaller in a symmetric advertising equilibrium. Thus, a convex density shape is more likely. In contrast, if 2 f / k 1 k 2 &gt; 0, the equilibrium advertising level would be higher than the case when 2 f / k 1 k 2 = 0. Here, a concave density shape is more likely.</p><p>24 v 2 also takes on a similar form, given Equation ( <ref type="formula">15</ref>). <ref type="bibr">25</ref> Where a = 1 + a 1 /12 and b = − a 2 /12 . For additional details on the intermediate steps in this derivation, please see the Technical Appendix, found at http://mktsci.pubs.informs.org.</p><p>Assume the individual true mean as x * i and x 1i and x 2i are the values for individual i pre-and postadvertising. If the only effect presented is a regression to mean, x * i will be unchanged pre-and postadvertising. We can define x 1i = x *</p><p>i − e i and x 1i = x * i + e i , where e i can be negative or positive with 0 mean and follows a symmetric distribution (e.g., a normal distribution).</p><p>For any symmetric distribution of preferences, its mean m is equal to its median so that there are an equal number of people on both sides of the mean Also, this mean should not change pre-and postadvertising. The conditional mean change for those with preadvertising preference less than m is m c post − pre =</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">x *</formula><p>i −e i ≤m</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">x * i + e i − x * i −e i ≤m</formula><p>x * i − e i n/2 = 2</p><p>x * i −e i ≤m e i n/2 = 4</p><formula xml:id="formula_31">x * i −e i ≤m e i n = 4 e i ≥x * i −m e i n &gt; 0</formula><p>where n is the number of people. In the above proof, we used the fact e i ≥− e i = 0 so that e i ≥x * i −m e i &gt; 0 given the symmetry in the distribution of e i . Similarly, we can show that the conditional mean change for those with preadvertising preference larger than m is less than 0. Thus, together they imply that conditional means can move to the middle purely due to the RTM effect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix 4. Overcoming the RTM Effect</head><p>Assume that an individual's true mean is x * i and x 1i and x 2i are the values for individual i pre-and postadvertising. If only the RTM effect is present, x * i will be unchanged before and after advertising exposures. We can define x 2i = x * i − e i and x 1i = x * i + e i , where e i can be negative or positive with 0 mean and follows a symmetric distribution (e.g., normal distribution). For any symmetric distribution of preferences, its mean is equal to its median so that the number of people on both sides are equal. Also, this mean does not change pre-and postadvertising. The total preadvertising distance to this mean m across all people is</p><formula xml:id="formula_32">D before = i x * i − e i − m = x * i −e i &gt;m x * i − e i − m + x * i −e i &lt;m m − x * i + e i = x * i −e i &gt;m −e i + x * i −e i &lt;m e i + x * i −e i &gt;m x * i + x * i −e i &lt;m −x * i</formula><p>In the above proof, we used the fact that the preference distribution is symmetric so that the number of people with x * i − e i &gt; m is equal to the number of people with x * i − e i &lt; m. Similarly, the total postadvertising distance to this mean m across all people is D after = i x *</p><p>i + e i − m =</p><p>x * i +e i &gt;m  −</p><formula xml:id="formula_33">2x * i = − x * i −m&gt;e i x * i −m&gt;−e i 2e i + x * i −m&lt;e i x * i −m&lt;−e i 2e i + x * i −m&gt;e i x * i −m&lt;−e i 2x * i − x * i −m&lt;e i x * i −m&gt;−e i 2x * i = e i &gt;0 − x * i −m&gt;e i 2e i + x * i −m&lt;−e i 2e i + e i &lt;0 − x * i −m&gt;−e i 2e i + x * i −m&lt;e i 2e i + e i &gt;0 x * i −m &gt; e i 2x * i − x * i −m &lt; e i 2x * i + e i &lt;0 x * i −m &lt; e i 2x * i − x * i −m &gt; e i 2x * i = e i &gt;0</formula><formula xml:id="formula_34">x * i −m&lt;e i 2e i + e i &lt;0 x * i −m&lt;e i 2e i + 0 + 0 = 0 + 0 + 0 + 0 = 0</formula><p>The last two steps are due to the fact that e is symmetrically distributed with zero mean. What this means is that by looking at the difference in the distances across the subjects, we cancel out any RTM effect so that any detected difference in distances can only be due to advertising exposures.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Consumer Response to Unilateral Advertising</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2 Consumer Response When Both Firms Advertise 2.0 1.6 1.2 0.8 0.4 0</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3Effect of Combative Advertising on the Equilibrium Price</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 4Combative Advertising and Equilibrium Profitability</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 5Effect of Combative Advertising on the Distribution of Consumer Preferences</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 6Variation in Preference Distribution with Advertising</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 7Effect of Advertising Costs</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 8 (a) Preadvertising Price Equilibrium; (b) Postadvertising Price Equilibrium</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Summary Statistics for the Control Group n = 108 Fdx, 100 = UPS] [0 = Aqua, 100 = Colg] [0 = MC, 100 = Visa] [0 = Audi, 100 = BMW] [0 = Dura, 100 = Energ]</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Courier services</cell><cell>Toothpastes</cell><cell>Credit cards</cell><cell>Cars</cell><cell>Batteries</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">[0 = Mean before</cell><cell>44 68</cell><cell>64 69</cell><cell>64 54</cell><cell>55 33</cell><cell>49 12</cell></row><row><cell>Mean after</cell><cell></cell><cell>47 07</cell><cell>64 31</cell><cell>62 3</cell><cell>5 4 82</cell><cell>50 38</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Median before</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>65</cell><cell>60</cell><cell>50 5</cell><cell>5 0</cell></row><row><cell>Median after</cell><cell></cell><cell>50</cell><cell>60</cell><cell>55</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>50</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">St. dev. before</cell><cell>18 46</cell><cell>22 91</cell><cell>23 39</cell><cell>20 58</cell><cell>17 9</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">St. dev. after</cell><cell>19 07</cell><cell>22 79</cell><cell>22 71</cell><cell>19 37</cell><cell>17 92</cell></row><row><cell>Table 2</cell><cell cols="3">Summary Statistics for the Exposure Group n = 164</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Courier services</cell><cell>Toothpastes</cell><cell>Credit cards</cell><cell>Cars</cell><cell>Batteries</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Analysis of Variance in the Pre-and Postexposure</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Preferences, Using the F -Test</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Courier</cell><cell></cell><cell>Credit</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">services Toothpastes</cell><cell>cards</cell><cell>Cars</cell><cell>Batteries</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Preadvertising 275 0</cell><cell>552 8</cell><cell>432 5</cell><cell>410 6</cell><cell>309 1</cell></row><row><cell>variance</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Postadvertising 290 6</cell><cell>441 1</cell><cell>302 0</cell><cell>280 5</cell><cell>357 4</cell></row><row><cell>variance</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>F -statistic</cell><cell>0 9463</cell><cell>1 2532</cell><cell>1 4321</cell><cell>1 4638</cell><cell>0 8649</cell></row><row><cell>p-value</cell><cell>0 372</cell><cell>0 076</cell><cell>0 011</cell><cell>0 008</cell><cell>0 188</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Analysis of Pre-and Postexposure Distances</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Courier</cell><cell></cell><cell>Credit</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>services</cell><cell>Toothpastes</cell><cell>cards</cell><cell>Cars</cell><cell>Batteries</cell></row><row><cell>Difference in</cell><cell>−0 528257</cell><cell>1 996356</cell><cell cols="3">3 805399 3 349048 −3 21163</cell></row><row><cell>pre-and</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>postexposure</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>distances</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>t-statistic</cell><cell>−0 492479</cell><cell>1 728975</cell><cell cols="3">3 664976 3 302581 −2 867211</cell></row><row><cell>p-value (2-tailed)</cell><cell>0 623043</cell><cell>0 085707</cell><cell cols="2">0 000334 0 001177</cell><cell>0 004688</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Equilibrium Analysis</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Visa</cell><cell>MasterCard</cell><cell>Engergizer</cell><cell>Duracell</cell><cell>Colgate</cell><cell>Aquafresh</cell><cell>UPS</cell><cell>FedEx</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>D before − D after is</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Marketing Science 28(1), pp. 1-19, © 2009 INFORMS</cell></row><row><cell>i −e i &gt;m Therefore, x  *</cell><cell>−e i +</cell><cell cols="3">x  *  i −e i &lt;m</cell><cell cols="2">e i −</cell><cell cols="3">x  *  i +e i &gt;m</cell><cell>e i −</cell><cell>x  *  i +e i &lt;m</cell><cell>−e i</cell></row><row><cell>+</cell><cell cols="2">x  *  i −e i &gt;m</cell><cell>x  *  i −</cell><cell cols="4">x  *  i −e i &lt;m</cell><cell cols="2">x  *  i −</cell><cell>x  *  i +e i &gt;m</cell><cell>x  *  i +</cell><cell>i +e i &lt;m x  *</cell><cell>x  *  i</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">= −</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="4">2e i +</cell><cell>2e i</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="5">x  *  i −e i &gt;m x  *  i +e i &gt;m</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">x  *  i −e i &lt;m x  *  i +e i &lt;m</cell></row><row><cell>+</cell><cell cols="5">x  *  i −e i &gt;m x  *  i +e i &lt;m</cell><cell cols="3">2x  *  i −</cell><cell>x  *  i −e i &lt;m x  *  i +e i &gt;m</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>x  *  i + e i − m</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>+</cell><cell>i +e i &lt;m x  *</cell><cell>m − x  *  i − e i</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>=</cell><cell>x  *  i +e i &gt;m</cell><cell>e i +</cell><cell>x  *  i +e i &lt;m</cell><cell>−e i +</cell><cell>x  *  i +e i &gt;m</cell><cell>x  *  i +</cell><cell>i +e i &lt;m x  *</cell><cell>−x  *  i</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">The key focus of the literature on dynamic effects of advertising is to understand how advertising affects market share by bringing over competitors' consumers. The more a firm spends on advertising, the more sales it stands to gain, but if both competing firms spend on advertising, then the efforts are negated. There is no proposed change to the preference structure of consumers, and firms do not make their pricing decisions. Dynamic models are primarily awareness driven, whereas in this paper we shall focus on a preference-driven model.2  In their nomenclature, they classify persuasive advertising as nonprice advertising.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Strickly speaking,<ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bloch and Manceau (1999)</ref> do not set up an equilibrium model for advertising decisions: their main focus is on investigating a firm's incentives to advertise in as general a way as possible. As they point out in the paper, "at this level of generality, we are unable to analyze the firms' choice of the level of advertising expenses and cannot capture the effects of advertising spending by both firms on the distribution of consumers" (p. 565).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">We thank the anonymous area editor for suggesting the addition of this discrete analysis.5  In some cases, firms may have loyal consumers. In our model, these consumers would translate to mass points at the two ends of the line. Having additional mass points will not affect the qualitative nature of our results. To keep our analysis simple, we focus our attention on the case of a uniform distribution.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">We expect our qualitative conclusions to remain unchanged when f is nonseparable in advertising. For more details, please see Appendix 1.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="10">t = 1, a = 0 2, b = 0 055.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="14">The case that best illustrates this posssibility is, perhaps, from the political marketplace where competing candidates use mediabased political campaigns to garner more votes. By and large, such combative political persuasion "mainly reinforces voters' preexisting partisan loyalties" (Iyengar and Simon 2000, p. 150).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Marketing Science 28(1), pp.1-19, © 2009 INFORMS   </note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="16">Students were familiar with the brands chosen.17  The stimuli used in the study are available from the corresponding author.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="18">The reader may recognize that this is consistent with assigning the consumers to a Hotelling line.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="19">We need to fit a continuous cdf to guarantee the existence of price equilibrium. Otherwise, a brand's pricing strategy is continuous, but its demand is not, such that a pricing equilibrium may not exist. In fitting the cdf, we ensure F 0 = 0 and F 100 = 1. For all 10 estimated functions, the minimum R 2 we get is 0.81 and the highest is 0.96, with the average being 0.92.20  While our analysis in this section confirms the possibility of intensified/reduced price competition as a consequence of combative advertising, it would be worthwhile to empirically observe this intensified/reduced price competition in test markets, given changes in advertising levels and differences in consumer responsiveness. Such an analysis is outside our current scope, but we believe it would be an interesting avenue for future research.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="21">One could argue that in place of our functional specification for f , a traditional beta distribution (as typically used in marketing to specify consumer preferences) could be used to generate the two distributions illustrated in Figure5. Although that is a possibility, the beta distribution was not amenable to closed-form solutions for problem setup considered in this paper.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="26">We numerically check for the stability of both the second-stage and first-stage equilibrium. Specifically, the following two conditions: 2</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank the editor, the area editor, four anonymous reviewers, and seminar participants at Harvard Business School, International Forum on Marketing Science (Chengdu, China 2006), University of California at Berkeley, University of Houston, Washington University at St. Louis, Wharton, and Yale University for their excellent feedback on prior versions of this manuscript. The first author also thanks the Greater China Business Research Institute at Cheung Kong Graduate School of Business for its support.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix 1. Derivation of the Continuous Distribution Function</head><p>To parameterize the density function f k 1 k 2 x , we shall rely on the regularity conditions and the known effects of advertising to generate a tractable but still fairly general model that lends itself to game-theoretic analysis. As a benchmark, we assume that in the absence of any advertising, consumers are uniformly distributed in the market, so that we have</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix 2. Establishing Existence and Uniqueness</head><p>We first establish the existence and uniqueness of the second stage pricing equilibrium. From the first-order conditions ( §3), we have</p><p>where</p><p>We now show that g d has a unique solution for d ∈ 0 1 . First, note that g 0 &lt; 0 and g 1 &gt; 0; hence a solution exists for</p><p>With this functional form for F d , solving for g d = 0 (in Mathematica) gives us three roots of which two are imaginary. Therefore, g d = 0 has a unique solution on d ∈ 0 1 . We can show that p * i solved from the unique solution for d * from g d * = 0 constructs the unique equilibrium. p * i is unique because d * is unique. We now argue that p * i is an equilibrium solution. Let us consider the case where it is not the equilibrium solution: then p * i is a local minimum. From the uniqueness of p * i , p * i must then be the unique local minimum, and this implies that the profit at p i = 0 is higher than the profit at p * i given the same p * j . However, we know p i D is 0 at p i = 0 but p * i D is positive. Hence, p * i cannot be a local minimum; thus it has to be a local maximum. The uniqueness of p * i then implies that p * i is also the unique global maximum. This completes the proof of the existence and uniqueness of the second-stage pricing equilibrium.</p><p>We establish uniqueness of the first-stage advertising equilibrium numerically by checking for deviations in the entire advertising strategy space followed by competitive price setting by both firms. Such a deviation is never profitable, establishing that the first-stage equilibrium exists and is unique. <ref type="bibr">26</ref> The expression for k * is</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Advertising Controversy Evidence on the Economic Aspects of Advertising</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Albion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Farris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
			<publisher>Auburn House Publishing Company</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Boston</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The economic analysis of advertising</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Bagwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Industrial Organization</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Armstrong</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Porter</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>North-Holland, Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Barriers to New Competition: Their Character and Consequences in Manufacturing Industries</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1956" />
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wearout effects of different advertising themes: A dynamic Bayesian model of the advertising-sales relationship</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Bruce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Majumdar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">P S</forename><surname>Murthi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="195" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Advertising Management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Batra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Aaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Upper Saddle River, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A simple theory of advertising as a good or bad. Quart</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="941" to="964" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Persuasive advertising in hotelling&apos;s model of product differentiation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bloch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Manceau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Indust. Organ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="557" to="574" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consumer preference formation and pioneering advantage</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Nakamoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="298" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-market network effect with asymmetric consumer loyalty: Implications for competitive advantage</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="52" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advertising, market structure and performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Comanor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="423" to="440" />
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Can repeating an advertisement more frequently than the competition affect brand preference in a mature market?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>D'souza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="32" to="42" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model of advertising competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Erickson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="304" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dynamic Models of Advertising Competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Erickson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Norwell, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How prices, ad expenditures, and profits are linked</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Farris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Reibstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Harvard Bus. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="173" to="184" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Econometric analysis of collusive behavior in a soft-drink market</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Gasmi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Laffont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Vuong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Management Strategy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="277" to="311" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competition as a moderator of the effects of advertising on sales</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gatignon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="387" to="398" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Informative advertising with differentiated products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Grossman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="81" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consumer learning: Advertising and the ambiguity of product experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hoch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y.-W</forename><surname>Ha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="221" to="233" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competitive reaction and feedback effects based on VARX models of pooled store data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Horvath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S H</forename><surname>Leeflang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Wieringa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wittink</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Res. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="415" to="426" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stability in competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Hotelling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economic J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="1929" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New perspectives and evidence on political communication and campaign effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Iyengar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. Rev. Psych</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="169" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The economic aspects of advertising</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Kaldor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="1950" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Price sensitivity and television advertising exposures: Some empirical findings</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kanetkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Weinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Weiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="359" to="371" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empirical generalizations about the impact of advertising on price sensitivity and price</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kaul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wittink</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3-2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="G151" to="160" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal marketing behavior in oligopoly</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-J</forename><surname>Lambin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Naert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bultez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Marketing Models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lilien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kotler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Moorthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Upper Saddle River, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aggregate advertising models: The state of the art</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D C</forename><surname>Little</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Oper. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="629" to="667" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How T.V. advertising works: A meta-analysis of 389 real world split cable T.V. advertising experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lodish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Abraham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kalmenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Livelsberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Lubetkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stevens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="139" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Industry and Trade A Study of Industrial Technique and Business Organization; and of Their Influences on the Conditions of Various Classes and Nations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Marshall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1919" />
			<publisher>MacMillan and Co</publisher>
			<pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The long-term impact of promotion and advertising on consumer brand choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Mela</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="248" to="261" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Informative advertising and product match</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Meurer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Stahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Indust. Organ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="19" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reliability of tests: A technique using the &quot;regression to the mean&quot; fallacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="93" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The economic consequences of advertising</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="241" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Performance regimes and marketing policy shifts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Pauwels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hanssens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="293" to="311" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The shape of the advertising response function</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Arndt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Advertising Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competitive reactions to advertising and promotion attacks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-B</forename><forename type="middle">E M</forename><surname>Steenkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Nijs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hanssens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Dekimpe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="54" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does advertising lower consumer prices?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Steiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The economics of information</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Stigler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="225" />
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Customized products: A competitive analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Syam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ruan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hess</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="569" to="584" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Effective Advertising Understanding When, How and Why Advertising Works</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<publisher>Sage Publications</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Thousand Oaks, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does TV advertising really affect sales? The role of measures, models and data aggregation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Weiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Advertising</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advertising and competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Telser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="537" to="562" />
			<date type="published" when="1964" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Theory of Industrial Organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tirole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<publisher>Prentice Hall of India</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New Delhi, India</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model of vertical differentiation, brand loyalty, and persuasive advertising</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tremblay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Martins-Filho</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advertising and Differentiated Products</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Baye</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier/JAI Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="221" to="238" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advertising with subjective horizontal and vertical product differentiation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tremblay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Polasky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Indust. Organ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="265" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How advertising works: What do we really know?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Vakratsas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Ambler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="43" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Persuasive advertising and product differentiation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N.-M</forename><surname>Von Der Fehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Stevik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Southern Econom. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="126" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A laboratory experiment of individual attitude response to advertising exposure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Winter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="130" to="140" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attitudinal effects of mere exposure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Zajonc</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Personality Soc. Psych</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
