<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Consumer Protection on Kickstarter</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2020-01-17">January 17, 2020</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Blaseg</surname></persName>
							<email>daniel.blaseg@esade.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Strategy and General Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Universitat Ramon Llull</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">ESADE</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08172</postCode>
									<settlement>Sant Cugat-Barcelona</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Schulze</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Finance &amp; Management</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>60322</postCode>
									<settlement>Frankfurt, Frankfurt am Main</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Bernd</forename><surname>Skiera</surname></persName>
							<email>skiera@skiera.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Economics and Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Goethe University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>60629</postCode>
									<settlement>Frankfurt, Frankfurt am Main</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">Deakin University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Consumer Protection on Kickstarter</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 (print)</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2020-01-17">January 17, 2020</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.2019.1203</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: September 23, 2018 Revised: June 6, 2019; September 27, 2019 Accepted: September 27, 2019 History: Avi Goldfarb served as the senior editor and Dina Mayzlin served as associate editor for this article. This paper has been accepted for the Marketing Science Special Issue on Consumer Protection.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:30+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>kickstarter</term>
					<term>crowdfunding</term>
					<term>consumer protection</term>
					<term>self-regulation</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>I FEEL CHEATED and LIED to. They promised retail price no less than $9 after Kickstarter but you can buy them on their website for $5. I thought Kickstarters were getting a special deal.</p><p>-M. A., backer of the Brimstone campaign</p><p>The project funded with KS backers being promised savings off retail of up to $1500. Yet they are actually selling them right now for $1000 LESS than Kickstarter backers paid 2 years ago! -J. S., backer of the Scrooser campaign Reward-based crowdfunding is no longer a niche phenomenon. In the past decade, more than 75 million backers have pledged more than $10 billion on <ref type="bibr">Kickstarter, Indiegogo, and</ref> GoFundMe. Yet despite their reach, size, and age, crowdfunding platforms still resemble more of a "wild west" environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Leamy 2018</ref>) than a maturing industry. The broad absence of regulation in such a sizeable market over a rather long period of time provides an interesting research setting for studying consumer protection.</p><p>In this article, we investigate consumer protection on Kickstarter, focusing specifically on price advertising claims (PACs). PACs are a form of advertising used in the sale of products whereby current prices are compared with a suggested reference price such as former prices, retail prices, or suggested prices by manufacturers (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Compeau and Grewal 1998</ref> for a review and metaanalysis of the literature). Regulators such as the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) have promulgated specific guidelines to determine the conditions under which a PAC is deceptive and causes economic injury to consumers. For example, if a seller makes a PAC such as "Sold for $25 only today, 50% off the regular retail price," regulation requires an immediate price increase after the end of the promotion (for example, Code. Mass. Law, 940 C.M.R. §6.05), an actual price increase to the stated amount (for example, FTC 16 C.F.R. Part 233), and maintenance of the stated amount for a reasonable time (Better Business Bureau Code of Advertising §9.4).</p><p>On Kickstarter, a campaign might ask consumers to pay $70 to receive a product they promise will later have a price of $140. The key question is as follows: "Do consumers actually get the price advantage that was promised or do they incur economic injury because they did not?" In the example in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>, consumers on Amazon ended up paying a retail price of $59.99 upon product launch-57% less than what was promised ($140) and even 14% less than what consumers on Kickstarter actually paid <ref type="bibr">($70)</ref>.</p><p>We focus this article on PACs because PAC regulation is widely applied in the United States and around the world <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Boddewyn 1982)</ref> and because it remains a current topic. For example, broken PAC promises resulting in economic injury of only $36 for the plaintiff recently led courts to grant a class action lawsuit that ended up costing offline retailer J.C. Penney $50 million in a settlement (Spann v. J.C. Penney Corp.; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Stempel 2015)</ref>. Still, PAC regulation has not been enforced on Kickstarter thus far.</p><p>Anecdotal evidence regarding PACs-as in the introductory quotes by angry Kickstarter backers or in the example in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>-points toward potential problems. If the anecdotal evidence is indeed indicative of a systematic and unresolved consumer protection problem, it might affect hundreds of thousands of consumers who could incur substantial economic injury from broken PAC promises.</p><p>To analyze consumer protection on Kickstarter systematically, we have compiled an extensive data set. We match the detailed data available on Kickstarter with information from various outside sources:</p><p>• Hand-collected prices from 1,548 webshops, as well as from Amazon, Steam, and price aggregators (e.g., camelcamelcamel and steamprices),</p><p>• Consumer reviews from Amazon and Steam,</p><p>• Official consumer complaints as filed with the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), the Better Business Bureau (BBB), the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), and the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB),</p><p>• Supplementary campaign data on nondelivery of rewards from Kickscammed and from news articles retrieved from CrunchBase,</p><p>• Survey data from 179 managers of successfully funded Kickstarter campaigns and 31 crowdfunding experts.</p><p>In total, we analyze 34,745 Kickstarter campaigns, complete backing histories of 442,185 backers, 4,279,494 consumer comments, 233,701 campaign updates, 1,704 blog articles from <ref type="bibr">Kickstarter,</ref><ref type="bibr">18,</ref><ref type="bibr">488</ref> news articles from 500 publishers (e.g., TechCrunch, Wired), 94,569 consumer reviews, and 4,432 pages of consumer complaints filed with official authorities.</p><p>We use this data to investigate five questions about consumer protection on Kickstarter: (1) Is there a substantial problem with broken PAC promises on Kickstarter? (2) Do consumers care? (3) Did consumers learn to avoid the problem? (4) Did campaign managers take actions that solved the problem? (5) Did Kickstarter take actions that solved the problem?</p><p>Our analyses provide the following main results:</p><p>1. There is a substantial problem with broken PAC promises on Kickstarter. More than 75% of consumers who fund campaigns that use PACs (subsequently referred to as PAC campaigns) on Kickstarter do not receive the promised discounts. The problem is widespread and affects more than 500,000 individual backers. Products from PAC campaigns that are later offered to the public on average command a retail price on product launch that is $45.72 lower than promised by the Kickstarter campaign (the average promised price in these campaigns is $137.34). Even worse, in almost 50% of all cases the retail price is even lower than what backers paid on <ref type="bibr">Kickstarter.</ref> Different from what PAC campaigns promise, their backers pay more, not less, than the retail price. All else equal, backers of campaigns that did not promise a discount (subsequently referred to as NoPAC campaigns) on average Blaseg, Schulze, and Skiera: Consumer Protection on Kickstarter received larger discounts than backers of PAC campaigns. In addition to not receiving the promised discount, consumers who funded campaigns that use (versus do not use) PACs also have a lower likelihood of ever receiving the product, experience longer delivery delays, and receive products of lower objective quality.</p><p>2. Consumers care. All else equal, consumers who fund campaigns that use (versus do not use) PACs on Kickstarter are unhappier, as indicated by lower sentiment in backers' comments on the Kickstarter platform, and have greater probability of filing consumer complaints with the FBI, FTC, BBB, SEC, or CFPB. Also, damaged consumers vote with their feet: consumers that did (versus did not) experience broken PAC promises firsthand are significantly less likely to fund another campaign on <ref type="bibr">Kickstarter.</ref> 3. Consumers did not learn to avoid the problem. We observe no PAC-specific population-level learning: all else equal, campaigns that use (versus do not use) PACs on Kickstarter do not experience a relative decrease in funding likelihood over time. We also do not observe learning for (expert) subpopulations of Kickstarter backers: a surveyed group of crowdfunding experts does not expect PAC campaigns to perform worse regarding savings over the retail price, delivery likelihood, delivery delay, or product quality. Finally, we observe no individual-level learning: PAC campaign backers who experienced damage firsthand do not show a disproportionate decrease in funding likelihood for future PAC campaigns (versus Kickstarter campaigns in general).</p><p>4. Campaign managers did not take actions that solved the problem. Only 13 of our 34,745 Kickstarter campaigns offer voluntary default-contingent signals in the form of money-back guarantees (4 campaigns, 0.01%) or warranties (9 campaigns, 0.03%); 21 campaigns (0.06%) provide default-independent signals such as external certifications via some seal of approval. An industry-wide code of conduct has not been adopted. Hence, there is no discernable sign of self-regulation by campaign managers.</p><p>5. Kickstarter did not take measures that solved the problem. Among the seven major policy updates introduced by Kickstarter between the platform's start in 2009 and the end of 2016, five policy updates protect Kickstarter (i.e., the platform), not the consumer. Among the two policy changes that could help improve consumer protection, the potentially most impactful change (introduction of a "risk and challenges" section and prototype requirements for technology products) was introduced in September 2012. The difference-in-difference-in-differences (DDD) analysis reveals no positive effect of this change on damage from PAC (versus NoPAC) campaigns.</p><p>In summary, we find no evidence of consumer protection "happening automatically," that is, without regulatory intervention, during the observed sixyear period. Instead, the evidence points toward a substantial and persistent problem with broken PAC promises on Kickstarter.</p><p>Our study first and foremost contributes to the fast-growing stream of literature on reward-based crowdfunding (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Kuppuswamy and Bayus 2017a</ref> for a review) as the first to study consumer protection. We explicitly focus on the consequences (rather than the antecedents) of PAC usage, adding to the sparse crowdfunding literature that investigates phenomena after successful funding. Extant articles have mainly focused on phenomena before successful (or unsuccessful) funding of the campaign (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Agrawal et al. 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">, Chan and Parhankangas 2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">, Kuppuswamy and Bayus 2017b</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">, Younkin and Kuppuswamy 2017</ref>. Only three articles look at what happens after campaign funding. <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Mollick (2014)</ref> examines delays in delivery, <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Roma et al. (2017)</ref> investigate how crowdfunding performance attracts professional investors, and Viotto da Cruz (2018) researches crowdfunding as an informational mechanism by linking products' crowd feedback to the probability of market releases. In addition, our research highlights the ongoing relevance of PAC regulation <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Pechmann and Silk 2013)</ref> and speaks more broadly to the widely debated topic of consumer protection in unregulated markets and platform economies <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Lagarde 2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">, Ohlhausen 2015</ref>.</p><p>In the remainder of the article, we detail the setting and available data for our empirical study and discuss the variables of interest. We then detail our identification strategy. Next, we present analyses, modelfree evidence and results along the five questions outlined above, investigating whether there is a substantial problem and whether it matters to consumers, whether consumers learn to avoid the problem, and whether the problem is mitigated by self-regulation by either campaign managers or the Kickstarter platform. We analyze the economic relevance of our findings and conclude with a summary, discussion of implications, and limitations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Data in the Empirical Study</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Data from Kickstarter and Related Websites</head><p>Consumers learn about Kickstarter campaigns via campaign websites that follow a standard format. Campaigns can describe their offerings using text, images, and videos. They specify the price of the "one standard product, unlimited availability" reward and potential other rewards, and inform consumers about the delivery date, shipping options, the identity and experience of the campaign manager, and potential campaign risks. Finally, campaigns must specify their <ref type="bibr">Skiera: Consumer Protection on Kickstarter Marketing Science, 2020, vol. 39, no. 1, pp. 211-233, © 2020 The Author(s)</ref> campaign goal and a campaign end date. If the campaign reaches or surpasses that goal (i.e., the campaign is funded) by the specified date, it receives backers' money and is obliged to deliver the reward. If the campaign does not reach the goal, then Kickstarter will not charge consumers' credit cards. All of this information, as provided by the campaign manager, is publicly available at the start of the campaign and is part of our data.</p><p>In our study, we specifically compare Kickstarter campaigns that use versus do not use PACs. To identify the use of PACs, we employ a rule-based text mining approach on reward descriptions-a popular approach to identifying patterns commonly observed in texts <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Netzer et al. 2012)</ref>. In line with <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Grewal and Compeau (1992)</ref>, we identify two main types: (1) PACs indicating direct potential savings (e.g., "$10 less than retail price" or "20% off retail") and (2) PACs containing a reference price (e.g., "Retail price will be $100"). Based on this information, we determine the promised price in U.S. dollars. Although other rewards might exist (for example, receiving a special or limitededition version of the product, early bird rewards, nontangible philanthropic rewards, or multiple products in a multibuy deal), we focus on the price of the most relevant "one standard product, unlimited availability" reward-the only reward type that is available in all campaigns and to all consumers at any time throughout the funding period, thus enabling us to compare all campaigns.</p><p>Beyond providing information about the campaign, crowdfunding websites offer a means for backers and the campaign manager to interact. The campaign manager can inform backers with updates about the current status and progress. These comments and updates are public and also part of our data.</p><p>Funded campaigns are obliged to deliver the product to backers. However, not all campaigns succeed in their endeavor and either entirely fail to deliver or deliver the product late. Information on (non)delivery is partially available on the Kickstarter platform (e.g., in the comments posted by backers and in the updates by campaign managers). We augment the information on Kickstarter through specialized thirdparty platforms Kickscammed and CrunchBase to assess the delivery status of funded campaigns. Matching of information from third-party websites and Kickstarter is done using campaign names. Based on this procedure, each campaign is categorized as "delivered" (i.e., delivery has been confirmed), "not delivered" (i.e., failure has been announced), or "not delivered yet" (i.e., no confirmed delivery and no announced failure).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Data from Amazon and Steam</head><p>After successfully funded Kickstarter campaigns deliver the rewards to their backers, they often seek to increase their market and sell to a broader set of consumers <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Mollick and</ref><ref type="bibr">Kuppuswamy 2014, Viotto da Cruz 2018)</ref>. The most relevant retail platforms are Steam for games and Amazon for technology products. We identified 361 campaigns that moved on to sell their products on these platforms. We use Steam and Amazon to gather information about consumer reviews of these products. Specifically, we use the Amazon star ratings and the Steam thumbs up/ thumbs down ratings as indicators of product quality. Moreover, we gather retail prices from Amazon and Steam directly, as well as from the websites Steamprices and camelcamelcamel for historical retail prices at launch.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Data from Other Webshops</head><p>Although Amazon and Steam are the most relevant retail platforms for selling Kickstarter games and technology products, many campaigns decide to sell through other, more specialized webshops. To gather pricing data from these pages, we trained four human coders to assess all links provided by campaign managers after the funding period in the campaign's header section to manually gather actual and, if available, historical product prices for the exact product sold in the Kickstarter campaign. In total, we identified 1,548 campaigns that sold their products on webshops other than Amazon and Steam. Each campaign was assessed by two independent coders. A Krippendorf's Alpha of 0.819 indicates an acceptable level of intercoder reliability. In case of disagreements, a final decision was made by a third coder.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.">Data from Consumer Protection Entities</head><p>(FBI, FTC, BBB, SEC, CFPB) For information about official complaints filed by backers of Kickstarter campaigns, we gathered data (requested directly or under the Freedom of Information Act) from the four most relevant consumer protection entities in the United States: the FTC, the BBB, the SEC, and the CFPB. In addition, we requested data from the FBI's Internet Crime Complaint Center for information on fraud related to Kickstarter. We received 4,432 pages of information, which we manually matched with Kickstarter campaign data using the names of campaigns and their campaign managers. Matching revealed that official complaints for 142 of 11,948 successfully financed campaigns (1.19%) were filed with FBI, FTC, BBB, SEC, or CFPB.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5.">Data from Campaign Managers and</head><p>Crowdfunding Experts We conducted an online survey among 179 managers of successfully funded Kickstarter campaigns, which provided insight into campaign managers' motivations for (not) offering PACs, into the effects of PACs Blaseg, Schulze, and Skiera: Consumer Protection on Kickstarter on campaign operations, and into otherwise unobservable campaign characteristics. Moreover, we surveyed 31 crowdfunding experts (academics and practitioners) via structured, face-to-face interviews about their expectations for PAC versus NoPAC campaigns regarding savings, delivery, delay, and product quality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Measures of Interest and Their Links to</head><p>Price Advertising Claims (PACs)</p><p>3.1. Link Between PACs and Promised Savings and Actual Savings The focal measure of interest when investigating consumer protection related to PACs is Promised Savings. Current regulation clearly states that not receiving (part of) the promised discount is considered an economic injury to consumers (for example, Hinojos v. <ref type="bibr">Kohl's Corp.,</ref>. Throughout this article, our use of the term economic injury strictly refers to this well-established legal interpretation. In line with this interpretation, we define Promised Savings = Retail Price / Promised Price -1, measuring the percentage difference between the retail price (found on Amazon, Steam, or other webshops) and the retail price promised to consumers by the Kickstarter campaign. If the promised price was $140, but the retail price turned out to be $59.99, then Promised Savings = $59.99/$140 -1 = -0.57. If Promised Savings takes on a negative value, the consumer did not receive the promised discount and incurred economic injury in the legal sense-we thus consider the PAC promise broken. If Promised Savings ≥ 0, then the Kickstarter campaign kept its PAC promise and brought the product to market at the announced retail price. By definition, NoPAC campaigns do not announce a retail price. We thus use the price paid on Kickstarter instead of the promised price to calculate Promised Savings for these campaigns.</p><p>In addition, we employ a second, more conservative measure for savings. We define Actual Savings = Retail Price / Kickstarter Price -1. Whereas Promised Savings lets us see whether backers of PAC campaigns on Kickstarter saved the promised amount, Actual Savings reveals whether backers on Kickstarter saved any amount at all. If Retail Price is $59.99 and Kickstarter Price is $70, then Actual Savings = $59.99 / $70 -1 = -0.14. The negative value means that backers did not realize any savings over the retail price by buying on Kickstarter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Link Between PACs and Delivery, Delay,</head><p>Product Quality Beyond Promised Savings and Actual Savings, we investigate three additional metrics commonly discussed as campaign outcomes in the crowdfunding literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Belleflamme et al. 2014</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">, Mollick 2014</ref>): Delivery (whether the campaign delivers a product), Delay (time difference between the announced and the actual date of delivery for the product), and Product Quality (consumer ratings for the product). We do not have causal evidence of a link between PAC usage and Delivery, Delay, or Product Quality. We analyze the three metrics because of the suggestive evidence presented below and leave it to future research to investigate the causality of this link further.</p><p>It is a well-established notion in the entrepreneurship literature that financial cushions improve new venture performance, because greater cushions allow ventures to absorb small mistakes and unexpected costs more easily <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Katz and</ref><ref type="bibr">Gartner 1988, Chrisman et al. 1998</ref>). On Kickstarter, PAC campaigns likely have smaller financial cushions than their NoPAC counterparts do. If a campaign decides to include a PAC, the discount it provides to backers reduces the gross margin and thus the financial cushion of the PAC campaign vis-à-vis an otherwise identical NoPAC campaign that does not offer a discount.</p><p>For Kickstarter-specific insights on this topic, we surveyed 179 Kickstarter campaign managers. 1 Many (freeform) comments by campaign managers support the notion that PAC campaigns in particular lack a financial cushion. Campaign managers pinpointed three specific consequences. First, campaigns might fail to deliver anything because they cannot afford to complete production. The managers stated, "Discounts reduce the contribution margin," "Costs turned out to be higher," and in consequence the "Discounted price does not cover production costs." If campaigns lack a financial cushion, they could fail to deliver the product altogether. Second, if campaigns do deliver, they might take longer because managers needed to identify ways to save costs: "Switching to overseas production" and "We had to switch suppliers in order to avoid a massive loss" are common comments that link a lack of financial cushion to delays. Finally, reduced margins might force campaigns to compromise on quality. "You can't produce high quality at low costs," one manager stated. One openly admitted, "We had to cut corners"; other managers reported using lower-quality materials or cheaper, lower-quality partners for production.</p><p>Suggestive evidence in the entrepreneurship literature and from interviews with Kickstarter campaign managers about a potential effect of PAC usage on Delivery, Delay, and Product Quality lead us to include these measures in our empirical study on consumer protection. Still, we focus on Promised Savings as our focal measure. <ref type="bibr">Skiera: Consumer Protection on Kickstarter Marketing Science, 2020, vol. 39, no. 1, pp. 211-233, © 2020</ref> The Author(s)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Terminology: Damage and Economic Injury</head><p>In the empirical analyses, we compare PAC and NoPAC campaigns on Kickstarter. The comparison of PAC versus NoPAC campaigns does not allow us to make statements about the absolute utility backers derive from supporting Kickstarter campaigns visa-vis outside options, such as preorders on Amazon or nonpurchase. It does, however, allow us to compare the relative benefit backers of (unregulated) PAC campaigns derived vis-à-vis Kickstarter backers of NoPAC campaigns. Throughout this article, we use the term damage to describe relative differences in Promised Savings and Actual Savings, Delivery, Delay, and Product Quality between PAC and NoPAC campaigns. Whenever we subsequently report damage experienced by PAC backers, we thus refer to relative damage in comparison with NoPAC backers.</p><p>In contrast, economic injury captures not relative but absolute injury as defined by regulators and enforced by courts. We strictly use the term in its legal sense with Economic Injury = Promised Price -Retail Price (Hinojos v. Kohl's Corporation, No. 11-55793).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Identification</head><p>The assignment of campaigns to the PAC versus NoPAC conditions is not random. As campaign managers make the decision to (not) use PACs before the start of the campaign, we expect that the assignment of PAC versus NoPAC systematically relates to precampaign characteristics. To help identify the effect of PACs in our study, we therefore employ propensity score matching (PSM) based on observable precampaign characteristics. This technique has been widely used in marketing <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Gensler et al. 2012)</ref> to control for potential endogeneity resulting from the nonrandom assignment of treatments. Propensity scores are calculated as the predicted probability that a campaign uses PACs given its observable and statistically significant precampaign characteristics <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Rosenbaum and Rubin 1984)</ref>.</p><p>The key question in using PSM for identification is whether matching on observables captures all relevant factors or whether potentially unobservable factors would alter the results. We will discuss both questions below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Observed Precampaign Characteristics</head><p>In matching PAC and NoPAC campaigns, we consider 20 known drivers of campaigns' funding success derived from the extant literature. These 20 drivers contain all known precampaign characteristics that have been confirmed to affect campaign success on Kickstarter in three or more published studies. Combined, they capture differences in campaign features, campaign quality, team quality, and campaigns' market environment on launch. For our analyses, we test whether these known drivers of campaign success also affect PAC usage. As shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, only 10 of these drivers do, and we subsequently include them in our analyses.</p><p>In addition to the 20 known drivers in the literature, we tested another 7 potential drivers, 3 of which indeed affect PAC usage. For example, we observe that if a campaign is started around a major holiday or sales event (where campaign managers encounter more PACs in the environment), the campaign is more likely to use PACs. In contrast, competition at campaign launch, campaign risk, or innovativeness do not affect PAC usage. We summarize all 27 precampaign characteristics in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> and use all significant drivers of PAC usage in the analyses going forward.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Unobserved Precampaign Characteristics</head><p>The list of 27 potential drivers of PAC usage covers campaign features (e.g., campaign goal, subcategory), campaign quality (e.g., header and body videos, endorsements, innovativeness), team quality (e.g., campaigns launched, credibility, incorporated firm) and market environment (e.g., location, competition, sales week). Still, other unobservable confounds might exist that could bias our results. Most prominently, these might relate to expected product quality, team quality (self-assessed team quality, ability to deliver, deliver on time), and financing characteristics (availability of alternative funding options, likelihood to reach funding goal). To address these points and better understand the data-generating process, we conducted a survey of 179 managers of successfully funded Kickstarter campaigns. Of these, 93 used PACs in their campaign and 86 did not.</p><p>As detailed in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">2</ref>, we asked campaign managers about product and team quality, as well as financing characteristics to uncover potential unobserved differences between PAC and NoPAC campaigns. Survey results provided no indication that PAC and NoPAC campaigns differ significantly along these dimensions in the prelaunch phase. To minimize adverse effects from potential social desirability bias, we designed the survey so that campaign managers were unaware about the study's focus on PACs when they answered the questions in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">2</ref>.</p><p>Moreover, we asked campaign managers about their decision to (not) use PACs in a free-form question. Of these managers, 45% (40 PAC managers and 41 NoPAC managers) did not provide any reason, and another 23% (23 PAC managers and 18 NoPAC managers) considered their choice for or against PACs as the norm ("Common practice on Kickstarter," or "It's not permitted by <ref type="bibr">Kickstarter"</ref>). Only about one-third of all surveyed campaign managers Blaseg, Schulze, and Skiera: Consumer Protection on Kickstarter noted that their choice for or against PAC usage was a deliberate decision. Nineteen percent (19 PAC managers and 15 NoPAC managers) stated that considerations of demand and profitability drove their decision ("To attract more backers," but also "Kickstarter is for early adopters. They are not price sensitive"). The remaining 13% (11 PAC managers and 12 NoPAC managers) provided other reasons, such as concerns about complexity. None of the answers pointed toward additional relevant drivers that are not included in our analyses already.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Potential Bias from Omitted Variables</head><p>The list of observed, considered precampaign characteristics is extensive, and differences between PAC and NoPAC campaigns along these dimensions are small and nonsystematic. In particular, we do not see any indication that PAC campaigns are systematically inferior to NoPAC campaigns, which could support the idea of "PAC usage as a last resort." Moreover, the existence of major differences in unobserved product quality, team quality, or financing characteristics is unlikely, given the answers of 179 campaign managers. Campaign managers' free-form answers also did not point toward additional relevant drivers. Still, it is possible that we do not completely address self-selection and that omitted variables bias our results. We thus investigate the robustness of our results to potential omitted variable bias following three slightly different approaches by <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Altonji et al. (2005)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">González and Miguel (2015)</ref>, and Oster (2019). <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Oster's (2019)</ref> approach to assess potential omitted variable bias is in essence an extension of the procedure of <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Altonji et al. (2005)</ref> to consider (a) the variation of the estimated coefficient of interest (e.g., PAC campaign) through the inclusion of additional covariates, as well as (b) the associated shift in R 2 to assess how sensitive results are to potentially omitted variables (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Oster (2019)</ref> for details and a formal derivation). The key assumption of the approach is that the selection on observable variables is informative about the selection on unobservable ones.</p><p>Following this approach, we calculate an estimate of the bias-adjusted treatment effect of using PACs on our main dependent variable of interest, Promised Savings (as detailed in Section 3.1). In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">3</ref>, we report the coefficient for PAC campaign β without any controls (column (1)) and with all precampaign characteristics as control variables (column (2)). <ref type="bibr">2</ref> In column (3), we report an identified set of parameters on the treatment effect, bounded on one side by the controlled treatment effectβ and on the other by the bias-adjusted effect β * with δ = 1 and R max 1.3R, as proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Oster (2019)</ref>. The identified set excludes zero and the bounds of the identified set are within the confidence interval ofβ, suggesting that the results  from our controlled regressions are robust to omitted variable bias. The calculation of β * is very sensitive to reasonable choices of the maximum R 2 . We thus assess the robustness of our analysis using a more conservative value of R max 0.5 <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(González and Miguel 2015)</ref>. The identified set in column (4) again excludes zero.</p><p>Finally, we calculate the ratio δ (i.e., the degree of proportionality) of the impact of unobserved variables relative to the observed explanatory variables. The degree of proportionality δ indicates how much stronger selection on unobservables (versus selection on observables) has to be for the coefficient of PAC campaign β to equal 0 <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Altonji et al. 2005)</ref>. The value of the δ ratio (column (5)) is well in line with values considered robust in the literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Manchanda et al. 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">, Krauth 2016</ref>) and indicates that any unobserved campaign characteristics would need to be 2.442 times as relevant as all the observed characteristics combined to nullify our results <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Altonji et al. 2005)</ref>. In summary, results from all three analyses consistently suggest that our findings are unlikely to be driven by omitted variables.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.">Propensity Score Matching (PSM) Procedure</head><p>In the subsequent PSM analyses, we apply nearest neighbor matching with caliper, which is preferred when analyzing large samples of untreated observations (NoPAC) relative to the treated group (PAC) <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Caliendo and Kopeinig 2008)</ref>. The method matches each PAC campaign with the NoPAC campaign that has the closest propensity score <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Rosenbaum and Rubin 1984)</ref>. The use of caliper width increases the quality of matching by ensuring that matching occurs only when the absolute difference between the propensity scores of two potentially matched campaigns is reasonably small and less than a predefined caliper distance (ε). In line with the literature, we define the caliper distance as the proportion of the standard deviation of the propensity score (σ P ), calculated as ε 0.25σ P <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Guo and Fraser 2014)</ref>. Results are stable to the use of kernel matching as an alternative technique.</p><p>Although campaigns show significant differences in precampaign characteristics before use of the PSM procedure, the Hotelling test of equal vector means reveals no significant differences between PAC and NoPAC groups after PSM, indicating successful matching <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Cao and Sorescu 2013)</ref>. We provide details on PSM and Hotelling test results in the online appendix.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Results of the Empirical Study</head><p>To investigate whether consumer protection "happened automatically" in the observed six-year period during which PAC regulation was not applied to Kickstarter or whether there is a substantial, persistent, and unresolved problem with broken PAC promises on Kickstarter, we investigate five questions: (1) Is there a substantial problem with broken PAC promises on Kickstarter? (2) Do consumers care? (3) Did consumers learn to avoid the problem? (4) Did campaign managers take measures that solved the problem? (5) Did Kickstarter take measures that solved the problem? We subsequently present our analyses, modelfree evidence, and results regarding each question.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Is There a Substantial Problem with Broken</head><p>PAC Promises on Kickstarter? 5.1.1. Analyses. Our analyses of potentially broken PAC promises focus on Promised Savings as the key measure, which allows us to reliably quantify economic injury. This measure is aligned with current regulation, by which not receiving the full promised discount is considered an injury to consumers <ref type="bibr">(Hinojos v. Kohl's Corporation,</ref>. In addition, we report Actual Savings as a second, more conservative measure for savings. Both Promised Savings and Actual Savings directly link to PACs (see Section 3.1 for details).</p><p>In addition, we report Delivery, Delay, and Product Quality. As noted in Section 3.2, all three measures are potential indirect sources of damage to backers that are commonly discussed in the crowdfunding literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Belleflamme et al. 2014</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">, Mollick 2014</ref>. We define Delivery = 1 if product has been delivered and 0 otherwise. Among both PAC and NoPAC campaigns, failure to deliver a product is not unusual. We are, however, interested in whether the likelihood of delivery is lower for PAC campaigns versus NoPAC campaigns.</p><p>To identify whether a campaign delivered (labeled as known positive) or has announced failure to deliver (known negative), we use text mining on three sources: (1) campaign updates posted on Kickstarter, (2) information from Kickscammed, a public website where users can report crowdfunding campaigns they consider to be scams, and (3) articles on CrunchBase, which provides 18,488 news articles relating to Kickstarter from websites such as Tech-Crunch, Wired, CNet and Gizmodo. We match information from Kickscammed and CrunchBase to the respective campaigns using the campaign names.</p><p>For the classification, we seek to extract information about whether the campaign has started to ship the promised rewards (e.g., "Shipped," or "Delivery started") or has announced failure (e.g., "We failed," or "We stopped work"). If information on successful delivery is available, we define this campaign as delivered (Delivery = 1). To circumvent false announcements, we also require at least one backer to confirm the receipt of the product in the comments. If information on failure is available, we define these campaigns as not delivered (Delivery = 0). If a campaign has not confirmed delivery and has not announced failure to deliver, we classify the campaign as not delivered yet.</p><p>Further, we operationalize Delay = min(Actual Delivery Date -Announced Delivery Date; 0), where delivery delays are measured in days, and early and punctual deliveries are coded as 0. We calculate the delay as the difference between the announced delivery date and the actual date of the shipping announcement (only for campaigns with Delivery = 1). As campaign managers announce shipping dates in a month-year format, we calculate delay based on the last day of the month and regard shipping within the announced month as on time (i.e., Delay = 0).</p><p>We base our measure of Product Quality on reviews from consumers outside the Kickstarter platform. Amazon enables consumers to submit reviews in text form and ratings of products in the form of numerical star ratings (ranging from one to five stars), whereas Steam allows users to submit text reviews and a thumbs-up or thumbs-down recommendation. Average ratings for a product are the average of the number of stars on Amazon and the share of positive recommendations on Steam. We make the rating systems comparable by rescaling the Amazon ratings to a percentage value (= (Average Star Rating -1)/4). We then compare the ratings from PAC and NoPAC campaigns. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The number of observations naturally differs among these five metrics (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>). We are able to observe Promised Savings and Actual Savings for a total of 1,909 4 campaigns (390 PAC campaigns, 20.43%). We observe Product Quality for a total of 361 campaigns (78 PAC campaigns, 21.61%), where the product is sold on either Amazon or Steam on successful completion of the Kickstarter campaign. We observe Delivery for 8,673 campaigns, which either delivered (8,385 campaigns, 96.68%) or officially failed to do so (288 campaigns, 3.32%). <ref type="bibr">5</ref> We observe Delay for all 8,385 campaigns that delivered.</p><p>The following analyses compare PAC campaigns against NoPAC campaigns, rather than against an ideal benchmark. The reason is that Kickstarter backers cannot expect the same experience as buyers in an online store. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Mollick (2014)</ref> has shown that backers should expect delivery delays when funding campaigns on Kickstarter. Because comparing PAC campaigns' Delay against an ideal benchmark of Delay = 0 would be misleading, we use comparable Kickstarter campaigns that do not use PACs (NoPAC) as a more conservative benchmark.</p><p>5.1.2. Model-Free Evidence. Model-free evidence on Promised Savings and Actual Savings (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3</ref>) reveals that PAC campaigns not only fail to deliver the promised discount in 75.9% of all cases (blue bars to the left of the dotted line, left histogram); in 47.2% of all cases, they even fail to deliver any savings at all.</p><p>In comparison, NoPAC campaigns (which by definition do not promise a discount) provide a significantly larger de facto discount to backers on Kickstarter, who pay lower prices than online retail consumers (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">4</ref>).</p><p>In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">4</ref>, we report model-free evidence for all five measures as they differ between NoPAC and PAC campaigns. We observe a significant difference between PAC and NoPAC campaigns across all measures. Promised Savings and Actual Savings are lower, Delivery likelihood is lower, Delay is longer, and Product Quality is lower for PAC (versus NoPAC) campaigns.</p><p>5.1.3. Results. After successful application of PSM (see the online appendix for details), we compare PAC and NoPAC campaigns via a simple t-test for Promised Savings and Actual Savings, Delay, and Product Quality, as well as via χ 2 -test for Delivery. Results for all five measures in this causal analysis confirm the model-free evidence: PAC campaigns have lower savings (promised and actual), lower likelihood of ever delivering the product, and longer delays and lower product quality in case of delivery compared with their NoPAC counterparts (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">5</ref>). The size of the effects is comparable to the model-free evidence.</p><p>5.2. Do Consumers Care? 5.2.1. Analyses. Crowdfunding research typically assumes that backers are maximizing their personal (financial) surplus <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Hu et al. 2015)</ref> and are motivated to support campaigns on Kickstarter because of attractive (and attractively priced) rewards <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Cholakova and Clarysse 2015)</ref>. However, backers might also engage in crowdfunding because the process itself provides them with additional utility (e.g., bringing the product to life) over buying via traditional retail <ref type="bibr">Bayus 2017b, Bitterl and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Schreier 2018)</ref>.</p><p>If backers gain a lot of utility from bringing the product to life, then the objectively measurable damage they incur from PAC (versus NoPAC) campaigns shown in Section 5.1 might not be relevant to them. To establish whether consumers care, we analyze whether backers, in particular PAC backers, react negatively when experiencing damage regarding Promised Savings and Actual Savings, Delivery, Delay, and Product Quality firsthand. To this end, we  compare PAC backers that differ regarding the outcome of their first PAC campaign. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> For the analysis of Promised Savings, for example, we compare backers whose first PAC campaign honored the promised price (no damage) against backers whose first PAC campaign did not and sold the product for less than the promised price at online retailers (damage). If backers care about the five metrics we analyze, then experiencing damage firsthand in any of these dimensions should result in a drop in funding likelihood for future Kickstarter campaigns compared with backers that experienced no damage in that dimension. Our composition of the no-damage control group is conservative, as backers in that group may have experienced other damages that reduce their likelihood to invest in another Kickstarter campaign in the future.</p><p>We base our analyses in this section on the complete backing histories of 442,185 backers-a sizeable subset 7 of all backers in Kickstarter's games and technology categories-and employ PSM to find comparable backers 8 that did versus did not experience damage along each of the five measures on their first PAC campaign.</p><p>Moreover, we investigate whether the damage experienced by backers of PAC campaigns (with backers of NoPAC campaigns as a reference group) is outweighed by countervailing benefits to these backers. If backers experience (unobserved) additional benefits from supporting campaigns using PACs that are not prevalent in NoPAC campaigns and that outweigh the damage experienced by PAC backers that we documented previously, we should observe that backers' sentiment for PAC campaigns is more positive than or identical to backers' sentiment for NoPAC campaigns. Also, we should expect a lower or identical likelihood of official complaints for PAC versus NoPAC campaigns.</p><p>We analyze backer sentiment through backers' comments posted on the campaign website after the end of the funding period. Of 11,948 successfully financed campaigns, 10,818 campaigns (90.54%) received at least one comment. The average number of comments per campaign is 396. We automatically analyzed these comments using Linguistic Inquiry and Word Count (LIWC). Using word counts for a given text, LIWC calculates the proportion of words that match predefined dictionaries for different types, such as positive and negative words. As one of the most popular tools used in social science research to measure emotional expression, the LIWC approach has been applied to a broad range of text categories, including crowdfunding campaign descriptions <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Younkin and Kuppuswamy 2017)</ref>. We base our analysis on the LIWC standardized summary variable of emotional tone, which combines positive and negative sentiment in a single variable scaled from 0 to 1, such that numbers greater than 0.5 suggest a predominantly positive sentiment. We then compare the average sentiment from PAC and NoPAC campaigns. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> We further define Complaint = 1 if a campaign has received official filing of a consumer complaint (with either FBI, FTC, BBB, SEC, or CFPB) and 0 otherwise.  We match 4,432 pages of complaints with all 11,948 successfully financed campaigns in our dataset by using names of campaigns and their campaign managers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.2.">Model-Free Evidence.</head><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">6</ref> shows that backers who experience damage 10 in their first PAC campaign see a (statistically significant) lower likelihood of ever funding another Kickstarter campaign in the games or technology categories when compared against backers who do not experience the same kind of damage. In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">7</ref>, we further report model-free evidence comparing backers' benefits between PAC and NoPAC campaigns. Model-free evidence suggests that backers of PAC campaigns show significantly lower average sentiment scores (i.e., are more negative in their comments) than backers of NoPAC campaigns.</p><p>Complaint rates mirror this finding. In total, we record at least one complaint for 94 NoPAC (0.93% of 10.160 funded NoPAC) and 48 PAC (2.68% of 1.788 funded PAC) campaigns. The likelihood of a PAC campaign backer filing an official complaint is thus substantially greater than for backers of NoPAC campaigns. Notably, we observe no complaints (0.00%) among the 94 PAC campaigns that kept their PAC promises. The relatively low share of campaigns with complaints overall reflects the substantial effort that is required to file such an official complaint <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Raval 2016)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.3.">Results.</head><p>Results after successful matching of PAC backers who do (versus do not) experience damage in their first PAC campaign confirm the model-free evidence. In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">8</ref> we see that damage regarding Promised Savings and Actual Savings, Delivery, Delay, and Product Quality matters to PAC backers. If they experience damage in the respective dimensions, their likelihood of funding another Kickstarter campaign in the games or technology categories drops by up to 90.65%.</p><p>We then compare the matched PAC and NoPAC campaigns regarding backer sentiment (t-test) and complaint likelihood (χ 2 test). Results shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">9</ref> mirror the model-free evidence: backers in PAC campaigns show significantly more negative sentiment in their comments on the campaign websites and are 50% more likely to file an official complaint (mean for PAC campaigns is 0.027; mean for NoPAC campaigns is 0.018 after matching).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.">Did Consumers</head><p>Learn to Avoid the Problem? 5.3.1. Analyses. Literature arguing against the explicit regulation of PACs contends that skeptical consumers will learn to discount PACs and thus protect themselves from deception <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Urbany et al. 1988</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">, Biswas and Blair 1991</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">, Kaufmann et al. 1994</ref>). In markets with high transparency (such as Kickstarter, where all historic transactions and backer comments are public), consumers might learn from past behavior (their own and others') and adapt their behavior and attitudes <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Dellarocas 2003)</ref>. As shown in Section 5.2, damaged consumers learn to avoid Kickstarter campaigns in general-the crucial question is, however, whether they learn to avoid PAC campaigns specifically.</p><p>In the following, we distinguish PAC-specific learning on three different levels: population (i.e., all consumers learn), subpopulation (i.e., groups such   <ref type="bibr">Marketing Science, 2020</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 39, no. 1, pp. 211-233, © 2020</ref> as the more knowledgeable consumers learn), and individual (i.e., consumers that experienced damage firsthand learn).</p><p>• On the population level, PAC-specific learning across all consumers (new and experienced) should be evident in a reduced funding likelihood for PAC campaigns as time progresses because they provide less consumer benefit than NoPAC campaigns.</p><p>• On the subpopulation level, we should see more experienced "crowdfunding experts" expecting greater damage from PAC (versus NoPAC) campaigns.</p><p>• For individual-level learning, we should see damaged (versus nondamaged) PAC campaign backers to show a decrease in the likelihood of funding another PAC campaign that is larger than the decrease in likelihood of funding another campaign on Kickstarter in general.</p><p>For the population-level analysis, we look for a reduction in funding likelihood for PAC campaigns over time. This reduction could be either an absolute reduction in funding likelihood for more recent versus older PAC campaigns (a conservative measure for learning: consumers learn that PAC campaigns are not as good as originally anticipated) or a relative reduction in funding likelihood for recent PAC campaigns compared with recent NoPAC campaigns (where consumers learn that PAC campaigns are less attractive than NoPAC campaigns, akin to a diff-indiff logic).</p><p>In the analysis, we define Recent Campaign = 1 if the campaign started between April and September 2016 and 0 if the campaign started in the same time frame in the year before <ref type="bibr">(April to September 2015)</ref>. Although learning about the economic injury associated with PAC campaigns should occur on a continuous basis given a constant stream of new PAC campaigns, we chose April 2016 as a turning point in our analysis, because it marks the time when the Kickstarter campaign Coolest Cooler failed. Coolest Cooler raised more than $13 million from more than 60,000 backers in 2014, making it one of the most prominent Kickstarter campaigns ever. When the campaign announced it would not deliver a product in April 2016, media coverage was tremendous. Coolest Cooler was a PAC campaign, promising a 38% discount over the retail price. We expect that the highly publicized failure of this PAC campaign added to consumer learning.</p><p>To assess population-level learning, we first compare the funding likelihood of more recent PAC campaigns with the funding likelihood of older PAC campaigns. Second, we compare the change in funding likelihood for recent versus older PAC campaigns against the change in funding likelihood for recent versus older NoPAC campaigns.</p><p>For the subpopulation-level learning analysis, we surveyed 31 crowdfunding experts (academics and practitioners attending a crowdfunding conference in 2016, each of whom backed on average 6.72 campaigns) via structured, face-to-face interviews. Specifically, we were interested in their expectations for PAC versus NoPAC campaigns regarding savings, delivery, delay, and product quality. We collected their answers on a seven-point Likert scale, such that smaller (greater) numbers signified worse (superior) performance of PAC versus NoPAC campaigns. The scale midpoint, 4, thus signified equal expected performance.  For the individual-level learning analysis, we extended the analysis presented in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">8</ref> to include the funding likelihood for future PAC campaigns. For individual-level learning about PACs to occur, the drop in funding likelihood for future PAC campaigns between the two groups (damage versus no damage) needs to be larger than the drop in funding likelihood for future Kickstarter campaigns in general.</p><p>Regulators typically step in unless there is populationlevel learning, in order to make sure that all consumers are protected (which is not the case with subpopulation-level learning) and to make sure that consumers are protected before they themselves experience damage (which is not the case if only individual-level learning is prevalent) (Financial Conduct Authority 2017). Still, we subsequently investigate all three levels.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.2.">Model-Free Evidence.</head><p>In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">10</ref> we report model-free evidence for the funding likelihood of recent and older PAC and NoPAC campaigns. The results show an increase in funding likelihood of PAC campaigns over time, which indicates a lack of PAC-specific consumer learning on the population level. While the increase in funding likelihood for PAC campaigns (0.511 -0.490 = 0.021) is slightly larger than for NoPAC campaigns (0.306 -0.295 = 0.012) in the same period, neither of the increases is statistically significant.</p><p>As previously reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">6</ref>, backers whose first PAC campaign caused damage are less likely to fund another Kickstarter campaign compared with backers whose first campaign caused no damage-indicating that backers care about the damage they experienced firsthand. In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">11</ref>, we present model-free evidence that compares the drops in funding likelihood for Kickstarter campaigns in general versus for PAC campaigns. The drop in funding likelihood for another PAC campaign is never larger than the drop in funding likelihood for Kickstarter campaigns in general. We thus have no indication of PAC-specific individual-level learning from the model-free evidence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.3.">Results.</head><p>For the population-level analysis, we first compare recent and older PAC campaigns after successful PSM. The probit regression in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">12</ref> shows that funding likelihood for these campaigns increases over time (positive coefficient for recent campaigns), offering no indication of PAC-specific consumer learning from this analysis. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> To compare the relative increase in funding likelihood for PAC campaigns over time with those of NoPAC campaigns, we first apply PSM and then follow the format of a diff-in-diff analysis. Please note that we do not claim that NoPAC campaigns are a perfect control group (after all, the failure of Coolest Cooler may have affected the funding likelihood of NoPAC campaigns as well). Results of the analysis confirm the model-free evidence: the difference in funding likelihood of PAC versus NoPAC campaigns is not significant. If anything, the average funding likelihood of matched PAC campaigns has seen a faster increase (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">13</ref>), which would contradict learning about PACs. We thus cannot observe signs of PAC-specific population-level consumer learning in these analyses.</p><p>For the subpopulation-level analysis, we surveyed 31 crowdfunding experts as detailed in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">14</ref>. In line with our previous analyses, we do not find evidence of PAC-specific consumer learning, not even among crowdfunding experts. Experts expect  PAC campaigns to offer greater savings and delivery likelihood. They do not expect differences in delay or product quality between PAC and NoPAC campaigns. Finally, we analyze individual-level learning. Results after PSM confirm the model-free evidence. Backers who experienced damage in their first PAC campaigns show no PAC-specific learning, as the decrease in funding likelihood for PAC campaigns is smaller, not larger, than for Kickstarter campaigns in general (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">15</ref>). Put differently, Kickstarter backers that experienced damage in their first campaign do care about this damage (as evidenced by substantially lower likelihoods of funding another campaign across all five dimensions), but they do not attribute their bad experiences to campaigns' usage of PACs and thus do not specifically avoid funding PAC campaigns in the future.</p><p>In summary, the above analyses examine the same topic from very different angles but provide the same conclusion: we do not see evidence of PAC-specific consumer learning, neither on the population level that is most relevant for regulators nor on the subpopulation or individual level.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4.">Did Campaign Managers Take Measures that</head><p>Solved the Problem? 5.4.1. Analyses. Self-regulation in the context of our study could include private self-regulation, by which an individual enterprise regulates itself independent of others, and industry self-regulation, by which enterprises decide to cooperate with each other and build an industry-level organization that sets rules and standards <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Gunningham and Rees 1997)</ref>. In rewardbased crowdfunding, such an industry-level organization currently does not exist. Because of this lack of industry self-regulation (potentially indicating market participants' lack of interest in addressing consumer protection), we focus on private self-regulation by campaign managers.</p><p>Self-regulation by campaign managers is closely connected to signaling theory, by which enterprises credibly communicate the level of some unobservable element in a transaction by providing an observable signal <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">(Tang et al. 2008</ref>). For such a signal to be effective in a crowdfunding setting, it must be observable by backers and be difficult (or too expensive) to mimic by a low-quality campaign <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Belleflamme et al. 2014</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">, Ahlers et al. 2015</ref>. The literature distinguishes between two types of signals: (1) defaultindependent signals of self-regulation, which involve an upfront expenditure in reputation building that will be forfeited should product quality turn out to be poor, and (2) default-contingent signals of selfregulation, which do not involve any up-front expenditure but place future profits at risk <ref type="bibr">(Rao et al. 1999, Kirmani and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Rao 2000)</ref>.</p><p>On Kickstarter, product quality is de facto unobservable to consumers when they make the decision to fund the campaign. Hence, campaign managers may try to signal credibility and convince consumers with quality assurances. Such self-regulation by campaign managers should be evident in a substantial number of campaigns containing default-independent signals like seal of approval <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">(Tang et al. 2008)</ref> or code of conduct <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Wotruba 1997</ref>) and default-contingent signals like money back guarantee <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Moorthy and Srinivasan 1995)</ref> and warranty <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Kirmani and Rao 2000)</ref>. We identify campaigns using such signals by employing a rule-based text mining approach on campaigns' descriptions and risk sections.   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4</ref> shows that only 21 of 34,745 Kickstarter campaigns (0.06%) in the games and technology categories provide default-independent signals such as external certifications via some seal of approval.</p><p>An industry-wide code of conduct is not adopted. Only 13 campaigns (0.04%) offer voluntary default-contingent signals in the form of money-back guarantees or warranties. We interpret the fact that in total, only 34 of the 34,745 Kickstarter campaigns studied (0.1%) use any of the four signaling devices as indication for the absence of effective self-regulation by campaign managers.</p><p>5.5. Did Kickstarter Take Measures that Solved the Problem? 5.5.1. Analyses. Kickstarter has strong incentives to protect consumer interests in order to maintain a good reputation, in particular with repeat backers. If backers become victims of deceptive behavior, they will be less likely to support further campaigns. More than 70% of all backers active in 2016 had previously funded another Kickstarter campaign. As the platform's long-term viability is dependent on the support of these repeat backers, we might expect to see self-regulation intended to protect consumersevident in a decrease (or even complete mitigation) in damage to PAC backers following acts of selfregulation by the platform.</p><p>We used 1,704 blog posts by Kickstarter to manually identify all major policy changes by Kickstarter since 2009, listed in Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>. Of seven major policy changes identified, five can be classified as selfregulation to benefit the platform (compliance efforts such as renaming of staff picks or change of incorporation; introduction of platform features benefitting campaign managers, such as the launch-now feature). Only two policy changes can be classified as self-regulation to benefit consumers. The first (and smaller) change mandated the introduction of estimated delivery dates in August 2011. The second policy change aimed for increased consumer protection through consumer education and increased requirements for campaign managers.</p><p>Neither of these proconsumer policy changes focuses on campaigns' use of PACs. Hence, we could simply conclude that the absence of such PAC-focused changes already establishes a lack of platform selfregulation in this regard. Still, the second proconsumer policy change implemented by Kickstarter could have an indirect effect on PAC campaigns. Announced in September 2012, the policy change "Kickstarter is not a store" <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Kickstarter 2012</ref>) mandated the inclusion of a "risk and challenges section" and included new guidelines for campaigns in the technology and design categories. Most notably, the policy   <ref type="bibr">Marketing Science, 2020</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 39, no. 1, pp. 211-233, © 2020</ref> prohibited simulations and renderings of the product and included a prototype requirement to protect consumers from misleading campaign statements. The prototype requirement might lead campaigns to form a more accurate assessment of the production costs, production timing, and product features, which could in turn affect retail price (and hence savings), delivery likelihood, and delay, as well as product quality.</p><p>The "Kickstarter is not a store" policy change did not affect PAC campaigns directly, yet it might indirectly improve the (relative) performance of PAC (versus NoPAC) campaigns. Forcing campaigns to create prototypes could lead to greater due diligence before promising retail prices, delivery dates, and product features, which could result in fewer differences between PAC and NoPAC campaigns after the policy's implementation. The policy change affected campaigns in the technology category of our dataset but not in the games category. We thus investigate whether this act of self-regulation by the platform was followed by decreases in damage to consumers in the treated category (technology) compared with the nontreated category (games) and whether the decreases (after policy change versus before) were greater for PAC versus NoPAC campaigns (difference-in-differencein-differences or DDD approach).</p><p>To identify the effect of the policy change on damage to consumers, we employ a model with a three-way-interacted dummy variable <ref type="bibr">(DDD estimator;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Gruber 1994</ref>). The first difference relates to the time of the policy change (before and after September 20, 2012), the second to the category (games or technology), and the third to the use of PACs. We estimate a linear regression for continuous dependent variables (savings, delay, product quality) and a probit regression for the binary dependent variable (delivery), with the three-way-interacted dummy variable as the variable of interest <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Gruber and Poterba 1994)</ref>. In line with previous analyses, we apply PSM to the four groups (defined by time of policy change and treatment) and balance them on precampaign characteristics respectively for PAC and NoPAC campaigns <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(Ravallion and Chen 2005)</ref>. 5.5.2. Model-Free Evidence. In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">16</ref>, we present model-free evidence on how the "Kickstarter is not a store" policy change affected damage to backers for PAC and NoPAC campaigns. Results are mixed. Whereas PAC campaigns improved less than NoPAC campaigns (before versus after the policy change) regarding promised savings, actual savings, and delivery likelihood, they developed more positively than NoPAC campaigns with respect to delay and product quality. 5.5.3. Results. We present the results of the five DDD regressions after successful PSM in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">17</ref>. The DDD estimator is not significant in any of the five analyses. As such, the findings of the formal analysis do not confirm the model-free evidence, which pointed to some positive and some negative changes for backers of PAC campaigns. From the analyses, we conclude that backers of PAC campaigns in the technology category did not benefit disproportionally from the "Kickstarter is not a store" policy change, vis-à-vis backers in NoPAC campaigns in the technology category. Given that the policy change did not specifically address PACs, this finding is not surprising. Instead, we regard this as additional evidence of the absence of effective platform self-regulation to protect consumers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Economic Relevance of Broken PAC Promises</head><p>Broken PAC promises are a substantial and persistent problem, but how big is their economic relevance? As only a fraction of campaigns actually use PACs and some of them keep their PAC promises, one might wonder whether PACs really pose a relevant consumer protection challenge in reward-based crowdfunding. We therefore analyze the impact of broken PAC promises along three dimensions: number of affected campaigns, number of affected consumers, and economic injury incurred by consumers.</p><p>Our analyses show that between 2009 and 2016, 296 different PAC campaigns have broken their PAC promises-75.9% of all 390 PAC campaigns that moved on to sell their product to the public. We thus conclude that the problem is widespread and not limited to a few black sheep.</p><p>In total, 569,507 backers invested in these campaigns, suggesting that the problem affects a substantial number of consumers. Because of broken PAC promises, these consumers experienced an average economic injury 12 of $45.72 per backer. Class action lawsuits fighting broken PAC promises have been granted (and won) on the basis of much smaller injuries in the recent past (e.g., $36.03 in Spann v. J.C. Penney Corp.; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Stempel 2015)</ref>. Because the problem is unresolved, consumers continue to pledge money in Kickstarter campaigns that use PACs. These consumers' average expected economic injury from a lack of promised savings is $14.85 13 -a conservative estimate, which takes into account that some PAC campaigns keep their promises and that not  all campaigns move on to sell their products to the public (and backers hence do not suffer quantifiable injury). This article focuses on consumer protection relating to PACs. Yet Kickstarter backers are also exposed to other risks-most prominently, the often discussed risk of nondelivery. In comparison with PACs, economic injury from confirmed nondelivery is larger for each affected backer at $87.16 (=the average Kickstarter price for campaigns that have announced failure to deliver). The average expected economic injury for each new backer, however, is only $4.58, as the share of backers that experience nondelivery is rather small. 14 7. Summary and Implications 7.1. Summary Kickstarter backers are currently not protected by regulation pertaining to PACs. A campaign can advertise its product on Kickstarter as "Now only $70, 50% off the retail price" but later sell its product via retailers for less than $140 without legal consequences. Indeed, our analyses show that more than 75% of all games and technology campaigns on Kickstarter that promised a discount broke their PAC promises, leading to an average economic injury of $45.72 per directly affected backer and an average expected economic injury of $14.85 for each backer of PAC campaigns. Even more severely, almost half of all campaigns that promised a discount not only gave a discount that was too low but did not give any discount at all. And to make things worse for backers, the average PAC campaign suffered from a lower likelihood of ever delivering the product, from long delays, and from low product quality. Backers' reactions show that all of these problems are relevant. Backers of PAC campaigns have worse sentiment and higher complaint rates. Backers who experience these damages firsthand display substantial drops in funding likelihood for future Kickstarter campaigns.</p><p>The problem is widespread. We identify 569,507 consumers affected by broken PAC promises in our data, but the 34,745 games and technology campaigns we analyze constitute only 16.5% of all Kickstarter campaigns launched before September 2016. Kickstarter's biggest competitor, Indiegogo, saw another 126,234 campaigns launched in the same time frame. It thus seems likely that many consumers beyond those identified in our study have experienced economic injury from broken PAC promises on crowdfunding platforms.</p><p>Our analyses show that consumer protection does not necessarily "happen automatically" without outside regulatory intervention if given enough time. Instead, the evidence points toward a substantial, persistent, and unresolved problem with broken PAC promises on Kickstarter more than six years after the platform's inception. We arrive at this conclusion after (1) establishing the existence of a substantial problem with broken PAC promises on <ref type="bibr">Kickstarter,</ref><ref type="bibr">(2)</ref> showing that these problems matter to affected consumers, (3) finding no evidence of consumers learning to avoid the problem, and (4) finding no evidence of effective self-regulation by campaign managers or (5) the Kickstarter platform.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2.">Implications</head><p>Our study provides new insights into reward-based crowdfunding. As one of the few articles to investigate phenomena after successful funding, it is the first to study consumer protection. Our study suggests that Kickstarter's current lack of policies to protect backers of PAC campaigns exposes consumers to substantial damage. We observe lower backer sentiment and higher complaint rates across all PAC campaigns, but negative effects from broken PAC promises are not limited to campaigns. Similar to the study of eBay by <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Nosko and Tadelis (2015)</ref>, we observe that backers' negative experiences with specific campaigns spill over to the Kickstarter platform as a whole. Backers who experienced damage in a particular campaign often leave Kickstarter altogether. That Kickstarter has not successfully addressed broken PAC promises thus far not only hurts backers but likely also hurts the Kickstarter brand.</p><p>Beyond Kickstarter, our study provides the first empirical evidence on the primarily theoretical and conceptual literature on self-regulation <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Ranchordas 2015)</ref>. The particular setting of our empirical study lets us reliably quantify the economic injury experienced by consumers <ref type="bibr">(Hinojos v. Kohl's Corporation,</ref> and allows us to observe market participants' behavior in an unregulated setting over a rather long time period. Capitalizing on this setting and using extensive data combining many different angles on the topic, we add to the ongoing high-profile discussion among policy makers <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Ohlhausen 2015</ref><ref type="bibr">, European Commission 2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">, Lagarde 2017</ref>) about consumer protection in unregulated markets. Our results show that regulators cannot always count on consumer learning or on enterprise self-regulation to ensure consumer protection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.3.">Limitations and Future Research</head><p>The empirical setup of this study comes with several limitations. As highlighted in the introduction, this article focuses on the consequences of PAC usage, not on the antecedents. Through our survey of 179 campaign managers, we can rule out many potential antecedents of PAC usage, such as product quality, team quality, or financing options (see Section 4.2 for details). Still, we acknowledge that a deeper Blaseg, Schulze, and Skiera: Consumer Protection on Kickstarter understanding of PAC usage antecedents would be desirable.</p><p>Similarly, we have limited insights into why PAC campaigns break their promises. Our survey of campaign managers provides no evidence of bad intentions (i.e., campaigns intentionally misleading backers). Instead, it seems that different-than-anticipated circumstances after the campaign (i.e., when determining the retail price) leads campaigns to deviate from the price they promised before the start of the campaign. According to the survey, campaigns typically use either cost-or value-based pricing, and with both approaches, they might be better off offering lower-than-promised retail prices. As highlighted in Section 3.2, campaigns that promise discounts to backers typically operate on lower margins. If margin pressure forces the campaign to identify cheaperthan-planned production options, then campaigns that use cost-based pricing will lower their retail price accordingly. At the same time, margin pressure might result in lower-than-planned product quality. If campaigns use value-based pricing, lower product quality will result in lower retail prices. Finally, reference price effects might influence the retail price. As one survey respondent noted, "Once a discount was introduced, we were not able to sell the product at the original price." Future research on the antecedents of PAC usage could provide further valuable insights into the underlying mechanisms at play.</p><p>In the same vein, we provide suggestive but no causal evidence as to why PAC campaigns come with lower delivery likelihood, longer delays, and lower product quality (see Section 3.2). Again, statements by 179 surveyed campaign managers point toward margin pressure and a lack of financial cushion as potential reasons. The identification of the exact causal mechanisms is another interesting topic for future research.</p><p>Finally, while we can quantify economic injury resulting from broken PAC promises in line with current regulatory guidelines, we cannot observe the total utility a consumer derives from backing a Kickstarter campaign. As a result, we must leave the assessment of alternative regulatory scenarios (e.g., existing PAC regulation is applied to Kickstarter or PACs are disallowed on Kickstarter) to future research. the data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Endnotes</head><p>1 We contacted 588 campaign managers via Kickstarter to receive 179 responses (30% response rate). Campaign managers were selected based on the use of PAC (equal proportions of PAC and NoPAC). We further considered the disclosed country as well as the number, success, and category of previous campaigns to create a representative sample of all campaign managers in our data set. We did not provide incentives for answering our questions.</p><p>2 In line with the literature, we use simple ordinary least squares regressions to assess potential omitted variable bias. We consider the derived insights as helpful, even though this simple approach differs from the analyses in our paper, where we carefully match campaigns via PSM using nearest neighbor matching with caliper. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> We control for the robustness of ratings as an indicator of product quality via a standard machine-learning technique and the LIWC dictionary approach to extract the sentiment of the consumer review texts. Results are essentially identical and are available on request. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Observations for Actual Savings and Promised Savings: 5 By the end of September 2016, 3,275 of the 11,948 successfully funded games or technology campaigns on Kickstarter had neither delivered nor officially announced failure. Rather than speculate about whether these campaigns will or will not deliver at a later point in time, we decided to exclude them from our analyses of delivery and focus on campaigns with certain outcomes only (confirmed delivery or announced failure to deliver). Our decision to exclude these campaigns from the analyses does not affect the other four metrics-Promised Savings, Actual Savings, Delay, Quality-as all of these variables mandate the product to have been delivered. At the same time, conditioning on successful delivery results in an important limitation, as all data on Promised Savings and Actual Savings, Delay, and Product Quality is right-censored.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">N</formula><p>6 Backers' first PAC campaign is defined based on the date of (non) successful delivery of the product, not based on the date of successful funding. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> The backer profile pages were publicly disclosed on the Kickstarter campaign pages until February 2016 and are available for all backers with at least one comment in a campaign. We retrieved all information from the publicly available and nondeleted profiles in December 2017.</p><p>Our final dataset includes the full backer history of 442,185 backers with 1,060,700 pledges in 3,297 PAC campaigns and covers on average 58.75% (median: 58.33%) of PAC campaign backers in our dataset. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> We match backers based on their experiences before supporting their first PAC campaign, using the number, categories, success rate, average amount pledged, and currency of previous supported campaigns as well as the number of comments and the time of the first supported campaign. Backers that never supported a PAC campaign are excluded from the analysis.</p><p>samples as input. Results are essentially identical and are available on request. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> We defined damage as follows: for savings, all campaigns that did not adhere to the promised retail price (i.e., the measure is &lt;0); for delivery, all campaigns that did not deliver the product (known failures); for delay, all campaigns that did not keep the promised delivery month; for product quality, all campaigns that have an average rating on Amazon or Steam below the average of all ratings after delivery. 11 As robustness checks, we performed the same analysis comparing recent campaigns (April to September 2016, after "Coolest Cooler") with even older campaigns <ref type="bibr">(April to September 2014</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">, 2012</ref> and results are robust. Alternative estimation methods (probit regressions without year-month fixed effects, χ 2 -test without prior PSM, logistic regression without prior PSM but with precampaign variables as controls) also yield the same findings. All robustness checks are available on request.</p><p>12 To calculate average economic injury per consumer, we first calculate campaign-level economic injury (= difference between promised price and retail price for the campaign * number of backers in the campaign) for each campaign that did not honor promised savings. We then sum campaign-level economic injury across all campaigns and divide by the total number of backers in PAC campaigns that did not honor promised savings. This assessment of economic injury incurred by consumers is in line with current regulatory practices (e.g., Hinojos v. Kohl's Corporation, No. 11-55793).</p><p>13 To calculate average expected economic injury, we divided economic injury across all PAC campaigns by the total number of backers in PAC campaigns.</p><p>14 The calculation of expected economic injury disregards all "not delivered yet" campaigns that have not delivered despite being delayed but that also have not announced failure to deliver. If we assumed that 33% (66%, 100%) of these campaigns will not deliver, the expected economic injury from nondelivery would increase to $7.07 ($9.38, $11.62) per backer.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. (Color online) Example for Use of PACs During Kickstarter Campaign and Lower than Promised Actual Retail Price at Product Launch on Amazon</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. Overview of Number of Available Observations for Analyses of Savings, Delivery, Delay, Product Quality,Complaints, and Sentiment (in Bold Boxes)    </figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3. (Color online) Distribution of Promised and Actual Savings for Campaigns Using Price Advertising Claims (PACs)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4. (Color online) Model-Free Evidence from 34,745 Kickstarter Campaigns on Self-Regulation via Use of Quality Assurance Signals by Campaigns Using Price Advertising Claims (PAC) vs. Campaigns Not Using Price Advertising Claims (NoPAC)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>27 Observable Precampaign Characteristics Tested to Affect Usage of Price Advertising Claims in Kickstarter Campaigns in a Logistic Regression Blaseg, Schulze, and Skiera: Consumer Protection on KickstarterMarketing Science, 2020, vol. 39, no. 1, pp. 211-233, © 2020 </figDesc><table><row><cell>Observable precampaign</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Found to affect</cell></row><row><cell>characteristic</cell><cell></cell><cell>Description</cell><cell>Source</cell><cell>PAC usage</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Known drivers of campaign success</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Campaign features</cell><cell>Reward count</cell><cell>Total number of different reward types</cell><cell>Courtney et al. (2017)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>offered</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Campaign features</cell><cell>Campaign goal</cell><cell>Natural logarithm of fundraising goal</cell><cell>Mollick (2014)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(USD)</cell><cell>amount (USD)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Campaign features</cell><cell>Subcategory</cell><cell>Dummy variables capturing all available</cell><cell>Mollick (2014)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>subcategories on Kickstarter</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Campaign quality</cell><cell>Header video</cell><cell>Dummy variable (1 if campaign has an</cell><cell>Mollick (2014)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>explanatory video, 0 otherwise)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Campaign quality</cell><cell cols="2">Body video count Number of embedded videos in full</cell><cell>Colombo et al. (2015)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>body description</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Campaign quality</cell><cell cols="2">Body length (000) Number of words in full body</cell><cell>Parhankangas and Renko</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>description</cell><cell>(2017)</cell></row><row><cell>Campaign quality</cell><cell>Endorsements</cell><cell>Dummy variable (1 for campaigns that</cell><cell>Calic and Mosakowski</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>were endorsed by tech and games</cell><cell>(2016)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>websites, 0 otherwise)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Team quality</cell><cell>Campaigns</cell><cell>Number of previous technology and</cell><cell>Parhankangas and Renko</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>launched</cell><cell>games campaigns on Kickstarter</cell><cell>(2017)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>started by the campaign manager</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Team quality</cell><cell>Credibility</cell><cell>Dummy variable (1 if campaign includes</cell><cell>Johnson et al. (2018)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>a link to own website, 0 otherwise)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Team quality</cell><cell>Firm</cell><cell>Dummy variable (1 if campaign is</cell><cell>Steigenberger and Wilhelm</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>initiated by a registered entity, 0</cell><cell>(2018)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>otherwise)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Campaign features</cell><cell>Price (USD)</cell><cell>Price of "one standard product,</cell><cell>Hu et al. (2015)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>unlimited availability" reward (USD)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Campaign features</cell><cell>Duration</cell><cell>Number of days for which a campaign</cell><cell>Mollick (2014)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>accepts funding</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Campaign quality</cell><cell cols="2">Spelling mistakes Dummy variable (1 for campaigns that</cell><cell>Mollick (2014)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>include a spelling error in full body</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>description, 0 otherwise)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Campaign quality</cell><cell>Linguistic style</cell><cell>Linguistic cues of full body description</cell><cell>Steigenberger and Wilhelm</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(use of numerical terms, passion,</cell><cell>(2018)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>authenticity, readability)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Team quality</cell><cell cols="2">Work experience Number of work-related words in</cell><cell>Allison et al. (2017)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>biography</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Team quality</cell><cell cols="2">Backer experience Campaign manager's number of</cell><cell>Calic and Mosakowski</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>previously backed campaigns (not</cell><cell>(2016)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>their own) on Kickstarter</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Team quality</cell><cell>Social capital</cell><cell>Dummy variable (1 if campaign includes</cell><cell>Greenberg and Mollick</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>a links to social media sites, 0</cell><cell>(2017)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>otherwise)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Team quality</cell><cell>Ethnicity</cell><cell>Ethnicity based on disclosed name of</cell><cell>Younkin and Kuppuswamy</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>campaign manager</cell><cell>(2017)</cell></row><row><cell>Team quality</cell><cell>Gender</cell><cell>Dummy variable (1 if campaign is</cell><cell>Johnson et al. (2018)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>initiated by a woman, 0 otherwise)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Market environment</cell><cell>Location</cell><cell>Country codes according to the United</cell><cell>Agrawal et al. (2015)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Nations geoscheme</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Additional characteristics</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Campaign features</cell><cell>Delivery time</cell><cell>Difference between end of campaign and</cell><cell>Own analysis</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>announced delivery in days</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Campaign quality</cell><cell>Worldwide</cell><cell>Dummy variable (1 if campaign offered</cell><cell>Own analysis</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>shipping</cell><cell>worldwide shipping, 0 otherwise)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Market environment</cell><cell>Sales week</cell><cell>Dummy variable (1 for campaigns</cell><cell>Own analysis</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>started during a sales week, 0</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>otherwise)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Campaign quality</cell><cell>Innovativeness</cell><cell>Textual analysis (scaled 0-1) of</cell><cell>Bellstam, Bhagat, and</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>campaign descriptions regarding</cell><cell>Cookson (2017)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>innovation topics</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>(Continued)    </figDesc><table><row><cell>Observable precampaign</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Found to affect</cell></row><row><cell>characteristic</cell><cell></cell><cell>Description</cell><cell>Source</cell><cell>PAC usage</cell></row><row><cell>Campaign quality</cell><cell>Risk index</cell><cell>Index (scaled 1-9) of 9 input factors</cell><cell>Madsen and McMullin</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>reflecting project complexity,</cell><cell>(2018)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>information, creator characteristics</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Campaign quality</cell><cell>Risk section word</cell><cell>Number of words in risk section</cell><cell>Own analysis</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>count</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Market environment</cell><cell>Competition</cell><cell>Number of concurrent campaigns on</cell><cell>Own analysis</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Kickstarter</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results of Survey of 179 Kickstarter Campaign Managers Regarding Their Assessment of Own Campaign's Product Quality, Team Quality, and Financing Options Before Campaign Start</figDesc><table><row><cell>Unobservable precampaign characteristic</cell><cell cols="3">PAC (n = 93) NoPAC (n = 86) Difference</cell><cell>Scale</cell></row><row><cell>Product quality</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Expected quality of main product before campaign start</cell><cell>5.39</cell><cell>5.31</cell><cell cols="2">−0.07 n.s. 1 (very low) to 7 (very high)</cell></row><row><cell>Team quality</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Self-assessed quality of team behind campaign</cell><cell>5.47</cell><cell>5.34</cell><cell cols="2">−0.14 n.s. 1 (very weak) to 7 (very strong)</cell></row><row><cell>Confidence in delivering main product to backers</cell><cell>5.05</cell><cell>5.01</cell><cell cols="2">−0.04 n.s. 1 (not confident) to 7 (very confident)</cell></row><row><cell>Confidence in keeping promised delivery date (rather</cell><cell>3.75</cell><cell>3.81</cell><cell cols="2">0.06 n.s. 1 (not confident) to 7 (very confident)</cell></row><row><cell>than deliver late)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Financing</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Confidence in reaching funding goal</cell><cell>5.25</cell><cell>5.38</cell><cell cols="2">0.14 n.s. 1 (not confident) to 7 (very confident)</cell></row><row><cell>Confidence in obtaining funding from other sources</cell><cell>4.01</cell><cell>4.31</cell><cell cols="2">0.30 n.s. 1 (not confident) to 7 (very confident)</cell></row><row><cell>in case of not reaching funding goal</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>n.s. p ≥ 0.10; *p &lt; 0.10; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.Blaseg, Schulze, and Skiera: Consumer Protection on Kickstarter</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Assessment of Potential Omitted Variable Bias Following Oster (2019),Gonzáles and Miguel (2015), and<ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Altonji, Elder, and Taber (2005)</ref> </figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>(1)</cell><cell>(2)</cell><cell>(3)</cell><cell>(4)</cell><cell>(5)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Baseline effecṫ</cell><cell>Controlled effect</cell><cell>Identified set</cell><cell>Identified set</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>β, (SE), [Ṙ]</cell><cell>β, (SE), [R]</cell><cell>[β, β* ′ (min{1.3R, 1}, 1)]</cell><cell>[R max = 0.5]</cell><cell>δ for β = 0</cell></row><row><cell>PAC campaign</cell><cell>−0.374***</cell><cell>−0.396***</cell><cell>[-0.436, -0.396]</cell><cell>[-1.771, -0.396]</cell><cell>2.442</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(0.023) [0.123]</cell><cell>(0.025) [0.161]</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Robust toward</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>3</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>3</cell></row><row><cell>omitted variable bias</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Reference</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Oster (2019)</cell><cell>Gonzáles and Miguel</cell><cell>Altonji, Elder, and</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(2015)</cell><cell>Taber (2005)</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">*p &lt; 0.10; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note> Skiera: Consumer Protection on Kickstarter   Marketing Science, 2020, vol. 39, no. 1, pp. 211-233, © 2020 The Author(s)   </note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc> Skiera: Consumer Protection on Kickstarter   Marketing Science, 2020, vol. 39, no. 1, pp. 211-233, © 2020 The Author(s)   </figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Results of T-and χ 2 -Tests Analyzing Differences in Damage to Backers Between Campaigns Using Price Advertising Claims (PAC) vs. Campaigns Not Using Price Advertising Claims (NoPAC) after Successful Propensity Score Matching</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Campaigns with less beneficial</cell></row><row><cell>After PSM</cell><cell>PAC campaigns</cell><cell>NoPAC campaigns</cell><cell>Difference in means</cell><cell>Observations</cell><cell>outcome for consumers</cell></row><row><cell>Promised Savings</cell><cell>−0.205</cell><cell>0.176</cell><cell>−0.381***</cell><cell>754</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row><row><cell>Actual Savings</cell><cell>0.048</cell><cell>0.176</cell><cell>−0.127***</cell><cell>754</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row><row><cell>Delivery</cell><cell>0.947</cell><cell>0.972</cell><cell>−0.025***</cell><cell>2,850</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row><row><cell>Delay</cell><cell>99.846</cell><cell>84.330</cell><cell>15.516***</cell><cell>2,702</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row><row><cell>Product Quality</cell><cell>0.735</cell><cell>0.802</cell><cell>−0.067**</cell><cell>132</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row></table><note>*p &lt; 0.10; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Model-Free Evidence on Damage to Backers of Campaigns Using Price Advertising Claims (PAC) vs. Campaigns Not Using Price Advertising Claims (NoPAC)</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Campaigns with less beneficial</cell></row><row><cell>Model-free</cell><cell>PAC campaigns</cell><cell>NoPAC campaigns</cell><cell>Difference in means</cell><cell>Observations</cell><cell>outcome for consumers</cell></row><row><cell>Promised Savings</cell><cell>−0.207</cell><cell>0.168</cell><cell>−0.374***</cell><cell>1,909</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row><row><cell>Actual Savings</cell><cell>0.049</cell><cell>0.168</cell><cell>−0.119***</cell><cell>1,909</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row><row><cell>Delivery</cell><cell>0.948</cell><cell>0.971</cell><cell>−0.023***</cell><cell>8,673</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row><row><cell>Delay</cell><cell>99.227</cell><cell>83.076</cell><cell>16.151***</cell><cell>8,385</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row><row><cell>Product Quality</cell><cell>0.709</cell><cell>0.806</cell><cell>−0.097***</cell><cell>361</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">*p &lt; 0.10; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>Blaseg, Schulze, and Skiera: Consumer Protection on Kickstarter</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Model-Free Evidence on Reductions in Funding Likelihood for Another Kickstarter Campaign Among Backers That Experienced Damage vs. No Damage in Their First PAC Campaign</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Drop in funding likelihood</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Model-free</cell><cell>for another campaign</cell><cell>Observations</cell></row><row><cell>Promised Savings</cell><cell>−4.4%***</cell><cell>182,821</cell></row><row><cell>Actual Savings</cell><cell>−12.2%***</cell><cell>191,317</cell></row><row><cell>Delivery</cell><cell>−91.3%***</cell><cell>408,571</cell></row><row><cell>Delay</cell><cell>−6.7%***</cell><cell>399,778</cell></row><row><cell>Product Quality</cell><cell>−29.3%***</cell><cell>87,577</cell></row><row><cell>*p &lt; 0.10; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Model-Free Evidence on Backer Sentiment and Likelihood of Official Complaints for Campaigns Using Price Advertising Claims (PAC) vs. Campaigns Not Using Price Advertising Claims (NoPAC)</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Campaigns with less beneficial</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Model-free PAC campaigns NoPAC campaigns Difference in means Observations</cell><cell>outcome for consumers</cell></row><row><cell>Sentiment</cell><cell>0.557</cell><cell>0.598</cell><cell>−0.041***</cell><cell>10,818</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row><row><cell>Complaint</cell><cell>0.027</cell><cell>0.009</cell><cell>0.018***</cell><cell>11,948</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row></table><note>*p &lt; 0.10; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.Blaseg, Schulze, and Skiera: Consumer Protection on Kickstarter</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Reductions in Funding Likelihood for Another Kickstarter Campaign Among Backers That Experienced Damage vs. No Damage in Their First PAC Campaign; Results After Successful Propensity Score Matching</figDesc><table><row><cell>After PSM</cell><cell>Promised savings</cell><cell>Actual savings</cell><cell>Delivery</cell><cell>Delay</cell><cell>Product quality</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Likelihood of funding another campaign</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Outcome of first PAC campaign</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>No damage</cell><cell>0.529</cell><cell>0.528</cell><cell>0.520</cell><cell>0.589</cell><cell>0.660</cell></row><row><cell>Damage</cell><cell>0.458</cell><cell>0.475</cell><cell>0.049</cell><cell>0.485</cell><cell>0.507</cell></row><row><cell>Drop in funding likelihood</cell><cell>-13.43%***</cell><cell>-10.06%***</cell><cell>-90.65%***</cell><cell>-17.69%***</cell><cell>-23.15%***</cell></row><row><cell>Number of observations</cell><cell>68,400</cell><cell>155,684</cell><cell>17,644</cell><cell>181,210</cell><cell>51,716</cell></row><row><cell>*p &lt; 0.10; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table 9 .</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Results of T-and χ 2 -Tests Analyzing Differences in Backer Sentiment and Likelihood of Official Complaints Between Campaigns Using Price Advertising Claims (PAC) vs. Campaigns Not Using Price Advertising Claims (NoPAC)</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Campaigns with less beneficial</cell></row><row><cell>After PSM</cell><cell>PAC campaigns</cell><cell>NoPAC campaigns</cell><cell>Difference in means</cell><cell>Observations</cell><cell>outcome for consumers</cell></row><row><cell>Sentiment</cell><cell>0.557</cell><cell>0.586</cell><cell>−0.028***</cell><cell>3,372</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row><row><cell>Complaint likelihood</cell><cell>0.027</cell><cell>0.018</cell><cell>0.009*</cell><cell>3,546</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row></table><note>*p &lt; 0.10; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.Blaseg, Schulze, and Skiera: Consumer Protection on Kickstarter</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>Table 10 .</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Model-Free Evidence on Average Funding Likelihood for Recent (April to September 2016) vs. Older (April to September 2015) Campaigns Using Price Advertising Claims (PAC) vs. Not Using Price Advertising Claims (NoPAC)</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">PAC campaigns</cell><cell cols="2">NoPAC campaigns</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Model-free</cell><cell>Older campaigns</cell><cell>Recent campaigns</cell><cell>Older campaigns</cell><cell>Recent campaigns</cell><cell>Observations</cell></row><row><cell>Funding likelihood</cell><cell>0.490</cell><cell>0.511</cell><cell>0.295</cell><cell>0.306</cell><cell>8,215</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12"><head>Table 11 .</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Model-Free Evidence on Reductions in Funding Likelihood for Another Kickstarter Campaign in General vs. Another PAC Campaign Among Backers That Experienced Damage in Their First PAC Campaign Blaseg, Schulze, and Skiera: Consumer Protection on Kickstarter</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Drop in funding likelihood for</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Model-free</cell><cell>Another campaign</cell><cell>Another PAC campaign</cell><cell>PAC-specific consumer learning?</cell><cell>Observations</cell></row><row><cell>Promised Savings</cell><cell>−4.4%</cell><cell>−0.4%</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>182,821</cell></row><row><cell>Actual Savings</cell><cell>−12.2%</cell><cell>−4.3%</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>191,317</cell></row><row><cell>Delivery</cell><cell>−91.3%</cell><cell>−89.3%</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>408,571</cell></row><row><cell>Delay</cell><cell>−6.7%</cell><cell>3.8%</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>399,778</cell></row><row><cell>Product Quality</cell><cell>−29.3%</cell><cell>−11.9%</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>87,577</cell></row></table><note>Note. PAC-specific consumer learning would require the drop in funding likelihood for "Another PAC campaign" to be significantly larger than the drop in funding likelihood for "Another campaign."</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_13"><head>Table 12 .</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Population-Level Learning: Results of Probit Regression Analyzing Differences in Funding Likelihood Between Recent (April to September 2016) vs. Older (April to September 2015) PAC Campaigns After Successful PSM</figDesc><table><row><cell>After PSM</cell><cell>Funding success (only PAC campaigns)</cell></row><row><cell>Recent campaign</cell><cell>1.029**</cell></row><row><cell>Intercept</cell><cell>34.864</cell></row><row><cell>Observations</cell><cell>340</cell></row><row><cell>Pseudo R-squared</cell><cell>0.031</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Note. Year-month fixed effects are included.</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">*p &lt; 0.10; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_14"><head>Table 13 .</head><label>13</label><figDesc>Population-Level Learning: Results of Probit Regression Analyzing Differences in Increase in Funding Likelihood Between Recent (April to September 2016) vs. Older (April to September 2015) PAC Campaigns vs. NoPAC Campaigns After Successful PSM</figDesc><table><row><cell>After PSM</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_15"><head>Table 14 .</head><label>14</label><figDesc>Subpopulation-Level Learning: Results of Expert Survey Regarding Expected Relative Performance of Campaigns Using Price Advertising Claims vs. Campaigns Not Using Price Advertising Claims</figDesc><table><row><cell>Variable</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>SD</cell><cell cols="5">Min p25 p50 p75 Max</cell></row><row><cell>Savings</cell><cell>4.516**</cell><cell>1.180</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>7</cell></row><row><cell>Delivery</cell><cell>4.548**</cell><cell>1.179</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>7</cell></row><row><cell>Delay</cell><cell cols="2">4.097 n.s. 1.326</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>7</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Product Quality 4.000 n.s. 1.211</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>6</cell></row><row><cell cols="8">Notes. Results of structured, face-to-face interviews with 31 crowd-</cell></row><row><cell cols="8">funding experts. Answers are collected on a 7-point Likert scale, such</cell></row><row><cell cols="8">that lower numbers (1-3) signified a worse performance of PAC</cell></row><row><cell cols="8">(versus NoPAC) campaigns, 4 signified no expected difference be-</cell></row><row><cell cols="8">tween PAC and NoPAC campaigns, and higher numbers (5-7) sig-</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">nified a superior performance of PAC (vs. NoPAC) campaigns.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="5">n.s. p ≥ 0.10; *p &lt; 0.10; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_16"><head>Table 15 .</head><label>15</label><figDesc>Individual-Level Learning: Reductions in Funding Likelihood for Another Kickstarter Campaign in General vs. Another Campaign that uses Price Advertising Claims (PACs) Among Backers that Experienced Damage vs. No Damage in their first PAC Campaign; Results after Successful Propensity Score Matching</figDesc><table><row><cell>After PSM</cell><cell cols="2">Promised savings</cell><cell cols="2">Actual savings</cell><cell cols="2">Delivery</cell><cell cols="2">Delay</cell><cell cols="2">Product quality</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Likelihood of funding another</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>PAC</cell><cell></cell><cell>PAC</cell><cell></cell><cell>PAC</cell><cell></cell><cell>PAC</cell><cell></cell><cell>PAC</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Campaign</cell><cell cols="2">campaign Campaign</cell><cell cols="2">campaign Campaign</cell><cell cols="2">campaign Campaign</cell><cell cols="2">campaign Campaign</cell><cell>campaign</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Outcome of first PAC campaign</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>No damage</cell><cell>0.529</cell><cell>0.196</cell><cell>0.528</cell><cell>0.196</cell><cell>0.520</cell><cell>0.196</cell><cell>0.589</cell><cell>0.234</cell><cell>0.660</cell><cell>0.211</cell></row><row><cell>Damage</cell><cell>0.458</cell><cell>0.186</cell><cell>0.475</cell><cell>0.192</cell><cell>0.049</cell><cell>0.026</cell><cell>0.485</cell><cell>0.197</cell><cell>0.507</cell><cell>0.164</cell></row><row><cell>Drop in</cell><cell>-13.43%</cell><cell>-5.23%</cell><cell>-10.06%</cell><cell>-2.28%</cell><cell>-90.65%</cell><cell>-86.86%</cell><cell>-17.69%</cell><cell>-15.66%</cell><cell>-23.15%</cell><cell>-22.48%</cell></row><row><cell>funding</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>likelihood</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Number of</cell><cell cols="2">68,400</cell><cell cols="2">155,684</cell><cell cols="2">17,644</cell><cell cols="2">181,210</cell><cell cols="2">51,716</cell></row><row><cell>observations</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>Note. PAC-specific consumer learning would require the drop in funding likelihood for "Another PAC campaign" to be significantly larger than the drop in funding likelihood for "Another campaign."Blaseg, Schulze, and Skiera: Consumer Protection on Kickstarter</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_17"><head>Table 16 .</head><label>16</label><figDesc>Model-Free Evidence on Damage to Backers of Campaigns Using Price Advertising Claims (PAC) vs. Campaigns Not Using Price Advertising Claims (NoPAC) Before and After the "Kickstarter is not a Store" Policy Change</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Campaigns with greater</cell></row><row><cell>Model-free</cell><cell cols="4">PAC campaigns NoPAC campaigns Difference in means Observations</cell><cell>improvement after policy change</cell></row><row><cell>Change in Promised Savings</cell><cell>−0.319</cell><cell>0.079</cell><cell>−0.398***</cell><cell>771</cell><cell>NoPAC</cell></row><row><cell>Change in Actual Savings</cell><cell>−0.113</cell><cell>0.079</cell><cell>−0.192</cell><cell>771</cell><cell>NoPAC</cell></row><row><cell>Change in Delivery</cell><cell>−0.017</cell><cell>0.021</cell><cell>−0.038</cell><cell>3,099</cell><cell>NoPAC</cell></row><row><cell>Change in Delay</cell><cell>−60.734</cell><cell>−24.215</cell><cell>−36.519*</cell><cell>2,987</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row><row><cell>Change in Product Quality</cell><cell>0.021</cell><cell>−0.056</cell><cell>0.077</cell><cell>203</cell><cell>PAC</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">*p &lt; 0.10; **p &lt; 0.05; ***p &lt; 0.01.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_18"><head>Table 17 .</head><label>17</label><figDesc>Results of Difference-in-Difference-in-Differences (DDD) Analysis After Successful PSM Investigating Effect of Kickstarter's Largest Proconsumer Policy Change on Damage to Backers of Technology PAC Campaigns</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_19"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>NoPAC 1,519 149 + 134 + 1,236; N PAC 390 66 + 12 + 312; N NoPAC 283 149 + 134; N PAC 78 66 + 12; N Total 361 283 + 78.</figDesc><table><row><cell>N Total 1,909 1,519 + 390.</cell></row><row><cell>Observations for Delivery:</cell></row><row><cell>N NoPAC 7,231 213 + 7,018; N PAC 1,442 75 + 1,367;</cell></row><row><cell>N Total 8,673 7,231 + 1,442.</cell></row><row><cell>Observations for Delay:</cell></row><row><cell>N NoPAC 7,018 2,069 + 4,949; N PAC 1,367 217 + 1,150;</cell></row><row><cell>N Total 8,385 7,018 + 1,367.</cell></row><row><cell>Observations for Product Quality:</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">MarketingScience, 2020, vol. 39, no. 1, pp. 211-233, © 2020 </note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">We control for robustness of the LIWC dictionary approach by using a standard machine-learning technique and different training data Blaseg, Schulze, and Skiera: Consumer Protection on KickstarterMarketing Science, 2020, vol. 39, no. 1, pp. 211-233, © 2020 </note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This article is based on the doctoral dissertation of the first author at Goethe University, Frankfurt. The authors are grateful to Senior Editor Avi Goldfarb and the entire anonymous review team for their comments and guidance. The authors thank the many colleagues whose suggestions helped in the development of this manuscript, specifically Christian Catalini. The authors thank Zhuoer Qiu, Shunyao Yan, Yanyao Zhu, and Fatemeh Zare for collecting and coding some of</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"> <ref type="bibr">Marketing Science, 2020</ref><ref type="bibr">, vol. 39, no. 1, pp. 211-233, © 2020</ref> </div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crowdfunding: Geography, social networks, and the timing of investment decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Catalini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Goldfarb</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Management Strategy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="274" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Signaling in equity crowdfunding</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ahlers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Cumming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Guenther</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Schweizer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Entrep. Theory Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="955" to="980" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Persuasion in crowdfunding: An elaboration likelihood model of crowdfunding performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Allison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Webb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Short</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Venturing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="707" to="725" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Selection on observed and unobserved variables: Assessing the effectiveness of Catholic schools</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Altonji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Elder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Taber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="184" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crowdfunding: Tapping the right crowd</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Belleflamme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lambert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Schwienbacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Venturing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="609" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Innovation in mature firms: A text-based analysis. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Bellstam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhagat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cookson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.bbb.org/code-of-advertising#Sales" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-10-21" />
			<pubPlace>Boulder</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Colorado Leeds School of Business</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Better Business Bureau. Code of advertising section 9</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contextual effects of reference prices in retail advertisements</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Biswas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Blair</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When consumers become project backers: The psychological consequences of participation in crowdfunding</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bitterl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schreier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Res. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="673" to="685" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advertising regulation in the 1980s: The underlying global forces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Boddewyn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="35" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Kicking off social entrepreneurship: How a sustainability orientation influences crowdfunding success</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Calic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mosakowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Management Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="738" to="767" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Some practical guidance for the implementation of propensity score matching</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Caliendo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kopeinig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Surveys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="72" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wedded bliss or tainted love? Stock market reactions to the introduction of cobranded products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="939" to="959" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crowdfunding innovative ideas: How incremental and radical innovativeness influence funding outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Csr</forename><surname>Chan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Parhankangas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Entrepreneurship Theory Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="237" to="263" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does the possibility to make equity investments in crowdfunding projects crowd out reward-based investments?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Cholakova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Clarysse</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Entrepreneurship Theory Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="172" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The determinants of new venture performance: An extended model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chrisman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bauerschmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Entrepreneurship Theory Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Internal social capital and the attraction of early contributions in crowdfunding</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Colombo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Franzoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Rossi-Lamastra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Entrepreneurship Theory Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="100" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparative price advertising: An integrative review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Compeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Grewal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Public Policy Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="257" to="273" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Resolving information asymmetry: Signaling, endorsement, and crowdfunding success</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Courtney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dutta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="290" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Entrepreneurship Theory Practice</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The digitization of word of mouth: Promise and challenges of online feedback mechanisms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dellarocas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1407" to="1424" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">FinTech: A more competitive and innovative European financial sector</title>
		<ptr target="https://ec.europa.eu/info/files/2017-fintech-consultation-document_en" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-09-27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="https://www.fca.org.uk/publication/corporate/our-mission-2017.pdf" />
		<title level="m">Financial Conduct Authority</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-09-27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impact of online channel use on customer revenues and costs to serve: Considering product portfolios and self-selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gensler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Leeflang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Skiera</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Res. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="192" to="201" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">War and local collective action in Sierra Leone: A comment on the use of coefficient stability approaches</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>González</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Public Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">128</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="30" to="33" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Activist choice homophily and the crowdfunding of female founders</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Greenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mollick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Admin. Sci. Quart</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="341" to="374" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparative price advertising: Informative or deceptive?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Grewal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Compeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Public Policy Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="52" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The incidence of mandated maternity benefits</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gruber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="622" to="641" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tax incentives and the decision to purchase health insurance: Evidence from the self-employed. Quart</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gruber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Poterba</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="701" to="733" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Industry self-regulation: An institutional perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Gunningham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rees</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law Policy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="363" to="414" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fraser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Propensity Score Analysis: Statistical Methods and Applications</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Thousand Oaks, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>SAGE Publications</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Product and pricing decisions in crowdfunding</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="331" to="345" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A woman&apos;s place is in the. . . startup! Crowdfunder judgments, implicit bias, and the stereotype content model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Stevenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Letwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Venturing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="813" to="831" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Properties of emerging organizations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Gartner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acad. Management Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="429" to="441" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deception in retailer highlow pricing: A &quot;rule of reason&quot; approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kaufmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ortmeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Retailing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="115" to="138" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Kickstarter is not a store</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kickstarter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://kickstarter.com/blog/kickstarter-is-not-a-store" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-09-27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">No pain, no gain: A critical review of the literature on signaling unobservable product quality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kirmani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Schulze</forename><surname>Blaseg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Skiera</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Consumer Protection on Kickstarter</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bounding a linear causal effect using relative correlation restrictions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Krauth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="141" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A review of crowdfunding research and findings</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kuppuswamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bayus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of New Product Development Research</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Golder</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cheltenham, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Edward Elgar Publishers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="361" to="373" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does my contribution to your crowdfunding project matter?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kuppuswamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bayus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Venturing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="72" to="89" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lagarde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://blogs.imf.org/2017/03/21/fintech-a-brave-new-world-for-the-financial-sector/" />
		<title level="m">Fintech: A brave new world for the financial sector? IMFBlog</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-03-21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Backer beware: What to know before you support a crowdfunding product</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Leamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://wapo.st/2pHhzIZ" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Washington Post</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-03-27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Economic consequences of risk and ability disclosures: evidence from crowdfunding. Working paper, University of Minnesota Twin Cities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Madsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mcmullin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<pubPlace>Minneapolis</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social dollars: The economic impact of customer participation in a firm-sponsored online customer community</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Manchanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Packard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pattabhiramaiah</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="367" to="387" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The dynamics of crowdfunding: An exploratory study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mollick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Venturing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">After the campaign: Outcomes of crowdfunding</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mollick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kuppuswamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">UNC Kenan-Flagler Research Paper</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2376997</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>Kenan-Flagler Business School</publisher>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Signaling quality with a money-back guarantee: The role of transaction costs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Moorthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="442" to="466" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mine your own business: Market-structure surveillance through text mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Netzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Goldenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fresko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="521" to="543" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The limits of reputation in platform markets: An empirical analysis and field experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Nosko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tadelis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>No. 20830</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>National Bureau of Economic Research</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">NBER Working Paper</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Three regulatory principles to promote innovation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ohlhausen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://ftc.gov/system/files/documents/public_statements/627591/150302-ppiregreform.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-09-27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unobservable selection and coefficient stability: Theory and evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Oster</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Econom. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="187" to="204" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linguistic style and crowdfunding success among social and commercial entrepreneurs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Parhankangas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Renko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Venturing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Policy and research related to consumer rebates: A Comprehensive review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Pechmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Silk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Public Policy Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="270" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does sharing mean caring? Regulating innovation in the sharing economy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ranchordas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Minnesota J. Law. Sci. Tech</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="413" to="475" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Signaling unobservable product quality through a brand ally</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Qu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ruekert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="258" to="268" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What determines consumer complaining behavior? Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Raval</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<pubPlace>Bureau of Economics, Federal Trade Commission, Washington, DC</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hidden impact? Household saving in response to a poor-area development project</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ravallion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Public Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11-12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2183" to="2204" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From the crowd to the market: The role of reward-based crowdfunding performance in attracting professional investors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Roma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Petruzzelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Perrone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Res. Policy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1606" to="1628" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reducing bias in observational studies using subclassification on the propensity score</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">387</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="516" to="524" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extending signaling theory to rhetorical signals: Evidence from crowdfunding</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Steigenberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wilhelm</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="357" to="546" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Judge certifies class action over JC Penney phantom discounts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Stempel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.reuters.com/article/jcpenney-lawsuit-idUSL1N0YA13M20150519" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-09-27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gaining trust through online privacy protection: Self-regulation, mandatory standards, or caveat emptor</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Management Inform. Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="173" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of plausible and exaggerated reference prices on consumer perceptions and price search</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Urbany</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Bearden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Weilbaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond financing: Crowdfunding as an informational mechanism</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cruz</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Viotto Da</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Venturing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="371" to="393" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Industry self-regulation: A review and extension to a global setting</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wotruba</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Public Policy Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="38" to="54" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The colorblind crowd? Founder race and performance in crowdfunding</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Younkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kuppuswamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2973" to="3468" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Schulze</forename><surname>Blaseg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Skiera</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Consumer Protection on Kickstarter Marketing Science</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="233" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>© 2020 The Author(s</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
