<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Invariant Proportion of Substitution Property (IPS) of Discrete-Choice Models</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Steenburgh</surname></persName>
							<email>tsteenburgh@hbs.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard Business School</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02163</postCode>
									<settlement>Boston</settlement>
									<region>Massachusetts</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Invariant Proportion of Substitution Property (IPS) of Discrete-Choice Models</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 08 2702 0300</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1070.0301</idno>
					<note type="submission">received October 4, 2004, and was with the authors 27 months for 2 revisions;</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:28+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>T his article introduces a newly discovered property of discrete-choice models, which I call the invariant proportion of substitution (IPS). Like the independence from irrelevant alternatives (IIA) property, IPS implies individual behavior that is counterintuitive in the context of choice among similar alternatives. But models that alleviate the concerns raised by IIA, such as generalized extreme value and covariance probit models, do not necessarily alleviate the concerns raised by IPS. I explore the implications of the IPS property on individual behavior in several choice contexts and discuss some models that alleviate the concerns raised by IPS.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Discrete-choice models are widely used in marketing and economics to describe individual choice behavior. Marketing applications range from conjoint experiments, which attempt to understand consumers' preferences for product attributes, to scanner panel studies, which attempt to understand how consumers respond to elements of the marketing mix. Nevertheless, like any model of behavior, discrete-choice models have known limitations. The independence from irrelevant alternatives (IIA) property has been a longstanding concern because it implies that individuals make counterintuitive choices when facing similar alternatives. Many modeling advances have been motivated by a desire to alleviate the concerns raised by IIA and to develop new choice models that allow more realistic behavior to occur; prominent examples include the generalized extreme value (GEV) family of models, which includes the nested logit as a member, and the covariance probit model.</p><p>Given the significant effort devoted to overcoming the limitations of IIA, it is surprising to discover that GEV and covariance probit models possess another property that implies individuals exhibit similarly counterintuitive choice behavior. I call this the invariant proportion of substitution (IPS) property, and I will show that some of the well-known models that alleviate IIA, including GEV and covariance probit models, do not necessarily alleviate IPS.</p><p>Let us begin the present discussion by revisiting the counterintuitive choice behavior implied by the IIA property. Suppose an individual faces a choice between two laptop computers:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Weight</head><p>Processor speed Laptop A 3 lbs. 2.0 GHz Laptop C 7 lbs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">GHz</head><p>Laptop A is the lighter alternative, but it runs at a slower speed. Laptop C is the faster alternative, but it is heavier in weight.</p><p>If a new alternative is added to the choice set, from which of the existing laptops would it draw its choice probability? Intuitively, we would expect the new alternative to draw a greater proportion of its choice probability from a given competing laptop if it is more similar to it because the alternatives are closer substitutes. In the extreme, if the new alternative is identical to Laptop A, we would expect it to draw 100% of its choice probability from Laptop A because the two alternatives are perfect substitutes. In contrast, if the new alternative is identical to Laptop C, we would expect it to draw 0% of its choice probability from Laptop A. The greater principle at work is that the similarity of the new alternative to the existing options should strongly affect the individual's substitution patterns.</p><p>The longstanding critique of models with IIA is that they prevent this type of choice behavior from occurring <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Debreu 1960</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">, Luce and Suppes 1965</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">, Tversky 1972</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">, McFadden 1974</ref>. Instead of allowing the individual's substitution patterns to depend on the similarity of the alternatives, the IIA property </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>301</head><p>requires the new alternative's choice probability to be drawn from each of the existing laptops in proportion to their original choice probabilities. Undesirably, this implies that the proportion of the new alternative's choice probability drawn from a given competing laptop is the same no matter how the new alternative is composed. Many well-known examples illustrate this point, including Beethoven/Debussy <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Debreu 1960</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">, Tversky 1972</ref>, pony/bicycle <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Luce and Suppes 1965)</ref>, and red bus/blue bus <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(McFadden 1974)</ref>. Now, consider a second example, which illustrates the counterintuitive behavior implied by the IPS property. Suppose an individual faces a choice among the following three laptop computers:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Weight</head><p>Processor speed Laptop A 3 lb. 2.0 GHz Laptop B 5 lb. 2.7 GHz Laptop C 7 lb.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">GHz</head><p>Laptops A and C are located in the same positions as before. Laptop B, the target alternative for the sake of this example, is located directly in the middle of the competing alternatives on each attribute; it has moderate speed and moderate weight. How would the individual substitute among the laptops if the target alternative is improved? Intuitively, we would expect a greater proportion of the growth in target alternative's choice probability to be drawn from a given competing laptop if the alternatives become more similar. In this example, reducing Laptop B's weight makes it more similar to Laptop A, but increasing its processor speed makes it less similar. Thus, we would expect a greater proportion of the growth to be drawn from Laptop A (the lightest alternative) if Laptop B is made lighter as opposed to faster.</p><p>Models with IPS, however, prevent this type of choice behavior from occurring. Instead of allowing the individual's substitution patterns to depend on whether the alternatives become more similar, the IPS property requires the growth in the improved good's choice probability to be drawn from each of the competing laptops in the same proportion no matter which attribute is improved. Like the choice behavior implied by IIA, the choice behavior implied by IPS is counterintuitive.</p><p>Let us put some numbers to the example to make it more concrete. Suppose either reducing the target alternative's weight or increasing its processor speed leads to a twenty unit increase in demand in a homogeneous customer segment. Suppose 70% (fourteen units) of the growth is drawn from Laptop A following the weight reduction. We would expect a smaller proportion of the growth, say 30% (six units), to be drawn from Laptop A following the processor speed increase. Nevertheless, it follows from the IPS property that 70% (fourteen units) of the growth must be drawn from Laptop A in this case too.</p><p>One reason the IPS property has been overlooked may be that it does not necessarily hold in aggregate even if it does hold in every subpopulation. Consider a third example, which allows for differences in consumers' tastes. Suppose there are two types of consumers, Salespeople and Scientists. Assume both types of consumers prefer laptops that weigh less and run faster. Nevertheless, suppose Salespeople are twice as responsive as Scientists to weight reductions, and Scientists are twice as responsive as Salespeople to processor speed increases. Suppose if asked to choose between Laptops A and C, a Salesperson chooses A with probability 0.7 and C with probability 0.3, whereas a Scientist chooses A with probability 0.3 and C with probability 0.7.</p><p>Given that Salespeople are twice as responsive as Scientists to weight reductions, if reducing Laptop B's weight leads to a twenty-unit increase in demand among Salespeople, it would lead to a ten unit increase in demand among Scientists. Given that Scientists are twice as responsive as Salespeople to speed increases, if increasing Laptop B's processor speed leads to a twenty-unit increase in demand among Scientists, it would lead to a ten-unit increase in demand among Salespeople.</p><p>How would individuals substitute among the laptops if a new alternative is added to the choice set? Under the multinomial logit model, the choice probabilities imply that Salespeople would draw 70% of the increase in demand from Laptop A and 30% from Laptop C no matter which type of improvement is made to Laptop B. Scientists would draw 70% of their demand from Laptop A and 30% from Laptop C following an improvement to Laptop B. This results in the following substitution patterns for each of the subpopulations: Laptop A −14 units −7 units −3 units −6 units (70%) (70%) (30%) (30%) Laptop B +20 units +10 units +10 units +20 units Laptop C −6 units −3 units −7 units −14 units (30%) (30%) (70%) (70%)</p><p>Central to the present discussion, note that the substitution patterns of neither subpopulation conform to our expectations because the proportion of demand In aggregate, it appears that individuals substitute among the laptops according to our expectations. A greater proportion of demand is drawn from Laptop A, the lightest alternative, if the target alternative becomes more similar to it (57% vs. 43%). Likewise, a greater proportion of demand is drawn from Laptop C, the fastest alternative, if the target alternative becomes more similar to it (57% vs. 43%). Still, we might not be entirely satisfied because models with IPS preclude individual behavior that seems reasonable. For example, the following substitution patterns result in the same aggregate changes in demand but would be precluded by models with the IPS property: Laptop A −11.3 units −4.3 units −5.7 units −8.7 units (57%) (43%) (57%) (43%) Laptop B +20 units +10 units +10 units +20 units Laptop C −8.7 units −5.7 units −4.3 units −11.3 units (43%) (57%) (43%) (57%)</p><p>As before, Salespeople differ from Scientists in their tastes for attributes. Salespeople are more responsive than Scientists to weight reductions, and Scientists are more responsive than Salespeople to processor speed increases. Nevertheless, the substitution patterns of both Salespeople and Scientists also depend on how similar the alternatives become. Both types of individuals draw a greater proportion of the growth in demand away from the lightest laptop when the target alternative becomes lighter as opposed to faster, and they draw a greater proportion of growth from the fastest alternative when the target alternative becomes faster as opposed to lighter. An ideal model would allow both of these substitution patterns to arise.</p><p>The implications of the IPS property are not limited to the context of choice among similar alternatives. Discrete-choice models are also used to study how marketing actions lead to market penetration. In this context, the IPS property implies that the proportion of growth due to market expansion (substitution away from the outside good) does not depend on which of the product's attributes 1 is improved. This also seems undesirable. For example, in a pharmaceutical drug market this would imply that the proportion of growth due to market expansion is the same no matter whether a drug is improved by lowering its risk of fatality, by lowering its price, or by increasing its consumer-directed advertising support.</p><p>The remainder of the article is organized as follows. In §2, I derive the form of the choice probabilities that give rise to IPS from fairly general assumptions about an individual consumer's utility-maximizing behavior; the choice probabilities of GEV and covariance probit models take this form. In §3, I show that the form of the previously derived choice probabilities implies the IPS property and use the nested logit model as an example. In §4, I conclude by discussing how a researcher can allow more flexible substitution patterns to emerge by relaxing the assumptions that lead to the IPS property.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">The Form of the Choice Probabilities</head><p>Let us begin by deriving the form of the choice probabilities from fairly general assumptions about an individual consumer's utility-maximizing behavior. These probabilities represent the researcher's belief about which alternative a consumer will choose from a set of alternatives. The underlying goal is to determine the class of discrete-choice models that possess the IPS property. Because the choice probabilities of GEV and covariance probit models take this form, I will show that these models possess the IPS property. Suppose a consumer faces a choice in which one alternative is to be selected from a set of J alternatives. Assume the consumer chooses the utility-maximizing alternative, but the utility that would be derived from any of the alternatives cannot be observed by the researcher. Denoting the utility derived from alternative j as u j , the decision rule assumed to be governing the individual consumer's behavior is to choose alternative j if and only if u j &gt; u k ∀ k = j.</p><p>Although utility cannot be observed, the researcher does observe a subset of the alternatives' attributes that influence the choice being made, and the component of utility that depends on these attributes is referred to as the representative utility. The representative utility of a given alternative is a function of that alternative's attributes and the consumer's tastes. Let the vector x j denote the observed attributes of alternative j, the vector denote the consumer's tastes, the scalar v j denote the representative utility derived from alternative j, and the function v denote the relationship between the observed attributes and the consumer's tastes v j = v x j In the standard case, the function v is assumed to be linear in the alternative's attributes, such that v j = x j , but this need not be true. Note that the representative utility of any alternative depends only on that alternative's attributes, not the attributes of other alternatives; this assumption is needed to ensure consistency with random utility theory (RUM).</p><p>The utility from alternative j is decomposed as u j = v j + j ∀ j, where j denotes idiosyncratic factors other than the observed attributes that influence utility. These factors may be correlated across alternatives, but j ⊥ x k ∀ j k. Let f denote the joint probability density function of the random vector = 1 J . Conditional on the consumer's tastes, the researcher's belief about whether the consumer will choose alternative j is described by the probability</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">P j = Pr k − j &lt; v j − v k ∀ k = j = I k − j &lt; v j − v k ∀ k = j f d</formula><p>where I denotes the indicator function.</p><p>GEV and covariance probit models arise from different assumptions about the distribution of . For example, under the multinomial logit model (a type of GEV model) the elements of are assumed to be i.i.d. extreme value across alternatives. This leads to choice probabilities with a closed form, but the substitution among alternatives is restricted by the IIA property. Other GEV models and the covariance probit model introduce correlation among the elements of to relax IIA. The random vector is the distributed generalized extreme value under GEV models and distributed multivariate normal with a full variancecovariance matrix under the covariance probit model. The choice probabilities of GEV models have a closed form, but the probabilities of the covariance probit model do not. It is important to note, however, that the choice probabilities under all of these models depend on the attributes of any alternative only through the representative utility of that alternative. In other words, P k depends on x j only through v j ∀ j k. As will become clear in the next section, it is this assumption that leads to the IPS property.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">The IPS Property</head><p>The IPS property represents one of the researcher's implicit assumptions about how an individual consumer will substitute away from competing alternatives if improvements are made to one of the available goods. It is said to hold if the proportion of demand generated by substitution away from a given competing alternative is the same no matter which own-good attribute is improved.</p><p>Definition. Let x ja be attribute a of alternative j. A discrete-choice model is said to possess IPS if and only if − P k / x ja</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">P j / x ja = k/j ∀ a</formula><p>where k/j is a numerical constant for any given k = j. The substitution ratio, − P k / x ja / P j / x ja , represents the proportion of the increase in expected demand for alternative j that is generated by substitution away from alternative k following an improvement to attribute x ja . By specifying a model that possesses IPS, the researcher expresses a belief that the substitution ratio does not depend on which attribute is improved. Since demand gained by one alternative must be drawn from another, the substitution ratios across all competing alternatives must sum to one, that is, ∀ k =j − P k / x ja / P j / x ja = 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Proposition. Suppose a discrete-choice model has the following characteristics:</head><p>1. The representative utility that an individual consumer derives from any alternative depends on the attributes of that alternative alone. v j = v x j ∀ j.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">The choice probabilities depend on the alternatives' attributes only through the representative utilities</head><formula xml:id="formula_2">. P j = g v 1 v J ∀ j. 2</formula><p>Then, the substitution ratio of alternative k into alternative j does not depend on which attribute is improved, − P k / x ja P j / x ja = k/j ∀ a and the discrete-choice model possesses the IPS property.</p><p>Proof. Since the representative utility that the consumer would derive from any alternative depends on the attributes of that alternative alone, v k / x ja = 0 for k = j. Furthermore, since the choice probabilities depend on the alternatives' attributes only through the representative utilities (as opposed to, let us say, through both the representative utilities and the attributes directly), the chain rule implies</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">P k x ja = P k v j • v j x ja ∀ j k</formula><p>Marketing Science 27(2), pp. 300-307, © 2008 INFORMS</p><p>The first term, P k / v j , describes the rate of change in the choice probabilities for a change in representative utility v j . This term does not depend on which attribute is improved. The second term, v j / x ja , describes the rate of change in representative utility v j for a change in attribute x ja . This term does depend on which attribute is improved. Yet, because a change in attribute x ja affects every choice probability only through representative utility v j , this term cancels out of the substitution ratio, leaving − P k / x ja P j / x ja = − P k / v j P j / v j Since the ratio − P k / v j / P j / v j does not depend on a, the discrete-choice model possesses the IPS property. Q.E.D.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>GEV Models</head><p>The GEV family <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(McFadden 1978)</ref> represents a large class of models that allow individuals to exhibit a wide variety of substitution patterns. These models are called generalized extreme value 3 because the unobserved component of the individual's utility is a distributed generalized extreme value, a distribution that allows the unobserved utility to be correlated across alternatives. When all correlations are zero, more complex GEV models become the standard multinomial logit. The multinomial logit <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(McFadden 1974)</ref> and the nested logit <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Ben-Akiva 1973</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">, Williams 1977</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">, McFadden 1978</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">, and Daly and Zachary 1978</ref> are the most widely used GEV models, but Koppelman and Sethi (2000) discuss a number of other models that fall into this class, including the paired combinatorial logit model <ref type="bibr">(Chu 1989, Koppelman and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Wen 2000)</ref>, the cross-nested logit model <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Vovsha 1997)</ref>, the generalized nested logit model <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Wen and Koppelman 2001)</ref>, the generation logit model <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Swait 2001)</ref>, the principles of differentiation model <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bresnahan et al. 1997)</ref>, and the cross-correlated model <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Williams 1977)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Daly and Bierlaire (2006)</ref> provide a general theoretical foundation for GEV models and propose an easy way of generating new models without a need for complicated proofs.</p><p>The choice probabilities of GEV models take the form</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">P j = y j G y 1 y J • G y 1 y J y j</formula><p>where y j ≡ e v j , v j is the representative utility of good j, and the function G satisfies:</p><p>1. G ≥ 0 for all positive values of y j . 2. G is homogeneous of degree one.</p><p>3. G → as y j → for any j.</p><p>4. The cross partial derivatives of G change signs in a particular way. Specifically, G/ y j &gt; 0 for all j;</p><p>2 G/ y j y k &lt; 0 for all j = k; 3 G/ y j y k y l &gt; 0 for all distinct j, k, and l; and so on.</p><p>Given the form of the choice probabilities, the substitution ratio for GEV models is − P k / y j P j / y j = k/j ∀ a (Proof in appendix.) Since the substitution ratio does not depend on which attribute is improved, GEV models possess the IPS property.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Example: Nested Logit</head><p>The nested logit model provides a nice illustration of the IPS property. The choice probabilities and their derivatives take a closed form, so we can analytically determine the substitution ratio. Yet, because the IIA property does not hold across all alternatives and the IPS property does, it is obvious that models that relax IIA do not necessarily also relax IPS.</p><p>Assume the nested logit model. Let the set of J alternatives be divided into M mutually exclusive nests where B m denotes the set of alternatives in nest m. The random vector of unobserved utility is distributed GEV with parameter 0 ≤ m &lt; 1 denoting the correlation among alternatives in nest m. ( m = 0 implies no correlation.) The choice probability of alternative j in nest B m is decomposed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">P j = P B m • P j B m</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">P j B m = e v j / 1− m i∈B m e v i / 1− m P B m = e 1− m I m M l=1 e 1− I I l I l = ln i∈B l e v i / 1− l P j B m</formula><p>is the probability of choosing alternative j given nest B m is chosen; P B m is the probability of choosing nest B m ; and I m is the inclusive value of nest B m .</p><p>The derivative of choice probability P k with respect to representative utility v j is</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">P k v j =                      P j 1− n 1− n P j B n − 1− n P j for k = j ∈ B n −P k 1 − n n P j B n + 1 − n P j for k = j and k j ∈ B n −P k P j for k = j k ∈ B n and j ∈ B m</formula><p>If the representative utility is a linear function of the attributes, as is most common, then the derivative of v j with respect to attribute x ja is a , where a is the coefficient of attribute x ja . This derivative allows the amount of demand that is generated by an improvement to vary across attributes, but it cancels out of the substitution ratio as previously discussed.</p><p>The substitution ratio, which is defined only for k = j, is</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">− P k / x ja P j / x ja =                      P k n P j B n + 1 − n P j P j 1 − n P j B n − 1 − n P j for k j ∈ B n P k 1 − n P j B n − 1 − n P j for k ∈ B n and j ∈ B m</formula><p>Since the substitution ratio does not depend on which attribute is improved, the nested logit model possesses the IPS property. This is to be expected, of course, because the nested logit is a GEV model, but a skeptical reader can verify this fact by directly taking the derivative of P k with respect to x ja .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Discussion</head><p>The implications of the IPS property on consumer behavior extend beyond the context of choice among similar alternatives. For example, many studies (c.f. <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Gupta 1988</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">, Chiang 1991</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">, Chintagunta 1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">, Bucklin et al. 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">, Bell et al. 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">, van Heerde et al. 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">, Steenburgh 2007</ref>) have examined how marketing actions affect consumers' decisions of whether, which, and how much to buy. A key question in these studies is whether a marketing action entices consumers to enter the market (whether to buy) or persuades them to switch brands (which brand to buy).</p><p>Choice models are commonly used to represent this aspect of the consumers' decision. Regardless of whether the model possesses the IPS property or not, the growth in own-good choice due to a marketing action can be decomposed into</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">P j x ja = − P 0 x ja − J k=1 k =j P k x ja</formula><p>where P 0 denotes the probability of choosing the outside good and P k for k = j 0 denotes the probability of choosing competing alternative k. The first term of the decomposition, − P 0 / x ja , measures the growth in the probability of own-good choice due to consumers entering the market, and the second term, − J k=1 k =j P k / x ja , measures the growth stolen from other brands.</p><p>The proportion of growth due to consumers entering the market from marketing action a is measured by the substitution ratio a = − P 0 / x ja P j / x ja to which the following interpretation applies: If marketing action a generates 100 additional purchases for the target good, then a * 100 of those purchases are made by consumers who would have bought nothing and 1 − a * 100 are made by consumers who would have bought another brand.</p><p>The IPS property implies that the proportion of growth due to consumers entering the market is the same no matter what type of marketing action is taken. This seems to be an undesirably strong assumption to make about how consumers behave. It is well known, for example, that advertising effects can spillover to other brands; thus, we might speculate that a greater proportion of the growth in owngood choice is due to consumers entering the market when firms invest in feature advertising as opposed to when they drop price. We would need to specify a model without the IPS property, however, to empirically test whether this is true.</p><p>A universal logit model <ref type="bibr">(McFadden 1975, Koppelman and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Sethi 2000)</ref> might provide a useful solution to this problem. The universal logit allows the representative utility of each alternative to depend on the attributes of competing alternatives in addition to its own attributes. In this example, the representative utility of each brand would depend on the price and advertising levels of competing brands in addition to its own price and advertising levels. Since the terms v k / x ja are no longer restricted to be zero, the term v j / x ja does not cancel out of the substitution ratio; thus, the universal logit model does not possess the IPS property. This generalization is described as the "universal" or "mother" logit because it can be used to approximate all qualitative choice models to any desired degree of accuracy. It is possible to specify the model such that the substitution ratio will vary across marketing instruments.</p><p>In spite of its promise as a flexible model, the universal logit does raise significant concerns. While it may be consistent with RUM in some cases, it is not guaranteed to be consistent in all cases. Further work would need to show when the universal logit satisfies RUM requirements. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Koppelman and Sethi (2000)</ref>, in fact, point out that few examples of the universal logit exist in the literature today and speculate that "This may be due to lack of consistency with [random] utility maximization in some cases, the potential to obtain counterintuitive elasticities, and the complexity of search for a preferred specification <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Ben Akiva 1974)</ref>."</p><p>A different modeling approach may be useful in the context of choice among similar alternatives. The trick in this case is to allow the unobserved utility of any two alternatives to become more correlated as the alternatives become more similar and therefore become closer substitutes. This can be accomplished by relaxing the assumption that the unobserved utility is statistically independent of the alternatives' attributes. For example, consider an error components model in which the unobserved utility is specified as k + x k , where k is a random variable and is a random vector. This results in choice probabilities of the form:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">P j = I k + x k − j + x j &lt; v j − v k ∀ k = j f d d</formula><p>These choice probabilities depend on the alternatives' attributes not only through the individual's representative utilities v j and v k , but also through the terms x j and x k ; thus, the model does not possess the IPS property. Furthermore, as any two alternatives become more similar, their errors become more correlated. By contrast, GEV and covariance probit models assume the correlation between alternatives to be fixed no matter how the alternatives' attributes change.</p><p>Discrete-choice models are undoubtedly useful in their current form, and the implications of the IPS property need to be balanced against many other considerations when specifying a choice model. Nevertheless, the IPS property does imply counterintuitive behavior that may be important to alleviate in some research settings, and the aforementioned models provide the interested researcher with immediate paths to follow. The hope is that further investigation will lead to even more robust choice models in the future. for providing useful comments. Kenneth Train deserves special thanks for several discussions that helped broaden the ideas presented in this article. Of course, the author alone is responsible for all remaining errors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix</head><p>Under GEV models, the choice probabilities take the form</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">P k = y k G y 1 y J • G y 1 y J y k for k = 1 J</formula><p>where y k ≡ e v k and v k is the representative utility of alternative k.</p><p>Since the representative utility of good j is a function of the attributes of only alternative j, the variable y j is a function of the attributes of only alternative j. Thus, y k x ja = 0 for k = j By the chain rule, this leads to P k x ja = P k y j • y j</p><p>x ja ∀ k Thus, the substitution ratio is − P k / x ja P j / x ja = − P k / y j P j / y j • y j / x ja y j / x ja = − P k / y j P j / y j Since the substitution ratio is the same no matter which attribute is improved, GEV models possess the IPS property. Q.E.D.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Steenburgh: The Invariant Proportion of Substitution Property (IPS) of Discrete-Choice Models</figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science 27(2), pp. 300-307, © 2008 INFORMS</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Marketing Science 27(2), pp. 300-307, © 2008 INFORMS drawn from a given competing alternative does not depend on whether the target good becomes more similar to it.Aggregating the changes in demand for Salespeople and Scientists results in the following substitution patterns for the full population:</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Aggregate substitution</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>B becomes</cell><cell>B becomes</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>lighter</cell><cell>faster</cell></row><row><cell>Laptop A</cell><cell>−17 units (57%)</cell><cell>−13 units (43%)</cell></row><row><cell>Laptop B</cell><cell>+30 units</cell><cell>+30 units</cell></row><row><cell>Laptop C</cell><cell>−13 units (43%)</cell><cell>−17 units (57%)</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">Products' attributes are broadly defined to include pricing and marketing investment levels in addition to physical characteristics in these studies.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">This would not be true, for instance, for socio-economic variables that enter the representative utility of every alternative. I thank an anonymous reviewer for suggesting this clarification.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3"> Train (2003, Chapter 3)  provides an excellent overview of GEV models.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The author thanks Andrew Ainslie, Greg Allenby, Jill Avery, David E. Bell, John Gourville, Steve Jordan, Frank S. Koppelman, Jordan Louviere, Elie Ofek, and Luc Wathieu</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The decomposition of promotional response</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Padmanabhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="504" to="526" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The structure of travel demand models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ben-Akiva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Department of Civil Engineering</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">PhD Thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Note on the specification of a logit model with utility functions that include attributes of competing alternatives. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ben-Akiva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Department of Civil Engineering, Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Market segmentation and the sources of rents from innovation: Personal computers in the late 1980s</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Bresnahan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Trajtenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">0</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="S17" to="S44" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determining segmentation in sales response across consumer purchase behaviors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Bucklin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Siddarth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="189" to="197" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A simultaneous approach to the whether, what, and how much to buy questions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="315" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating purchase incidence, brand choice, and purchase quantity decisions of households</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="184" to="208" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A paired combinatorial logit model for travel demand analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Chu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Fifth World Conf. Transportation Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="295" to="309" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Improved multiple choice models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Daly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Zachary</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>D. A. Hensher, Q. Dalvi</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
			<publisher>Saxon House</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="335" to="357" />
			<pubPlace>Sussex, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Determinants of Travel Choice</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A general and operational representation of generalised extreme value models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Daly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bierlaire</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transportation Res. Part B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="305" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Review of R. D. Luce Individual Choice Behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Debreu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="186" to="188" />
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impact of sales promotions on when, what, and how much to buy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="342" to="355" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Closed form discrete choice models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Koppelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Sethi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Transportation Modeling</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hensher</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Button</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Pergamon, Oxford, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="228" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The paired combinatorial logit model: Properties, estimation, and application</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Koppelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C.-H</forename><surname>Wen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transportation Res. Part B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="89" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Preference, utility and subjective probability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Luce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Suppes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Mathematical Psychology</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Luce</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bush</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Galanter</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>III. John Wiley and Sons</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1965" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="249" to="410" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Invariant Proportion of Substitution Property (IPS) of Discrete-Choice Models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Steenburgh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>INFORMS 307</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="300" to="307" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditional logit analysis of qualitative choice behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mcfadden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Econometrics</title>
		<editor>P. Zarembka</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="142" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On independence, structure, and simultaneity in transportation demand analysis. Working Paper 7511, Urban Travel Demand Forecasting Project</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mcfadden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
			<pubPlace>Berkeley, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Institute of Transportation Studies, University of California</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling the choice of residential location</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mcfadden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Spatial Interaction Theory and Planning Models</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Karlqvist</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Lundqvist</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Snickars</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Weibull</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>North Holland</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="96" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Econometric analysis of qualitative response models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mcfadden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbooks of Econometrics</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Griliches</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Intrilligator</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">II</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1396" to="1456" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An application of diagnostic tests for the independence from irrelevance alternatives property of the multinomial logit model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mcfadden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Train</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tye</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transportation Record Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">637</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring consumer and competitive impact with elasticity decompositions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Steenburgh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="636" to="646" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choice set generation within the generalized extreme value family of discrete choice models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Swait</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transportation Res. Part B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="305" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Train</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Discrete Choice Methods with Simulation</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Elimination by aspects: A theory of choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psych. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="281" to="299" />
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is 75% of the sales promotion bump due to brand switching? No, only 33% is</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Heerde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wittink</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="481" to="491" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The cross-nested logit model: Application to mode choice in the Tel-Aviv metropolitan area</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Vovsha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">76th Annual Meeting</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Washington, D.C.</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Transportation Research Board</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Paper 970387</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The generalized nested logit model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C.-H</forename><surname>Wen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Koppelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transportation Res. Part B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="627" to="641" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the formation of travel demand models and the economic evaluation measures of user benefit</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Environment Plann. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="344" />
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
