<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Impact of Survey Participation on Subsequent Customer Behavior: An Empirical Investigation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sharad</forename><surname>Borle</surname></persName>
							<email>sborle@rice.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Jesse H. Jones Graduate School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rice University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>6100 Main Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>77005</postCode>
									<settlement>Houston</settlement>
									<region>Texas</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Utpal</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dholakia</surname></persName>
							<email>dholakia@rice.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Jesse H. Jones Graduate School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rice University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>6100 Main Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>77005</postCode>
									<settlement>Houston</settlement>
									<region>Texas</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Siddharth</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
							<email>sssingh@rice.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Jesse H. Jones Graduate School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rice University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>6100 Main Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>77005</postCode>
									<settlement>Houston</settlement>
									<region>Texas</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Westbrook</surname></persName>
							<email>westbro@rice.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Jesse H. Jones Graduate School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rice University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>6100 Main Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>77005</postCode>
									<settlement>Houston</settlement>
									<region>Texas</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Impact of Survey Participation on Subsequent Customer Behavior: An Empirical Investigation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 07 2605 0711</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1070.0268</idno>
					<note type="submission">received December 21, 2004, and was with the authors 11 months for 3 revisions; processed by Joel Huber.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:25+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>survey research</term>
					<term>customer behavior</term>
					<term>mere measurement effect</term>
					<term>survey participation effect</term>
					<term>hierarchical Bayes</term>
					<term>Conway-Maxwell-Poisson History: This paper was</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>R ecent research studies have shown that, in the aggregate, survey participation is associated with increased purchase behaviors. Whereas selective customer response could be responsible for some of this correlation, we conclude that survey participation does cause changes in purchase behavior. On the basis of this conclusion, we investigate the possible differential impact of participating in a firm-sponsored satisfaction survey on (1) services purchases, (2) responsiveness to promotions, (3) interpurchase time, and (4) spending, across customers. We develop a joint model of these four customer behaviors and explicitly examine the role of customer characteristics and store-specific variables in moderating the effects of survey participation. We also study how these effects change over time.</p><p>The data used for the analysis come from a longitudinal field study of customer satisfaction conducted by a U.S. automotive services firm. It contains two groups of customers. One group was administered a customer satisfaction survey and the other was not. Our results reveal a substantial positive relationship between satisfaction survey participation and all the customer behaviors studied. Assuming a causal relationship, we also find the effects of satisfaction survey participation to vary across customers and stores, and over time.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction and Research Motivation</head><p>Professional marketing researchers tend to think of their work as primarily eliciting customer opinions and as separate from influencing customer opinions or behaviors. Yet a growing number of research studies reveal that such a distinction is, for the most part, an artificial one. They show that even when survey research is conducted without any overt intent to influence customers, it is still associated with significant and broad-based changes in customers' behaviors regarding the firm.</p><p>Research on this issue can be traced to the findings on the mere measurement effect, which revealed that simply asking customers their purchase intentions can significantly change their subsequent purchase behaviors in product categories such as cars and personal computers <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Morwitz et al. 1993)</ref>.</p><p>More recently, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Dholakia and Morwitz (2002;</ref><ref type="bibr">D&amp;M henceforth)</ref> extended this finding to firm-sponsored satisfaction surveys. They conducted a field study of U.S. financial services customers participating in a firm-sponsored telephone-based satisfaction survey, and found that surveyed customers opened significantly more accounts after the survey, were more profitable, and had lower defection rates when compared to a control group of similar customers who had not participated in the survey. The intergroup differences in new account openings, profitability, and loyalty behaviors between the surveyed and the control groups were observable even up to a year after the survey. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Chandon et al. (2004;</ref><ref type="bibr">CMR henceforth)</ref> generalized these findings to online grocery purchases. They conducted their field study with customers of a French online grocer and found that customers who responded to three purchase intentions questions via a telephone survey sponsored by the firm made their first repeat purchase sooner, relative to similar nonparticipants, were more likely to make repeat purchases for up to three months postsurvey and were more profitable to the firm over the course of a ninemonth period. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Prior research has argued that such effects of survey participation occur for two reasons. One reason is that survey participation often induces respondents to form judgments regarding the sponsoring firm and its products or services that they otherwise would <ref type="bibr">Borle, Dholakia, Singh, and Westbrook:</ref> The Impact of Survey Participation on Subsequent Customer Behavior 712 Marketing Science 26(5), pp. 711-726, © 2007 INFORMS not have formed in the absence of survey questioning <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Feldman and Lynch 1988)</ref>. These measurementinduced judgments remain accessible in customers' memories, and influence their postsurvey behavior <ref type="bibr">Williams 2000, Morwitz and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Fitzsimons 2004)</ref>. A second reason is that the survey provides a useful source of information regarding the firm to many customers. It generates positive inferences regarding the firm's customer orientation and responsiveness, and it positively influences postsurvey behaviors <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Dholakia et al. 2005)</ref>. Recently, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Janiszewski and Chandon (2007)</ref> argued that in addition to any effect that attitude accessibility might have, the effect of asking an intention question also serves to make the target behavior more perceptually fluent; this fluency contributes to the mere measurement effect.</p><p>From a practical standpoint, these findings are important, because they suggest that survey-based marketing research projects do not simply incur costs for the sake of gaining insights into customer sperceptions as is conventionally believed, but they might bring in additional revenues through such avenues as increased sales, reduced defection, and other positive behaviors by the respondents. At the same time, these studies also raise a host of interesting and important questions that still remain to be answered. Some of these questions that form the focus of this research are these: Do the effects of survey participation extend to customers' subsequent responsiveness to the firm's promotions? How are these effects affected by customer and store characteristics? How do these effects vary over time?</p><p>Our objective in this paper is to develop and estimate a joint customer behavior model to answer these questions. Such an analysis is important for several reasons: It enhances our understanding of the potential effects of survey participation on a firm's customers. The insights so obtained might allow for a more accurate accounting of the net cost (or gain) of individual customer satisfaction research projects, given a particular composition of respondents. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> In this paper, we consider two types of variables that might help uncover individual differences in susceptibility to survey participation influences: customer characteristics, and characteristics of the firm. First, attributes of the customers themselves could determine the extent to which they are susceptible to the influences of survey participation. We refer to these factors as customer characteristics. They include variables such as the customer's tenure with the firm and the age of his or her car, in addition to conventional demographic variables such as age, gender, household income, and household size.</p><p>Second, firm characteristics are also likely to play a role in how survey participation affects customers subsequently. Because the firm in our study is a national chain store providing automotive services, customers purchase products by visiting the firm's individual stores. Our data set and analysis are also at the individual service-visit level. Consequently, several store-level variables are included in our analysis, such as whether the store was company owned or franchisee owned, whether it had a customer lounge, the number of service bays in the store, and a measure of throughput times at the store.</p><p>Apart from these two types of variables (customer and store characteristics), we also investigate the likely effects of survey participation over time. That is, how long does it take for the survey participation effect to begin wearing off? 3 Finally, in addition to dependent measures related to purchase (number of services purchased, purchase frequency, and amount spent on each visit), we explicitly study the potential impact of survey participation on customers' subsequent promotion responsiveness (number of coupons redeemed).</p><p>Our analysis reveals a number of interesting factors that moderate the likely effects of survey participation on respondents. Some key findings follow: The household size, income, and newness of the customer's vehicle increase the potential impact. The customer's age as well as tenure with the firm diminishes this effect. The company-owned stores gain more (as compared to franchisee-owned stores) from the survey participation effect. We also investigate the time trend in potential impact of survey participation on the four behaviors and find that the likely impact on purchase frequency is much delayed when compared to the effects on other customer behaviors.</p><p>The rest of the paper is organized as follows. In §2, we introduce the data in more depth and then explain the model and discuss the results in § §3 and 4, respectively. Finally, in §5, we discuss the managerial implications of our findings along with some of the limitations of this study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">The Data</head><p>The data come from a large-scale survey, conducted by a leading U.S. automotive services firm, and cover the period from January 2001 to April 2003. This firm has an ongoing survey-based customer satisfaction tracking program; it randomly selects customers for participation in the survey within seven days of a service visit. Customers who participate in the survey do not receive another survey for at least one year after their participation. Of all the customers who participated and responded to the satisfaction survey during the first quarter (January-March) of 2002, a random sample of 3,773 single-automobile 4 active 5 customers was drawn. In the discussion that follows, we refer to these customers as the experimental group. A second random sample of 1,227 single-automobile active customers, who had purchased service at least once during the first quarter of 2002 but were not surveyed by the firm, forms the control group. Thus, we use a total of 5,000 customers (3,773 experimental group and 1,227 control group) in our analysis. Due to the selection of the data sample as described, our conclusions from the study are valid for regular customers only.</p><p>The survey was conducted by telephone; it first identified the firm as the survey's sponsor, and then asked, among others, a question regarding the customer's overall satisfaction with the service visit. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> In the present study, the firm averaged contact response rates in the range of 90%-95% (i.e., 90%-95% of contacted people responded to the survey). 7 However, the firm did not collect data on how many of the customers chosen for the survey it was able to reach. Consultations with the market research vendor and experience with other such studies led us to believe that contact rates were between 60% and 70%, leading to a net response rate (i.e., percentage of chosen customers responding to the survey) between 54% and 67%.</p><p>We gathered detailed behavioral information for these 5,000 customers in our data sample from the firm's database for approximately a year prior to the survey period and a year afterward. This procedure yielded a data set with a total of 35,866 service visits or purchase occasions. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> Since this rate seemed high, we verified this by using data available to us from the last weeks of two recent quarters. We found response rates of 89.9% and 95.3% in these two time periods. This high response rate could be due to the nature of the product involved. Automobiles are high involvement products and expensive to maintain. They form an important part of a person's life, and hence customers might take more interest in the survey directly concerning their vehicle.</p><p>The data consist of four dependent measures of customer behavior: (1) the number of promotions redeemed by a customer on each visit (customers have access to the promotional coupons of the firm through multiple sources 8 and this variable captures the extent to which these promotions are redeemed by them); (2) the number of automotive services purchased on each visit (the firm provides various maintenance services such as brake service, transmission service, oil changes, etc.); (3) time since the last visit in days (interpurchase time); and (4) the amount spent during each visit.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> provides histogram plots of these four dependent measures across the 35,866 service visits. Panels A and B in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> are histograms of the number of promotions redeemed and the number of services bought on each service visit, respectively, while panels C and D are histogram plots of the interpurchase times and the purchase amounts, respectively.</p><p>On a majority of the visits (52.1% of the visits) no promotions are redeemed; if promotions are redeemed, most of the time (44.4%) only a single promotion is redeemed. Multiple promotions are redeemed on fewer than 5% of the service visits. In other words, the variance in number of promotions redeemed across service visits is relatively low. On the other hand, the number of services bought on each occasion (panel B) shows a greater variance. Although a single service is purchased on a majority of the visits (57.5% occasions), buying multiple services is not uncommon; on about 16.4% of the visits, three or more different services were bought by the customer.</p><p>On average, the interpurchase time is 103 days, and the purchase amount on each visit is $42 for the sample (panels C and D in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>). However, as seen in the plots, there is considerable heterogeneity in these measures.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref>(a) contains the summary statistics (mean and standard deviation) for these four dependent measures across four groups: the control group in the periods before and after the survey, and the experimental group before and after the survey.</p><p>Simple tests for differences in means across the groups do not indicate any significant differences between the control and experimental groups in the period prior to the survey on two of the four dependent measures (number of services bought and the purchase amount). For the remaining two dependent measures, there is a significant difference indicating that any modeling effort should control for these differences (which we do, as explained in §3).  Tests 9 to infer the effect of survey done on this aggregate data yield positive survey effects in the interpurchase time behavior (i.e., the interpurchase time decreases postsurvey). However, the tests fail to detect any difference on the other three behaviors. This is at best a partial indication of the existence of the survey effect. The data are a combination of longitudinal and survey data. Thus, they are not generated by a laboratory experiment wherein the researcher can carefully control confounding effects. Therefore, to generate valid inferences, we need to use sophisticated individual level statistical models. This is what we attempt in setting up a model to make inferences from the available data. The model is introduced in §3.</p><p>Apart from these four dependent measures, the data also contained a host of customer and storespecific variables. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref>(b) provides some summary statistics (mean and standard deviation) of the customer-specific variables across the two groups.</p><p>In the next section, we build a joint model for these four dependent measures and introduce customer characteristics and store-specific measures to study the differential impact of survey participation across <ref type="bibr">9</ref> The tests are t-tests for difference in means based on aggregate group data. these four measures of customer behavior in depth.</p><p>Using an individual-level model (as opposed to an aggregate model) becomes important because one of our goals is to also study the differential effects of survey participation across individuals and stores, based on various individual-specific and store-specific characteristics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">The Model</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Model Structure</head><p>We develop a joint model of the number of promotions redeemed (PROM ht , the number of services bought (SERV ht , the time since last purchase Household size 2 6 2 7 0 52 0 47 * The variables "Age," "Median household income," and "Household size" have been estimated from the Block Demographic Trends available for the area of residence of the household.</p><p>(TIME ht , and the dollar amount spent (AMNT ht by customer h on purchase occasion t. The approach followed in building the joint model is to impose distributional assumptions on each of these four dependent variables and then allow a correlation structure across the four distributions.</p><p>The distributional assumptions are as follows:  <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Conway and Maxwell 1961)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> The COM-Poisson is a generalization of the Poisson distribution with an extra parameter that governs decay. The probability mass function of this distribution is as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">PROM ht ∼ CMP 1ht 1 (<label>1</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_1">)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_2">SERV</formula><formula xml:id="formula_3">P z = k=0 k k! −1 z z! z= 0 1 (5)</formula><p>It is a distribution with thicker or thinner tails than the Poisson <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Boatwright et al. 2003</ref>. The Poisson, the Geometric, and the Bernoulli distributions are special cases of the COM-Poisson (with = 1 0, and , respectively). This distribution is defined over positive integers and is flexible in representing a variety of shapes. In particular, it is flexible in accounting for overdispersion as well as underdispersion in the data relative to the Poisson. Although neither the mean nor variance of this <ref type="bibr">10</ref> We model Z ht = SERV ht − 1) so that the domain of Z ht is 0 .</p><p>distribution has convenient closed-form expressions, modern computing overcomes this inconvenience, allowing us to utilize the advantages this distribution offers over simpler discrete distributions. The parameter 1ht 2ht given 1 2 is proportional to the expected number of promotions redeemed (services bought) on each purchase occasion by customer h (from the probability mass function of the COM-Poisson distribution; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Shmueli et al. 2005)</ref>, making it a measure of central tendency.</p><p>The interpurchase time (TIME ht ) and the purchase amount (AMNT ht ) are modeled as log-normal processes (Equations ( <ref type="formula">3</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>)) with ( 3ht 3 ) and 4ht 4 ) as the corresponding parameters (mean and variance, respectively) of the distributions.</p><p>The effects of survey participation and various customer and store-specific variables are introduced by specifying 1ht , 2ht , 3ht , and 4ht as follows: In the above equations, I ht is an indicator variable that takes on a value = 1 if customer h participated in the satisfaction survey and the purchase occasion t was postsurvey participation. In all other cases, I ht takes on value = 0. The variable T ht indexes the purchase occasions (for customer h, purchase occasion t) after the administration of the survey. <ref type="bibr">12</ref> The variables HH m h , m = 1 M are the M customer characteristics and ST n ht , n = 1 N are the N store-specific variables. In our application, we use six customer characteristics and four store-specific variables that are expected to moderate the effects of survey participation on customers. These variables are listed and defined in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">2</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">11 log 1ht = 10h + 11 T ht + M m=1 1m HH m h + N n=1 1n ST n ht + / 10 + / 11 T ht + M m=1 / 1m HH m h + N n=1 / 1n ST n ht I ht + 1 I h (6) log 2ht = 20h + 21 T ht + M m=1 2m HH m h + N n=1 2n ST n ht + / 20 + / 21 T ht + M m=1 / 2m HH m h + N n=1 / 2n ST n ht I ht + 2 I h (7) 3ht = 30h + 31 T ht + M m=1 3m HH m h + N n=1 3n ST n ht + / 30 + / 31 T ht + M m=1 / 3m HH m h + N n=1 / 3n ST n ht I ht + 3 I h (8) 4ht = 40h + 41 T ht + M m=1 4m HH m h + N n=1 4n ST n ht + / 40 + / 41 T ht + M m=1 / 4m HH m h + N n=1 / 4n</formula><p>The customer characteristics and store-specific variables were chosen because they represent potentially important-and from a managerial standpoint, actionable-variables that could moderate the potential impact of survey participation on customers.</p><p>Thus, Equations ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>) through ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) specify the impact of customer characteristics and store-specific variables and the time trend (denoted by T ht ) on the four dependent variables in two ways: First, parameters 1m , 2m , 3m , and 4m where m = 1 6 and parameters 1n , 2n , 3n , and 4n where n = 1 4 specify the impact of the six customer characteristics and the four storespecific variables, respectively, on the overall behavior (as specified by the four dependent measures) in the absence of survey participation, i.e., for the control group, and for the experimental group prior to survey participation. Similarly, the parameters 11 , 21 , 31 , and 41 specify the impact of the time trend (T ht ) on the four dependent variables in the absence of survey participation. Second, parameters where n = 1 4 specify the differential impact of these variables on the overall behavior in the presence of survey participation. Thus we can delineate the contributing impact of a time trend and the customer-and storespecific variables on the effect of participating in the survey. The sum of these sets of parameters would specify the overall impact of the corresponding variables on the four behaviors in the presence of survey participation. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> The remaining parameters in Equations ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>) through ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) are the overall customer-specific intercepts ( 10h , 20h , 30h , and 40h ), the difference in the intercept terms due to survey participation ( / 10 , / 20 , / 30 , <ref type="bibr">12</ref> Thus, for the first purchase occasion of customer h in the period after survey participation T ht = 1, for the second T ht = 2, and so forth. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> For example, the sum * 11 = 11 + / 11 would specify the impact of the first customer characteristic (GENDER h ) on the number of promotions redeemed in the presence of survey participation.  Next, to allow for covariation in the four dependent variables, we introduce a correlation structure across the four equations ((6) through ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>)) as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">0h ∼ MVNormal ¯ 0 (<label>10</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_6">)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_7">where 0h = 10h 20h 30h 40h / ,¯ 0 = ¯ 10 ¯ 20 ¯ 30 ¯ 40</formula><p>/ and is the 4 × 4 variance-covariance matrix. The off-diagonal elements of the matrix specify the structure of covariance across the four variables (i.e., number of promotions redeemed, number of services bought, interpurchase time, and purchase amount). Incorporating such a covariance structure allows for dependencies across the four behaviors and is a more efficient use of information in the data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Model Estimation</head><p>The Bayesian specification of the model (Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">1</ref>) through ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_5">10</ref>)) is completed by assigning appropriate prior distributions on the parameters to be estimated. Appendix 1 lays out the prior distributions used in the analysis. The model is estimated using an MCMC sampling algorithm, details of which can be obtained from the authors on request. The result is a set of posterior distributions on each parameter to be estimated. These posterior distributions are summarized in the next section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">The Estimated Results</head><p>The posterior distributions obtained from the sampling scheme are summarized by their means and standard errors. The following section, along with Appendix 2, 15 interprets and describes the estimated coefficients. The figures in parentheses (in various tables) are the posterior standard deviations. The convergence diagnostics were carried out using the Bayesian Output Analysis (BOA) program Version 0.5.0.</p><p>Before we present and discuss the impact of customer characteristics and store-specific variables on the effects of survey participation, we must point out that, as a validation check (for the existence of the survey participation effect), we also estimated a simpler version of Equations ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>) through ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) with just the customer-specific intercepts, a single coefficient on I ht and I h . In this simpler version, the estimated coefficient on I ht would be a measure of the average effect of survey participation. The signs of these coefficients ratify previous findings such as those of D&amp;M and CMR regarding how survey participation potentially influences customer behaviors. In particular, at the aggregate level, participation in the customer satisfaction survey is associated with an increase in number of promotions redeemed (about 7.4% increase), an increase in number of services bought (a 3.5% increase), a decrease in interpurchase time (a decrease of 4.9%), and an increase in the dollar amounts spent on each occasion (increase of about 5.6%). <ref type="bibr">16</ref> Table <ref type="table">3</ref> contains estimates for the parameters other than the customer characteristics, store, and time trend variables.</p><p>The parameters 1 and 2 are the "decay" parameters of the COM-Poisson distributions (the distribution of number of promotions redeemed and number of services bought, respectively, Equations (1) and ( <ref type="formula">2</ref> The correlation matrix and 2 are significantly different from 1, thus rejecting a Poisson model. Furthermore, 1 is greater than 1 and 2 is less than 1, indicating underdispersion in the distribution of number of promotions redeemed and an overdispersion in the distribution of number of services bought. This demonstrates the added flexibility of the COM-Poisson whereby it can account for both under-and overdispersion observed in the data. It is pertinent to point out here that there are other options to dealing with overdispersion in the data; for example, the NBD distribution is a good candidate for modeling overdispersed data. However, the COM-Poisson has the added flexibility to account for underdispersion as well.</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">PROM</formula><p>The vector ¯ 10 ¯ 20 ¯ 30 ¯ 40 / is the mean of the heterogeneity distribution over the customer-specific intercepts in Equations ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>) through ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>), and the correlation matrix specifies the correlation structure across these intercepts. All the estimated terms of the correlation matrix have intuitive signs, and this lends some robustness and credibility to the estimated model. An interesting phenomenon observed in this matrix is that customers who redeem more promotions tend to be cherry pickers: They buy fewer services (a negative correlation with number of services bought) and spend less money during their visits. The other interesting correlation observed is between the interpurchase time and the purchase amount (8.22%). This implies that customers who spend more take more time to spend; However, the relationship is weak.</p><p>The set of parameters 1 , 2 , 3 , and 4 attempt to control for any selection bias differences between the experimental and the control customer groups; their estimated values indicate that there was no selection  bias with respect to the number of services bought and the total amount spent across the two groups. However, the customer groups do differ in terms of number of promotions redeemed and the interpurchase times, and the parameters 1 and 3 control for this residual difference.</p><p>The finding regarding the positive effect of survey participation on coupon redemption is particularly noteworthy. These results demonstrate-for the first time, to our knowledge-that survey participation is not only associated with increased service purchase and use, as previous studies have found, but also potentially positively affects respondents' subsequent responsiveness to the firm's promotions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Potential Impact of Customer Characteristics on Effects of Survey Participation 17</head><p>The table of estimated coefficients and their detailed description is provided in Appendix 2. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">4</ref> contains a verbal description of the impact of customer characteristics on the four customer behaviors (number of promotions redeemed, number of services bought, interpurchase time, and purchase amounts). In the table, shaded boxes are areas where the survey had a significant impact on behavior.</p><p>Considering the customer's age, the results may be interpreted as suggesting a diminishing effect of survey participation with increasing age. Upon survey participation, younger customers tend to buy more services when compared to older customers (about 2% more services for every 10 years' age difference). With respect to tenure of the customer (as defined in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">2</ref>), we find that the effect of customer tenure diminishes after survey participation. Previous research on the role of customer experience has found that greater customer experience with the firm at the time of survey participation tends to attenuate the survey participation effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Morwitz et al. 1993)</ref>. In our study, we used customer tenure with the firm as a measure of the customer's experience level and our results seem to agree with these previous findings in the sense that we find no differential impact of survey participation on three of the four customer behaviors (number of promotions redeemed, number of services bought, and interpurchase times). However, we do find a negative effect of tenure on the amounts spent on each purchase occasion.</p><p>The finding that the customer's age diminishes the impact of participating in the satisfaction survey can be explained by the fact that older customers are likely to be more experienced not only with purchasing automotive services, but also with respect to the firm, even before the survey. Such customers should therefore be less likely to gain additional useful information from the survey, or to form measurementinduced judgments that are posited to underlie the survey participation effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Fitzsimons and Williams 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">, Morwitz and Fitzsimons 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">, Dholakia et al. 2005</ref>. In contrast, younger customers will be the ones that are likely to have uncrystallized opinions regarding the firm. The survey should therefore be more impactful for them, leading to greater effects afterward.</p><p>Considering the age of the customer's vehicle, the results show that the newer the customer's vehicle, the greater the impact of survey participation on his or her subsequent behaviors. The tendency of customers with newer vehicles to buy fewer services is nullified on responding to the survey (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">4</ref>). Furthermore, following survey participation, customers with newer vehicles tend to spend more money on each purchase occasion (on average, one year of "newness" roughly corresponds to an increase of about 0.4% spent on each occasion).</p><p>Along the lines of previous research <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Fitzsimons and Williams 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">, Morwitz and Fitzsimons 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">, Dholakia et al. 2005</ref>, it can be argued that customers with newer vehicles are likely to care more about which service provider they use for their vehicle's maintenance and are therefore more likely to consider the survey to provide information regarding the firm's customer orientation. Such customers might also be relatively less experienced with the firm, having purchased the car relatively recently. As a result, they should be more affected by the survey, consistent with our finding.</p><p>We find that there is a minor increase in the interpurchase times for customers with newer vehicles in the presence of survey participation, but this effect is very small, and the net effect still is that newer vehicles tend to visit the store more often.</p><p>We find that customers with newer vehicles redeem fewer promotions, and this remains unchanged even after survey participation. One possibility for this could be that, conditional on the income and other factors, customers with newer vehicles might be relatively less price sensitive with respect to the services they purchase for their vehicle. Thus, they would be less likely to care about and hence redeem more promotions.</p><p>Considering the impact of customer's household income and household size, the results suggest that the difference in promotion sensitivities between higher-income and lower-income customers vanishes on survey participation and that the tendency of higher-income customers to visit the store less often gets significantly reduced (by almost 50%). <ref type="bibr">18</ref> Further-more, we find that the tendency of larger households to spend less per visit diminishes postsurvey participation, indicating yet another positive effect of survey participation.</p><p>These results regarding the positive effects of household income and household size on the impacts of survey participation are more difficult to explain directly using the explanations of either measurement-induced judgments or informativeness of the survey itself. It could be that these demographic variables are positively associated with psychological variables such as thoughtfulness of information processing or persuasion knowledge of individual customers (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Friestad and Wright 1994)</ref>, which in turn lead to greater impact of survey participation. More research at the psychological level is needed to better understand why the influence of survey participation increases with household income and household size.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Potential Impact of Store-Specific Variables</head><p>on Effects of Survey Participation Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">5</ref> contains a verbal description of the impact of store-specific variables on the four customer behaviors. (For details, please see Appendix 2.) As in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">4</ref>, shaded boxes are areas where the survey had a significant impact on behavior.</p><p>A very interesting result in the analysis concerns the impact of store ownership (whether the store is company owned or franchisee owned <ref type="bibr">19</ref> ) on the survey participation effect. In the absence of survey participation, the company-owned stores seem to be underperformers relative to the franchisee-owned stores. In particular, customers tend to redeem fewer promotions as well as buy fewer services at such stores. On average, 8.2% fewer promotions are redeemed and 2.2% fewer services are bought in company-owned stores. However, these stores tend to benefit the most from the effects of survey participation on customers. The tendency of customers to redeem fewer promotions at company-owned stores is reversed in the presence of participation in the customer satisfaction survey; the company-owned stores now tend to get 7.5% more redemptions from these customers as compared to the franchisee-owned stores. The tendency of customers to buy fewer services at company-owned stores also is nullified following survey participation: Now there is no difference in the number of services bought in company-owned versus franchisee-owned stores. Additionally, the positive effects of survey participation to a company-owned store are manifested in the higher amounts being spent by respondents at the survey participation effect, this increase gets lowered to a net 1.7% increase in interpurchase times.  the store following survey participation (about 2.7% greater spends on the part of the survey respondents in company-owned stores as opposed to franchiseeowned stores).</p><p>This finding, that survey participation has more beneficial effects on customers purchasing at company-owned stores of the firm than at franchiseeowned stores, which is robust across three of the four customer behaviors studied-promotion sensitivity, number of services purchased, and amount spentrepresents, to our knowledge, the first instance of a firm characteristic determining the strength of the survey participation effect on customers. Two possibilities could explain this difference. The first possibility arises from the fact that, on average, this firm's company-owned stores offer a larger menu of services to their customers than its franchisee-owned stores. As a result, it could be that following survey participation, customers visiting company-owned stores simply have more opportunities to act in accordance with their positive evaluations relative to those visiting franchisee-owned stores. Second, this firm also has a well-developed CRM system, and at the point of sale, service technicians (in both the company-owned and franchisee-owned stores) have access to customer details. It could be that, postsurvey, company-owned store employees are more responsive to their customers when compared to employees of franchiseeowned stores, leading to more positive behaviors from customers who visit the former stores. Further research is needed to examine which (or both) of these explanations, or other explanations, are responsible for these differences. At any rate, this finding is significant for managers and is likely to raise the profile of customer satisfaction surveys among them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Potential Impact of Time Trend on Effects of</head><p>Survey Participation Equations ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>) through ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) also contain a time trend variable T ht , which is the index number of the purchase occasion (for customer h, purchase occasion t) in the period after participation in the survey. The corresponding coefficients delineate the impact of a time trend 20 in the presence and absence of survey participation; Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">6</ref> contains a verbal description of the impact (for details, please see Appendix 2).</p><p>In the absence of survey participation (i.e., in the time period following survey administration for the control group customers), we find that there is an increasing time trend for number of services bought (an increase of about 2.3% with each purchase occasion), a decreasing time trend for interpurchase times (a decrease of 1.2% in the interpurchase times with each purchase occasion). For the purchase amounts, too, there is an increasing time trend (an increase of 2.5% expenditure with each purchase occasion). 21 In general, we would expect the survey participation effect to wear off with time (D&amp;M). We have one year's observations postsurvey participation, so our time horizon to notice this wearing-off effect is one year. We find that in the presence of survey participation, one year is enough time for the impact to start wearing off on the number of services bought and the amount expended. The rate of increase in the number of services bought and the amount expended decreases from 2.3% and 2.5%, respectively, to less than 1%.</p><p>One year, however, does not seem to be enough time for the effects of survey participation on number of promotions redeemed and the interpurchase times to wear off. The rate of increase in the number of promotions redeemed with every purchase occasion remains at a similar level (to that in the absence of survey participation). However, the rate of decrease in interpurchase times further decreases from a decrease of 1.2% to a decrease of 3.3% in the presence of survey participation. We find that the impact of participating in the survey on the interpurchase times has a much-delayed effect relative to the impact on the other behaviors (number of promotions redeemed, number of services bought, and amount expended). This result is interesting and raises the possibility that survey participation could produce complex timevarying effects. We believe that this result provides opportunity for further research. 22</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">General Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Summary of Results</head><p>Consistent with prior research (e.g., D&amp;M, CMR) and our own assessment of the evidence, we attribute the correlation between survey participation and customer behavior to the impact of survey participation <ref type="bibr">22</ref> We also explored fitting a quadratic trend variable and found it (the quadratic part of the trend variable) to have insignificant impact on three of the four behaviors (number of services bought, interpurchase time, and purchase amounts). However, there was a nonlinear impact on the number of promotions redeemed. This is being further investigated in a related but different work by the authors.</p><p>on customer behavior. Given such an attribution, in our study conducted with a U.S. automotive services firm we found substantial effects of survey participation on all customer behaviors examined, including number of coupons redeemed, number of services purchased, purchase frequency, and amount of money spent on each visit to the firm's stores. Building on the previous studies that had examined customer behaviors in the aggregate, we found the effects of survey participation to be moderated by customer characteristics as well as store-specific variables, and also to vary over time.</p><p>In particular, using a joint modeling methodology, we found that newness of the customer's vehicle, household income, and household size all generally increased the impact of participating in surveys on customer behavior. On the other hand, the customer's age and his or her tenure with the firm were generally found to reduce the impact of survey participation.</p><p>Considering the role of store-specific variables, we found survey participation to have more beneficial effects on customers purchasing at company-owned stores of the firm than at franchisee-owned stores. This finding was robust across three of the four customer behaviors studied with regard to promotion sensitivity, number of services purchased, and amount spent. To our knowledge, this is the first documented instance of a firm characteristic determining the strength of the survey participation effect on customers.</p><p>Finally, analyses of the effects of survey participation over time reveal that the increase in both number of services purchased and amount spent postsurvey starts wearing off within a year after the survey, but the increase in number of promotions redeemed and reduction in interpurchase times persists even a year afterward. These findings affirm the persistence of the impact of conducting a short survey that previous studies such as those of D&amp;M have found.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Managerial Implications</head><p>Although future research might verify our inferences about the direction of causality, our research has potentially significant substantive implications for commercial marketing research practice. Although Marketing Science 26(5), pp. 711-726, © 2007 INFORMS recent concerns have been raised over the growing resistance of consumers to participation in commercial survey research studies (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Bearden et al. 1998, Shea and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">LeBourveau 2000)</ref>, we find that, for the firmsponsored satisfaction survey in the present case, customers do not appear to be so negatively disposed, at least as reflected by their subsequent behaviors. In fact, we found that survey participants engaged in more of each form of behavior we studied, relative to their behavior prior to the satisfaction survey, and that of a control group of survey nonparticipants. At the aggregate level, the finding regarding the positive impact of satisfaction survey participation on promotion responsiveness is especially noteworthy. This result establishes a link between participation in a customer satisfaction survey and subsequent responsiveness of the customer to the firm's promotions.</p><p>Our analysis, which revealed the moderating role of customer characteristics and store-specific variables, provides a useful approach to marketing researchers to minimize the unintended consequences of conducting survey-based satisfaction research. In particular, researchers can first identify which variables accentuate the impact of satisfaction survey participation, then quantify the degree of this impact as in the present case, and finally use this information to develop appropriate sampling schemes in subsequent survey-based projects. Such a procedure is especially relevant for commercial marketing research applications where researchers usually have considerable leeway in choosing their sampling procedures, and have access to large customer databases from which to draw their samples (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Almquist and</ref><ref type="bibr">Wyner 2001, Crosby and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Johnson 2001)</ref>.</p><p>Managers commissioning survey-based satisfaction studies are often interested in understanding the net financial impact of conducting the research <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Dholakia et al. 2005</ref>). Studies such as those of D&amp;M and CMR have implied that positive benefits can be significant. However, while findings such as these suggest that the conventional view of the marketing research function as a cost center needs to be rethought (at least for satisfaction surveys), the present research provides managers who are interested in valuing the financial impact of conducting satisfaction surveys guidance toward a more accurate way of doing so. In particular, by identifying the specific drivers that moderate the impact of satisfaction survey participation, a scoring procedure could easily be implemented to determine the expected impacts on each of the respondents, yielding a cumulative estimate that is more accurate.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.">Limitations</head><p>One concern that has been raised by prior research examining influences of survey participation (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Morwitz et al. 1993</ref>) is that such effects might be explained, at least in part, by nonresponse bias because responders to the survey may be more involved and interested than are nonresponders, and therefore more prone to engage in product purchase and use subsequently. In the present survey, the response rate of customers (number of contacted people responding to the survey) was in the 90%-95% range. The number of customers actually chosen for the survey was not available; however, consultations with the market research vendor and experience with other such studies led us to believe that contact rates were between 60% and 70%, leading to a net response rate between 54% and 67%. Although this response rate is high compared to industry standards, our results should be interpreted cautiously. It could be that there is an oversampling of interested and involved customers simply because they chose to be contacted, and then they participated in the survey.</p><p>A second related concern is the issue of concluding causality, i.e., drawing the conclusion that survey participation causes changes in customer behaviors, in mere measurement research. (See Shugan 2006 for a detailed discussion regarding this issue.) In the present study as well as in prior research we have cited, such as the D&amp;M and the CMR studies, causality cannot be definitively established because there is at least some degree of selection bias in the respondent sample. In particular, customers who were accessible and agreed to be surveyed were compared against a control group of nonparticipants. A stronger test to establish causality requires an experimental design in which the firm creates two random lists of customers. One list is then assigned to the marketing research vendor which then conducts the survey using the list. The second list of customers serves as the control list. The appropriate test of the mere measurement effect is to compare the behaviors of all the customers from the two lists with each other. Future research should execute such a test to unequivocally show existence of the mere measurement effect. 23 A1.1. Prior Specifications Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">A1</ref>.1 provides the priors used in the estimation. Parameters 1 , 2 , 3 , and 4 specify the scale parameters of the two COM-Poisson distributions and two log-normal distributions, respectively (Equations ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">1</ref>) through ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>)). Other than the information that scale parameters are defined over the positive real line, we do not have any a priori information on the likely magnitudes. A prior of inverse gamma (2.5, 0.5) is consistent with these prior beliefs.</p><p>Similarly, all the parameters that specify the impact of a time trend ( 11 , 21 , 31 , 31 and  <ref type="formula">6</ref>) through ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>)), impact of customer characteristics (various s and / s, Equations ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>) through ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>)) and impact of storespecific variables (various s and / s, Equations ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>) through ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>)) on the four dependent variables are given a prior of Normal 0 100 . The reason is that we do not have any sharp prior beliefs on either the magnitude or the signs of these effects, and a Normal 0 100 is a reasonable representation of these prior beliefs.</p><p>Parameters 1 , 2 , 3 , 4 in Equations ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>) through ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) are the coefficients on the dummy variable I h , which in turn is introduced as an attempt to control for any residual selection bias. We expect the magnitudes for these coefficients to be relatively closer to zero since a random procedure was used by the firm to select respondents. However, we still use a relatively diffuse prior (a Normal 0 100 ) for these parameters.</p><p>The parameter¯ 0 = ¯ 10 ¯ 20 ¯ 30 ¯ 40 / is the mean of the heterogeneity distribution over 0h = 10h 20h 30h 40h / (Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_5">10</ref>)). We center our prior distribution about zero on¯ 0 , the four-dimensional expectation of 0h . The prior specified has a large variance to accommodate a wide range of¯ 0 . The parameter , is the covariance matrix for 0h , and the inverse wishart prior on introduces a mild shrinkage and is consistent with our little prior knowledge on this parameter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix 2. The Set of Estimated Coefficients</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A2.1. Potential Impact of Customer Characteristics on</head><p>Effects of Survey Participation Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">A2</ref>.1 contains estimates of parameters (of our full model) reflecting the impact of customer characteristics on the four customer behaviors (number of promotions redeemed, number of services bought, interpurchase time, and purchase amounts). The two sets of parameters (one set with no superscripts in panel A and the other set with a " * " superscript in panel B) delineate this impact in terms of an impact in the absence of and in the presence of survey participation, respectively. <ref type="bibr">24</ref> The customer's gender is a significant variable in the overall context; however, gender does not have a differential impact in presence of survey participation (the differences * 11 − 11 , * 21 − 21 , * 31 − 31 , and * 41 − 41 are all statistically insignificant). With respect to overall behavior, women (binary code = 0) redeem more promotions (about 9.7% more promotions) as well as buy more services on each purchase occasion (5.1% more services) (parameters 11 and 21 , respectively) when compared to men. However, men visit the store more often than women (men's frequency of visits is about 12% more than women) (parameter 31 ). <ref type="bibr">25</ref> Furthermore, gender does not seem to be associated with differences in the impact of survey participation on subsequent customer behaviors, because both genders have similar coefficients in both presence and absence of survey participation.</p><p>As with gender, the age of the customer has a significant overall impact on behavior. On the whole, older customers tend to redeem more promotions, visit the store less frequently, and tend to spend less on each visit (parameters 13 , 33 , and 43 , respectively). Upon survey participation, there is no change in the increased promotion sensitivity and decreased expenditure on the part of older customers ( * 13 and * 43 , respectively). However, younger customers tend to buy more services than older customers ( * 23 , about 2% more services for every 10 years of age difference), an effect not seen in the absence of survey participation. Furthermore, the differing impact of age on the frequency of visits disappears after survey participation ( * 33 vs. <ref type="bibr">33</ref> .</p><p>Regarding the role of customer experience (operationalized as the TENURE variable in our study) the results largely agree with previous findings in the sense that we find no differences pre-and postsurvey participation on three of the four customer behaviors (number of promotions redeemed, number of services bought, and interpurchase times). However, we do find a negative impact of tenure postsurvey participation with respect to the purchase amount spent on each service visit. In our data, we observe that long-standing customers spend more ( 46 ) in the absence of survey participation, although the magnitude of this effect is small (every extra encounter with the firm results in 0.2% more expenditure by the customer). However, postsurvey participation, this tendency of longstanding customers to spend more is attenuated, and disappears (the net result is a null effect, * 46 .</p><p>24 With reference to Equation (6) through (9), for example, * 12 = 12 + / 12 , and so forth. <ref type="bibr">25</ref> It is pertinent to mention that the men/women comparison already accounts for the correlation across various behaviors (as specified by the variance covariance matrix). Thus it is a finer comparison than one without accounting for the correlation, which might be suspect in that it would pick up the natural covariance between these behaviors.  Considering the age of the customer's vehicle, the results show that customers with newer vehicles redeem fewer promotions (are less promotion sensitive) and buy fewer services (parameters 12 and 22 , respectively). However, they tend to visit the store more often ( 32 ). The impact of vehicle vintage in the presence of survey participation is interesting: The tendency of customers with newer vehicles to buy fewer services gets nullified postsurvey participation (parameter * 22 . Furthermore, postsurvey participation, customers with newer vehicles spend more money on each purchase occasion (on average, one year of "newness" leads to an increase of about 0.4% spent on each occasion). Conversely there is also a minor increase in the interpurchase times for customers with newer vehicles in the presence of survey participation (the difference is * 32 − 32 . However, the net effect still is that newer vehicles tend to visit the store more often (there is no sign reversal of the parameter).</p><p>Overall, customers with higher income buy more services and spend more on each purchase occasion (parameters 24 and 44 , respectively). They also tend to visit the store less often ( 34 ). However, these higher-income customers tend to be more promotion sensitive ( 14 is positive and significant). Postparticipation in the survey, this tendency of higher-income customers to be promotion sensitive is attenuated ( * 14 ), i.e., survey participation potentially tends to make higher-income customers less sensitive (as compared to the lower-income customers) to promotions. From the firm's perspective, the good news is that the tendency of higher-income customers to visit the store less often gets significantly diminished postparticipation in a satisfaction survey ( * 34 vs. 34 . Finally, we find that an increase in the customer's household size is associated with a diminishing amount expended by the customer per visit ( 45 . In the absence of survey participation, customers with larger households spend less per visit. However, this effect gets attenuated postparticipation in the survey ( * 45 is not significantly different from 0), indicating yet another positive effect of survey participation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A2.2. Potential Impact of Store-Specific Variables on</head><p>Effects of Survey Participation Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">A2</ref>.2 contains estimates of parameters reflecting the impact of the store-specific variables on the four customer behaviors.</p><p>Parameters in panel A of Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">A2</ref>.2 specify the impact of the store-specific variables on the four behaviors in the absence of survey participation, and those in panel B specify the impact of the store-specific on participation in the satisfaction survey.  The TPUT ht variable is a measure of the total throughput time per service at the store. A greater value for this variable indicates a greater time taken for services at a particular store (in comparison to other stores of the firm). In general, we find that fewer promotions are redeemed and visits are made less frequently at stores with higher throughput times ( 11 and 31 , respectively). On the other hand, higher amounts are spent per service visit at these stores ( 41 . It is important to note that a higher average throughput time could be either an indicator of inefficiency by a particular store, or a reflection of the fact that the store provides more time-consuming services. <ref type="bibr">26</ref> Because is likely that timeconsuming services cost more, our results point to this latter explanation: that there are particular stores that customers typically visit for their bigger maintenance needs. <ref type="bibr">27</ref> It would be very interesting and informative for the firm to uncover such a cluster of stores. In postsurvey participation, there is no differential impact of the store throughput time on the four customer behaviors when compared to those cases where customers did not participate in the survey (parameters 11 through 41 are not significantly different from parameters * 11 through * 41 . There is a positive relationship between the number of service bays at the store and the number of promotions redeemed (an additional bay corresponds to approximately 3.6% more promotions being redeemed at the store). However, this effect is not significantly influenced by survey participation. Other than this one overall impact, the number of bays in the store does not have a significant impact on the other three customer behaviors. Bigger stores are likely to have more bays and also generate more revenues; however, the revenue that we are measuring in this study is the revenue per customer per visit, and we find that this variable is not affected by the number of bays that a store has. It is possible that such bigger stores offer more services and subsequently have more promotion redemptions.</p><p>The presence of a customer lounge in the store has a positive relation to the number of promotions being redeemed by customers at the store ( 13 (possibly, larger stores offering more services are more likely to have a lounge, therefore customers are more likely to redeem more promotions at such stores). However, this effect gets nullified in postsurvey participation ( * 13 . In particular, following survey participation, the presence or absence of a lounge in the store has no impact on the number of promotions redeemed by the customers.</p><p>Considering the impact of store ownership (whether the store is company owned or franchisee owned), <ref type="bibr">28</ref> we find that customers redeem fewer promotions as well as buy fewer services at the company-owned stores ( 14 and  satisfaction survey, the company-owned stores get 7.5% more redemptions compared to the franchisee-owned stores ( * 14 . Furthermore, in postsurvey participation there is no difference in the number of services bought in companyversus franchisee-owned stores ( * 24 . Additionally, higher amounts are spent by respondents at the store following survey participation ( * 44 .</p><p>A2.3. Potential Impact of Time Trend on Effects of Survey Participation Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">A2</ref>.3 contains the set of coefficients on the variable T ht (Equations ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>) through ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>)).</p><p>In the absence of survey participation (i.e., in the time period following survey administration for the control group customers) there is an increasing time trend for number of services bought (an increase of about 2.3% with each purchase occasion, parameter 21 ), and a decreasing time trend for interpurchase times (a decrease of 1.2% in the interpurchase times with each purchase occasion, calculated from 31 ). For the purchase amounts, too, there is an increasing time trend, showing an increase of 2.5% expenditure with each subsequent purchase occasion (parameter 41 ). <ref type="bibr">29</ref> We have one year's observation postsurvey participation, so our time horizon to notice any time effects is one year. The differences 21 − * 21 and 41 − * 41 are both positive and significant, indicating that one year is enough time for the impact to start wearing off on the number of services bought and the amount expended. However, the difference 11 − * 11 is statistically insignificant, while the difference 31 − * 31 is actually positive, indicating that one year does not seem to be enough time for the effects of survey participation on number of promotions redeemed and the interpurchase times to wear off.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Histogram Plots of the Four Dependent Measures</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>and the coefficients on a dummy variable I h (= 1 if customer h participated in the satisfaction survey). The dummy variable I h is introduced as an attempt to control for selection bias.14  The values of the coefficients / 10 through / 40 would specify any residual survey effect not explained by either the time trend nor the household or store characteristics.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>)). A value of 1 for this parameter indicates a Poisson distribution, while values less than 1 indicate overdispersion and values greater than 1 indicate underdispersion relative to the Poisson. Interestingly, both 1</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>*</head><label></label><figDesc>The bold italicized estimates indicate that the 95% posterior interval does not contain 0.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>(a)</cell><cell cols="2">Summary Statistics</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Control group</cell><cell cols="2">Experimental group</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Time period Time period</cell><cell>Before</cell><cell>After</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">before survey after survey</cell><cell>survey</cell><cell>survey</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">No. of promotions</cell><cell>0 48</cell><cell>0 49</cell><cell>0 52</cell><cell>0 55</cell></row><row><cell>redeemed</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 4358</cell><cell>0 5138</cell><cell>0 4237</cell><cell>0 4666</cell></row><row><cell>No. of services</cell><cell></cell><cell>1 63</cell><cell>1 71</cell><cell>1 66</cell><cell>1 73</cell></row><row><cell>bought</cell><cell></cell><cell>0 6365</cell><cell>0 7737</cell><cell>0 6365</cell><cell>0 7271</cell></row><row><cell>Interpurchase</cell><cell></cell><cell>98 07</cell><cell>95 54</cell><cell>107 47</cell><cell>102 56</cell></row><row><cell>time (days)</cell><cell></cell><cell>79 08</cell><cell>37 79</cell><cell>58 10</cell><cell>48 84</cell></row><row><cell>Purchase</cell><cell></cell><cell>40 38</cell><cell>43 92</cell><cell>41 39</cell><cell>44 54</cell></row><row><cell>amount ($)</cell><cell></cell><cell>16 21</cell><cell>19 96</cell><cell>16 27</cell><cell>20 41</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Customer Characteristics and Store-Specific Variables Used in the Analysis BAYS ht Number of service bays in the store in which customer h shopped on purchase occasion t OWNERSHIP ht Dummy variable indicating the ownership of the store (whether company owned, code = 1, or franchisee owned, code = 0) LOUNGE htDummy variable indicating the presence of a customer lounge in the store in which customer h shopped on purchase occasion t * It is the total throughput time weighted by the number of services bought. This variable is then normalized by dividing it by the average throughput time across all the stores.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Variable</cell><cell>Description</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Panel A. Customer characteristics</cell></row><row><cell>GENDER h</cell><cell>Dummy variable indicating customer h's gender</cell></row><row><cell>AGE h</cell><cell>Estimated average age of customer h in years</cell></row><row><cell>TENURE h</cell><cell>Number of times customer h bought from the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>prior to the survey</cell></row><row><cell>YEAR h</cell><cell>Year of manufacture of the vehicle of customer h</cell></row><row><cell>INCOME h</cell><cell>Natural log of the estimated median household</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>income ($) for customer h</cell></row><row><cell>HHSIZE h</cell><cell>Customer h's estimated household size</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">PANEL B. Store-specific variables</cell></row><row><cell>TPUT ht</cell><cell>A measure of the average throughput time for the store</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>in which customer h shopped on purchase</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>occasion t.</cell></row></table><note>*    </note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Potential Impact of Customer Characteristics</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">No. of promotions redeemed</cell><cell cols="2">No. of services bought</cell><cell cols="2">Interpurchase time</cell><cell cols="2">Purchase amount</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Baseline</cell><cell>Survey</cell><cell>Baseline</cell><cell>Survey</cell><cell>Baseline</cell><cell>Survey</cell><cell>Baseline</cell><cell>Survey</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">GENDER h Women redeem No change</cell><cell>Women buy</cell><cell>No change</cell><cell>Men visit</cell><cell>No change</cell><cell>No impact</cell><cell>No change</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>more</cell><cell></cell><cell>more services</cell><cell></cell><cell>the store</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>promotions</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>more often</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>AGE h</cell><cell cols="2">Older customers No change</cell><cell>No impact</cell><cell>Younger</cell><cell cols="2">Older customers No change</cell><cell cols="2">Older customers No change</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>redeem more</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>customers</cell><cell>visit store</cell><cell></cell><cell>spend less</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>promotions</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>buy more</cell><cell>less often</cell><cell></cell><cell>money</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>services</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">TENURE h No impact</cell><cell>No change</cell><cell>No impact</cell><cell>No change</cell><cell>Larger tenure</cell><cell>No change</cell><cell>Larger tenure</cell><cell>This tendency</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>customers</cell><cell></cell><cell>customers</cell><cell>gets nullified</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>visit store</cell><cell></cell><cell>spend more</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>less often</cell><cell></cell><cell>money</cell></row><row><cell>YEAR h</cell><cell cols="2">Newer vehicles No change</cell><cell cols="4">Newer vehicles This tendency Newer vehicles Minor decrease</cell><cell>No impact</cell><cell>Newer vehicles</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>redeem fewer</cell><cell></cell><cell>buy fewer</cell><cell>of newer</cell><cell>visit store</cell><cell>in store visits</cell><cell></cell><cell>spend more</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>promotions</cell><cell></cell><cell>services</cell><cell>vehicles gets</cell><cell>more often</cell><cell>by new</cell><cell></cell><cell>money</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>nullified</cell><cell></cell><cell>vehicles</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">INCOME h Richer</cell><cell>No difference</cell><cell>Richer</cell><cell>No change</cell><cell>Richer</cell><cell>This tendency</cell><cell>Richer</cell><cell>No change</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>customers</cell><cell>in redemption</cell><cell>customers</cell><cell></cell><cell>customers</cell><cell>of richer</cell><cell>customers</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>redeem more</cell><cell>across</cell><cell>buy more</cell><cell></cell><cell>visit store</cell><cell>customers</cell><cell>spend more</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>promotions</cell><cell>incomes</cell><cell>services</cell><cell></cell><cell>less often</cell><cell>gets diminished</cell><cell>money</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">HHSIZE h No impact</cell><cell>No change</cell><cell>No impact</cell><cell>No change</cell><cell>No impact</cell><cell>No change</cell><cell>Larger</cell><cell>This tendency</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>households</cell><cell>of larger</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>spend less</cell><cell>households</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>money</cell><cell>gets nullified</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Potential Impact of Store-Specific Variables</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">No. of promotions redeemed</cell><cell cols="2">No. of services bought</cell><cell cols="2">Interpurchase time</cell><cell cols="2">Purchase amount</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Baseline</cell><cell>Survey</cell><cell>Baseline</cell><cell>Survey</cell><cell>Baseline</cell><cell>Survey</cell><cell>Baseline</cell><cell>Survey</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell></row><row><cell>TPUT ht</cell><cell>Fewer</cell><cell>No change</cell><cell>No impact</cell><cell>No change</cell><cell>Fewer visits</cell><cell cols="2">No change More money</cell><cell>No change</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>redemptions</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>made to high</cell><cell></cell><cell>spent on high</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>at high</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>throughput</cell><cell></cell><cell>throughput</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>throughput</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>time stores</cell><cell></cell><cell>time stores</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>time stores</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>BAYS ht</cell><cell>More</cell><cell>No change</cell><cell>No impact</cell><cell>No change</cell><cell>No impact</cell><cell cols="2">No change No impact</cell><cell>No change</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>promotions</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>redeemed at</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>stores with</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>more bays</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">OWNERSHIP ht Fewer</cell><cell>Greater</cell><cell>Fewer</cell><cell>No difference</cell><cell>No impact</cell><cell cols="2">No change No impact</cell><cell>More amount</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>promotions</cell><cell>promotions</cell><cell>services</cell><cell>in services</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>spent on</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>redeemed at</cell><cell>redeemed at</cell><cell>bought at</cell><cell>bought across</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>company-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>company</cell><cell>company</cell><cell>company-</cell><cell>stores</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>owned stores</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>owned stores</cell><cell>owned stores</cell><cell>owned stores</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>LOUNGE ht</cell><cell>More</cell><cell>No difference</cell><cell>No impact</cell><cell>No change</cell><cell>No impact</cell><cell cols="2">No change No impact</cell><cell>No change</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>promotions</cell><cell>in redemptions</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>redeemed at</cell><cell>across stores</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>stores with</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>a lounge</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Potential Impact of a Time Trend</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">No. of promotions redeemed</cell><cell cols="2">No. of services bought</cell><cell cols="2">Interpurchase time</cell><cell cols="2">Purchase amount</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Baseline</cell><cell>Survey</cell><cell>Baseline</cell><cell>Survey</cell><cell>Baseline</cell><cell>Survey</cell><cell>Baseline</cell><cell>Survey</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>impact</cell></row><row><cell>T ht</cell><cell>An increase</cell><cell>No change.</cell><cell>An increase</cell><cell>This increasing</cell><cell>Increase in</cell><cell>This rate of</cell><cell>Increase in</cell><cell>This increasing</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>in number of</cell><cell></cell><cell>in services</cell><cell>time trend</cell><cell>store visits</cell><cell>increase</cell><cell>money spent</cell><cell>time trend is</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>promotions</cell><cell></cell><cell>bought with</cell><cell>is diminished.</cell><cell>with time.</cell><cell>in store visits</cell><cell>with time.</cell><cell>diminished.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>with time.</cell><cell></cell><cell>time.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>is further</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>increased.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>Table A1</head><label>A1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>.1</cell><cell cols="4">The Priors Used in the Estimation</cell></row><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Priors</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">1 , 2 , 3 , 4 11 , 21 , 31 , 41 , / 11 , / 21 , / 31 , / 41 Various 's and / 's [Equations (6)</cell><cell>Inverse gamma (2.5,0.5) Normal 0 100 Normal 0 100</cell></row><row><cell>through (9)]</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Various 's and / 's [Equations (6)</cell><cell>Normal 0 100</cell></row><row><cell>through (9)]</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">1 , 2 , 3 , 4 / 10 , / 20 , / 30 , / 40 ¯ 0 = ¯ 10 ¯ 20 ¯ 30 ¯</cell><cell>40</cell><cell>/</cell><cell>Normal 0 100 Normal 0 100 MVNormal 0 0 0 0 10I</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Inv Wishart (1,10I,10)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12"><head>Table A2</head><label>A2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>.1</cell><cell cols="3">Potential Impact of Customer Characteristics</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>GENDER h</cell><cell>AGE h</cell><cell>TENURE h</cell><cell>YEAR h</cell><cell>INCOME h</cell><cell>HHSIZE h</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_13"><head>Table A2</head><label>A2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>.2</cell><cell cols="3">Potential Impact of Store-Specific Variables</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>TPUT ht</cell><cell>BAYS ht</cell><cell>OWNERSHIP ht</cell><cell>LOUNGE ht</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_14"><head>Table A2</head><label>A2</label><figDesc>.3 Potential Impact of a Time Trend in the Absence and Presence of Survey Participation Absence T ht Presence T ht</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">It is worth noting here that in these research studies, the authors only provided correlational and logical evidence of causality. We discuss this issue in more detail in §5.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">However, this would require additional analysis not presented here.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Although prior studies such as those of CMR and D&amp;M have studied time effects on dependent variables, the analysis there was done at an aggregate level, analyzing each dependent variable separately.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">We excluded multiple-automobile households from the analysis to prevent unknown factors from contaminating our results, e.g., the possibility that the person purchasing the service might not be the automobile's owner, that the patterns of intrahousehold communication influence the survey respondent, or other forms of interpersonal influence.5  We defined customers as active when they had at least one service visit during the period of the analysis (January 2001-April 2003), and if they had at least five service visits to the firm's stores during the seven-year period of January 1996 to December 2002, so all our analysis is restricted to the more regular customers of the firm.6  The surveyed customers indicated high satisfaction levels on this measure, with the average satisfaction score (on a 10-point scale) being 8.3 (s.d. = 1 9).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8">Mails and reminder mails from the firm, joint promotions with partner firms, flyers, newspaper advertisements, online promotions, etc.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="11">This approach is similar to that followed in<ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Borle et al. (2005)</ref> wherein they studied the impact of product assortment changes across a set of experimental and control groups.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="14">Although the firm purports to have randomly selected the survey participants, there is always a possibility of inadvertent selection bias and one needs to attempt to control or account for this bias to the extent possible.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="15">For simplicity in presentation in the main text, many of the estimated coefficients and their detailed description have been provided in Appendix 2.16  The details of this simpler analysis can be obtained from the authors on request.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="17">Throughout the paper, for reasons to be discussed later ( §5), we attribute significant correlations to a causal relationship. We thank the editor and the associate editor for suggesting this clarification.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="18">For example, a 50% increase in income leads to an overall increase of 3.4% in the interpurchase times. However, in the presence of</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="19">OWNERSHIP ht = 1 implies company owned and = 0 implies franchise store.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="20">Please note that we use a very general interpretation of the word trend. Our interpretation simply is that, given the time span of data postsurvey, how the survey effect across the four behaviors changed (linearly) across purchase occasions.21  The estimated time trend for the number of promotions redeemed is also positive, a 1.2% increase. However, the parameter 11 is significant only at a 90% significance level.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="23">We thank the associate editor for pointing this issue out to us, and for suggesting this unequivocal test for the existence of the mere measurement effect.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="24">, respectively). On average, 8.2% fewer promotions are redeemed and 2.2% fewer services are bought in companyowned stores. However, postparticipation in the customer26  The data contain no further information to segregate these effects.27  If the predominant reason for the increases in throughput was inefficiency, then it seems unlikely that customers would tend to spend more per visit in these inefficient stores.28  OWNERSHIP ht = 1 implies company owned and = 0 implies franchisee owned.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="29">The estimated time trend for the number of promotions redeemed is also positive, a 1.2% increase. However, the parameter 11 is significant only at a 90% significance level.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank the automotive services firm that sponsored this study. The names of the authors are listed in alphabetical order.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix 1. Prior Specification</head><p>The joint model to be estimated is specified by Equations (1) through (10). We use a hierarchical Bayes approach using an Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) sampler <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Casella and</ref><ref type="bibr">George 1992, Gelfand and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Smith 1990)</ref> to estimate the model. The following subsection lays out the prior parameter specifications associated with the estimated model.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Boost your marketing ROI with experimental design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Almquist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Wyner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Harvard Bus. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">R0109K</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The pool is drying up</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Bearden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Madden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Uscátgui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Res. (Spring)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model of the joint distribution of purchase quantity and timing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Boatwright</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Borle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kadane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="564" to="572" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="711" to="726" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effect of product assortment changes on customer retention</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Borle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Boatwright</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kadane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Nunes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Shmueli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="616" to="622" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Explaining the Gibbs sampler</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Casella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>George</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="327" to="335" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The short-and long-term effects of measuring intent to repurchase</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Chandon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morwitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Reinartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="566" to="572" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A queuing model with statedependent service rate</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Conway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Maxwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Indust. Engrg</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="132" to="136" />
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The democratization of data. Marketing Management (Spring)</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Crosby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8" to="9" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The scope and persistence of mere measurement effects: Evidence from a field study of customer satisfaction measurement</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dholakia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morwitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="167" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Survey participation effects on customer purchase behavior: Evidence for a positivity effect of firm-sponsored satisfaction surveys</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dholakia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morwitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Westbrook</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">MSI Working Paper Series</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-generated validity and other effects of measurement on belief, attitude, intention, and behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lynch</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Psych</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="421" to="435" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Asking questions can change choice behavior: Does it do so automatically or effortfully?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Fitzsimons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Experiment. Psych.: Appl</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="206" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The persuasion knowledge model: How people cope with persuasion attempts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Friestad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="1994-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sampling-based approaches to calculating marginal densities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Gelfand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">F M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Amer. Statist. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="398" to="409" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transfer appropriate processing, response fluency, and the mere measurement effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Janiszewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Chandon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="323" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The mere measurement effect: Why does measuring intentions change actual behavior?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morwitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Fitzsimons</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Psych</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1&amp;2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="64" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does measuring intent change behavior?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morwitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Schmittlein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="61" />
			<date type="published" when="1993-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jumping the &quot;hurdles&quot; of marketing research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Shea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lebourveau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Res. (Fall)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="30" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A useful distribution for fitting discrete data: Revival of the COM-Poisson</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Shmueli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Minka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kadane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Borle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Boatwright</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Roy. Statist. Soc., Ser. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="142" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Errors in the variables, unobserved heterogeneity, and other ways of hiding statistical error</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="216" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
