<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Cross-Market Network Effect with Asymmetric Customer Loyalty: Implications for Competitive Advantage</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yuxin</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<email>ychen@stern.nyu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jinhong</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
							<email>xie@cba.ufl.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Leonard N. Stern School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">New York University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>10012</postCode>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>New York</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Warrington College of Business Administration</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Florida</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>32611</postCode>
									<settlement>Gainesville</settlement>
									<region>Florida, Jinhong</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Cross-Market Network Effect with Asymmetric Customer Loyalty: Implications for Competitive Advantage</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 07 2601 0052</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1060.0238</idno>
					<note type="submission">received December 19, 2002, and was with the authors 32 months for 3 revisions; processed by Chakravarthi Narasimhan.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:30+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>In some industries, a firm produces two different products sold in two different markets and the value of one product depends on the demand for the other. We refer to this type of dependence as a crossmarket network effect. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The cross-market network effect is widespread across many different industries. For example, a newspaper publisher produces newspapers sold to readers and advertising space sold to advertisers. The value of the newspaper as a medium for advertisers to reach their potential buyers increases with its level of circulation. Consequently, <ref type="bibr">1</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Strauss (2000)</ref> uses the term "cross-market network externalities." We use "cross-market network effect" because, in economics, externalities are typically associated with the potential of market failure, which is not true in our context. In IS literature, the term "twosided markets" is also used to describe the similar phenomenon <ref type="bibr">(Parker and</ref>  <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Van Alstyne 2005, Rochet and Tirole 2003)</ref>. the newspaper's revenue from the advertising market depends on its demand in the readers' market. The cross-market network effect is also present in the computer software industry. For example, Adobe Acrobat and RealPlayer each have two different products: a document creator targeting the content providers and a document viewer targeting the readers of the content produced by the document creator. The acceptance of a document creator by the content providers depends on the number of people who have the corresponding viewer. As mentioned in <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Strauss (2000)</ref>, according to the U.S. Bureau of the Census (1997) (Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">886, 903</ref>), the industries in which a crossmarket network effect occurs, such as newspapers, television, radio, software, and the like, generate annual revenues of approximately $200 billion in the United States alone.</p><p>Despite the ubiquitous existence of the cross-market network effect, little work has been done to examine its impact on firms' business strategies, with the exception of a few recent studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Chaudhri 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">, Strauss 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">, Godes et al. 2003</ref><ref type="bibr">, Cabral and Villas-Boas 2005</ref>. In studying the pricing policies of a monopoly newspaper publisher, <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Chaudhri (1998)</ref> suggests that it can be optimal for the monopolist to lower the newspaper price even below its marginal cost in order to increase its circulation and thus obtain higher advertising revenue. <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Strauss (2000)</ref> asserts that the existence of a cross-market network effect affects the optimal prices of the two interdependent products in opposite directions: the stronger the cross-market network effect, the larger the difference in profit margins between the two products. He also shows that increased product compatibility among firms leads to increased profit. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Godes et al. (2003)</ref> examine the relative source of profits from the audience market versus advertising market for media firms. They show that a firm's decision to become an advertising medium depends on both the within-industry and the between-industry competition of the firms in the two markets. <ref type="bibr">Cabral and Villas-Boas (2005)</ref> study oligopoly price competition between multi-product firms whose products interact in their profit functions through either demand externalities or cost externalities. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> They find that a "Bertrand supertrap" can occur, whereby the strategic effect of competition on firms' profits by an economic force may dominate its direct effect on profit that applies to a monopoly firm. They show, for example, that stronger economies of scope may lead to lower profitability for firms in competition if their products interact in profit functions.</p><p>Although the studies mentioned above provide important insights into the behavior of firms in markets with a cross-market network effect, no studies to date have addressed the question of how asymmetry in customer loyalty may affect firms' competitive strategies in the presence of a cross-market network effect. However, in reality, competing firms in an industry are more likely to be asymmetric in their customer loyalty, as a result of differences in product positioning, marketing effectiveness, and order-of-entry of the firms. In general, an incumbent in an industry is more likely to enjoy higher customer loyalty than a potential entrant <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Carpenter and Nakamoto 1989)</ref>. Therefore, examining the impact of asymmetry loyalty is also important in understanding firms' entry strategies. In markets with a cross-market network effect, the issue of asymmetry in customer loyalty is particularly interesting because firms in such <ref type="bibr">2</ref> The cross-market network effect can be viewed as one type of such externalities. Such externalities may also include other types of cross-market interaction, e.g., the price interaction of different brands across different geographic markets <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Chintagunta and Desiraju 2005)</ref>. markets face competition in multiple interdependent markets so that the installed user base and customer loyalty in one market affect competition not only in that market but in other markets as well. Moreover, loyalty build-up is especially important among industries characterized by the cross-market network effect because consumer commitments (e.g., in subscriptionbased industries such as newspapers and cable TV) and switching costs (e.g., the sizeable learning costs to become familiar with functions of a software package such as Windows Media Player) play very significant roles in competition. Finally, understanding the competitive implications of asymmetry loyalty is practically relevant for industries characterized by the cross-market network effect as they are witnessing the entry of new players. For example, established newspapers are now facing increasing competition from the entry of free newspapers such as Metro and amNew York <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Carvajal 2004</ref>). The growing popularity of blogs also imposes challenge to the traditional media companies <ref type="bibr">(Business Week 2005)</ref>.</p><p>In this paper, we examine the impact of a crossmarket network effect on firms' competitive strategies, paying special attention to the interaction between the cross-market network effect and asymmetry in customer loyalty. Specifically, we address the following question: All else being equal, does higher customer loyalty always lead to higher profit and market share for a firm with more loyal customers than its rival in industries with a cross-market network effect? Previous literature has suggested a positive effect of customer loyalty on a firm's competitive advantage <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Narasimhan 1988)</ref>. We examine whether or not this conclusion is still true in the presence of a cross-market network effect.</p><p>To address the research question, we have developed a model composed of two competing firms, each selling two products (a primary and a secondary product) in two markets with a cross-market network effect: i.e., the value of the secondary product depends on the demand for the primary product. The firms differ in customer loyalty in the market of the primary product with one firm having more loyal customers than the other. Our analysis reveals that, under certain conditions, loyalty advantage can surprisingly lead to both profit and market share disadvantage in markets with a cross-market network effect. Specifically, we show that a high or low loyalty advantage in the market of the primary product allows a firm to gain a higher total profit than the firm with disadvantage in customer loyalty. However, a mid-range loyalty advantage in the market of the primary product may lead to a lower total profit for the firm compared with its competitor. A firm with a mid-range loyalty advantage has an incentive to set a high price to target its loyal segment, because its loyalty advantage Marketing Science 26(1), pp. 52-66, © 2007 INFORMS is quite significant and the existence of a price lower bound limits its ability to obtain non-loyal customers by further undercutting the competitor in price. As a result, this can lead to a disadvantage in market share in the primary product market if the firm's customer loyalty advantage is not high enough to outnumber the non-loyal customers attracted by its competitor. Consequently, its profit from the secondary product can be lower than that of its competitor, and its total profit from both markets can also be lower than that of its competitor. Therefore, it is possible for the firm with disadvantage in customer loyalty to achieve a higher market share and profit than the firm with a loyalty advantage.</p><p>To examine the implications of this finding on firms' entry strategy and the first-mover's advantage and disadvantage in markets with the cross-market network effect, we extend our model to a two-period entry game. We further show that when the fixed cost of entry is small, an entrant with no loyal customer base at entry may obtain higher profit than the incumbent. This is due to the fact that the incumbent is most vulnerable with a mid-sized loyal customer base, while profit for the entrant is highest in such a situation.</p><p>This result complements previous research on entry <ref type="bibr">Yoon 1990, Narasimhan and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Zhang 2000)</ref> and first-mover advantage. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Lieberman and Montgomery (1988)</ref> suggest that the first mover in a product category can enjoy an advantage over later comers. However, empirical evidence is mixed <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Glazer 1985</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">, Robinson and Fornell 1985</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">, Robinson 1988</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, Golder and Tellis 1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">, Kalyanaram et al. 1995</ref>. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> This paper suggests a new source of first-mover advantage or disadvantage. As shown by our model, in the presence of a cross-market network effect, a first mover has an advantage over an entrant if its loyalty base in the market of the primary product is either small or large. However, a first mover may be at a disadvantage to the entrant in terms of profitability if its loyalty base is in the midlevel range.</p><p>It is worth noting that the findings reported in this paper result from the unique features of a crossmarket network effect, which are profoundly different from the direct and indirect network effects studied extensively in the marketing and economics literature. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> A cross-market network effect has two basic characteristics: (1) firms provide multiple products to different sets of customers; and (2) the value of one product depends on the demand for the other products. In markets with a direct network effect (e.g., fax machines), the main concern of potential buyers of a product is the user base of the same product. However, in markets with a cross-market network effect, the main concern of the potential buyers of one product (e.g., advertisers in the newspaper industry) is the user base of the other products (e.g., circulation of the newspaper). Interaction between different products (e.g., hardware and software) also exists in markets with an indirect network effect in which different products are usually made by different firms but are sold to the same customers. However, in markets with a cross-market network effect, different products are produced by the same firm but are sold to different customers.</p><p>The remainder of this paper is organized as follows. In §2, we present our basic model, derive the key theoretical results, and provide three predictions. In §3, we examine some of the predictions using data from the newspaper industry. In §4, we discuss the robustness of our main results, derive the implication of loyalty asymmetry on market entry strategy and first-mover's advantage/disadvantage, and conclude the paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">The Model</head><p>In this section, we start with a simple model to examine the competitive implications of asymmetric customer loyalty in a market characterized by a crossmarket network effect. Our objective is to first use a simple model to capture the essence of the crossmarket network effect and the key economic insights to be shown in the paper without introducing unnecessary mathematical complexity. In §4, we examine the robustness of our results derived from this basic model by relaxing some of the assumptions. Notations used in our theoretical models are summarized in the Table of Notations (see the appendix). Proofs of the theoretical results are also given in the appendix.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Assumptions</head><p>We consider two competing firms that differ in customer loyalty, i.e., a high-and a low-loyalty firm i = H L . Both firms sell two different, but related, products: a primary product and a secondary product j = P S . The market of the primary product has a size of one (1) and consists of two customer segments: (a) a segment of customers of size 0 &lt; &lt; 1 , who are loyal to firm H, and (b) a segment of customers of size 1 − , who are loyal to neither firm. The <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Shankar and Bayus (2003)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Basu et al. (2003)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Srinivasan et al. (2004)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Sun et al. (2004)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Harikesh et al. (2004)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Chakravarti and Xie (2006)</ref>, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Wang and Xie (2006)</ref>.</p><p>loyalty difference can stem from a variety of sources or factors. For example, in the newspaper industry, such loyalty difference can be due to quality of editorial/commentary, topic coverage, and political inclination (i.e., conservative versus liberal). <ref type="bibr">5</ref> In addition, loyalty can also be related to customer satisfaction <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Mittal et al. 2005)</ref>. Each consumer has a unit demand in the primary product market. Let k and s denote the reservation price of the loyal and non-loyal customers, respectively, where s ≤ k. Denote p iP as firm i's price in the market of the primary product. Loyal customers buy only from firm H , provided that p HP ≤ k. Nonloyal customers (i.e., switchers) buy from the firm that offers a lower price for the primary product provided that such price is not higher than s. If two firms set the same price, switchers buy from each firm with a probability of 50%. We assume s = 0 in the basic model and relax this assumption later in §4. The marginal cost of production of each firm in the primary market is c, where k &gt; c.</p><p>To capture the cross-market network effect, we assume that firm i's profit from the secondary product market is iS = hD iP , where D iP is firm i's demand in the primary product market and h &gt; 0 captures the strength of the cross-market network effect. This profit specification assumes that a firm's profit from the secondary product is derived solely from the demand for its primary product. A similar assumption is used by <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Chaudhri (1998)</ref> to model the circulation industry (e.g., newspapers). Because our empirical investigation uses data from the newspaper industry, we take an additional step of providing a formal justification for this profit specification in the context of the circulation industry in Appendix A.1.</p><p>Our model assumes a cross-market network effect from the primary to the secondary product, but not vice versa. The rationale behind this assumption is that in many circumstances (e.g., the newspaper industry), the cross-market network effect in one direction dominates the other. As demonstrated by <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Strauss (2000)</ref>, it is analytically sufficient to consider only the "net" effect of a bi-directional cross-market network effect.</p><p>Finally, we assume that neither firm will charge a price below a lower bound, p 0 ≤ 0. We first assume p 0 = 0 and relax this assumption later in §4. Generally, a price less than zero could not be optimal because it would be equivalent to giving money away, even to those who have nothing to do with the product <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Strauss 2000 and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Chaudhri 1998)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> For example, if a newspaper publisher pays people to receive copies of the newspaper, those who do not want to read the newspaper can take the copies, receive the money, and dispose of the newspaper without paying attention to the contents and ads. As a result, the circulation generated from such demand will not provide value to advertisers. Therefore, unless a firm can enforce the desirable behavior of customers (e.g., actually reading the newspaper) at a negative price, setting a price below zero will not be optimal. Our assumption of a lower bound price is also consistent with industry practice. For example, the Audit Bureau of Circulations does not count any newspaper sold under 75% of its listed price (e.g., give-away copies in hotel rooms) as circulation that can be used to negotiate rates with advertisers. In addition, the publishers have to report the circulation figures for copies sold at discount separately from those sold at full price. Under these rules, deep discounting has been used "sparingly if at all" <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Editor &amp; Publisher 2002)</ref> because the reported discounted sales are not "going to look good" (The Wall Street Journal 2001) because they may not constitute the circulation market in which advertisers are interested.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Equilibrium</head><p>We can see that, for firm H , the optimal price of the primary product is either p HP = k or p HP = 0. Similarly, for firm L the optimal price of the primary product is p LP = 0. 7 The two competing firms set prices simultaneously in the market of the primary product. firm i's profit can be written as</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">i = D iP p iP − c + hD iP (1)        D HP = D LP = 1 − if p HP = k D HP = + 0 5 1 − D LP = 0 5 1 − if p HP = 0 (2)</formula><p>Firms' total profits are given in ( <ref type="formula">3</ref>):</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">H = k − c + h if p HP = k 0 5 1 + h − c if p HP = 0 L = h − c 1 − if p HP = k 0 5 1 − h − c if p HP = 0 (3) 6</formula><p>In some cases, a negative price is possible. For example, local radio stations sometimes offer a number of prizes to listeners to keep them listening. We thank an anonymous reviewer for pointing out this fact. The feasibility of such negative prices is critically dependent upon the ability of firms to ensure the real consumption of the primary product (e.g., ensuring that customers receiving the prizes actually listen to the radio). If h ≤ c, firm H will set price at k with H = k − c • + h , but firm L cannot make any profit. In the following discussion, we assume h &gt; c so that both firms participate in the competition. The equilibrium results under h &gt; c are provided in Lemma 1.</p><p>Lemma 1 (Equilibrium). Firms' equilibrium price, demand, and profit are given in <ref type="table">Table 1.</ref> As shown in Lemma 1, firm L always sets its price at zero because it has no loyal customers. Firm H 's optimal price is determined by the trade-off between the profit from the primary and the secondary product because a higher price leads to a higher profit margin but a lower demand from the primary product, which in turn reduces its profit from the secondary product due to the cross-market network effect. It is optimal for firm H to adopt a high price only if the size of the loyal segment for its primary product is sufficiently large, so that the amount firm H gains by charging a high price to the loyal customers of its primary product is sufficient to compensate for its loss from the secondary market resulting from its small share in the primary product market. We call the high-price and low-price strategies "primary-productdriven" and "secondary-product-driven" strategies, respectively, because the former focuses on profit of the primary product and the latter focuses on profit of the secondary product.</p><p>Lemma 1 suggests that, as loyalty varies more dramatically across competing firms, &gt; , firms move from symmetric (i.e., both pursue a secondaryproduct-driven strategy) to asymmetric strategies (H becomes primary-product-driven but L remains secondary-product-driven). Furthermore, as shown in Lemma 1, d /h &gt; 0 and d /k &lt; 0, which imply that the asymmetry in pricing strategy is more likely (i.e., is smaller) when the advertising market is less attractive (i.e., when h is smaller) or when the loyalty premium is higher (i.e., when k is larger).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table 1</head><p>Equilibrium Results for Lemma 1</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Asymmetry in customer loyalty</head><formula xml:id="formula_2">≤ = h − c / 2k + h − c &gt; = h − c / 2k + h − c Price (primary product)    p * HP = 0 p * LP = 0    p * HP = k p * LP = 0 Market share (primary product)    D * HP = + 0 5 1 − D * LP = 0 5 1 −    D * HP = D * LP = 1 − Total profit    * H = 0 5 1 + h − c * L = 0 5 1 − h − c    * H = k − c + h * L = h − c 1 − Comparisons    MS P = D HP − D LP = = H − L = h − c    MS P = D HP − D LP = 2 − 1 = H − L = k + 2 h − c − h − c</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Profit</head><p>We now look at the implications of asymmetric customer loyalty for firms' profits in the presence of a cross-market network effect. While Lemma 1 presents firms' equilibrium profits, Proposition 1 formally states the conditions under which each firm has a profit advantage. </p><formula xml:id="formula_3">     h = ch = k + c = h − c 2k + h − c¯ = h − c k + 2 h − c (4)</formula><p>Proposition 1 reveals an interesting but counterintuitive result: A loyalty advantage can lead to a profit disadvantage. Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> graphically illustrates this result. As shown in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>, although firm L's profit decreases within both regions, 0 and 1 , it increases at = . The increase in firm L's profit at = leads to a dramatic change in the firms' relative profits, i.e., firm H loses its profit advantage and firm L becomes the profit leader. The reason for this dramatic change is that, when the size of the loyal segment increases, a secondary-product-driven strategy is less profitable and a primary-product-driven strategy is more profitable for firm H . The two strategies bring firm H the same profit at = . However, when firm H switches to a primary-product-driven strategy at = , firm L's customer base increases substantially because firm H gives up the non-loyal customers. This increased customer base, in turn, significantly increases firm L's profit from the secondary market and results in a profit advantage over firm H . When a profit-reversal situation occurs, a question arises: Will firm H have an incentive to price lower than firm L in order to obtain a higher demand in the primary market? The answer is no, for two reasons: First, firm L can always compete more aggressively because it has a lower opportunity cost of losing margin from its loyal customers. Therefore, any effort to cut prices by firm H will be countered by firm L. Second, the existence of a lower bound of price, p 0 , in the primary market also discourages firm H from further undercutting the rival firm's price. This is because, at a negative price below p 0 , a firm starts to give away money to customers. Unless a firm can enforce the desirable behavior of customers at such a price (e.g., actually reading the newspaper, paying attention to the radio station, using the computer software), a negative price will bring in a large number of irrelevant customers in the primary market who do not provide value to the customers in the secondary market. Consequently, the firm will lose profit at prices below p 0 . This fact prevents firms from endlessly undercutting each other's prices. It is worth noting that this feature of pricing consideration is closely related to the nature of the cross-market network effect. In essence, the cross-market network effect exists because the actions (e.g., attention, usage) of the customers in the primary market affect the utility of the customers in the secondary market. Merely paying customers to receive the product is unlikely to bring desirable actions from those customers in the primary market unless proper monitoring and enforcing methods are in place.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> also shows that, for &gt; , firm H 's profit increases and firm L's profit decreases with . As a result, firm L's profit advantage decreases and finally disappears at =¯ . Hence, firm L will have a profit advantage over firm H only when firm H 's loyalty advantage falls into the loyalty window, ¯ . Note that the existence of a loyalty window depends on the relative magnitude of both the crossmarket network effect h and the loyalty premium k . The size of the loyalty window for firm L to obtain a profit advantage is l <ref type="bibr">8</ref> which is positive only for markets with a mid-range cross-network effect, c &lt; h &lt; k + c. Thus, an opportunity loyalty window that would allow firm L to outperform firm H does not exist if the cross-market network effect is too weak or too strong. In the case of a very weak cross-market network effect, the user base of a primary product has little impact on the value of the secondary product. As in the markets without a crossmarket network effect, an advantage in customer loyalty always leads to a profit advantage. In the case of an overwhelmingly strong cross-market network effect, the user base of the primary product is too valuable for firm H to give up the non-loyal customers in the primary market. Consequently, firm L cannot establish a large user base for the primary product.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">=¯ − = h − c • k − h + c / k + 2h − 2c 2k + h − c ,</formula><p>Finally, it is worth mentioning that Proposition 1 by no means downplays the importance of obtaining high customer loyalty. This is because while firms' relative profit depends on whether or not is in the midrange, firm H 's absolute profit always increases with the size of its loyal customer segment regardless of whether it adopts a primary-product-driven strategy (i.e., when ∈ 0 or a secondary-product-driven strategy (i.e., when ∈ 1 . Therefore, as shown in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>, firm H always benefits from higher customer loyalty.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.">Market Share</head><p>It is also interesting to examine the impact of asymmetry in customer loyalty on firms' market shares in the primary product market. Because the size of this market is normalized to one in our model, the market share of firm i in the primary product market is equal to D iP . Proposition 2 follows. </p><formula xml:id="formula_5">  h = c h = 2k + c = h − c 2k + h − c ¯ = 1 2 (5)</formula><p>Proposition 2 shows that, similar to the loyalty window for firm L to obtain a higher profit than firm H , there exists a loyalty window, ¯ , for firm L to obtain a higher market share than firm H . Note that h and¯ given in Proposition 2 are higher thanh and given in Proposition 1 (h &gt;h,¯ &gt;¯ . This implies that the window for firm L's market share advantage is wider than that for its profit advantage. Hence, if firm H loses its advantage in profit, it also loses its potential advantage in market share. However, firm L's market share advantage does not guarantee its profit advantage.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5.">Predictions</head><p>The above lemma and propositions suggest that, in the presence of a cross-market network effect, asymmetry in customer loyalty affects firms' competitive strategies and their relative advantages in market share and profit. Specifically, our theoretical findings lead to the following three predictions:</p><p>• P1 (Pricing Strategy): In a market with a crossmarket network effect, sufficient asymmetry in customer loyalty leads to asymmetry in pricing strategy. Specifically, (a) when neither firm has a large loyalty base, both pursue a secondary-product-driven strategy, (b) when one firm has a sufficient loyalty advantage, the firm with loyalty advantage pursues a primary-product-driven strategy, but the firm with loyalty disadvantage pursues a secondary-productdriven strategy.</p><p>• P2 (Market Share): In a market with a cross-market network effect, the impact of loyalty on a firm's market share advantage in the primary product market is non-monotonic. Specifically, the market share advantage generated from a loyalty advantage can be less under a mid-range loyalty advantage than under a small or large loyalty advantage. It is even possible that a mid-range loyalty advantage results in a market share disadvantage.</p><p>• P3 (Profit): In a market with a cross-market network effect, the impact of loyalty on a firm's overall profit advantage from both the primary and the secondary product market is non-monotonic. Specifically, the profit advantage generated from a loyalty advantage (in the primary product market) can be less under a mid-range loyalty advantage than under a small or large loyalty advantage. It is possible that a mid-range loyalty advantage results in a profit disadvantage.</p><p>In the next section, we provide some empirical evidence gathered from the newspaper industry to examine our model predictions. The recent anecdotal evidence from the newspaper industry indicates a noticeable trend of the growing popularity of free newspapers, such as Metro and amNew York <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Carvajal 2004</ref><ref type="bibr">, Crain's New York Business 2005</ref>. This trend has imposed pressure on more established newspapers such as Murdoch's Sun in the United Kingdom (The Guardian 2005a). Interestingly, facing this trend, the New York Times has started to charge for its online content that formerly was free (The Guardian 2005b).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Empirical Evidence</head><p>To provide some empirical evidence for the external validity of our main theoretical results, we use data collected from the newspaper industry to examine some of our predictions. Notations used in our empirical analysis are summarized in the Table of Notations in the appendix.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Data and Measurement</head><p>We collected data from the Ayer Directory of Publications (ADP) <ref type="bibr">(1973)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1974)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1975)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1976)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1977)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1978)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1979)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1980)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1981)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1982)</ref>, an annual listing by town/ city of all local newspapers in the United States, published by Ayer &amp; Son, Inc. The period from 1973 to 1982 was chosen because it was the only period for which ADP was available to us for consecutive years. ADP lists the dates on which a newspaper began and ceased publication. It also provides information on subscription rates, circulation, and advertising rates for the many newspapers it lists.</p><p>Because the data do not provide direct measures of the sizes of firms' loyalty segments, we focus on towns/cities with two competing newspapers that entered the market at different times. For those towns/cities, we can reasonably assume that the newspaper that entered earlier had a loyalty advantage at the time when the later comer entered the market. Our samples included all towns/cities in the United States that satisfied the following three criteria: (1) at least one of the two newspapers entered the market between 1974 and 1979; (2) data on circulation, subscriber rates, and advertising rates were reported in the ADP; and (3) neither newspaper exited the market within the first three years after entry. A total of twenty-two cases satisfied these criteria within the period examined. In order to satisfy the last criterion, we did not use data from 1980 to 1982. Data from 1973 were used to measure pre-entry conditions if applicable.</p><p>Let j = 1 2 22 denote the incumbents (H firms) and j = 23 24 44 denote the entrants (L firms). Let T = −1 0 1 denote the year before entry, the year of entry, and the year after the entrant entered the market. A summary of our data is provided in Table <ref type="table">2</ref>. The following variables were used in our analysis:</p><p>Table <ref type="table">2</ref> Data Summary Note. The numbers in parenthesis are standard deviations. T − 1, T , and T + 1 are the year before the entry, at the entry, and after entry. * Circulation statements obtained from the publisher are for the latest date possible and generally represent an average circulation for six months preceding the compilation of the directory in which they appear.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">Incumbent N = 22 Entrant N = 22 T = −1 T = 0 T = 1 T = 0 T =</formula><p>* * Subscription rate is the per issue rate. * * * Black and white general line rates.</p><p>Subscription Rate. The subscription rates reported by ADP were annual fees paid by local subscribers. We converted the reported subscription rate to subscription rate per issue. We denote the subscription rate for firm j at time T as SR T j .</p><p>Advertising Rate. The advertising rates reported by ADP were black and white general line rates. The advertising rate for firm j at time t is denoted as AR T j .</p><p>Circulation. The circulation data reported by ADP were obtained from publishers that "generally represent an average circulation for six months preceding the compilation of the directory in which they appear." We denote firm j's circulation at time T as C T j .</p><p>Market Share of Circulation. To facilitate the crosssectional comparison of the circulation levels, we define the market share of circulation of firm j at time t T = −1 0 1 as MS T j = C T j /C 1 , <ref type="bibr">9</ref> where C 1 is the total circulation of the two competing newspapers after the entry of the second firm.</p><p>Incumbent's Penetration Level at Entry. We define the penetration level of incumbent j at the time of entry as IP j = MS 0 j . Because data on the size of the incumbent firms' loyal followings were not available to us, we use IP j as a proxy measure of the size of the loyal segment of incumbent j. This choice implicitly assumes that there exists a monotonic relation between the number of an incumbent's loyal subscribers at the time of entry and IP j .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Analysis and Results</head><p>Because data on firms' profits were not available, we focused on pricing strategies and market shares. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> More precisely, MS −1 should be interpreted as the incumbent's market coverage since it is a monopolist at T = −1.</p><p>Existence of Cross-Market Network Effect. First, we verify the existence of a cross-market network effect in our data. We ran simple regressions both before (T = −1 and after entries occurred (T = 1 :</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">   AR −1 j = −1 +h −1 C −1 j + j j = 1 2 22 AR 1 j = 1 +h 1 C 1 j + j j = 1 2 44 (6)</formula><p>The regression results are given in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref>. Circulation alone explains 42% and 24% of variances in advertising rate for the pre-entry monopoly market T = −1 and post-entry competitive market T = 1 , respectively. Given that advertising rates are also affected by many other factors not considered in the models (i.e., the quality of the newspapers and the type of readers), the regression results are satisfactory. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref> shows that circulation has a significant positive effect on advertising rate p &lt; 0 001) in both monopoly and duopoly markets, confirming the existence of a cross-market network effect in our data. It is also interesting to note from Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref> that the strength of the cross-market network effect, h, is about the same in both pre-entry and post-entry markets h = 0 003 .</p><p>Impact of Loyalty on Pricing Strategy Subscription Rate . Based on P1, we expect that the difference in post-entry subscription rate between the incumbent and the entrant is not significant when the incumbent's penetration level at the time of entry is small, but is positive when such a penetration level is large.</p><p>To test this, we define SR j = SR j 1 − SR j+22 1 / SR j 1 to measure the difference in the post-entry subscription rate between incumbent j and the corresponding entrant. We then divide the sample into two groups based on the median-split of IP j . Each group consists of 11 incumbents. In the group where IP j is low IP j &lt; 0 6 , the mean of SR j is −0 13 with standard error 0.66. As expected, the mean of SR j in this group is not significantly different from 0 (p &gt; 0 85 in a two-tail test). In the other group, where IP j is high IP j &gt; 0 6 , the mean of SR j is 0.37 with standard error 0.15. The mean of SR j in this group is significantly larger than 0 (p &lt; 0 02 in a one-tail test). This result is consistent with our prediction on the impact of loyalty on pricing strategy. Note that it is possible that there are other forces that may also drive such a price pattern. For example, when the incumbent's penetration level at the time of entry is large, the entry may have a higher need to offer price break to general trial since the quality of the new newspaper is unknown and the incumbent has established a large reader base. Impact of Loyalty on the Market Share. P2 suggests that the loyalty advantage has a positive effect on market share advantage, but this relationship is not linear. Our theoretical results given in Lemma 1 specify how MS changes with in two regions: a small loyalty difference, &lt; , and a large loyalty difference, &gt; . The functional forms of MS with regard to in Lemma 1 suggest that MS increases with in both regions but decreases at = . This functional form implies that MS can be smaller when is in a middle range than when is small or large. To test this, our data analysis focuses on the relationship between MS (the market share difference between the incumbent and the entrant) and IP (the incumbent's penetration level at entry) in two regions, with high and low values of IP, respectively. Specifically, we examine if MS increases with IP in both regions, but decreases with IP at the border of the two regions. The observations are sorted so that IP j is in ascending order. Let J denote the cutoff level between a high j &gt; J and low j ≤ J penetration level for the incumbent at the time of entry. Define D j as a dummy variable such that D j = 1 if j &gt; J and D j = 0 otherwise. The regression ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_8">7</ref>) is used:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">MS j = 0 + 1 D j + 2 IP j + 2 D j IP j + j (<label>7</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_9">)</formula><p>where MS j = MS 1 j − MS 1 j+22 is the difference between the incumbent's market share and the entrant's market share after the entry. To determine the cutoff level J , we empirically tested different cutoff levels, Dependent variable = MS j , where MS j = MS 1 j − MS 1 j+22 D i = 1 if j &gt; J and D j = 0 otherwise. Constant −0 866 0 000 * * D j −1 584 0 009 IP j 1 728 0 000 D j IP j 1 946 0 011 Adjusted R-square (maximized at J = 13) 0 929 * The results reported are for J = 13. * * The numbers in parentheses are the p-values in two-tail test. J = 0 1 22, and chose the one that maximizes the adjusted R-squared of the regression model ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_8">7</ref>).</p><p>The results of estimations are given in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">4</ref> (J = 13, Adjusted R-square = 0 929). Two regions are identified, with 13 and nine observations, respectively. All coefficients are significant (p &lt; 0 011, a two-tail test). In the data, we have MS 13 = 0 327 (with IP 13 = 0 663) but MS 14 = −0 095 (with IP 14 = 0 709). This is consistent with P2. Using the estimated coefficients (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">4</ref>), the relationship between MS and IP can be written as MS j = −0 866 + 1 728IP j for j ≤ 13 and MS j = −2 450 + 3 674IP j for j &gt; 13. As expected by P2, the predicted MS increases with IP in both regions, but decreases at the border of the two regions (i.e., MS 14 &lt; MS 13 . <ref type="bibr">10</ref> In addition, we can see that the coefficient of IP j is higher (3.674) for j &gt; 13 than for j ≤ 13 (1.728). This is also consistent with the results reported in Lemma 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Discussion and Conclusions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Robustness of Main Findings</head><p>To examine the robustness of our main findings, we relax several simplified assumptions in our basic model by allowing (a) a positive reservation price for switchers, k ≥ s &gt; 0; (b) both firms to have loyal customers; (c) a less restrictive lower bound of firms' prices (p 0 can be negative); and (d) three different competitive structures in the primary product market (i.e., a simultaneous-move game, an H -led sequentialmove game, and an L-led sequential-move game). The key findings derived from the basic model still hold under these more general conditions (see a technical appendix available on the Website of this journal for detail proofs).</p><p>The basic model uses a simple form, iS = hD iP , to establish the relationship between the two markets. To further explore the dependence of the strategies in the two markets, we can also explicitly model the competition in the secondary product market with heterogeneous buyers by adopting a model of horizontal differentiation à la <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Hotelling (1929)</ref>. The main results of our basic model still hold in such an extended model. The size of the loyalty window, l , for firm L to obtain a profit advantage can be as large as 2/7 in this case. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> One additional aspect of our basic model that may be worth exploring is the asymmetry in cross-market network effects generated by loyal and non-loyal customers. Such asymmetry is possible because the crossmarket network effect may not only depend on the size of the user base in the primary market, but also on the type of users. For example, in the newspaper market, the incremental value of an additional reader to an advertiser may depend on whether the reader has a high or low willingness to pay, because it is more likely for the former to purchase the advertised product than the latter. Hence, a reader with a high willingness to pay may generate a stronger cross-market network effect than a reader with a low willingness to pay. If we believe that loyal customers generally have a higher willingness to pay than nonloyal customers, then the network effect generated by the former may be higher than the latter. We can incorporate this possibility into our basic model by letting h and h denote the cross-market network effect generated by the loyals and non-loyals, respectively, with h &gt; h. Remark 1 follows.</p><p>Remark 1 (Asymmetric Cross-Market Network Effect). The loyalty window stated in Proposition 1 can still hold in the presence of asymmetric crossmarket network effect.</p><p>Remark 1 shows that the main result in our basic model is robust under an asymmetric cross-market network effect. However, from the derivations given in the appendix, the window of for firm L to outperform firm H becomes smaller as the difference between h and h increases. This is quite intuitive because it becomes more difficult for a firm with smaller loyal customer base to be more profitable if loyal customers in the primary market are much more attractive than non-loyals to customers in the secondary market.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Implications for Market Entry and</head><p>First-Mover Advantage/Disadvantage We explore the possible strategic implications of our main findings for market entry and entry deterrence decisions by extending our basic model to a twoperiod game. We consider an incumbent and a potential entrant. In Period 1, the incumbent can establish a loyal segment, 0 ≤ ≤ 0 ≤ 1, where 0 is the incumbent's maximum feasible loyalty-building level. We assume that the incumbent's cost of loyalty-building up to 0 is zero, but its cost to build a loyal segment larger than 0 is infinite. In Period 1, the incumbent decides its optimal level of loyalty-building to be effective in Period 2 with the anticipation of a potential entrant in Period 2. In Period 2, the entrant decides whether or not to enter the market at a fixed cost, F . The entrant enters if and only if its expected profit is higher than the fixed cost of market entry. If the entrant enters, firms decide their prices simultaneously. Otherwise, the incumbent decides its optimal price as a monopoly. We also assume that the incumbent in Period 1 cannot commit to its Period 2 price. <ref type="bibr">12</ref> We denote the incumbent and the entrant to be firm H and L, respectively. Other assumptions are the same as in the basic model.</p><p>Solving firms' maximization problem leads to a total of four cases, as summarized in Lemma 2.</p><p>Lemma 2 (Optimal Strategies in the Entry Game). The firms' optimal strategies depend on the incumbent's feasible loyalty-building level, 0 , and the entrant's fixed entry cost, F , as shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">5</ref>.</p><p>Lemma 2 shows that the optimal strategy of the incumbent after entry occurs is to charge a high price when 0 is large. This is consistent with <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Davis et al. (2004)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Hauser and Shugan (1983)</ref>, who suggest that responding with a price increase by the incumbent can be an optimal defensive strategy when a new product enters the market.</p><p>Lemma 2 also shows that an incumbent can earn a higher profit by strategically limiting its loyalty base even if loyalty-building is costless. Specifically, this "limited-loyalty" strategy is optimal when the incumbent's feasible loyalty-building level is in a mid-range and the entrant's entry cost is high (i.e., Case 2).</p><p>To understand this result, recall that the profit of the entrant maximizes at the midlevel of (see Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>). The entrant will enter the market only if its profit will be higher than the fixed cost of entry. If 0 is at the midlevel, it is possible for the incumbent to discourage the entrant from entering the market by building a smaller loyal base, * &lt; 0 , because the entrant's profit can be lower when * &lt; 0 than * = 0 . Therefore, it can be optimal for the incumbent to under-invest in customer loyalty so that it can keep a "lean and hungry look" <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Fudenberg and Tirole 1984)</ref> in order to deter entry.</p><p>Although we think this strategy of limiting loyalty base to deter entry is interesting, it should be applied  </p><formula xml:id="formula_10">p * HP 2 = 0 * = h − c 2k + h − c &lt; 0 Low High Maximum Yes Can be Entrant 3 F ≤ F 0 p * HP 2 = k ( * = 0 Small Low Maximum Incumbent 4 ( 0 ≤ (p * HP 2 = 0 ( * = 0    Yes if F &lt; F No if F ≥ F Where: = 0 5 h − c k + 0 5 h − c = h − c k + h − c F 0 = k h − c 2k + h − c F = h − c 1 − 0 F = 0 5 h − c 1 − 0</formula><p>with caution for two reasons. First, literature on entry deterrence (see Gruca and Sudharshan 1995 for a detailed review) has suggested many strategic actions for an incumbent firm to take for entry deterrence.</p><p>Because strong loyalty always benefits the incumbent firm after the entrant's decision is made (no matter whether entry occurs or not), limiting its loyalty base should not be used as a primary strategy to deter entry when other strategic actions for entry deterrence are available. Second, firms with a technology advantage sometimes prefer to keep their technologies proprietary, which results in a limited loyalty base. Such strategy, however, often invites competitive entry, for example, Apple Computer's "firewire" technology invites competition from USB2. However, the technologically advantageous firms, such as Apple Computer, may still enjoy a high profit because they can charge high prices. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> Proposition 3 below is a direct extension of Proposition 1 in a two-period setting when the loyalty level is allowed to be determined endogenously.</p><p>Proposition 3 (Second Mover Advantage). In markets with a cross-market network effect, an entrant firm with a disadvantage in customer loyalty can earn a higher profit than the incumbent firm with an advantage in customer loyalty. Specifically, the entrant can outperform the incumbent if (a) the incumbent's feasible loyalty level is at a midlevel, and (b) the entrant has a low entry cost (i.e., Case 3 in Lemma 2).</p><p>When the entry is inevitable (i.e., a low cost of entry), with a mid-range of loyalty, the incumbent earns a higher profit by focusing on its loyal customers than by competing with the entrant for <ref type="bibr">13</ref> We thank the editor for pointing out this issue and providing the example.</p><p>switchers. As explained in our basic model, this offers the entrant an opportunity to enjoy a higher profit than the incumbent. Previous marketing literature on pioneer advantage suggests various sources of pioneer advantage or disadvantage <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Robinson and Fornell 1985</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">, Robinson 1988</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, Golder and Tellis 1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">, Kalyanaram et al. 1995</ref>. Complementing this stream of literature, our results in Proposition 3 and Lemma 2 indicate that customer loyalty established by a pioneer in a market with a cross-market network effect can be another important source of advantage or disadvantage for the pioneer. In particular, a pioneer with a midlevel number of loyal followers is likely to be leapfrogged by a second comer in a market with a cross-market network effect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we investigate the competitive implications of asymmetric loyalty in the market when presented with a cross-market network effect. We show that:</p><p>• Different from the traditional markets where an advantage in customer loyalty leads to an advantage in profit, in markets with a cross-market network effect, a firm with an advantage in customer loyalty can be leapfrogged by its rival in both profit and market share if its advantage in loyalty is neither sufficiently small nor sufficiently large.</p><p>• A cross-market network effect generates strategic dependence between the two markets such that the more competitive the secondary product market the more likely it will be for the firms to adopt differentiated pricing strategy in the primary product market, and the more likely that the firm with a loyalty disadvantage will be the market share leader in the primary product market.</p><p>• If the fixed cost of entry is low and the incumbent can only build a mid-sized loyalty segment, a secondmover advantage may endogenously occur because the entry cannot be deterred and the entrant may leapfrog the incumbent in profit.</p><p>Our findings indicate that a loyalty advantage may not lead to a profit advantage for an incumbent firm in markets with a cross-market network effect, but this by no means discounts the importance of building customer loyalty. As we have shown in this paper (also see Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>), a firm's profit in competition increases with the level of its customer loyalty, and the firm with very high customer loyalty can always outperform its competitor in both profit and market share. Therefore, it is still crucial for an incumbent firm in an industry characterized by a cross-market network effect to establish a sufficiently high level of customer loyalty.</p><p>Our study contributes to the literature on network effects by focusing on an understudied type of network effect: the cross-market network effect. It also complements the literature on first-mover advantage/disadvantage by showing a new source of first-mover advantage/disadvantage for industries presented with a cross-market network effect. In a broad sense, as suggested by <ref type="bibr">Cabral and Villas-Boas (2005)</ref>, the inter-temporal dependency of a firm's demand/profit can also be regarded as a type of cross-market network effect. For example, due to the existence of switching costs, a firm's demand/profit in the future may depend on its demand in the present <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Klemperer 1995)</ref>. Analogous to the crossmarket network effect discussed in this paper, we may treat the future period as the market of the secondary product market and the present as the primary product market. In that case, our findings may also be applied in the context of an inter-temporal market dependency. However, future research is desirable to further investigate the interaction of customer loyalty management and inter-temporal market dependency in a dynamic setting.</p><p>Some limitations to our study suggest directions for future research. First, data collected from the newspaper industry were used to examine the pricing and market share implications generated from our theoretical model. Even though our empirical results were largely consistent with those implications, there were many shortcomings in our data. For example, we lack a good measure of consumer loyalty and firms' profits. It would be worthwhile in future empirical research to test the findings of this paper using more detailed data as well as data from different industries. Second, our theoretical model did not consider the potential means for a firm with a loyalty advantage to price discriminate among loyal versus non-loyal consumers, e.g., by using targeted promotions or introducing a "fight brand" to the low-end customers.</p><p>Future research should also incorporate those strategies into the analysis. We expect price discrimination to benefit a firm with a large loyal customer base as long as the value of its demand in the product of primary market to the customers in the product of secondary market does not deteriorate severely due to such a practice. Finally, we assume that each customer purchases at most one unit of the primary product. Future research may explore potential usage differences between loyal versus non-loyal customers to further enrich our findings. paper, the participants at the Marketing Science Conference 2001 and the seminar participants at the Wharton School of the University of Pennsylvania and University of British Columbia for their helpful comments, and the editor, area editor, and three anonymous reviewers for their constructive suggestions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix. Table of Notations Theoretical Model:</head><p>Notations in Basic Model i: Firms (high-or low-loyalty firm), i = H, L. j: Type of products (primary or secondary product), j = P , S. : The size of loyal segment of firm H. k, s: The reservation price of the loyal and non-loyal customers, respectively. p ij : firm i's price for type j product. D ij : firm i's demand for type j product. ij , i : firm i's profit from type j product, and firm i's total profit, respectively. h: Parameter that measures the strength of the crossmarket network effect. p 0 : The lower bound of price in the product of primary market. c: Marginal cost.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additional Notations Used in §4 D S</head><p>iP : firm i's demand from non-loyals in the primary product market. m: The number of buyers in the secondary product market. d i : The customer's distance to firm i on the unit line.</p><p>t: The disutility per unit distance.</p><p>0 : The incumbent's maximum feasible loyalty-building level. F : The fixed cost of entry. p * HP 2 : The incumbent's optimal period 2 price in the twoperiod model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Empirical Analysis</head><p>j: Firms, j = 1 2 22 = the incumbents, j = 23 24 44 = the entrants. T : Time, T = −1 0 1 denote the year before, when, and after the entry. SR T j : firm j's subscription rate at time T . AR T j : firm j's advertising rate at time T .</p><p>Marketing Science 26(1), pp. 52-66, © 2007 INFORMS C T j : firm j's circulation at time T . MS T j : firm j's market share of circulation at time T .</p><p>IP j : The penetration level of incumbent j at the time of entry. J : The cutoff level between a high j &gt; J and low j ≤ J penetration level for the incumbent at the time of entry. D j : Dummy variable, D j = 1 if j &gt; J and D j = 0, otherwise.</p><p>A.1. Justification of the Profit Specification iS = hD iP We provide a justification of the profit specification iS = hD iP made in §2 in the context of the circulation industry.</p><p>In the circulation industry, firms sell newspapers or magazines to readers as the primary products and sell advertising space as the secondary product. We assume a representative advertiser with a fixed budget h that must be spent between the two firms in the market (it is equivalent to assume that there are n homogeneous advertisers, each with a budget of h/n to spend). Let D iS be the amount of advertising on firm i, p iS be firm i's unit rate for advertising, and e D iS ) be the average gain of advertising from reaching a reader of firm i. We assume that the advertising response function e D iS ) follows the typical S-shape, which is approximated by e D iS = ln D iS if D iS &gt; D 0 &gt; 1 and e D iS = 0 if otherwise. Then the total gain of the advertiser from advertising through firm i is D iP ln D iS if D iS &gt; D 0 and is 0 if otherwise, where D iP is the total number of readers of firm i.</p><p>For a profit maximizing firm, p iS will be such so that D iS &gt; D 0 . Otherwise, the firm obtains no revenue from the advertiser. The advertiser maximizes the total gain of advertising subject to the budget constraint, which leads to Solving the above optimization problem results in iS = p iS D iS = hD iP , which gives the profit specification assumed in §2. We can see that the strength of the cross-market network effect, h, in this context can be interpreted as the budget (expenditure) per reader by the advertiser (as the size of reader's market is normalized to 1).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.2. Proofs of Lemmas and Propositions</head><p>Proof of Lemma 1. From firm H's profit function given in (3), firm H will optimally set p HP = k if and only if k − c + h &gt; 0 5 1 + h − c , i.e., if &gt; = h − c / 2k + h − c . Otherwise, firm H will set p HP = 0. Given this condition, the corresponding prices, market shares and profits for both firms under &gt; and ≤ can be directly obtained from equations (2) and (3). The results are reported in the Table <ref type="table">1</ref> in Lemma 1.</p><p>Proof of Proposition 1. From Lemma 1, if ≤ , = H − L = h − c &gt; 0 always holds as h is assumed to be larger than c. If &gt; , then = H − L = k + 2 h − c − h − c &lt; 0 leads to &lt;¯ = h − c / k + 2 h − c . Therefore, the condition for &lt; 0 is &lt; &lt;¯ . To ensure &lt;¯ , we must have h &lt;h = k + c. In addition, &gt; 0 implies h &gt; c. Hence, the necessary and sufficient condition for &lt; 0 is c = h &lt; h &lt;h and &lt; &lt;¯ .</p><p>Proof of Proposition 2. From Lemma 1, if ≤ , MS P = D HP − D LP = ≥ 0 always holds. If &gt; , then MS P = 2 − 1 leads to &lt;¯ = 1/2. Therefore, the condition for MS P &lt; 0 is &lt; &lt;¯ . To ensure &lt;¯ we must have h &lt;h = 2k + c. In addition, &gt; 0 implies h &gt; c. Hence, the necessary and sufficient condition for MS P &lt; 0 is c = h &lt; h &lt;h and &lt; &lt;¯ .</p><p>Proof of Remark 1. Let D S iP , i = 1 2 denote firm i's demand in the primary market among the non-loyals. Similar to the results in our basic model, firm L will adopt a secondary-product-driven strategy at a low price, p LP = 0. But firm H has two options: (1) adopting a "primaryproduct-driven" strategy at a high price, or (2) adopting a "secondary-product-driven" strategy at a low price, depending which strategy leads to higher profit. If h </p><formula xml:id="formula_11">− c + 0 5 1 − h − c &lt; k + h − c ,</formula><formula xml:id="formula_12">− c + 0 5 1 − h − c &lt; k + h − c and 1 − h − c &gt; k + h − c , i.e., = h − c / 2k + h − c &lt; &lt; h − c / k + h + h − 2c =¯ .</formula><p>To ensure &lt;¯ and¯ &gt; 0, we must have c = h &lt; h &lt; h &lt; h = k + c. Hence, the necessary and sufficient condition for H &lt; L is h &lt; h &lt; h &lt;h and &lt; &lt;¯ . We can seē − decreases with h − h because¯ = h − c / k</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">+ h + h − 2c = h − c / k + h − h + 2 h − c decreases as h − h increases.</formula><p>Proof of Lemma 2. The incumbent's optimal price in Period 2 is: Monopoly Market:</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">p * HP 2 =    k if h + k − c &gt; h − c 0 otherwise (A1)</formula><p>Duopoly Market:</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">p * HP 2 =    k if h + k − c &gt; 0 5 h − c 1 + 0 otherwise (A2)</formula><p>The entrant's entry decision depends on the cost of entry, F , and profit, L . The latter, as shown in (A3), depends on the incumbent's price:</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">L =              0 5 h − c 1 −</formula><p>if The incumbent prices low p HP 2 = 0 h − c 1 − if The incumbent prices high p HP 2 = k (A3)</p><p>The entrant will enter if L &gt; F as shown in (A4):</p><p>The entrant:</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">            </formula><p>Enter if 0 5 h−c 1− &gt;F Not Enter, otherwise when p HP 2 = 0 Enter if h−c 1− &gt;F Not Enter, otherwise when p HP 2 = k (A4)</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Profits of Competing Firms</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>62</head><label></label><figDesc>Marketing Science 26(1), pp.52-66, © 2007 INFORMS    </figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>max D HS D LS D HP ln D HS + D LP ln D LS s.t. p HS D HS + p LS D LS ≤ h</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>D S iP = 1 − if p iP &gt; p 3−iP . Otherwise, D S iP = 0. Firms' profit can be written as    H = p HP − c + D S HP + h + hD S HP L = p LP − c D S LP + hD S LP</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>then we have p HP= k, p LP = 0, H = k + h − c , and L = 1 − h − c . If h − c + 0 5 1 − h − c ≥ k + h − c , then p HP = 0, p LP = 0, H = h − c + 0 5 1 − h − c , and L = 0 5 1 − h − c .H &lt; L occurs if and only if h</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Regression Results: Existence of Cross-Market Network Effect</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Dependent variable = advertising rate ($)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>T =−1 (Monopoly)</cell><cell>T = 1 (Competition)</cell></row><row><cell>Constant</cell><cell>0.128 (0.000)  *</cell><cell>0.160 (0.000)</cell></row><row><cell>Circulation (000)</cell><cell>0.003 (0.001)</cell><cell>0.003 (0.001)</cell></row><row><cell>R 2</cell><cell>0.42</cell><cell>0.24</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>*   The numbers in parentheses are the p-values in two-tail test.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Regression Results: Change in Market Share *</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Results for Lemma 2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Market condition</cell><cell cols="2">Incumbent's decision</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Feasible</cell><cell>Entry</cell><cell>Optimal</cell><cell></cell><cell>Entrant's decision</cell><cell>Profit</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>loyalty</cell><cell>cost</cell><cell>price</cell><cell>Optimal loyalty</cell><cell>entering (Y/N)</cell><cell>advantage</cell><cell>Case</cell></row><row><cell>High</cell><cell></cell><cell>High</cell><cell>Maximum</cell><cell>  Yes if F &lt; F</cell><cell>Incumbent</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>( 0 ≥</cell><cell></cell><cell>p  *  HP 2 = k</cell><cell>(  *  = 0</cell><cell> No if F ≥ F</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Mid-range</cell><cell>High</cell><cell>Low</cell><cell>Non-maximum</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>Incumbent</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>( &lt; 0 &lt;</cell><cell>F&gt;F 0</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Another paper relating to this literature is<ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Pauwels and Srinivasan (2004)</ref>, which examines the impact of store brand entry on the performance of the incumbent brands. A recent review paper<ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Soberman and Gatignon 2005)</ref> calls for more research on the factors determining the degree to which a market will be dominated by a first mover.4  For example,<ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Katz and Shapiro (1985)</ref>,<ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Farrell and Saloner (1986)</ref>, Gandal (1992, 1993),<ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Xie and Sirbu (1995)</ref>, Padmanabhan et al. (1997), Gupta et al. (1999), Ofek and Sarvary (2001),</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">Note that as commented by<ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Wernerfelt (1991)</ref>, "While the concept of brand loyalty has been used extensively in the marketing literature, the field has not reached consensus on a single definition." Our definition of loyalty is consistent with<ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Narasimhan (1988)</ref>,<ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Chen et al. (2001)</ref>, and segmentation literature where loyalty is defined by consumer preference.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">For example, in the plug-in software industry, many firms give away their primary product (e.g., Adobe Viewers). Free newspapers such as Metro and amNewYork are also gaining popularity<ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Carvajal 2004</ref>).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="10">The predicted MS is 0.28 and 0.15 at j = 13 and j = 14 respectively as IP 13 = 0 663 and IP 14 = 0 709 in the data. The actual values of MS in the data also decrease at the border of j = 13 MS = 0 327 and j = 14 MS = −0 095 .</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="11">The details can be found in a technical appendix available on the Website of this journal and in a working paper by the authors upon request.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="12">Our results in Lemma 2 and Proposition 3 will not be qualitatively different if we allow the incumbent to commit to its second period price in the first period.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank Qi Wang for her help in data collection, Peter Golder for his comments on an early version of this</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Marketing Science 26(1), pp. <ref type="bibr">52-66, © 2007 INFORMS 65</ref> Finally, the incumbent chooses the optimal loyalty level, * , that maximizes its profit:</p><p>The optimization problem specified in Equation (A5) leads to four exhaustive and mutually exclusive cases below.</p><p>This case corresponds to the High Feasible Loyalty case in Lemma 2. In this case, the incumbent can obtain a higher profit by setting p HP = k and = 0 regardless of firm L's entering decision. Therefore, we have</p><p>Case 2 and 3. 0</p><p>These two cases correspond to the Mid-range Feasible Loyalty case in Lemma 2. In these cases, if firm H is a monopoly, it can obtain a higher profit by setting p HP = 0 to get all the consumers than by setting p HP = k and * = 0 . However, firm H can attract all the consumers only if firm L does not enter. Therefore, firm H will discourage firm L from entering if it can successfully do so. For this purpose, firm H should choose to minimize firm L's profit after entering. From firm L's profit function given in equation (A3), L is minimized at * that solves 0 5</p><p>firm L does not enter so that firm H 's deterrence strategy works. We have p HP = 0 and H = h − c. This corresponds to Case 2 in Lemma 2.</p><p>However, if</p><p>, firm L will enter anyway so that firm H's deterrence strategy cannot work. In this situation, it is optimal for firm H to set * = 0 and p HP = k because 0 5</p><p>This corresponds to Case 3 in Lemma 2. We can see that</p><p>which results in the same conditions as those given in Proposition 1.</p><p>Case 4. 0 k + h − c ≤ 0 5 h − c 1 + 0 This case corresponds to the Small Feasible Loyalty case in Lemma 2. In this case, it is always optimal for firm H to set * = 0 and p HP = 0 regardless of firm L's entering decision. Therefore, we have * = 0 , p HP = 0, L = 0 5 • h − c 1 − 0 , H = 0 5 h − c 1 + 0 &gt; L if F &lt; F = L and H = h if F ≥ L . Firm L enters if L − F &gt; 0.</p><p>Proof of Proposition 3. This results directly from the derivations of Case 3 in Lemma 2.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Indirect network externality effects on product attributes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amiya</forename><surname>Basu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tridib</forename><surname>Mazumdar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Raj</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="221" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Big media, little blogosphere</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-10-24" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Business Week</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bertrand supertraps</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luis</forename><forename type="middle">M B</forename><surname>Cabral</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="599" to="613" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Miguel Villas-Boas</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consumer preference formation and pioneering advantage</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kent</forename><surname>Nakamoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="298" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fast-reading free papers win readers and imitators</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Doreen</forename><surname>Carvajal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New York Times</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">C10</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004-10-18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of standards competition on consumers: Effectiveness of product information and advertising formats</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amitav</forename><surname>Chakravarti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jinhong</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="224" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pricing and efficiency of a circulation industry: The case of newspapers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vivek</forename><surname>Chaudhri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inform. Econom. Policy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="76" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual marketing with imperfect targetability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yuxin</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chakravarthi</forename><surname>Narasimhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">John</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Network effects, software provision and standardization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Church</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Neil</forename><surname>Gandal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Indust. Econom. XL</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="104" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Complementary network externalities and technological adoption</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Church</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Neil</forename><surname>Gandal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Indust. Organ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="260" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Free AM, metro papers pressing paid dailies</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-04-18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Crain&apos;s New York Business</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Entry, pricing, and product design in an initially monopolized market</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kevin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Topel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="S188" to="S225" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Jersey dailies discount ABC rule</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">&amp;</forename><surname>Editor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Publisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002-03-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Installed base and compatibility: Innovation, product preannouncements, and predation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Farrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Garth</forename><surname>Saloner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="940" to="955" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The fat-cat effect, the puppydog ploy and the lean and hungry look</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Drew</forename><surname>Fudenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jean</forename><surname>Tirole</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="361" to="366" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Murdoch worried as metro eats into sales of the sun</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">The</forename><surname>Guardian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-02-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">New York Times gambles on fees for online content: &quot;National&quot; brand sees Web advertising tailing off as market matures</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">The</forename><surname>Guardian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-05-18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The advantage of being first</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Glazer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="473" to="480" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Products vs. advertising: Media competition and the relative source of firm profits</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Godes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elie</forename><surname>Ofek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Miklos</forename><surname>Sarvary</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Working paper</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pioneer advantage: Marketing logic or marketing legend?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Golder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gerard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Tellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="158" to="170" />
			<date type="published" when="1993-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A framework for entry deterrence strategy: The competitive environment, choices, and consequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Gruca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sudharshan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="1995-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling the evolution of markets with indirect network effect: An application to digital television</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Jain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sawhney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="396" to="416" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empirical analysis of indirect network effects in the market for personal digital assistants</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nair</forename><surname>Harikesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pradeep</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jean-Pierre</forename><surname>Dube</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quant. Marketing Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="58" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Defensive marketing strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="359" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stability in competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Hotelling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">153</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="1929" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xie</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cross-Market Network Effect with Asymmetric Customer Loyalty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="52" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Order of market entry: Established empirical generalizations, emerging empirical generalizations, and future research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gurumurthy</forename><surname>Kalyanaram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Glen</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Urban</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="G212" to="G221" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Network externalities, competition, and compatibility</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carl</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="424" to="440" />
			<date type="published" when="1985-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competition when consumers have switching costs: An overview with applications to industrial organization, macroeconomics, and international trade</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Klemperer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="515" to="539" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">First-mover advantage</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marvin</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Lieberman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Montgomery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Strategic Management J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="58" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The timing of competitive market entry: An exploratory study of new industrial products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gary</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lilien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eunsang</forename><surname>Yoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="568" to="585" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dual emphasis and the long-term financial impact of customer satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Mittal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eugene</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Vikas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Akin</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sayrak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="544" to="555" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Pandu Tadikamalla</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competitive promotional strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chakravarthi</forename><surname>Narasimhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="427" to="449" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Market entry strategy under firm heterogeneity and asymmetric payoffs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chakravarthi</forename><surname>Narasimhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z. John</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="327" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leveraging the customer base: Creating competitive advantage through knowledge management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elie</forename><surname>Ofek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Miklos</forename><surname>Sarvary</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1441" to="1456" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New products, upgrades, and new releases: A rationale for sequential product introduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Padmanabhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kannan</forename><surname>Surendera Rajiv</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="456" to="476" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Two-sided network effects: A theory of information product design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marshall</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Van Alstyne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1495" to="1504" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Who benefits from store brand entry?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Koen</forename><surname>Pauwels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shuba</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="364" to="390" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategic pricing and detailing behavior in international markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Pradeep</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ramarao</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Desiraju</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="80" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sources of market pioneer advantage: The case of industrial goods industries</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="94" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sources of market pioneer advantage in consumer goods industries</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Claes</forename><surname>Fornell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="305" to="317" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Platform competition in two-sided markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jean-Charles</forename><surname>Rochet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jean</forename><surname>Tirole</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Eur. Econom. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="990" to="1029" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Network effects and competition: An analysis of the home video game industry. Strategic Management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Shankar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bayus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="375" to="384" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Research issues at the boundary of competitive dynamics and market evolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Soberman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hubert</forename><surname>Gatignon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="165" to="174" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">First in, first out? The effects of network externalities on pioneer survival</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gary</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Raji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arvind</forename><surname>Lilien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Rangaswamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="58" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Marketing strategies for products with crossmarket network externalities. Working paper, Yale School of Management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Strauss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<pubPlace>New Haven, CT</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Product strategy for innovators in markets with network effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Baohong</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jinhong</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Henry</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="243" to="254" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Audit bureau moves to change magazine rules</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wall Street Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-03-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Intra-standard competition: Impact of supporting-firm-base and stage-dependent competitive interaction. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jinhong</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<pubPlace>Gainesville, FL</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Florida</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Brand loyalty and market equilibrium</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Birger</forename><surname>Wernerfelt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="229" to="245" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Price competition and compatibility in the presence of positive demand effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jinhong</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marvin</forename><surname>Sirbu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="909" to="926" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
