<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Invited Commentary-Why Does Poor Service Prevail?</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
							<email>egerstner@ucdavis.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Barak</forename><surname>Libai</surname></persName>
							<email>libai@post.tau.ac.il</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of California</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">AOB IV</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>One Shields Avenue</addrLine>
									<postCode>95616</postCode>
									<settlement>Davis</settlement>
									<region>California</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Recanati Graduate School of Business Administration</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tel Aviv University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>69978</postCode>
									<settlement>Tel Aviv</settlement>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Invited Commentary-Why Does Poor Service Prevail?</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 06 2506 0601</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1050.0154</idno>
					<note type="submission">received June 14, 2005, and did not require revision; processed by Subrata Sen.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:24+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In their article "Marketing Models of Service and Relationships," <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Rust and Chung (2006)</ref> provide a detailed and useful review of service and relationship marketing models and outline interesting new directions for future research. One would hope that the recent attention to service marketing will help services improve financial performance while improving customer satisfaction and loyalty.</p><p>Recent reports in the popular media, however, suggest that service quality and customer satisfaction are declining. "It's a Service Economy, But Where's the Service?" wondered the author of a New York Times article a few years ago <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Miller 1997)</ref>, and "Why Service Stinks?" asked a Business Week cover story <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Brady 2000)</ref>. According to the latter, "studies by groups ranging from the Council of Better Business Bureaus Inc. to the University of Michigan vividly detail what consumers already know: Good service is increasingly rare. From passengers languishing in airport queues to bank clients caught in voicemail hell, most consumers feel they're getting squeezed by Corporate America's push for profits and productivity." More recently, a Wall Street Journal article titled "Cases of 'Customer Rage' Mount as Bad Service Prompts Venting" suggests that "U.S. companies are driving their customers crazy" <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Spencer 2003)</ref>.</p><p>The purpose of this comment is to briefly discuss why, in light of all the research <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Rust and Chung (2006)</ref> point to, poor service may still prevail. We review some of the existing marketing models aimed at addressing this issue and suggest directions for future Although invited commentaries are not formally peer-reviewed and represent the opinion of the author, authors were carefully chosen based on their outstanding expertise in the areas of their respective commentaries. research. To do so, we distinguish between unintentional poor service and intentional poor service.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Unintentional Poor Service</head><p>Poor service results from poor selection of employees, lack of training, service process failures, or misalignment of incentives <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Loveman 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">, Chase and Stewart 1993</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">, Hauser et al. 1994</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">, Chu and Desai 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">, Chu et al. 1998</ref>) and, more generally, gaps in organizational knowledge and perceptions <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Zeithaml et al. 1990)</ref>.</p><p>Clearly, we are far away from eliminating unintended poor service. In fact, the law of unintended consequences used by economists and other social scientists states that the actions of people, organizations, and governments always have unanticipated or "unintended" effects. Moreover, working to eliminate all service failure contingencies may be counterproductive <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Rust et al. 2002)</ref>.</p><p>Still, an intriguing research question emerges: Does poor service exist by design? Next we review marketing models that explain how intentional poor service may prevail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Intentional Poor Service</head><p>Service Customization Service providers who apply CRM view customers as assets <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Rust et al. 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">, Shugan 2005</ref>. Advances in technologies and database management techniques enable managers to effectively customize service based on customer profitability <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Shugan 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">, Rust et al. 2000</ref>. One implication of this approach is that customers are sorted into service tiers, with poor service delivered to low-tier customers <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Brady 2000)</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Service Differentiation</head><p>Poor service also prevails because sellers strategically differentiate themselves according to the service quality they provide. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Gerstner et al. (1993)</ref> and  show that retailers may intentionally use hard-selling techniques or reduce service systematically to differentiate themselves from retailers who use soft-selling techniques with better service. Under this differentiation strategy all retailers profit compared to a strategy in which both retailers offer good service. Poor service also results when retailers deliberately limit product availability in order to "up sell" more expensive products <ref type="bibr">Gerstner 1987, Balachander and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Farquhar 1994)</ref> or when they use bait-and-switch tactics <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Gerstner and Hess 1990;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Lazear 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Hess and Gerstner 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr">Wilkie et al. 1998a, b)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Switching Costs</head><p>According to the "service profit chain" paradigm, investing in employee recruitment, training, and retention leads to increased service quality, customer satisfaction and retention which eventually results in profit improvements <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Heskett et al. 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">, Loveman 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, Kamakura et al. 2002</ref>). An alternative to increasing customer retention and profits is creating switching costs that make it difficult for customers to defect to competitors <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Klemperer 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">, Sudhir 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">, Buschken 2004</ref>). If sellers use switching costs to retain customers as a substitute for improving customer satisfaction, service will deteriorate and poor service will prevail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Misleading Pricing</head><p>Service providers may believe that they will profit in the short run from unsatisfactory service. Consider for example department stores that advertise discounted items, but at the register the full price is charged <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Goodstein 1994, Goodstein and</ref><ref type="bibr">Escalas 1995)</ref>. Such "service failures" have been documented repeatedly by academic researchers and by the popular media. Amazingly, even when store managers were notified about the problem, they did not fix it. Is it possible that top management discourages such mistakes, but the local managers ignore them to show short-term profit results? Cases of misleading pricing such as billing overcharges and hidden fees exist in the banking, credit card, hotel, and utility service industries <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Thornton and Arndt 2003)</ref>. Customers who check their bills are able to question the charges and get a refund. The rest end up overpaying. Misleading practices, however, can hurt long-term profits if customer defections increase as a result.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>The popular media have drawn our attention to the deterioration of service quality and customer satisfaction in the United States. Did advancements in technology and service models encourage service providers to profit on the back of customers (who are denied good service)?</p><p>Future research should investigate this question and suggest ways to create win/win solutions that simultaneously improve customer satisfaction and profitability. For example, service providers with limited capacity such as hotels and airlines overbook capacity because some buyers who make reservations do not show up. Overbooking, however, creates customer dissatisfaction when the number of the overbooked customers who show up exceeds capacity, thus some customers are denied service by being "bumped" or "walked" <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Desiraju and Shugan 1999)</ref>.</p><p>Instead of bumping customers (which creates a win/lose situation), service providers can increase profits and improve customer satisfaction by overselling capacity at a high price and then offering compensation to low-paying customers who agree to cancel if high-paying customers show up at the last minute <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Biyalogorsky et al. 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Biyalogorsky et al. , 2000</ref>. Service providers can also encourage customers to cancel services in advance by offering refund incentives for cancellations <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Xie and Gerstner 2005)</ref>. These advance notices reduce the need to overbook capacity because of no shows, and therefore customers are not denied service. Moreover, the service provider has an opportunity to resell the cancelled service units, often at a higher price, so both customer and provider gain, converting the win/lose situation to a win/win.</p><p>Marketing models are typically designed to assist service providers in improving financial performance. Can they also show services how to improve profits and at the same time increase customer surplus and customer satisfaction?</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>602</head><label></label><figDesc>Marketing Science 25(6), pp.601-603, © 2006 INFORMS    </figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors appreciate the editing help of Michal Gerstner and Jacqueline Romo.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gaining more by stocking less: A competitive analysis of product availability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Balachander</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Subramanian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Farquhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overselling with opportunistic cancellations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eyal</forename><surname>Biyalogorsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ziv</forename><surname>Carmon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gila</forename><surname>Fruchter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="605" to="610" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Should airlines and hotels use short selling?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eyal</forename><surname>Biyalogorsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ziv</forename><surname>Carmon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gila</forename><surname>Fruchter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">OR/MS Today</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">22</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why service stinks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Diane</forename><surname>Brady</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bus. Week</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="118" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="2000-10-23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Invited Commentary: Why Does Poor Service Prevail?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Libai</forename><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>INFORMS 603</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="601" to="603" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Higher Profits Through Customer Lock-In</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joachim</forename><surname>Buschken</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<publisher>South-Western Educational Publishing</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Mason, OH</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fail-safing services. The Service Quality Handbook</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Chase</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<publisher>AMACOM</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="347" to="357" />
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Channel coordination mechanisms for customer satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Chu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Preyas</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Wujinand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Desai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="343" to="359" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Costs and benefits of hard-sell</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wujinand</forename><surname>Chu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hess</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="102" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing dissatisfaction, how to decrease customer opportunism by partial refunds</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wujinand</forename><surname>Chu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>James</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hess</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Service Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="140" to="154" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategic service pricing and yield management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ramarao</forename><surname>Desiraju</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="56" />
			<date type="published" when="1999-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Can bait and switch benefit consumers?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Eitan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hess</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="114" to="124" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Demarketing as a differentiation strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Eitan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wujin</forename><surname>Hess</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Chu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">UPC scanner pricing systems: Are they accurate?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ronald</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Goodstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="30" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving pricing accuracy at the supermarket: Electronic shelving systems and public policy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ronald</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Goodstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Public Policy Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="216" to="224" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Customer satisfaction incentives</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Duncan</forename><surname>Simester</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Birger</forename><surname>Wernerfelt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="327" to="350" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Service Profit Chain: How Leading Companies Link Profit and Growth to Loyalty, Satisfaction, and Value</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Heskett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Earl</forename><surname>Sasser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leonard</forename><surname>Schlesinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>The Free Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Loss leader pricing and rain check policy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hess</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="358" to="374" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Yes, bait and switch really benefits consumers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hess</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="283" to="289" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assessing the service-profit chain</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wagner</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kamakura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><forename type="middle">De</forename><surname>Vikas Metal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Rosa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">José Afonso Mazzon</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="294" to="317" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Marketing Sci.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competition when consumers have switching costs: An overview with applications to industrial organization, macroeconomics, and international trade</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Klemperer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="515" to="539" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bait and switch</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Edward</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Lazear</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="813" to="830" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Employee satisfaction, customer loyalty and financial performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gary</forename><surname>Loveman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Service Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">It&apos;s a service economy, but where&apos;s the service? New York Times</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julie</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>13CN.1</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Marketing models of service and relationships</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roland</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Rust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Tuck Siong Chung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="560" to="580" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Return on marketing: Using customer equity to focus marketing strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roland</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Rust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katherine</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Lemon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Valarie</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Zeithaml</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="127" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Getting return on quality: Revenue expansion, cost reduction, or both?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roland</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Rust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Moorman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Dickson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Driving Customer Equity, How Customer Lifetime Value is Reshaping Corporate Strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roland</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Rust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Valarie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katherine</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Zeithaml</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lemon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>The Free Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of advancing technology on marketing and academic research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="469" to="475" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Brand loyalty programs: Are they shams?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="185" to="193" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cases of &quot;customer rage&quot; mount as bad service prompts venting</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jane</forename><surname>Spencer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wall Street J</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-09-17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competitive pricing behavior in the auto market: A structural analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sudhir</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="42" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Thornton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Arndt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Fees! Fees! Fees! Bus. Week</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="98" to="102" />
			<date type="published" when="2003-09-29" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does &quot;bait and switch&quot; really benefit consumers?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wilkie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Carl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Mela</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gundlach</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="290" to="293" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does &quot;bait and switch&quot; really benefit consumers?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wilkie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Carl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Mela</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gundlach</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="282" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Service escape: Profit from customer cancellations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jinhong</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<pubPlace>Davis, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of California</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Manuscript</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Delivering Quality Service: Balancing Customer Perceptions and Expectations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Valarie</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Zeithaml</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Parasuraman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leonard</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Berry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<publisher>The Free Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
