<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Research Perspectives at the Interface of Marketing and Operations: Applications to the Motion Picture Industry</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Sanjeev</forename><surname>Swami</surname></persName>
							<email>sswami@iitk.ac.in</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Industrial and Management Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Indian Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kanpur</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">U.P</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Research Perspectives at the Interface of Marketing and Operations: Applications to the Motion Picture Industry</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 06 2506 0670</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1050.0163</idno>
					<note type="submission">received September 16, 2005, and was not revised; processed by Steven Shugan.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:31+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>motion picture industry</term>
					<term>operations</term>
					<term>scheduling</term>
					<term>decision support systems History: This invited commentary was</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>I n this comment, I discuss some research issues at the interface of marketing and operations particularly relevant to the motion picture industry. The major focus of my comments will be on the exhibition component of the motion picture value chain. Based on research findings and available data, I discuss the following issues: dynamic and interesting characteristics of the motion picture industry, the applicability of management science tools to artistic products, the practitioners' viewpoint, and the possibility of moving from specific to general research problems (and vice versa) in this field. Four promising research areas have been identified for marketing academics and researchers: (i) an integrated scheduling approach, (ii) relationship management and contract design, (iii) the role of forecasting accuracy in movie decision support systems, and (iv) the impact of digital conversion of movies on operations scheduling.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The review paper by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Eliashberg et al. (2006)</ref> in this issue of Marketing Science employs a different approach from most review articles, which typically are either methodological (e.g., state of the art in yield-management techniques) or substantive (e.g., short-and long-term effects of advertising) in nature. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Eliashberg et al. (2006)</ref> focus on what is known about an industry and take the perspective of industry executives in drawing conclusions and raising questions for future research. Not only are the authors to be praised for their timely review, but so is the editor of Marketing Science for inviting such an industry specific article.</p><p>My own interest in this research stream falls under the broad paradigm of implementing marketing strategy ("shelf space management") in an operationsdominated environment ("movie scheduling"), as noted by <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Shugan (2004)</ref> in his commentary, "Evolving to a New Dominant Logic in Marketing." Accordingly, I view my comment as discussion of research issues at the interface of marketing and operations in the motion picture industry. The major focus of my Although invited commentaries are not formally peer-reviewed and represent the opinion of the author, authors were carefully chosen based on their outstanding expertise in the areas of their respective commentaries. comments will be on the exhibition component of the motion picture value chain shown in the <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Eliashberg et al. (2006)</ref> article.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Motion Pictures: A Dynamic and Interesting Industry</head><p>Besides the broad indicators of the movie industry's importance as listed in the introduction of the article by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Eliashberg et al. (2006)</ref>, I consider movies one of the most dynamic industries in any country/culture because of the emergence of various innovations and technologies, such as digital production and exhibition, and newer retail formats, such as multiplexes or megaplexes ("Star Wars" Is Mother of Technology 2005, Jardin 2005). For example, as of March 2005, there were 73 multiplex locations in India in almost all major Indian cities with a multiplex/megaplex (Changing Face of Cinema 2005); in 1997 there were virtually none.</p><p>Movies are interesting because of their experiential nature, which requires cocreation by both producer and consumer to consummate the consumption. This aspect raises distinctive challenges, because the same product (i.e., the movie) may appeal differently to different people, making the task of forecasting movie's success a difficult one. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Hirschman and Holbrook (1982)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Holbrook and Hirschman (1982)</ref>, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Eliashberg and Sawhney (1994)</ref> have discussed the experiential aspects of such hedonic consumption goods. More research of this kind would greatly benefit the managers in need of assessing the market potential of their movies.</p><p>A key property of the demand pattern of the majority of movies that adds complexity to movie scheduling problems is exponential decay of demand over time. This demand perishability for multiple movies, coupled with a sliding scale box office revenuesharing contract between the distributor and the exhibitor, makes the movie scheduling problem a serious one (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Swami et al. 1999)</ref>. As a contrast, in inventory control problems, perishability is typically considered in terms of physical deterioration of a product (e.g., a grocery item with an expiration date). This view comes from the supply side of the product. The movie-scheduling problem adopts a "demand side view" in which the physical product (i.e., a copy of the movie) remains the same, but its demand declines over time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Can Hard Tools Be Applied to Soft (Artistic) Products?</head><p>The experiential characteristic of movies raises an interesting issue as to whether science, or a scientific approach, can be used in an arena in which both practitioners and researchers traditionally favor an artistic approach. <ref type="bibr">1</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Hirschman (1983)</ref> has also argued that artists do not actively engage in marketing their products because they primarily produce, or create, for "self." A general impression that appears to prevail even in the movie industry is that the scientific, or even technomanagerial, approaches are less relevant for the movie business. A major source of this impression stems from the considerable uncertainty inherent in predicting success, or market potential, of a movie. Every movie, with its unique mix of components, such as stars, music, and director, can be treated as a new product, which has short life cycle.</p><p>As discussed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Belson (1996)</ref>, however, several functions of the movie-making process are quite amenable to be approached as management science/ industrial engineering problems, such as systems analysis, queuing and simulation, engineering economy, productivity improvement, and work measurement and analysis. Recent research efforts have resulted in the use of fairly advanced scientific approaches, such as Markov decision processes and genetic algorithms for deriving normative implications for the movie industry, such as replacement policies <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Swami et al. 2001</ref>) and contract design <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Raut et al. 2005)</ref>.</p><p>The Practice-Oriented View <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Eliashberg et al. (2006)</ref> note that "industry practitioners rely heavily on tradition, conventional wisdom, and simple rules of thumb " This has also been our experience from consulting and interacting with managers in the operations-intensive exhibition environment in the movie industry <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Eliashberg et al. 2001)</ref>. Although there are variations in managers' abilities and propensities to adopt a rigorous or sophisticated analysis in decision making, the analytical part of decision making is primarily dominated by some use of spreadsheet software. Clearly, there appears to be a strong case for adopting a "50% manager, 50% model" approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Blattberg and Hoch 1990</ref>) in this industry.</p><p>In an implementation report, Eliashberg et al. ( <ref type="formula">2005</ref>) discuss the use of a close variant of <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Blattberg and Hoch's (1990)</ref> approach, which is labeled as "60% model, 40% manager." It was found that management completely followed the recommendations of the scheduling model, SilverScreener, in about 60% of the cases and used their own discretion, aided by model recommendation, the rest of the time. Managers always had more information and other concerns that could not be reflected in the model (e.g., distributor's pressure, unexpected events in the city, or participation in film festivals, etc.). Thus, it is recommended that the marketing modelers should adopt a flexible approach in an implementation setting in this industry and should not expect managers to follow the model's recommendation all the time.</p><p>One approach that works quite effectively is to generate a list of several feasible and good solutions for implementation, one of which the manager may choose. This would probably work out better than one "optimal" solution, which could be rejected by the manager for several reasons. Finally, model development in this industry could be done in an evolutionary manner. The movie-scheduling research began with a decision-support system (SilverScreener) having a promise of implementability, which was first applied at a single-theater setting <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Eliashberg et al. 2001</ref>) and subsequently at multiple theaters in a city <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Eliashberg et al. 2005)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>From Specific to General Problems</head><p>The SilverScreener model aimed at helping exhibitors decide each week which movies to continue playing and which to replace at the multiplex theater screens. The model is based on an integer-programming algorithm, which visualizes theater screens as parallel machines and movies as jobs. The resulting retail shelf space management problem can also be conceptualized as a general parallel machine-scheduling problem, which is quite well studied in operations management literature. However, in that literature, It appears that the industry-specific movie-scheduling problem helps define a new type of highly complex and general scheduling problem. Preliminary analysis suggests that even the single machine-scheduling problem, with deteriorating job values and maximization of cumulative job values, falls under the domain of so-called NP-hard problems <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Raut et al. 2005</ref>). Analysis of this general problem has applications in diverse areas, such as movie scheduling, remanufacturing environment with high-technology products <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Fleischmann et al. 1997)</ref>, and web object transmission <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Xia and Tse 2000)</ref>. Thus, I agree with the assertion by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Eliashberg et al. (2006)</ref> that "insights from the motion picture industry may help to better understand industries that share certain characteristics " Similar efforts could be extended to other areas, such as contract design, in which "surprisingly little work " has been done.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>From General to Specific Problems</head><p>The movie-scheduling problem could be addressed at two levels-macro and micro. The first level, macroscheduling, has been explained above in the context of SilverScreener model. Level two of the movie scheduling problem, microscheduling, addresses the screen-scheduling problem of a stand-alone theater on a within-the-day basis. The microscheduling problem can be formulated as an integer linear program. The computational complexity of the integer linear program increases remarkably with the addition of constraints in the model. One possible approach to solving this tough problem could follow a heuristic that is usually developed for a general knapsack problem. It can be applied to the industry-specific microscheduling problem by recognizing that the availability of each screen of a multiplex throughout the day is like a knapsack with limited capacity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A Partial List of Potential Research Problems</head><p>I conclude my comment with a description of research problems in which modeling efforts similar to ours could readily be extended.</p><p>• Integrated approach to macro-and microscheduling: Traditionally, large theater chains would plan for selection of movies (macro view) at the central planning department and, based on managerial assessment, give a list of the short-listed movies to the individual theaters, which would then solve their specific screen-scheduling problem on a daily basis (microview). However, it would be interesting to compare this approach with an integrated approach, which performs both macro and microplanning for the entire chain at the central level. This may require addressing challenging operational issues such as the schedules being identical on Thursday, Friday, Monday, and Tuesday on the one hand and on Saturday, Sunday, and Wednesday on the other hand. Also, because theaters have to advertise their schedules in advance for local information, this task may have to be performed more efficiently at the planning department level.</p><p>• Relationship management and contract design: Relationship management in the motion picture industry is considered by many as crucial. For example, one reason for the observed discrepancy between a scheduling model's recommendation and the actual schedule could be a distributor's pressure: "If you do not free up a screen for my new movies, I will keep it in mind when our new blockbuster is released." <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Filson et al. (2005)</ref> provide an interesting discussion of long-term contractual relationships in the movie industry. For example, exhibitors do not share concession revenues with distributors. Leaving concession revenue out of the contract creates a problem: The exhibitor has an incentive to reduce the ticket price after signing the contract, thus increasing traffic for more profitable concession sales, and sharing less with the distributor. However, a long-term relationship with the distributor can prevent the exhibitor from lowering ticket prices. Similar issues could be examined in future research concerning optimal contract design in the movie industry.</p><p>• Examining the forecasting part of the DSS (Decision Support Systems) equation: Forecasting + Scheduling → Effective DSS: The best scheduling (i.e., optimization) algorithms would be rendered useless unless they were supported by an equally efficient forecasting routine. It would be interesting to examine the sensitivity of the results of a DSS to the changes in forecasting effectiveness.</p><p>• Impact of digital conversion on scheduling: Switching to digital exhibition systems would give exhibitors greater flexibility in movie scheduling. For example, if a blockbuster generates more demand than anticipated, an exhibitor could dynamically reallocate screens that were not selling by adjusting their capacities to handle the overflow. In a nondigital scenario, such changes can be cumbersome, time consuming, and costly-requiring an additional print and a reel swap. It would be interesting to examine the impact of such changes in movies' format on real-time multiplex scheduling. Finally, researching movies implies a "road less traveled" for marketing academics. However, based on the review by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Eliashberg et al. (2006)</ref>, it can be concluded that this road is full of fruitful research opportunities and reasons for watching a lot of movies!!</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Marketing</head><label></label><figDesc>Science 25(6), pp. 670-673, © 2006 INFORMS the scheduling problem with maximization objective function and deteriorating job value function has rarely been examined.</figDesc></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1"><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Weinberg (1986)</ref> provides one of the very few published studies of arts managers actually using management science models.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">IEs and the movies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Belson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IIE Solutions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="1996-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Database models and managerial intuition: 50% models and 50% manager</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Blattberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Stephen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hoch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="887" to="899" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Changing Face of Cinema</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.screenindia.com/fullstory.php?content_id=10858" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-07-29" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling goes to Hollywood: Predicting individual differences in movie enjoyment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Eliashberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mohanbir</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Jehoshua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sawhney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1151" to="1173" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The motion picture industry: Critical issues in practice, current research, and new research directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jehoshua</forename><surname>Eliashberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anita</forename><surname>Elberse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A M</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Leenders</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="638" to="661" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implementing and evaluating Silverscreener: A marketing management support system for movie exhibitors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jehoshua</forename><surname>Eliashberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sanjeev</forename><surname>Swami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Weinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Berend</forename><surname>Wierenga</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Interfaces</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="S108" to="S127" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Operations research in the movies: Scheduling the multiplexes. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jehoshua</forename><surname>Eliashberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sanjeev</forename><surname>Swami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Weinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Berend</forename><surname>Wierenga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<pubPlace>British Columbia, Vancouver, Canada</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of British Columbia</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">At the movies: The economics of exhibition contracts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Darren</forename><surname>Filson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Switzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Portia</forename><surname>Besocke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econom. Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="354" to="369" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantitative models for reverse logistics: A review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fleischmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bloemhof-Ruwaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dekker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Van Der Laan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A E E</forename><surname>Van Nunen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Van Wassenhove</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. J. Oper. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aesthetics, ideologies and the limits of the marketing concept</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hirschman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hedonic consumption: Emerging concepts, methods and propositions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hirschman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Morris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Holbrook</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="92" to="101" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The experiential aspects of consumption: Consumer fantasies, feelings and fun</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Morris</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Holbrook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Elizabeth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hirschman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="132" to="140" />
			<date type="published" when="1982-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Cuban revolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xeni</forename><surname>Jardin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.wired.com/wired/archive/13.04/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Capacitated single machine scheduling with deteriorating job values</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Raut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sanjeev</forename><surname>Swami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Jatinder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Oper. Res. Soc. India</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-01-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Channel contracts in the motion picture industry. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Raut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sanjeev</forename><surname>Swami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eunkyu</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Weinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<pubPlace>Kanpur</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Indian Institute of Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SilverScreener: A modeling approach to movie screens management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sanjeev</forename><surname>Swami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jehoshua</forename><surname>Eliashberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Weinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="352" to="372" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Play it again, Sam? Optimal replacement policies for a motion picture exhibitor</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Swami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Sanjeev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Puterman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Weinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Manufacturing Service Oper. Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="369" to="386" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finance, operations and marketing conflicts in service firms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.sci-tech-today.com/story.xhtml?story_id=35013" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2004-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Star Wars&quot; is mother of technology</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ARTS PLAN: Implementation, evolution and usage</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Weinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="158" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Survey of single machine scheduling with application to web object transmission</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Tse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="www.eecs.berkeley.edu/pubs/techRpts/2000" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Dept. of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, University of California, Berkeley</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
