<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org A General Theory of Pass-Through in Channels with Category Management and Retail Competition</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Sridhar</forename><surname>Moorthy</surname></persName>
							<email>moorthy@rotman.utoronto.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Rotman School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Toronto</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>105 Street George Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>M5S 3E6</postCode>
									<settlement>Toronto</settlement>
									<region>Ontario</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Rotman School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Toronto</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>105 Street George Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>M5S 3E6</postCode>
									<settlement>Toronto</settlement>
									<region>Ontario</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org A General Theory of Pass-Through in Channels with Category Management and Retail Competition</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 05 2401 0110</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1030.0053</idno>
					<note type="submission">This paper was received August 30, 2001, and was with the author 14 months for 3 revisions; processed by Charles Weinberg.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:28+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>pass-through</term>
					<term>retailing</term>
					<term>category management</term>
					<term>game theory</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>The general problem of retail pass-through is the question of how a retailer reacts to changes in its costs-in particular, to what extent it changes its prices when its costs change. In the marketing literature, this is most often interpreted as trade promotion pass-through: How much of a manufacturer's promotional price-cut a retailer passes on to consumers (see, for example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Chevalier and Curhan 1976</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">, Walters 1989</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">, Neslin et al. 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">, Tyagi 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">, Kumar et al. 2001</ref>. But the problem is broader than that. Pass-through issues arise not only with trade promotions, but also when a manufacturer changes its regular wholesale price-downward or upward. 1 These 1 For example, recently Universal Music Group cut the wholesale price of its CDs "permanently" by 25% to deal with the problem of illegal Internet file-sharing <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Smith 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">, Strauss 2003</ref>. Mike Spinozzi, Borders' senior vice president and chief marketing officer, was quoted in the Seattle Times <ref type="bibr">(Veiga 2003, p. C1)</ref> as saying: "We intend on passing the reduction to the consumer."</p><p>An example of pass-through issues created by wholesale price increases is the reaction of cable TV operators to a price increase by ESPN for its sports programming <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Grant and Flint 2003)</ref>.</p><p>issues also arise independent of any manufacturerinitiated price changes. For instance, they arise when a retailer experiences an idiosyncratic cost shock (e.g., temporary change in its inventory position), or a marketwide cost shock (e.g., a change in currency exchange rates with respect to imported goods). <ref type="bibr">2</ref> This paper presents a general formulation of the pass-through problem as a comparative static of the retail price equilibrium. In this view, retail passthrough is a comparison between two price equilibria: one corresponding to the retailer's cost environment before the cost change, and the other corresponding to the cost environment after the cost change. The usual methodology for doing this is to model the retail price equilibrium as a function of retail costs, and examine the total derivatives of this function with respect to the various costs. I provide a general characterization Moorthy: A General Theory of Pass-Through in Channels Marketing Science 24(1), <ref type="bibr">pp. 110-122, © 2005 INFORMS 111</ref> of these derivatives for category-profit maximizing retailers competing with each other. The cost changes themselves are exogenous to my analysis-I study pass-through, not why costs change. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The comparative-static perspective virtually forces a broader interpretation of the pass-through problem by focusing attention on the structural features of the retailer's environment-features that are relevant to a variety of pass-through situations. For instance, whether the cost change at the retailer is a trade promotion or a permanent wholesale price reduction, the retailer's response depends on the brand's elasticity of demand, the number and nature of other brands in the product category, and its competitive position vis-à-vis other retailers. The same factors play a role when passing through cost increases or cost decreases and for manufacturerinitiated or manufacturer-independent cost changes. To be sure, there are additional dynamic issues that come into play when a dynamic cost change such as a trade promotion occurs-for example, forwardbuying and diversion-but their presence does not obviate the structural issues <ref type="bibr">(Neslin et al. 1995, Drèze and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Bell 2003)</ref>. A retailer making a forward-buying and diversion decision must consider pass-through as an option, for which the structural features discussed in this paper are relevant. In addition, of course, as <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Drèze and Bell (2003)</ref> point out, whereas forward-buying and diversion can be eliminated by administering the trade promotion as a scan-back promotion-the retailer is given the promotional price on the units it sells, not on the units it buys-the passthrough problem does not go away and continues to be informed by the structural features of the market. <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Tyagi (1999)</ref> was the first, to my knowledge, to model pass-through as a comparative static. I generalize Tyagi's formulation in several directions. First, I do not limit myself to brand-specific cost changes such as wholesale price changes. Instead, I consider the full complement of cost changes: brandand retailer-specific cost changes (such as temporary inventory positions in a brand that are idiosyncratic to a retailer), retailer-specific (nonbrand-specific) cost changes (such as a change in labor costs localized to an online retailer), and general (nonretailer-specific, nonbrand-specific) cost changes (such as a change in credit card or debit card fees). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> The point of recognizing this variety in cost changes is to argue that passthrough responses differ depending on the nature of the cost change being passed through (cf. Proposition 1). By not recognizing these distinctions, the existing literature does not present a complete picture of the pass-through issue, and more importantly, does not provide the right intuitions for understanding it.</p><p>Second, in contrast to much of the literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Tyagi 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">, Kumar et al. 2001</ref>, in my model there are multiple retailers handling multiple brands. By incorporating multiple brands in the category I am recognizing the retailer's category-management concerns. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> By incorporating multiple retailers I am recognizing the impact of retail competition. Intuitively, it seems obvious that both of these factors should be important to the pass-through issue. A retailer with several brands in a product category is concerned about category profit, not individual brands' profits. On the one hand, such a retailer might not pass on a brand-specific cost change if it diverts sales from another, more profitable brand such as a private label. On the other hand, a retailer facing competition from other retailers might be quite interested in passing on a national brand's wholesale-price cut, because not doing so would almost certainly result in loss of sales to a competitor.</p><p>I examine the impact of category management and retail competition on pass-through, focusing on brand and retailer differences and the nature of the cost change. A category-managing retailer's response to a brand-specific cost change is not limited to that brand alone; it will also change the prices of other brands in its portfolio. Similarly, a retailer competing with other retailers will find that its cost changes evoke a response from others. Traditionally, pass-through behavior has been conceptualized and studied from an individual brand or retailer's perspective. My analysis shows that this is a mistake on at least three counts. First, it misses a part of the retailer's response that affects pass-through. For instance, pass-through tends to be higher when the cross-brand effect is positive than when it is negative. Second, it misses the reaction of the other retailers, which might increase or decrease the retailer's pass-through. Third, it prevents us from seeing that a price change in a brand or retailer might not be caused by any changes to its cost at all. Rather, it might be caused by a cost change on another brand or retailer in the market. Empirical studies that do not capture cost changes in all brands in the retailer's category (such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Drèze and Bell 2003)</ref> are therefore susceptible to biased passthrough estimates. Equally, empirical studies that do not capture cost changes in competing retailers (such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Chintagunta 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">, Besanko et al. 2005</ref>) might also be susceptible to biased pass-through estimates.</p><p>Marketing Science 24(1), pp. 110-122, © 2005 INFORMS I show that the cross-brand effect can be positive or negative, i.e., in the same direction or in the opposite direction as the cost change. This is because with category management, there are two types of effects of a brand-specific cost change: a margin-based demandsubstitution effect, which pushes for a negative price change in the other brand, and a strategic complementarity effect, which pushes for a positive price change in the other brand. In a nested-logit model (without an outside good), the two effects are roughly in balance for brand-specific cost changes, resulting in zero cross-brand effects when the brand is equally strong at both retailers, or in an equal number of positive and negative cross-brand effects when the brand is stronger at one retailer. However, for brandand retailer-specific cost changes, the nested-logit model produces only negative cross-brand effects. In a linear-demand model without retail competition, the "equal number of positive and negative crossbrand effects" result holds for brand-specific cost changes, but with retail competition only positive cross-brand effects arise in a symmetric model. These observations explain, perhaps, why <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Besanko et al.'s (2005)</ref> regressions of prices on costs show both types of cross-brand effects in roughly equal number. They also explain why a retailer might want to shield its private-label brand by reducing its price in conjunction with the price of the national brand being tradepromoted (cf. <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Willis and O'Keeffe 1992)</ref>.</p><p>By studying retailer-specific and marketwide cost changes I refine the intuition regarding the impact of retail competition on pass-through. The standard intuition is that competition enhances pass-through, but this intuition is based on single-brand retailers passing through general cost changes. For instance, in a model with no retailer differentiation, general cost changes get 100% pass-through. The impact of competition on pass-through is smaller for retailerspecific cost changes. For brand-specific cost changes, the effect of competition is further complicated by the possibility of negative cross-brand effects.</p><p>Finally, my study of two special cases, linear demand and nested logit, reveals the different ways in which the main forces manifest themselves in different demand structures. The linear-demand model is predisposed toward greater harmony among the brands within a retailer. By contrast, in the nestedlogit model, the interests of competing brands are almost completely opposed within a retailer. Another major difference is that in the linear-demand model equilibrium market-share positions do not matter at all: Pass-through behavior is completely characterized by the various slopes of the demand functions. In the nested-logit model, however, equilibrium market-shares matter a great deal. Therefore, the relations between brand or retailer strength and passthrough are different in the two cases, and the conditions under which one brand or retailer produces greater pass-through than another are also different.</p><p>In §2, I present the general theory. In §3, I apply it to the two special cases of linear demand and nestedlogit demand. Section 4 summarizes my results and discusses their empirical implications. All proofs not in the text are in a technical appendix available from the journal's web site.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">The General Theory</head><p>My basic modeling framework is that of several manufacturers-brands-in a product category selling through several competing retailers on a nonexclusive basis. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Without loss of generality I operationalize it as two retailers, 1 and 2, each with two brands, 1 and 2, with brand 1 common to both retailers and brand 2 not necessarily so. This allows me to examine situations in which brand 1 is a national brand and brand 2 is either a retailer-specific brand such as a private label or another national brand. As a shorthand I will refer to "brand j at retailer i" as "brand ij" i j = 1 2 . The basic ingredient of my model is the demand function for each brand at each retailer. I shall assume that these demand functions are "nice" in the sense that they lead to "nice" profit functions that, in turn, lead to a unique pure-strategy retail equilibrium. In particular, I assume that the profit functions are twice-continuously differentiable (whenever positive) and have negative-definite Hessians (a property that implies concavity). My formulation is to be contrasted with discrete demand-function models such as Lal and Villas-Boas (1998) that have mixed-strategy equilibria only.</p><p>Let D ij , i = 1 2, j = 1 2, denote brand j's demand function at retailer i. In general, these demand functions are functions of all four retail prices: p 11 , p 21 , p 12 , p 22 . I make no specific assumptions at this stage regarding the form of the demand functions other than to assume, naturally, that each demand function is downward sloping in its own price and upward sloping in the other prices. So, for instance, D 21 is downward sloping in p 21 and upward sloping in p 11 , p 12 , and p 22 . The brands are in the same product category, and both retailers participate in this category, so each brand at each retailer is a partial substitute for three other products.</p><p>A basic regularity property of the demand functions ought to be that the same brand across two retailers are closer substitutes than the same brand and a different brand across the same two retailers. In particular, D i1 p / p k1 &gt; D i1 p / p k2 for i, k = 1 2, k = i (wherep = p 11 p 12 p 21 p 22 ). Second, I require that demand for each brand at each retailer decrease (increase) when all prices are increased (decreased) by the same amount in coordinated fashion. That is, D ij p / p ij + kl =ij D ij p / p kl &lt; 0 for i = 1 2, j = 1 2. This allows the category or market to expand or contract when all prices fall or rise. Third, I require that a price change on a given brand at a given retailer has a greater effect on demand for that brand at that retailer than all the other demand effects put together. That is, D ij p / p ij + kl =ij D kl p / p ij &lt; 0. This simply recognizes that all the brands are in the same category and that the two retailers constitute the market. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> Note that I do not assume any symmetry among the brands or the retailers <ref type="bibr">(unlike, say, Trivedi 1998)</ref>. This allows me to investigate the impact of retailer differentiation and brand differentiation on pass-through. I summarize the demand function assumptions in Assumption 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Assumption 1. (Properties of the demand function.)</head><formula xml:id="formula_0">For i j k l = 1 2 andp ∈ 4 + : (a) D ij p ij p &lt; 0, D ij p kl p ≥ 0 for kl = ij, 8 (b) D i1 p k1 p &gt; D i1 p k2 p for k = i, (c) D ij p ij p + kl =ij D ij p kl p &lt; 0, (d) D ij p ij p + kl =ij D kl p ij p &lt; 0. Retailer i's i = 1 2 category profit function is given by i p = p i1 − w 1 − c i1 − c i − c D i1 p + p i2 − c i2 − c i − c D i2 p (1)</formula><p>where I distinguish among a variety of retailer costs that might have pass-through implications. First and foremost is the wholesale price w 1 of the national brand. This brand-specific cost is usually assumed to <ref type="bibr">7</ref> Evidence for the within-retailer demand assumptions appears in numerous marketing studies, for example <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Walters (1991)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Kumar and Leone (1988)</ref>. For the cross-retailer assumptions, evidence is scarcer because of the paucity of multistore studies. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Kumar and Leone (1988)</ref> provide strong supportive evidence. <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Walters (1991)</ref>, however, finds weak cross-retailer effects in general, and some of them have the wrong sign, and the wrong magnitudesinterstore substitution effects involving substitute brands stronger than interstore substitution effects involving the same brandwhich he terms "somewhat puzzling" (p. 26). <ref type="bibr">8</ref> We allow for the possibility of zero cross-effects in order to evaluate submodels without category management or competition.</p><p>be common to both retailers because of Robinson-Patman Act considerations. I shall do so, as well, but note that this is an assumption, and its purpose in this paper is not just to respect the Robinson-Patman Act, but also to model correlated wholesale prices. In reality, wholesale prices often differ across retailers-in part because they incorporate volumebased discounts that vary by size of retailer (for example, see Shepard 1993 for the case of gasoline retailing) or because the manufacturer would like to encourage differentiation among retailers <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Iyer 1998</ref>)-and to capture that possibility and to reflect other retailer operating costs that are brand-and retailer-specific (for example, brand-and retailer-specific inventory costs), I introduce another cost term, c ij . Thus, c i1 and c i2 are retailer i's brand-specific marginal costs for brands 1 and 2, respectively. In (1) I am interpreting the second brand at each retailer as a private-label brand, whose wholesale prices are not coordinated across the retailers. I do not model a separate wholesale price for these brands; their retailer-specific wholesale prices are subsumed in c i2 . <ref type="bibr">9</ref> Next, c i is retailer i's nonbrand-specific marginal operating cost (for example, an online retailer's volume-sensitive labor cost), and finally, c refers to nonretailer-specific, nonbrand-specific marginal operating costs (for example, excise taxes). Of course, not all of these costs might apply in any given application, but by modeling all these costs we give ourselves the opportunity to discover whether different types of costs have different pass-through implications. I omit fixed costs because they do not have any implications for passthrough behavior.</p><p>As noted earlier I assume that i is concave in the sense that it has a negative-definite Hessian matrix. That is, for i j = 1 2, 2 i p / p 2 ij &lt; 0, and</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">2 i p / p 2 i1 2 i p / p 2 i2 − 2 i p / p i1 p i2 2 &gt; 0.</formula><p>In addition, I shall assume that the two brands are complementary within each retailer's profit function in the sense that the marginal profit from each brand is increasing in the other brand's price. That is, 2 i p / p ij p ik ≥ 0 j = k . I call this internal strategic complementarity to distinguish it from external strategic complementarity, which, in this context, speaks to the interaction between retailers. I also assume external strategic complementarity: 2 i p / p ij p lk ≥ 0 i = l . Internal and external strategic complementarity are natural in my setting. They imply that, for any pair of demand-substitutes, if one 114 Marketing Science 24(1), pp. 110-122, © 2005 INFORMS of them were to increase in price while prices outside of the pair were held constant, then whoever controls the other demand-substitute's price would find it optimal to raise it. Together, internal strategic complementarity and external strategic complementarity make each retailer's profit function supermodular when viewed as a function ofp <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Sundaram 1996)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> Finally, I assume the marginal profit analogues of Assumptions 1(b), (c), and (d):</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">2 i p i1 p k1 p &gt; 2 i p i1 p k2 p for k = i 2 i p 2 ij p + kl =ij 2 i p ij p kl p &lt; 0 and 2 i p 2 ij p + kl =ij 2 k p kl p ij p &lt; 0 Assumption 2. (Properties of the profit function.) For i j l k = 1 2, andp ∈ 4 + : (a) (Concavity.) 2 i p p 2 ij &lt; 0 and 2 i p p 2 i1 2 i p p 2 i2 − 2 i p p i1 p i2 2 &gt; 0. (b) (Internal and external strategic complementarity.) 2 i p p ij p lk ≥ 0 for ij = lk. 11 (c) 2 i p i1 p k1 p &gt; 2 i p i1 p k2 p for k = i. (d) 2 i p 2 ij p + kl =ij 2 i p ij p kl p &lt; 0. (e) 2 i p 2 ij p + kl =ij 2 k p kl p ij p &lt; 0.</formula><p>Note that Assumptions 1 and 2 are satisfied by the linear demand function</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">D ij p = ij − ij p ij + ik p ik + lj p lj + lk p lk (i j k l = 1 2, k = j, l = i), provided ij &gt; 0; ik lj lk ≥ 0; l1 ≥ l2 ; ik + lj + lk ij + ij + ij &lt; ij −2 ij + ik + ij + lj + lk &lt; 0; and −2 ij + ik + ij + ij + ij &lt; 0 (all of which are satisfied by, for example, ij ≡ 1, ik lj ≡ 0 4, lk ≡ 0 1).</formula><p>Henceforth, I shall revert to subscripts to indicate partial derivatives. Thus, subscript ij refers to a first-order partial derivative with respect to the retail price p ij , and subscript ijkl refers to a second-order partial derivative with respect to the retail prices p ij and p kl .</p><p>By writing each retailer's profit function as the sum of brand 1 profit and brand 2 profit, I am cap-turing the retailer's category-management perspective. Such a retailer takes the vector of marginal costs w j c ij c i c as given and chooses two retail prices to maximize its category profit, recognizing the interdependencies among the brands in the category. Assuming interior solutions, the four first-order conditions are</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">i ij p = p i1 −w 1 −c i1 −c i −c D i1 ij p + p i2 −c i2 −c i −c •D i2 ij p +D ij p = 0 i j = 1 2</formula><p>The solution to these first-order conditions defines the retail price equilibrium. Given Assumptions 1 and 2, a retail equilibrium exists and is unique <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(McKenzie 1959</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">, Takayama 1974</ref>. What I am interested in, however, is not so much the equilibrium itself, but how the equilibrium changes when one of the marginal costs changes, i.e., the comparative statics of the retail equilibrium with respect to various costs. By symmetry, I need examine only one cost change of each type, i.e., w 1 c 11 c 1 c . Totally differentiating all the firstorder conditions with respect to these costs, one by one, and solving for dp ij /dw 1 , dp ij /dc 11 , and so on, I get the set of equations −HP = C</p><p>where,  Assumptions 2(d), (e) guarantee that H has a dominant diagonal <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(McKenzie 1959</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">, Takayama 1974</ref>. Therefore, we get Lemma 1.</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">H ≡        1 1111</formula><formula xml:id="formula_6">       C ≡        1 11w 1 1 11c 11 1 11c 1 1 11c 1 12w 1 1 12c 11 1 12c 1 1 12c 2 21w 1 0 0 2 21c 2 22w 1 0 0 2 22c        =        −D</formula><p>Lemma 1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(McKenzie 1959)</ref>. H &gt; 0, H −1 exists, all the elements of −H −1 are nonnegative, and its diagonal elements are positive.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>So</head><formula xml:id="formula_7">P = −H −1 C (2)</formula><p>One could interpret this equation as saying that the pass-through effect of various cost changes is the net result of the interaction of two types of forces: the −H −1 forces and the C forces. The C forces are the simple ones, representing our most basic intuition regarding cost changes-that they must be passed on where they arise, shrinking demand if there is a cost increase, expanding demand if there is a cost decrease.</p><p>In a category-management context, for brand-specific cost changes, this intuition gets expanded to include the other brands whose costs have not changed: These brands' prices will be changed in the opposite direction to accelerate the desired demand-change at the focal brand by encouraging interbrand substitution. For example, 1 11w 1 = 1 11c 11 = −D 11 11 &gt; 0 is capturing the "cost changes must be passed on to shrink/expand demand" effect for brand 11, and</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">1 12w 1 = 1 12c 11 = −D 11</formula><p>12 &lt; 0 is capturing the substitution effect via an opposite change in the price of brand 12. So if the cost of brand 1 increases, and the C forces were the only ones that mattered, one might expect the retailers to increase the price of brand 1 and decrease the price of brand 2. For categorywide cost increases, whether retailer-specific or not, there are no within-retailer substitution issues to contend with, so the C forces reduce to "cost changes must be passed on" for both brands: 12 1 11c 1 = 1 11c = − D 11 11 + D 12 11 &gt; 0 (by Assumption 1), 1 12c 1 = 1 12c = − D 11 12 + D 12 12 &gt; 0, and</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">2 21c = − D 21 21 + D 22 21 &gt; 0, 2 22c = − D 21 22 + D 22</formula><p>22 &gt; 0. Therefore, using Lemma 1 it is immediate that dp 11 /dc 1 , dp 12 /dc 1 , dp 21 /dc 1 , and dp 22 /dc 1 and dp 11 /dc, dp 12 /dc, dp 21 /dc, and dp 22 /dc are all positive. The C forces specify the direction of pass-through for categorywide cost changes.</p><p>But progress in specifying the pass-through effects of brand-specific cost changes depends on coming to grips with the −H −1 forces. These forces might be called the strategic effects of price changes. These effects can be internal to a retailer, arising from changes in the other brand's price at the same retailer, or external, arising from the other retailer's price changes (on the same or a different brand). It is these strategic considerations that lead to much of the complexity in the pass-through analysis of brand-specific cost changes. Even the simple assertion that own pass-throughs are positive for brandspecific cost changes is not obvious. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> However, <ref type="bibr">12</ref> Therefore, the profit functions i are supermodular with respect to p c and p c 1 , but not with respect to p w 1 and p c 11 . <ref type="bibr">13</ref>   (a) A categorywide cost change, whether retailer-specific or general, elicits a positive price change from both retailers, for both brands. However, the price changes are greater when the cost change is general.</p><p>(b) A brand-and retailer-specific cost change elicits a positive pass-through on that brand, from that retailer. The other brand's retail price at that retailer, and both brands' prices at the other retailer will also change in general, but the direction of these changes is ambiguous, depending on specific magnitudes in the −H −1 and C matrices. For example, dp 12 /dc 11 &gt; 0 if and only if −H −1 21 −D 11 11 &gt; −H −1 22 D 11 12 . (c) A brand-specific (marketwide) cost change, such as a change in the national brand's wholesale price to both retailers, will in general elicit a price change in both brands at both retailers. Under the conditions of Lemma 3, pass-through is positive at both retailers. However, the cross-effect on the other brand's price continues to be ambiguous, depending on specific magnitudes in the −H −1 and C matrices. For example, dp 12 /dw 1 &gt; 0 if and only <ref type="bibr">15 14</ref> The conditions in this lemma might be interpreted as saying that each retailer's profit function is weakly more concave in brand 2 than brand 1, so that price changes are bigger in brand 1 than brand 2 when w 1 changes marginally; and retailer 2's (retailer 1's) brand 1 has a bigger effect on retailer 1's (retailer 2's) marginal profit with respect to either brand than retailer 2's (retailer 1's) brand 2 (on the corresponding marginal profit). Effectively, we are trying to limit the effect of the intraretailer substitution effect at the other retailer (changes in p 22 if dp 11 /dw 1 is the focus) from overturning the "cost changes must be passed on" effect at the retailer in question. Note that if brand 2 were also a national brand and we wanted to be able to assure dp 12 /dw 2 dp 22 /dw 2 &gt; 0, then these sufficient conditions point to symmetry between retailers and brands.</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">if −H −1 21 −D 11 11 + −H −1 23 −D 21 21 &gt; −H −1 22 • D 11 12 + −H −1 24 D 21 22 .</formula><p>15 For brand-specific or retailer-specific cost-changes, or both, I shall reserve the term pass-through for the price-responses of the retailer or brand whose costs changed. For instance, when a brand-and retailer-specific cost change occurs in brand 11, then dp 11 /dc 11 is the pass-through response (not, say, dp 12 /dc 11 ), whereas when a retailer- Notice that a retailer-specific categorywide cost change will elicit a response not only from the retailer affected by the cost change (the pass-through response), but also from the other retailer. This is because of the competition between the retailers. In particular, strategic complementarity implies that price changes at one retailer are transferred in kind to the other retailer. However, note that the price change is smaller in this case than when the cost change is marketwide. This is because marketwide cost changes provide two reasons for a price change, not one: the change in own costs that must be passed on, and the strategic-complementarity effect of a price change in the other retailer (cf. footnote 12). Stated differently, pass-through is greater under marketwide cost changes because competition is fiercer under marketwide cost changes; competition is fiercer under marketwide cost changes because both retailers experience the cost change (their relative competitive positions do not change).</p><p>Brand-specific cost changes, whether retailerspecific or not, elicit a response not only in the brand in question (own effects), but also in the other brand (cross-brand effects), at both retailers. As the proposition suggests, these cross-brand effects can be positive or negative. What drives these crossbrand effects? Consider the statement dp 12 , then the strategic effect wins out, and a positive cross-brand effect results; otherwise, a negative cross-brand effect results.</p><p>The discovery of cross-brand effects is a by-product of the comparative-statics approach to pass-through. Given that much of the previous pass-through literature has not taken a comparative-statics approach, these effects do not find much mention there. However, they have been discussed in the private-label literature, under the rubric of shielding <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Cotterill et al. 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">, Hoch et al. 2001</ref>. Shielding is the phenomenon of a retailer protecting its private-label's category share by discounting the private label in step with any discounts on the national brand (Willis and O'Keeffe specific cost change occurs at retailer 1, then dp 11 /dc 1 and dp 12 /dc 1 are both pass-through responses. Sometimes I refer to the passthrough response as an "own effect" when the meaning is clear. 1992). In my framework, shielding is a positive crossbrand effect, and is not an inevitable consequence of category management. In fact, I will show later that in a nested-logit model without an outside good, brand-specific retailer-specific cost changes produce only negative cross-brand effects. 16</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Retail Competition Without Category</head><p>Management A retailer who does not practice category management views each brand in isolation, ignoring the interdependencies among the brands in the category. I capture such behavior by setting D ij ik = 0 for k = j and, correspondingly, i ijik = 0 and i ijlk = 0 for k = j and l = i. Then Proposition 2. Without category management: (a) Brand-specific cost changes, whether retailer specific or not, elicit positive pass-through effects but no crossbrand effects.</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">−H −1 =        − 2 2121 /A 0 1 1121 /A 0 0 − 2 2222 /B 0 1 1222 /B 2 2111 /A 0 − 1 1111 /A 0 0 2 2212 /B 0 − 1 1212 /B        and C =        −D</formula><p>(b) A brand-and retailer-specific cost change has the same positive pass-through effect as an equivalent categorywide retailer-specific cost change.</p><p>(c) A retailer-specific cost change elicits a larger pricechange at that retailer than at the other retailer.</p><p>(d) Marketwide cost changes elicit greater pass-through than equivalent retailer-specific cost changes.</p><p>Part (d) of the proposition is probably the most interesting: It extends the second part of Proposition 1(a) <ref type="bibr">16</ref> Anecdotal evidence for a real-world negative cross-brand effect is provided in the following quotation from David Nickila of Portland French Bakery, a small bakery supplying grocery stores in Portland, Oregon: "Now, they've taken that-one day they all of a sudden up-price all your products, and then right next to you they're running 99 cents on all the major player's products" (http://www. ftc.gov/bc/slotting/slotting (1.pdf, p. 179).</p><p>to brand-specific cost changes. Marketwide cost changes generate greater pass-through than retailerspecific cost changes because, as noted earlier, the retailers compete harder when their competitive positions are equally affected by cost changes.</p><p>What is the effect of retail competition on passthrough? Suppose there was no retail competition in this case. Then −H −1 would further simplify to </p><formula xml:id="formula_12">      − 2 2121 /A 0 0 0 0 − 2 2222 /B 0 0 0 0 − 1 1111 /A 0 0 0 0 − 1 1212 /B       </formula><p>where Proposition 3. Without category management, the presence of retail competition boosts pass-through for every type of cost change.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Category Management Without Retail</head><p>Competition This is the model assumed in much of the empirical literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Sudhir 2001)</ref> and in some of the theoretical literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shugan and Desiraju 2001)</ref>. Without retail competition, (a) Retailer-specific cost changes, whether brand specific or not, do not elicit cross-retailer price responses.</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">−H −1 =        − 1 1212 /X 1 1112 /X 0 0 1 1211 /X − 1 1111 /X 0 0 0 0 − 2 2222 /Y 2 2122 /Y 0 0 2 2221 /Y − 2 2121 /Y        and C =        −D</formula><p>(b) A retailer-specific cost change has the same passthrough effect on the retailer's two brands as an equivalent general cost change.</p><p>(c) A retailer-and brand-specific cost change evokes the same price response in the retailer's two brands as an equivalent brand-specific cost change.</p><p>(d) A brand-specific cost change has a positive passthrough effect at both retailers. The cross-brand effect of brand 1 at retailer 1 (retailer 2) is positive if and only if ). If the cross-brand effect is positive, then its magnitude is always smaller than the own effect. If the cross-brand effect of brand 1 at retailer 1 (retailer 2) is negative, then its magnitude is smaller than the own effect if 11 . This condition generalizes the condition in <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shugan and Desiraju (2001)</ref> for the linear-demand case. In Shugan and Desiraju there is a cross-brand effect only if the two brands are asymmetrically differentiated. My condition shows that even symmetrically differentiated brands could elicit cross-effects in response to brand-specific cost changes.</p><p>How does retail competition interact with category management? In general, the effect of competition is to boost strategic complementarity in the system, but this means that both positive and negative price changes are transmitted in kind to the other retailer, reinforcing those changes. This will increase passthrough for general and retailer-specific cost changes because cross-brand effects are positive in these cases, but for brand-specific cost changes, where the possibility of negative cross-brand effects arises, the net effect is ambiguous.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Two Examples</head><p>In this section, I illustrate Propositions 1-4 by examining two popular demand functions: linear demand and nested-logit demand.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Linear Demand</head><p>Let D ij p = ij − ij p ij + ik p ik + lj p lj + lk p lk (i j k l = 1 2 k = j, l = i). As noted earlier, in order to satisfy Assumptions 1 and 2, I need ij &gt; 0, ik lj lk ≥ 0, <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Trivedi (1998)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shugan and Desiraju (2001)</ref> examine special cases of this demand function. </p><formula xml:id="formula_14">l1 ≥ l2 , ik + lj + lk ij + ij + ij &lt; ij , −2 ij + ik + ij + lj + lk &lt; 0, and −2 ij + ik + ij + ij + ij &lt; 0.</formula><formula xml:id="formula_15">      </formula><p>It is easy to establish that: 1. Pass-through of any kind is independent of cost differences and demand-intercept differences among retailers or brands. Therefore, empirical models that rely on demand intercepts to capture brand or retailer fixed effects are structurally incapable of finding passthrough differences among brands or retailers. Slope differences are necessary.</p><p>2. Without category management:</p><p>• For retailer-specific cost changes each retailer has the same pass-through rate, even when the retailers are asymmetric. However, the cross-retailer price changes, although positive, are not symmetric in general: dp 21 /dc 11 = dp 21 /dc 1 &gt; dp 11 /dc 21 = dp 11 /dc 2 if and only if 11 11 &gt; 21 21 ; dp 22 /dc 1 &gt; dp 12 /dc 2 if and only if 12 12 &gt; 22 22 .</p><p>• Brand-specific cost changes generate asymmetric pass-throughs at the two retailers: dp 11 /dw 1 = dp 11 /dc &gt; dp 21 /dw 1 = dp 21 /dc if and only if 21 21 &gt; 11 11 ; dp 12 /dc &gt; dp 22 /dc if and only if 22 22 &gt; 12 12 .</p><p>• Brand-specific cost changes generate more passthrough than retailer-specific cost changes because, as noted before, the strategic-complementarity effect of competition is bigger when both retailers experience the cost change.</p><p>3. Without retail competition:</p><p>• Brand-specific cost changes generate less than 100% own pass-through. Comparing brands (assuming brand 2 is national for the w-change comparison), dp 11 /dw 1 = dp 11 /dc 11 &gt; dp 12 /dw 2 = dp 12 /dc 12 if and only if 11 &gt; 12 .</p><p>• Brand-specific cost changes have a cross-brand effect if and only if the brands are asymmetric on the -dimension: dp 12 /dw 1 = dp 12 /dc 11 ∝ 11 − 12 11 ; dp 11 /dw 2 = dp 11 /dc 12 ∝ 12 − 11 12 . <ref type="bibr">17</ref> In other words, the final arbiter of whether the strategic-complementarity forces or the C forces win out depends on the nature of cross-demand asymmetries. If brand 1 has a bigger effect on brand 2's demand than vice versa 11 &gt; 12 , then its cross-brand effect will be positive. Furthermore, if one brand has a positive cross-brand effect then the other must have a negative cross-brand effect. This explains perhaps why <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Besanko et al. (2005)</ref> find approximately 50% of their significant cross-brand effects positive.</p><p>• Positive cross-brand effects support greater pass-through for brand-specific cost changes. For instance, for a given 11 , a positive dp 12 /dc 11 implies dp 11 /dc 11 &gt; 2 12 11 − 11 + 12 11 /X whereas a negative dp 12 /dc 11 implies dp 11 /dc 11 &lt; 2 12 11 − 11 + 12 11 /X (where X is positive). 4. In the symmetric linear model, cross-brand effects are positive under retail competition. This is to be contrasted with the no-retail-competition case above where asymmetry between brands was necessary for a nonzero cross-brand effect. The difference tells a story about the role of retail competition. Retail competition boosts the strategic complementarity between brands leading to a positive cross-brand effect when the internal battle between the strategic forces and the C forces is a dead heat.</p><p>5. From the foregoing observations, it is difficult to define a simple measure of brand or retailer strength that can order brands or retailers in terms of their pass-through. Brand or retailer strength, insofar as pass-through is concerned, is a multidimensional object in the linear model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Nested Logit</head><p>Logit demand structures are common in empirical work in marketing, perhaps second only to lineardemand functions in popularity, but they are usually single-stage models with brand choice only (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Sudhir 2001)</ref>. Because retail competition is a crucial part of my analysis, and the linear model has already dealt with it in a single-stage manner, I examine a nested-logit model here, with retailer choice forming the first stage, and brand choice forming the second stage. That is, D ij = NS i S ij for i j = 1 2, where N is the size of the market, S ij is brand j's share within retailer i, and S i is retailer i's share. In the nested-logit specification,</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">S ij = exp ij − p ij / b 2 k=1 exp ik − p ik / b</formula><p>(3)</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">S i = exp R i / r 2 k=1 exp R k / r (<label>4</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_18">)</formula><p>where R i = b ln 2 k=1 exp ik − p ik / b for i = 1 2, r ≥ b are the heterogeneity parameters for retailer choice and brand choice, respectively, and the ij are parameters reflecting the quality of the retailer-brand combination ij. In practice, one would split up ij into r i + b j , with r i referring to the quality of retailer i, e.g., service quality, and b j brand j's quality. Note that we are making the "no outside good" assumption. In this context, the no-retail competition case does not make sense: Category management implies infinitely high prices on both brands then. The analysis can be extended to incorporate an outside good along the lines of footnote 19.</p><p>For the nested-logit demand structure, instead of computing H −1 , it turns out to be easier to exploit a special property of this structure, namely that at each retailer category profit maximization implies equal margins for both brands <ref type="bibr">(Anderson et al. 1992, p. 251</ref>). <ref type="bibr">18</ref> That is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">p ij − w j + c i1 + c i + c = r 1 − S i for i j = 1 2 (5)</formula><p>Totally differentiating these equations with respect to w 1 , c 11 , c 1 , and c, I get</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">P =                1+ 1 S 1 1−S 1 2 S 21 −S 11 1− 1 S 1 1−S 1 2 S 11 1 1 1−S 1 1 1 S 1 1−S 1 2 S 21 −S 11 − 1 S 1 1−S 1 2 S 11 1 1 1−S 1 1 1− 1 S 21 −S 11 1 S 11 1 1 − 1 S 21 −S 11 1 S 11 1 1               <label>(6)</label></formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">= 1 + S 1 /1 − S 1 + S 1 /1 − S 1 2 &gt; 1. Note that 1/ 1 − S 1 = 1 − S 1 / 1 − S 1 1 − S 1 &lt; 1 and S 2 1 / 1 − S 1 2 = S 2 1 / S 2 1 + 1 − S 1 &lt; 1.</formula><p>From this, we can establish:</p><p>1. General cost changes generate 100% passthrough in both brands at both retailers.</p><p>2. Retailer-specific cost changes generate equal, positive, less than 100% pass-through in both brands of the retailer, and a smaller, positive, equal passthrough in both brands of the other retailer.</p><p>• The pass-through is greater for the retailer with the bigger equilibrium marketshare.</p><p>3. Retailer-and brand-specific cost changes generate positive, less than 100%, own pass-through, but negative cross-brand effects. This shows that the nested-logit model without an outside good is naturally predisposed toward negative cross-brand effects. It is possible for the cross-brand effect to be greater in magnitude than the pass-through if the equilibrium within-retailer share of the brand is large. Both brands of the other retailer see equal, positive, price changes.</p><p>• Comparing brands within a retailer (i.e., comparing dp 11 /dc 11 and dp 12 /dc 12 ), pass-through is greater for the brand that has a lower within-retailer equilibrium market share at that retailer. <ref type="bibr">19</ref> • Comparing retailers for a given brand, say brand 1 (i.e., comparing dp 11 /dc 11 and dp 21 /dc 21 ), own pass-through is greater at retailer 1 than at retailer 2 if and only if S 1 / 1 − S 1 2 S 11 &lt; S 2 / 1 − S 2 2 S 21 4. Marketwide brand-specific cost changes generate positive pass-through at both retailers, greater than the pass-through with retailer-and brandspecific cost changes. The pass-through is 100% at both retailers if the brand has equal market share at both retailers; otherwise, it may be greater or less than 100% depending on whether the brand has a smaller or larger market share at the retailer where the passthrough is examined. The cross-brand effect is positive whenever the pass-through is greater than 100%; otherwise, it is negative or zero.</p><p>• Comparing brands within a retailer (i.e., comparing dp 11 /dw 1 and dp 12 /dw 2 ), which brand gets greater pass-through depends not so much on its strength vis à vis the other brand, but rather on its strength at the subject retailer vis à vis its strength at the other retailer. For example, it is possible that brand 1 is stronger than brand 2 at both retailers (say, market shares of 0.7 and 0.3, respectively, at retailer 1, and market shares of 0.6 and 0.4 at retailer 2), but because brand 1 does relatively poorly at retailer 2 it gets less pass-through at retailer 1 than does brand 2. Note that brand 1 is weaker at retailer 1 versus retailer 2 if and only if brand 2 is stronger at retailer 1 versus retailer 2.</p><p>• Comparing retailers for a given brand, passthrough is greater at the retailer where the brand has a smaller within-retailer market share.</p><p>5. Unlike the linear model, equilibrium marketshare positions matter for pass-through. Market shares are higher for the brand or retailer with lower cost or higher quality. This means that inherited advantages and disadvantages-advantages and disadvantages independent of the cost change in question, for example, due to other costs-play a role in pass-through in the nested-logit model.</p><p>The possibility of positive cross-brand effects under marketwide brand-specific cost changes, when only negative cross-brand effects obtain for retailer-and brand-specific cost changes, shows once again the strategic-complementarity-increasing effect of retail competition. Competition's effect is weaker under retailer-specific cost changes, and the nested-logit Marketing Science 24(1), pp. 110-122, © 2005 INFORMS model has naturally strong demand-substitution forces. So the latter prevail under retailer-and brand-specific cost changes. Under marketwide brand-specific cost changes, however, competition's strategic-complementarity effect is stronger, so the cross-brand effect ends up being both positive and negative. In the linear model, where the demandsubstitution forces are naturally weaker, positive cross-brand effects are seen even without competition for retailer-specific cost changes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Conclusion</head><p>This paper presents a comparative-statics analysis of equilibrium pass-through in channels where retailers manage product categories with several brands and face competition from other retailers. The focus of the analysis is on how different types of cost changes are passed through, and how retail competition, category management, and brand and retailer differences affect pass-through.</p><p>A virtue of the comparative-statics approach is that it demonstrates the systemwide effects of a cost change. Because of category management, a retailer's response to a brand-specific cost change is not limited to the brand whose costs changed; other brands will be affected as well. Whether this cross-brand effect is in the same direction as the cost change (a positive price change) or in the opposite direction (a negative price change) depends on how two forces play out. A demand-substitution force argues for demand to be substituted away from (toward) the brand whose costs have increased (decreased), hence a negative price change, but a strategic-complementarity force argues that a positive price change in other brands will support passing through the cost change. Retail competition adds a layer of strategic complementarity to this picture, transmitting the positive and negative forces in kind to the other retailer, strengthening both and leaving the net cross-brand effect ambiguous in general. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Besanko et al. (2005)</ref> find evidence of both positive and negative cross-brand effects, roughly equal in number, which is consistent with this paper.</p><p>The theory laid out in this paper sheds light on the practice of shielding private-label brands when national brands are promoted in response to a trade promotion. In my framework, this is nothing but a positive cross-brand effect, resulting from a strategic-complementarity effect overcoming a demand-substitution effect. But, as I have argued, it could go the other way-the cross-brand effect can be negative. Casual discussions of the phenomenon, however, paint a picture of a retailer always looking for opportunities to favor or protect the private-label brand, the argument being that margins are higher on the private label. But margins are not exogenous objects; they arise endogenously in price equilibrium. Any basis for favoring a private-label brand is already reflected in equilibrium prices. When costs change on the national brand, we move to a new retail equilibrium, and in this movement it is not clear that private labels need further protection.</p><p>The possibility of cross effects means that it is a mistake to automatically categorize any price changes in a brand or retailer as a pass-through response. In fact, these changes might have a causal basis in other brands or retailers, and not recognizing these external roots in empirical analyses might lead to biased pass-through estimates. For instance, <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Drèze and Bell (2003)</ref> regress a given retailer's prices against corresponding trade promotions only (among other variables). If trade promotions of other brands or retailers are correlated with the ones in the study, then their pass-through coefficients could be biased. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Chintagunta (2002)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Besanko et al. (2005)</ref> account for the wholesale prices of all brands at a retailer, avoiding one potential source of bias, but they do not consider retail competition. So their pass-through and cross-brand effect estimates could be biased if wholesale price changes at their retailers are correlated with wholesale price changes at competing retailers.</p><p>This paper focuses on retail price changes motivated by cost changes, but there is a literature in marketing and economics of retail price changes motivated by price discrimination <ref type="bibr">(Conlisk et al. 1984, Banks and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Moorthy 1999)</ref> and competitive considerations <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Varian 1980</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, Narasimhan 1988</ref>). Whereas it is not a question of which of these models is the "right" onereal-world retailing probably features all of these models to some extent, and nothing prevents more than one model from applying at the same time (for example, Sobel 1984 combines price discrimination and competition)-it is nevertheless useful to ask, in specific retailing contexts, whether retail price changes are occurring more for one reason than another. On the one hand, if price changes are motivated by cost changes, especially common cost changes, then they should be positively correlated across retailers. On the other hand, price changes motivated by price discrimination or competitive considerations are more likely to be uncorrelated across retailers.</p><p>What do the data show? Not much data are available, and the data that are available are somewhat contradictory. <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Walters (1991)</ref>, working with grocerystore scanner data on spaghetti and spaghetti sauce, reports correlations ranging from −0 35 to 0.57 for the same brand across stores and correlations in the range −0 38 to 0.59 for different brands across stores. Villas-Boas (1995) finds, in grocery-scanner data on coffee and saltine crackers, that the same-brand correlation is, on average, 0.74, whereas for different brands it is 0.52. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Rao et al. (1995)</ref> do not examine price correlation directly, but rather the concurrence of unadvertised specials on the same brand of ketchup across stores. They find that the concurrence varies by brand and the nature of the stores involved (whether high-low (Hi-Lo) or everyday-low-price (EDLP)). For example, for the two Hi-Lo stores in their sample, the two leading brands, Heinz and Hunt's, have concurrent unadvertised specials 18.1% and 37.7% of the time, respectively. <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Pesendorfer (2002)</ref> also finds that price changes in Hunt's are more correlated across stores (0.21) than price changes in Heinz (0.04).</p><p>It should be noted, however, that strictly coincident price changes across stores-say, in the same week-might be too strong a test of cost changes being passed through. As I noted earlier, even cost changes specific to a retailer trigger a response from other retailers in equilibrium, but this response arises as a reaction to the price change by the retailer whose costs changed-the cost change itself being unobserved by the other retailers. In reality, such a response is unlikely to be simultaneous, even in a simultaneous-move game. More likely, the reaction occurs after the focal retailer has adjusted its price. By contrast, a trade promotion common to all retailers might trigger a more simultaneous response from all retailers, although still not exactly simultaneous. This is because each retailer might independently delay its response to the promotion for idiosyncratic reasons such as inventory positions. In short, pass-through of cost changes might not necessarily show up as simultaneous price changes at competing stores.</p><p>In addition, of course, competition between retailers takes different forms. In grocery retailing-the type of retailing most studied in the marketing literature-competition between stores is unlikely to be revealed in individual product categories. Each category is low priced, and consumers typically buy many groceries on each visit. Their unit of comparison, if there is one, is likely to be shopping baskets rather than individual categories, much less individual brands. The decision on where to shop becomes a strategic long-term decision, not a tactical weekto-week decision. <ref type="bibr">20</ref> Store loyalty over long periods is inevitable <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Pesendorfer 2002)</ref>. Under these circumstances it might be the overall positioning of the store <ref type="bibr">20</ref> There is, of course, an extremely price-sensitive group of consumers that shops individual grocery categories every week, but by all accounts this cherry-picking segment is a small group. Exceptions also must be made for shoppers whose needs in particular categories are large enough to make them want to switch grocery stores on a week-to-week basis. For families with infants, for example, disposable diapers might be such a category. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Kumar and Leone (1988)</ref> find cross-store demand effects several orders of magnitude larger in the disposable-diaper category than those found in smaller-ticket grocery-store categories, such as spaghetti or cake mix <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Walters 1991)</ref>, or tuna <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(van Heerde et al. 2004</ref>).</p><p>that matters-by which I mean the strategic choices the store makes with respect to things such as quality of meat or produce, assortment, availability of parking, price level, and so on-rather than individual brands' weekly prices. For high-ticket goods bought less frequently, however, where the phenomenon of focussed shopping exists, competition is likely to be more tactical, and competitiveness in individual categories, and in focal brands, are both likely to be more important. In these product categories price changes across retailers, particularly in response to common external events, are more likely to be correlated <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Warner and Barsky 1995)</ref>.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Consider, for example, dp 11 /dc 11 = −H −1 11 −D 11 11 + −H −1 12 • −D 11 12 . Even though −D 11 11 &gt; 0 ≥ −D 11 12 and −D 11 11 &gt; D 11 12 (by Assumption 1), there is the possibility that −H −1 12 &gt; −H −1 11 . Although we assumed H 11 &gt; H 12 in Assumption 2(d), it is by no means obvious that −H −1 11 ≥ −H −1 12 .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>12 /dc 11 &gt; 0 if and only if −H −1 21 −D 11 11 &gt; −H −1 22 D 11 12 . Suppose c 11 increased. As noted earlier, −D 11 11 and D 11 12 capture the simple effects; these point to a negative cross-brand effect. Strategic considerations, as represented in −H −1 21 and −H −1 22 , filter these simple effects, and push for a positive cross-brand effect. Under 1 1112 &gt; 0 (internal strategic complementarity), a price increase in brand 2 supports a price increase in brand 1. If 1 1112 is relatively large vis à vis 1 1111 (which corresponds roughly to −H −1 22 / −H −1 21 being close to 1), while −D 11 11 is relatively large vis à vis D 11</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Without retail competition:   </figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>of the proposition documents the obvious effect of no retail competition. Part (b) changes the second part of Proposition 1(a). In the absence of retail competition, general cost changes do not elicit greater pass-through than retailer-specific cost changes. The first part of 4(d) says that, in the absence of retail competition, a positive pass-through of brand-specific cost changes is guaranteed: No longer do we need the conditions of Lemma 3. Part (c), in conjunction with part (d), removes the ambiguity in Proposition 1(b) with respect to the cross-brand effect of brand-specific cost changes. In the simpler setting of no retail competition, −H −1 21 and −H −1 22 have a direct interpretation in terms of 1 1211 and 1 1111 , respectively. Now I can state that a change in brand 1's cost will have a positive effect on brand 2's retail price if and only</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>dp 11 /dw 1 dp 11 /dc 11 dp 11 /dc 1 dp 11 /dc dp 12 /dw 1 dp 12 /dc 11 dp 12 /dc 1 dp 12 /dc dp 21 /dw 1 dp 21 /dc 11 dp 21 /dc 1 dp 21 /dc dp 22 /dw 1 dp 22 /dc 11 dp 22 /dc 1 dp 22 /dc</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1 1211 2 2111</cell><cell>1 1112 1 1212 2 2112</cell><cell>1 1121 1 1221 2 2121</cell><cell>1 1122 1 1222 2 2122</cell><cell>      </cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>2 2211</cell><cell>2 2212</cell><cell>2 2221</cell><cell>2 2222</cell></row><row><cell>P ≡</cell><cell>     </cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>I am able to report progress. Lemma 2 below states that my assumptions already guarantee −H −1 11 ≥ −H −1 12 and −H −1 33 ≥ −H −1 34 ; hence dp 11 /dc 11 &gt; 0 is assured. Lemma 3 identifies sufficient conditions for −H −1 13 ≥ −H −1 14 to assure dp 11 /dw 1 , and</figDesc><table><row><cell>−H −1</cell><cell>31 ≥ −H −1</cell><cell cols="2">32 to assure dp 21 /dw 1 &gt; 0.</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Lemma 2. −H −1 −H −1 33 ≥ −H −1 34 ; and −H −1 11 ≥ −H −1</cell><cell>12 ; −H −1 44 ≥ −H −1 22 ≥ −H −1 43 .</cell><cell>21 ;</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Lemma 3. If 2 2222 ≥ 2 2121 , 1 1221 ≥ 1 1122 and 1 1121 ≥ 1 1222 , then −H −1 13 ≥ −H −1 14 . Similarly, if 1 1212 ≥ 1 1111 , 2 2211 ≥ 2 2112 , and 2 2111 ≥ 2 2212 , then −H −1 31 ≥ −H −1 32 . 14</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Given Lemmas 2 and 3, Proposition 1 summarizes</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">my general results.</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Proposition 1.</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">See, for example,<ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Singer (2003)</ref> on the pass-through issues Starbucks faces in the Japanese market due to exchange-rate fluctuations. Another example of a manufacturer-independent cost change is the recent decrease in debit card fees U.S. retailers experienced due to an antitrust court settlement involving Visa and MasterCard.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Other papers with exogenous cost changes include<ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Tyagi (1999)</ref>,<ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Kumar et al. (2001)</ref>,<ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shugan and Desiraju (2001)</ref>,<ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Besanko et al. (2005)</ref>.4  In the sequel, when I say brand-specific cost changes without further qualification I mean brand-specific, nonretailer-specific cost changes. Similarly, retailer-specific cost changes means retailer-specific nonbrand-specific cost changes.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">Retailers might carry multiple product categories, but if they do, they are assumed to be independent of each other.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">Even though this is easily the most common situation in retailing, it is surprisingly rare in the marketing literature, the notable exceptions beingLal and Villas-Boas (1998)  and<ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Trivedi (1998)</ref>. More common are the special cases of one retailer with multiple brands (e.g.,<ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Choi 1991)</ref>, multiple retailers and one brand (e.g.,<ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Iyer 1998)</ref>, and multiple retailers with exclusive brands (e.g.,<ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Moorthy 1988</ref>).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">When brand 2 at each retailer is a common national brand, statements about its pass-through with respect to w 2 can be derived by analogy to brand 1's pass-through with respect to w 1 .</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="10">Note, however, that these profit functions when viewed as a function of p w 1 w 2 c ij c i c are not supermodular, as we show below.11  Once again, we only assume weak internal and strategic complementarity in order to evaluate submodels without category management or retail competition.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="17">This point is also made in<ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shugan and Desiraju (2001)</ref>.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="18">With an outside good at each retailer, the equal-margins result still holds, but the expressions for the equilibrium margins are different from below, namely m i = 1/ 1 − S i 1 − S i0 / r + S i0 / b for i = 1 2, where S i0 is the outside good's equilibrium share at retailer i.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="19">This result, and earlier ones, on the effect of retailer-and brandspecific cost-changes, are consistent with<ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Sudhir's (2001)</ref> results obtained in a single-stage logit model with outside good and no retail competition.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" />
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Discrete Choice Theory of Product Differentiation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Palma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J-F</forename><surname>Thisse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model of price promotions with consumer search</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Banks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Moorthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Indust. Organ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="371" to="398" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Own-brand and cross-brand retail pass-through</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Besanko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>J-P. Dubé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="123" to="137" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Retail promotions as a function of trade promotions: A descriptive analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chevalier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Curhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sloan Management Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating category pricing behavior at a retail chain</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="154" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Price competition in a channel structure with a common retailer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="271" to="297" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cyclic pricing by a durable goods monopolist. Quart</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Conlisk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sobel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="489" to="505" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assessing the competitive interaction between private labels and national brands</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Cotterill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Putsis</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="137" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Creating win-win trade promotions: Theory and empirical analysis of scan-back trade deals</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Drèze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="39" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ESPN annual rate boost provokes howls of protest</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Grant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Flint</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wall Street J</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-05-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Long-term growth trends in private label market shares. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hoch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Montgomery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<pubPlace>Philadelphia, PA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Wharton School, University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coordinating channels under price and nonprice competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Iyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="338" to="355" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Moorthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">General Theory of Pass-Through in Channels</title>
				<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">122</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="110" to="122" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring the effect of retail store promotions on brand and store substitution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Leone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="178" to="185" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effectiveness of trade promotions: Analyzing the determinants of retail pass-through</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rajiv</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Jeuland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="382" to="404" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Villas-Boas. 1998. Price promotions and trade deals with multiproduct retailers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Lal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="935" to="949" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Matrices with dominant diagonals and economic theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mckenzie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Mathematical Methods in the Social Sciences</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K J</forename><surname>Arrow</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Karlin</surname></persName>
			<persName><surname>Suppes</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Stanford, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Stanford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1959" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategic decentralization in channels</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Moorthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sridhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="335" to="355" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competitive promotional strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Narasimhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="427" to="449" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of retailer and consumer response on optimal manufacturer advertising and trade promotion strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Neslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Powell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="749" to="767" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Retail sales: A study of pricing behavior in supermarkets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Pesendorfer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Game theory and empirical generalizations concerning competitive promotions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Arjunji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">P S</forename><surname>Murthi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="G89" to="G100" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contractual form, retail price, and asset characteristics in gasoline retailing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shepard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">RAND J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="58" to="77" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Retail product-line pricing strategy when costs and products change</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Desiraju</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Retailing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="38" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Starbucks Japan plans changes as it struggles for profitability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wall Street J</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-02-19" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Universal&apos;s CD price slashes will squeeze music retailers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wall Street J</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-09-18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The timing of sales</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sobel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="353" to="368" />
			<date type="published" when="1984-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Retailers begin slashing prices for CDs. Globe Mail</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Strauss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-10-03" />
			<biblScope unit="page">B1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structural analysis of manufacturer pricing in the presence of a strategic retailer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sudhir</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="244" to="264" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A First Course in Optimization Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Sundaram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mathematical Economics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Takayama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
			<publisher>The Dryden Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Hinsdale, IL</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distribution channels: An extension of exclusive retailership</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Trivedi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="896" to="909" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A characterization of retailer response to manufacturer trade deals</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Tyagi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="510" to="516" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decomposing the sales promotion bump with store data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Heerde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S H</forename><surname>Leeflang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wittink</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="317" to="334" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model of sales</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Varian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="651" to="659" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Low CD prices: Music fans may rejoice, retailers mixed. Seattle Times</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Veiga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-09-05" />
			<biblScope unit="page">C1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Models of competitive price promotions: Some empirical evidence from the coffee and saltine crackers market</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Villas-Boas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Management Strategy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="107" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Vertical contracts between manufacturers and retailers: Inference with limited data. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Villas-Boas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Sofia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<pubPlace>Berkeley, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of California-Berkeley</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical investigation into retailer response to manufacturer trade promotions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rockney</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Walters</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Retailing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="272" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assessing the impact of retail price promotions on product substitution, complementary purchase, and interstore sales displacement</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rockney</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Walters</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="1991-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The timing and magnitude of retail store markdowns: Evidence from weekends and holidays. Quart</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Warner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Barsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="352" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Loblaw Companies Limited: Food distribution in the 1990s</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Willis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>O'keeffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>593- 033</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Harvard Business School Case</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
