<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Channel Coordination in the Presence of a Dominant Retailer</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jagmohan</forename><surname>Raju</surname></persName>
							<email>rajuj@wharton.upenn.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">The Wharton School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>700 Jon M. Huntsman Hall, 3730 Walnut Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>19104-6340</postCode>
									<settlement>Philadelphia</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">The Wharton School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>700 Jon M. Huntsman Hall, 3730 Walnut Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>19104-6340</postCode>
									<settlement>Philadelphia</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">John</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<email>zjzhang@wharton.upenn.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">The Wharton School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>700 Jon M. Huntsman Hall, 3730 Walnut Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>19104-6340</postCode>
									<settlement>Philadelphia</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">The Wharton School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>700 Jon M. Huntsman Hall, 3730 Walnut Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>19104-6340</postCode>
									<settlement>Philadelphia</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Channel Coordination in the Presence of a Dominant Retailer</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 05 2402 0254</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1040.0081</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:31+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>The retailing industry today is increasingly dominated by large, centrally managed "power retailers," such as chain supermarkets, mass merchandizers, wholesale clubs, and category killers <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Schiller and Zellner 1992</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">, Kahn and McAlister 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">, Useem 2003</ref>. In this paper, we draw from the well-known dominantfirm model in economics <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Samuelson and Nordhaus 1989</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">, Shepherd 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">, Riordan 1998</ref> and develop a channel model with the presence of a dominant retailer and a passive fringe of identical retailers to examine how a manufacturer can achieve channel coordination profitably in this channel environment.</p><p>Our channel model with a dominant retailer captures three characteristics salient in some of today's retailing markets. First, due to their ability to offer consumers the unprecedented opportunity for onestop shopping and their ability to offer manufacturers effective promotional services, often unmatched by independents or mom-and-pop stores, power retailers are dominant players, commanding a large market share in nearly every retail market <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Epstein 1994</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">, Zerrillo and Iacobucci 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">, Wahl 1992</ref>). <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Second, they <ref type="bibr">1</ref> In the grocery industry, for instance, chain supermarkets account for only 16% of the total number of stores in US in 1999, while are frequently the largest distributors for manufacturers. Sales through Walmart, for instance, account for 17% of the P&amp;G's total sales in 2002, 39% of Tandy's, and a double-digit percentage for many other large manufacturers <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Useem 2003)</ref>. Third, power retailers are frequently the price leaders <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Stone 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">, Weinstein 2000</ref>. As a pricing consultant characterized it, "it used to be that shelf prices [at independents and convenience stores] were set by buying (illegally) a copy of the price book from the store manager of a famous national chain, and adding two cents (improperly) to each item Over time, that famous national chain changed, the facts changed, and so did their policies and strategy Shelf prices are now set by buying the price book from the store manager of the same store of the same national chain, but instead of adding two cents, they now subtracted two cents" <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Partch 1991)</ref>.</p><p>Previous studies, such as those of <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">McGuire and Staelin (1983)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Coughlan (1985)</ref>, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Coughlan and Wernerfelt (1989)</ref>, examine the manufacturers' choice independent supermarkets and small stores with sales below $2 million account for nearly 40%. However, in terms of sales, chain supermarkets account for 61.8% of the total while independents and small stores account for about 27%. See Progressive Grocer Annual Report <ref type="bibr">(2000)</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>255</head><p>of channel structure but do not address the issues of channel coordination directly. <ref type="bibr">Shugan (1983, 1988</ref>) study how quantity discounts can coordinate a dyadic channel where both price and nonprice decision variables are involved. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Moorthy (1987)</ref> shows that a two-part tariff can be used to motivate the retailer to set the channel-profit maximizing price in a dyadic channel. This is also the case, as <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Lal (1990)</ref> shows in the context of franchising, even if the retailer provides the value-added service. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> We build on these studies by extending their analysis to a different channel structure with new insights. We show that optimal channel coordination entails a judicious choice on the part of a manufacturer between quantity discounts à la <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Jeuland and Shugan (1983)</ref> and a menu of twopart tariffs.</p><p>To the extent that asymmetry is introduced at the retail level, <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ingene and Parry (1995a)</ref> is closely related to our study. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> However, our research differs from theirs in that our channel structure incorporates price leader and follower behavior seen in some markets, while theirs does not; we seek to characterize the most profitable way for a manufacturer to achieve the integrated channel profit or channel coordination, while theirs derives a pricing mechanism that would maximize a manufacturer's own profit, or channel profit, but not both. In addition, our model incorporates retail services to shed light on the frequently observed phenomenon of "street money" in the context of distribution channels-a lump sum, discretionary payment from a manufacturer to a retailer for demand stimulating services such as feature advertisement. Our analysis suggests that street money helps to coordinate a dominant retailer channel profitably. As such, we derive some testable implications as to how a manufacturer may spend street money.</p><p>Our study also complements <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Iyer (1998)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Ingene and Parry (2000)</ref>. The former examines a channel with two symmetric retailers engaging in price and nonprice competition and concludes that neither quantity discounts nor a menu of two-part tariffs are sufficient to coordinate such a channel. The latter examines a two-retailer channel competing on price only and concludes that it is not always optimal to use either quantity discounts or a menu of two-part tariffs to coordinate such a channel. In contrast, we show that in the presence of a dominant retailer, it is always optimal for a manufacturer to coordinate the channel, so long as it chooses the right mechanism.</p><p>In the rest of the paper, we first set up our model and discuss coordination problems therein. We then show how quantity discounts plus a lump sum payment or a menu of two-part tariffs can be used by a manufacturer to coordinate the channel profitably. Finally, we compare these two coordination mechanisms to develop more managerial insights, and we conclude with suggestions for future research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Dominant Retailer and Channel Conflict</head><p>Our channel consists of a manufacturer selling through a dominant retailer and a competitive fringe. Specifically, we assume that the dominant retailer has market power and faces a downward-sloping demand curve given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Q d = − p + s (2.1)</formula><p>where ≤ 1 is the fraction of the market demand accounted for by the dominant retailer and s is the demand-stimulating service that only the dominant retailer provides to the manufacturer's product that goes beyond what the competitive fringe can provide. For instance, the dominant retailer can run feature advertisement or information seminars to promote the manufacturer's product. The cost of providing such service is f , which could be the opportunity cost of feature ad space. We assume that the dominant retailer is the price leader in the market and behaves as a monopolist in setting its price p and in deciding whether to provide the demand-stimulating service s given its demand. Once the dominant retailer sets its price, all retailers in the competitive fringe take this price as the market price. Our analysis will not be qualitatively altered if the competitive fringe simply adds a fixed markup or deducts a fixed dollar amount off the leader's price. This is generally consistent with the industry practice described earlier where small retailers use the pricing book of a large retailer. At that price, the demand facing the competitive fringe as a whole is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Q c = 1 − − p + s (2.2)</formula><p>which is, we assume, shared equally by the N fringe retailers. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> The total market demand is then simply Note that our specification of the demand function (2.2) implicitly assumes that a fringe retailer benefits from the demand-stimulating service provided by the dominant retailer. While this assumption greatly facilitates our analysis, it does not drive our main conclusions. 5</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">Q m = − p + s (2.3)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">The Integrated Channel</head><p>Channel profit is maximized if the manufacturer integrates forward and sets the market price p , and service s directly. Assuming a zero marginal cost, 6 the manufacturer solves the following optimization problem max</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">p 0 1 − p + s p − f (2.4)</formula><p>Assuming f ≤ s 2 + s / 4 , which ensures that the manufacturer can induce such service even when the channel is not integrated, we have the optimal channel profit and price as</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">* = 1 * s f = + s 2 4 − f p * = + s 2 and Q * m = + s 2 (2.5)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Independent Retailers</head><p>We assume that the manufacturer moves first in this channel, making a take-it-or-leave-it offer of its wholesale price (w) to all retailers. At any given wholesale price (w), the dominant retailer decides what price to charge and whether to provide any demand stimulating service. If such service is provided, the retailer's optimal price is determined by</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">max p − p + s p − w − f (2.6)</formula><p>which yields the optimal profits and price as p w s f = + s + w 2 and</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">d w s f = + s − w 2 4 − f (2.7)</formula><p>Because retail service cannot be monitored perfectly and hence is not contractable, the dominant 5 An alternative specification is to have Q d = − p + s and Q c = 1 − − p to eliminate the service externality and to let a retailer's market share to vary with s. Our analysis shows that this alternative model does not qualitatively alter our basic conclusions. The details of our analysis are available upon request from the authors and are posted at www.marketingscience.org. We thank an anonymous reviewer for suggesting this model. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Assuming nonzero, but constant production costs does not affect our substantive conclusions and hence are set equal to zero for simplicity.</p><p>retailer will provide such service only if d w s f ≥ d w 0 0 , or w ≤ w s , where</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">w s = s 2 + s − 4 f 2 s (2.8)</formula><p>Anticipating the decision by the dominant retailer, the manufacturer decides whether to induce service or not. By comparing the maximum profits that the manufacturer can obtain from inducing or not inducing the dominant retailer's service, we can characterize the equilibrium of this decentralized channel. The results are summarized in Table <ref type="table">1</ref>. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> The decentralized channel does not achieve the maximum channel profit for two reasons. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> First, due to the classic double marginization problem resurfaced in this channel with a dominant retailer, the retail price is too high to achieve the channel maximum (p &gt; p * for all f ≤ s 2 + s / 4 ). Second, the incentive facing the dominant retailer for service provision is also distorted, partly by double marginalization and partly by a smaller demand facing the dominant retailer. Consequently, it might choose not to render any service even when doing so will increase the channel profits (see the last column of Table <ref type="table">1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Quantity Discount and Channel Coordination</head><p>To achieve a coordinated channel, the manufacturer does not need to integrate forward and depart from its core competence. It can do so through pricing mechanisms. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> In that case, the manufacturer must find a pricing mechanism that can simultaneously achieve three objectives: first, to motivate the dominant retailer to set the retail price and to provide the desired service to maximize the channel profit; second, to maximize the manufacturer's own profit while securing the dominant retailer's cooperation; and third, to take as much profit away from the competitive fringe as possible. A quantity discount schedule à la Jeuland and Shugan ( <ref type="formula">1983</ref>) is one such pricing mechanism.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Optimal Quantity Discount Schedule</head><p>Let t q f be the unit price charged by the manufacturer when the order quantity from a retailer is q and 7 To facilitate the equilibrium analysis, we assume ≥ + s / + s + Ns and ≥ 7s. These conditions essentially imply that the effect of service is not very large relative to the base level of demand.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table 1</head><p>Equilibrium for Decentralized Channel</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">Service Service No service 0 ≤ f ≤ s 4 s 4 &lt; f ≤ s + s 2 + s 4 s + s 2 + s 4 &lt; f ≤ s 2 + s 4 p 3 + s 4 4 s + 3 s 2 − 4 f 4 s 3 4 w + s 2 s 2 + s − 4 f 2 s 2 m + s 2 8 4 f + s 2 s 2 + s − 4 f 8 s 2 2 8 d + s 2 16 − f s 2 − 4 f 2 16 s 2 2 16 c 1 − + s 2 16 1 − s 2 + 4 f 2 16 s 2 1 − 2 16 3 + s 2 16 − f 2 s 3 4 + 3s + 8 f s 2 + s − 2 s − 2 f 16 s 2 3 2 16</formula><p>the cost of service provision is f . Facing such a pricing schedule, the dominant retailer solves the following optimization problem:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">max p Q d p p − t Q d p f − f (3.1)</formula><p>The manufacturer needs to find a pricing schedule t q f whereby the retailer's profitability is aligned with the manufacturer's. They are aligned if the retailer's optimization problem (3.1) is transformed into the following instead:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">max p k 1 Q m p p − k 2 f (3.2)</formula><p>In the above equation, 0 &lt; k 1 &lt; 1 is the fraction of the total channel profit, excluding service cost, that the dominant retailer can capture. The parameter k 2 , where 0 ≤ k 2 ≤ 1, is the fraction of service cost that the dominant retailer cannot recover. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> The following proposition makes it clear that such a transformation is feasible and unique.</p><p>Proposition 1. A manufacturer can coordinate the channel with a dominant retailer by offering a quantity discount schedule with the unit price given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">t q f = − k 1 + s − q − 1 − k 2 f q</formula><p>Proposition 1 can be verified by substituting t q f into Equation (3.1) to obtain Equation (3.2). We can take the quantity discount schedule à la <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Jeuland and Shugan (1983)</ref> one step further by determining k 1 and k 2 . By noting that the manufacturer's discount 10 Note that k 1 and k 2 are similar but not identical to those in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Jeuland and Shugan (1983)</ref>.</p><p>schedule must ensure that the retailers in the competitive fringe are not priced out of the market and that the manufacturer uses minimum incentives to induce the dominant retailer to service its product, we have (see Appendix A)</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">k * 1 = N + − 1 2N + − 1 and k * 2 =        1 i f0 ≤ f ≤ k * 1 s 2 + s 4 k * 1 s 2 + s 4 f if k * 1 s 2 + s 4 &lt; f ≤ s 2 + s 4 (3.3)</formula><p>The optimal quantity discount schedule that coordinates the channel is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">t * q f = − k * 1 + s − q − 1 − k * 2 f q (3.4)</formula><p>Note that k * 1 &gt; 0 is strictly less than so that t * q f is indeed a quantity discount schedule. Under this schedule, a dominant retailer purchasing a quantity of q and providing the merchandizing service s will pay a unit price of t * q f . This means that when buying from the manufacturer a quantity of q, the dominant retailer pays a unit price of</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">− k * 1 + s − q</formula><p>and receives a lump sum compensation of 1 − k * 2 f for the service provision, making a profit of k</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">* 1 + s 2 / 4 − k *</formula><p>2 f . The competitive fringe retailer will simply pay a unit price depending on their order quantity according to t * q f when f is set equal to zero 11 Marketing Science 24(2), pp. 254-262, © 2005 INFORMS and makes a zero profit. We can show that for all f ≤ s 2 + s / 4 , the manufacturer is strictly better off when this quantity discount schedule is used to coordinate the channel than when it is not. Note that this quantity discount schedule favors the dominant firm not only with a lower unit price as in Shugan and <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Jeuland (1983)</ref>, but also with a potential service subsidy because a competitive fringe does not provide the same level of service by assumption.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Phenomenon of Street Money</head><p>"Street money" is the lump-sum cash payment that a manufacturer offers to a retailer for servicing its product, and it is frequently offered only to certain major players in a market in order to motivate their service provision <ref type="bibr">(Weinstein et al. 1990</ref>). The past literature has attributed the rise of street money-slotting fees in specific-mainly to the scarcity of shelf space and facilitating practices <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Chu 1992</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">, Shaffer 1991</ref>. Our analysis suggests that a different motivation is possible as summarized in the following proposition.</p><p>Proposition 2. (a) Street money from the manufacturer to the dominant retailer can arise as part of a manufacturer's effort to coordinate a dominant retailer channel. (b) For the purpose of coordinating the channel, the manufacturer offers more street money as service cost increases (larger f ) and as consumers become more price sensitive (higher ). It offers less street money when the dominant retailer is more dominant (larger ), when the number of retailers in the competitive fringe is larger (larger N ), or when the retail service is more effective (larger s).</p><p>The channel coordination role of street money can be seen from the fact that whenever the dominant retailer is sufficiently motivated to provide the desired service without any prodding from the manufacturer (when 0 &lt; f ≤ k * 1 s 2 + s / 4 ), the manufacturer's lump-sum payment for the service is zero even though the manufacturer is also a beneficiary of the service (Equations (A.1) and (3.4)). However, as service cost increases the manufacturer starts to offer service subsidies to motivate the retailer's cooperation. As a testable implication, this channel coordination perspective on street money suggests that a manufacturer may not mete out street money to all dominant retailers. Street money will be dispensed only to those retailers whose cost of service is sufficiently high. Anecdotal evidence seems to suggest that this is indeed the case, as chain supermarkets seem to collect a lion's share of street money from food and beverage product categories.</p><p>The phenomenon of street money is unique to our dominant retailer channel with asymmetrical capability of service provision. In a dyadic channel as studied by <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Jeuland and Shugan (1983)</ref>, street money is not required for channel coordination, although a side payment not related to the cost of providing service is possible. Neither is it required to coordinate a competitive channel according to <ref type="bibr">Parry (1995a, 2000)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Two-Part Tariffs and Channel Coordination</head><p>In practice, a manufacturer frequently uses a menu of two-part tariffs to implement quantity discounts <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Oren et al. 1982)</ref>. When devising such a menu, the manufacturer offers a set of price schedules, each of which consists of a fixed fee component F i ≥ 0 and a unit price component w i ≥ 0, where i indexes the price schedule. Because there are only two types of retailers in this channel, the manufacturer needs to set up only two such schedules, (F d w d ) intended for the dominant retailer and (F c w c ) for the competitive fringe. As we show in Appendix B, the manufacturer's optimal strategy is to set w d = 0 to align the interests of the dominant retailer and the manufacturer in the retail price and service provision, and set rest of its tariffs such that all surplus is taken away from the competitive fringe, leaving the dominant retailer indifferent choosing either price schedule. We have</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">F c =      0 i f 0 ≤ f ≤ s 4 1− +s 4 f − s 4 N s if s 4 &lt;f ≤ s 2 +s 4 F d =        3 +s 2 16 if 0 ≤ f ≤ s 4 F d if s 4 &lt;f ≤ s 2 +s 4 w c =      p * if 0 ≤ f ≤ s 4 w s if s 4 &lt;f ≤ s 2 +s 4 m =        4− +s 2 16 if 0 ≤ f ≤ s 4 m if s 4 &lt;f ≤ s 2 +s 4</formula><p>where F d and m are defined in Appendix B and p * and w s are, respectively, given by Equations (2.5) and (2.8). Some straightforward analysis of this menu yields the following proposition.</p><p>Proposition 3. A menu of two-part tariffs can coordinate a dominant retailer channel, whereby a retailer choosing to pay a low fixed fee pays a higher wholesale price and vice versa. However, channel coordination with a menu of two-part tariffs is not always profitable for the manufacturer.</p><p>The negative correlation between the wholesale price and the fixed fee is essential for the manufacturer to be able to separate the two types of retailers in </p><formula xml:id="formula_17">✲ ✻ # # # # # # # # # # # # # # # # ✦ ✦ ✦ ✦ ✦ ✦ ✦ ✦ ✦ ✦ ✦ ✦ ✦ ✦ ✦ ✦ ✥ ✥ ✥ ✥ ✥ ✥ ✥ ✥ ✥ ✥ ✥ ✥ ✥ ✥ ✥ ✥ γ = γ t ❤ ❤ ❤ ❤ ❤ ❤ f f f 1 = f f 3 = f f 4 Decentralization Coordination 1 2 N+2 Note.</formula><p>Parameter definitions are given in Table <ref type="table">2</ref>. Shaded region is where coordination is more profitable.</p><p>the market and to achieve channel coordination profitably. This feature of the pricing scheme is in sharp contrast to the quantity discount schedule discussed in the previous section where the dominant retailer pays a lower unit price and gets paid a lump sum, while a fringe retailer pays a higher unit price without being paid a lump sum. This is necessitated by the fact that the manufacturer must motivate a retailer to choose the intended tariffs. More specifically, the manufacturer must leave a potentially sizable surplus to the dominant retailer. As a result, the manufacturer is not always better off using a menu of two-part tariffs to coordinate the channel than not coordinating the channel at all. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows that when the dominant retailer is very dominant, and the service cost is high, the manufacturer is worse off using a menu of two-part tariffs to coordinate the channel.</p><p>With a menu of two-part tariffs, street money resurfaces when service cost is high. As shown by Equation (B.7) in Appendix B, when f &gt; s/ 4 , the manufacturer compensates the dominant retailer for providing retail service. This payment from the manufacturer to the dominant retailer once again demonstrates the channel coordination role of street money-such a payment does not have to occur even when the service cost is not zero. When such a payment does occur, it covers only part of the </p><formula xml:id="formula_18">f 1 s 2 + s 4 f 2 s 2 f 3 s + s 2 + s 4 f 4 s 4 f 5 k * 1 s 2 + s 4 b + s + s + Ns t 1 − N 2 2 1 + N + s 2</formula><p>cost when the dominant retailer has a small market share, but it exceeds the cost when the dominant retailer has a sufficiently high market share. This variation in the service fees reflects the manufacturer's effort to mete out the minimum incentive to induce channel coordination.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Winners and Losers of Channel Coordination</head><p>In our model, channel profits always increase due to coordination. However, not all channel members will benefit from this increase. In general, regardless of which pricing scheme is used to coordinate the channel, the competitive fringe is always worse off with coordination than without. The dominant retailer may become better or worse off, relative to an uncoordinated channel, when the manufacturer coordinates the channel with either quantity discounts or a menu of two-part tariffs. Consumers, however, always benefit from a lower price in a coordinated channel, and so does society as whole because the channel profit also increases when the channel is coordinated. Finally, the manufacturer is better off with coordination, so long as it judiciously chooses its coordination mechanism.</p><p>The following proposition makes it more precise.</p><p>Proposition 4. The manufacturer prefers quantity discounts to a menu of two-part tariffs as a channel coordination mechanism when the service cost is sufficiently high (f ≥ f 6 ). However, it may prefer a menu of two-part tariffs at a given service cost when the dominant retailer is sufficiently dominant.</p><p>It is straightforward to verify Proposition 4 by comparing the manufacturer's payoffs under quantity discounts and two-part tariffs. In Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>, we illustrate the results of this analysis.  <ref type="table">2</ref>. The existence of f 6 , where f 5 &lt; f 6 &lt; f 2 , is shown in Appendix C. The shaded area is the region where a mean of two-part tariffs is preferred to quantity discounts.</p><p>Intuitively, when the service cost is high, the manufacturer must provide increasingly more incentives in the form of a lump-sum payment to the dominant retailer, not only to motivate the dominant retailer to provide service but also to neutralize the retailer's incentive to choose the unintended pricing schedule. This is why at a high service cost, the manufacturer over-compensates the dominant retailer. Because of the overcompensation, the manufacturer's profit drops precipitously with a higher service cost. This is not the case, however, when a quantity discount schedule is used. The manufacturer's profit under the optimal quantity discount schedule decreases with the cost as expected, but it decreases slowly to make the pricing scheme stand out as the manufacturer's choice when the service cost is high.</p><p>A menu of two-part tariffs might however, stand out as the manufacturer's coordination mechanism when the dominant retailer is sufficiently dominant. A more dominant retailer has a smaller incentive to choose the pricing schedule intended for the competitive fringe and, hence, allows the manufacturer to extract more surplus from the dominant retailer when it uses a menu of two-part tariffs. In other words, channel power, measured as the relative profitability of a channel member <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Messinger and Narasimhan 1995)</ref>, can shift to the manufacturer when the channel is coordinated with a menu of two-part tariffs. In contrast, when quantity discounts are used, power shifts from the manufacturer to the dominant retailer as the latter becomes more dominant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusions</head><p>In this paper, we have developed a parsimonious model of a channel with a dominant retailer to capture some of the salient characteristics in some of today's distribution channels: power retailers, independents, price leadership, and retail service. The focus of our analysis was primarily on how such a channel can be coordinated profitably by a manufacturer. Our analysis identifies the challenges and opportunities specific to coordinating such a channel and sheds some new light on channel coordination as a managerial imperative.</p><p>We show that a manufacturer is better off coordinating a dominant retailer channel through quantity discounts when the cost of retail services is high, and through a menu of two-part tariffs, when the cost is low, or when the dominant retailer is sufficiently dominant. We also show that channel coordination can motivate the provision of retail services by power retailers and the choice of coordination mechanisms may have a bearing on channel power. In this context, we show that the phenomenon of "street money" can arise from the manufacturer's effort to mete out minimum incentives to power retailers in order to coordinate a channel.</p><p>Our model is a first step in studying issues related to coordinating a channel populated by power retailers. Future research can, for instance, relax some of our assumptions such as a single dominant retailer and a fixed level of retail services. It can also empirically test some of our predictions regarding street money.</p><p>the two-part tariffs intended for them, their profits are, respectively,</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">d = + s 2 4 − f − F d c = 1 − + s 2N p * − w c − F c (B.1)</formula><p>To motivate participation by all retailers, the manufacturer must choose its price schedules so that they all make nonnegative profit, or d ≥ 0 and c ≥ 0. These two inequalities We can show that the case w c &gt; w s is never optimal for the manufacturer. Thus, the manufacturer solves the following optimization problem: Solving this optimization problem, we have</p><note type="other">max</note><formula xml:id="formula_20">F d = F d = 4 2 N + −1 +4 s 2N + −1 +3N s 2 16 N − f 2 fN +s 2 −1+ +s N +2 −2 2N s 2 (B.7) m = m = 4 2 N + − 1 + 4 s 2N + − 1 + N 4 − s 2 16 N − f 2 fN + s 2 −1 + + N + 2 − 2 s 2N s 2</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix C</head><p>In this appendix, we show that a f 6 exists, where f 5 &lt; f 6 &lt; f 2 , so that whenever f &gt; f 6 , the manufacturer prefers quantity discounts and whenever f &lt; f 6 the manufacturer prefers a menu of two-part tariffs. Let m f = q m − t m , where q m is the manufacturer's payoff when quantity discounts are used to coordinate the channel and t m is the manufacturer's payoff when a menu of two-part tariffs are used. We can easily show that m f 5 &lt; 0 but m f 2 &gt; 0. Furthermore, we have m f / f &gt; 0. Thus, there must exist a f 6 ∈ f 5 f 2 so that m f 6 = 0.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1Menu of Two-Part Tariffs and Channel Coordination</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2Optimal Channel Coordination Mechanism</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>imply F d ≤ + s 2 / 4 − f and F c ≤ 1 − + s / 2N • p * − w c . A competitive fringe firm will choose (F c w c ), instead of (F d 0), if F d − F c ≥ 1 − + s / 2N w c . The equivalent condition for the dominant retailer is, when w c ≤ w s , F d − F c ≤ w c 2 + s − w c 4</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>F</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Raju and Zhang: Channel Coordination in the Presence of a Dominant Retailer</figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science 24(2), pp. 254-262, © 2005 INFORMS</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">More recently,<ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Gerstner and Hess (1995)</ref> examine the channel coordination role of pull promotions in the same channel context and<ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Weng (1995)</ref> examines that of quantity discounts from an operations management perspective.<ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Srivastava et al. (2000)</ref> as well as<ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Kadiyali et al. (2000)</ref> empirically investigate pricing issues within a channel. Issues related to advertising in a distribution channel are discussed in<ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shaffer and Zettelmeyer (2004)</ref>.3  In a separate article,<ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Ingene and Parry (1995b)</ref> extend the analysis to the case of a manufacturer dealing with many independent retailers and controlling channel breadth.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">Our analysis is not qualitatively altered if we allow retailers in the competitive fringe to be of unequal size.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8">Note that we have * &gt; for all f ≤ s 2 + s / 4 .9  Potentially, a firm can also achieve the same objective through varying its product offering. See<ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bergen et al. (1996)</ref>.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="11">As stated earlier, we assume that the competitive fringe does not provide s and therefore does not incur the cost of f .</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank four anonymous reviewers, the area editor, and the editor for their constructive comments. They also thank Eric Bradlow for his helpful comments.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix A</head><p>To determine k 1 , note that the unit price each competitive fringe will pay under the pricing schedule t q f will be</p><p>To achieve the coordinated outcome, the manufacturer must set its quantity discount schedule so that the competitive fringes are not priced out of the market. This means that we must have w * c = p * , or</p><p>as in Proposition 1.</p><p>To determine k 2 , we note that the manufacturer has every incentive, for the sake of maximizing its own profit, to let the retailer bear as much burden of service costs as it is consistent with providing sufficient motivation for the retailer to service its product. Under the quantity discount schedule in Proposition 1, the difference between the retailer's optimal profit when the service is provided and that when it is not is given by k * 1 s 2 + s / 4 − k 2 f . This means that the k 2 that maximizes the manufacturer's profit and yet provides sufficient incentive for the retailer to service its product is given by</p><p>Thus, the optimal pricing schedule that the manufacturer sets to coordinate the channel is given by</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix B</head><p>The key to coordinating this channel is to motivate the retailer to set its price at p * as defined in Equation (2.5). From Equation (2.7), we can see that the manufacturer can do so only if it sets w d = 0. Then, given (F d 0) and (F c w c ), if the dominant retailer and the competitive fringe all choose</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Branded variants: A retail perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bergen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dutta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="19" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Demand signaling and screening in channels of distribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wujin</forename><surname>Chu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="327" to="347" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competition and cooperation in marketing channel choice: Theory and application</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anne</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Coughlan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="110" to="129" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On credible delegation by oligopolists: A discussion of distribution channel management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anne</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Coughlan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Birger Wernerfelt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="226" to="239" />
			<date type="published" when="1989-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Power retailers are not going to control it all</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eddie</forename><surname>Epstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Beverage World</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="15" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pull promotions and channel coordination</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Eitan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hess</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Channel coordination when retailers compete</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ingene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Parry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="360" to="377" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coordination and manufacturer profit maximization: The multiple retailer channel</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ingene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Parry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Retailing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="151" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is channel coordination all it is cracked up to be?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ingene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Parry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Retailing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="511" to="547" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coordinating channels under price and nonprice competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ganesh</forename><surname>Iyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="338" to="355" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing channel profits</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abel</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Jeuland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="272" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing channel profits-reply</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abel</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Jeuland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manufacturer-retailer channel interactions and implications for channel power: An empirical investigation of pricing in a local market</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kadiyali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pradeep</forename><surname>Vrinda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Naufel</forename><surname>Chintagunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Vilcassim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="148" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Grocery Revolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leigh</forename><surname>Mcalister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Reading, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving channel coordination through franchising</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rajiv</forename><surname>Lal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="299" to="318" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An industry equilibrium analysis of downstream vertical integration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mcguire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Staelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="190" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Has power shifted in the grocery channel?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Messinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chakravarthi</forename><surname>Narasimhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="189" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing channel profits: Comment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Moorthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sridhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="375" to="379" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonlinear pricing in markets with independent demand</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Oren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="287" to="313" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The components and consequences of pricing: Interview with Jack Cohen</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ken</forename><surname>Partch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Supermarket Bus</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="42" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anticompetitive vertical integration by a dominant firm</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Riordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1232" to="1248" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Samuelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Nordhaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economics</title>
		<editor>13. McGraw-Hill</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clout! More and more, retail giants rule the marketplace</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zachary</forename><surname>Schiller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><surname>Zellner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Business Week</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="72" />
			<date type="published" when="1992-12-21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Slotting allowances and resale price maintenance: A comparison of facilitating practices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Shaffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rand J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="120" to="135" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advertising in a distribution channel</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Shaffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Zettelmeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="619" to="628" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Economics of Industrial Organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Shepherd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="62" to="64" />
			<pubPlace>Upper Saddle River, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Price and margin negotiations in marketing channels: An experimental study of sequential bargaining under one-sided uncertainty and opportunity cost of delay</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joydeep</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dipankar</forename><surname>Chakravarti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amnon</forename><surname>Rapoport</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="184" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Competing with the Retail Giants</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kenneth</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>John Wiley and Sons</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="254" to="262" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How retailing&apos;s superpower-and our biggest most admired company-is changing the rules for corporate America</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jerry</forename><surname>Useem</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Fortune</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">65</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003-02-18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Wahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Store Marketing: A New Dimension in the Share Wars</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Sawyer Pub. Worldwide</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The price is righter</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Weinstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Progressive Grocer</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="94" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New deal: Out of the case and into the street</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Weistein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Hammonds</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Helmut</forename><surname>Radtke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Progressive Grocer</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="44" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Channel coordination and quantity discounts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Weng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1509" to="1522" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trade promotions: A call for a more rational approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Zerrillo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dawn</forename><surname>Iacobucci</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bus. Horizons</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="80" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
