<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Customized Advertising via a Common Media Distributor</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2003-07-10">July 10, 2003</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Esther</forename><surname>Gal-Or</surname></persName>
							<email>esther@katz.pitt.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Mordechai</forename><surname>Gal-Or</surname></persName>
							<email>galor@duq.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Palumbo</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Katz Graduate School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">368A Mervis Hall</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>15260</postCode>
									<settlement>Pittsburgh</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Duquesne University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>470 Rockwell Hall</addrLine>
									<postCode>15282</postCode>
									<settlement>Pittsburgh</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Customized Advertising via a Common Media Distributor</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 05 2402 0241</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2003-07-10">July 10, 2003</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1040.0092</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:26+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>In this paper we investigate how media content distributors can utilize customized advertising to alleviate price competition in product markets. We focus, in particular, on distributors that act as common agents for competing advertisers by delivering commercials on their behalf. Sophisticated information technologies, combined with greater availability of information concerning consumption habits of consumers, offer tremendous opportunities to deliver targeted ads to different segments of the population. Television cable companies, radio broadcasters, and Internet providers can utilize the new technologies to deliver commercials to consumers that are better aligned with their preferences.</p><p>Consider, for instance, the emergence of the digital personal video recorder (PVR) technology in the television market. Because PVRs are programmable, they can record and transmit household viewing patterns. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Data mining techniques can be used to predict a household's characteristics from its viewing choices, and customized advertising that is relevant to the household's type can be sent to its PVR. 2 Such targeted advertisements are more likely to be viewed and influence purchasing behavior than nontargeted ones. They are also more efficient because fewer placements are necessary to achieve the same number of exposures to the desired demographic group. The emergence of the PVR has led to the creation of several start-up companies such as ACTV, Vision World, and MSA-Jovio to develop the necessary software to support customized advertising, with the anticipation that cable operators will find it profitable to subsidize the cost of the PVR to customers. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The main result of our investigation is that under certain circumstances the distributor can implement monopoly pricing in product markets by controlling the extent of information that consumers have about competing products. Specifically, when consumers have only limited outside information about the specific product class and rely heavily on the commercials delivered by the distributor to gain such 2 Some privacy concerns might arise with the use of the profiling system that monitors and analyzes viewing behavior (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Franzak et al. 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">, Phelps et al. 2000</ref> for a summary of such concerns in the context of online shopping). <ref type="bibr">3</ref> Several patents that are related to individually addressable digital recording devices have been already granted <ref type="bibr">(Patent No. 6,</ref><ref type="bibr">002,</ref><ref type="bibr">393,</ref><ref type="bibr">Hite et al.</ref> System and Method for Delivering Targeted Advertisements to Consumers Using Direct Commands, December 14, 1999).</p><p>Marketing Science 24(2), pp. 241-253, © 2005 INFORMS information, monopoly pricing in the product market arises as an equilibrium. This result is related to the literature on a common agency in oligopoly (see <ref type="bibr">Whinston 1985, 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Gal-Or 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Villas-Boas 1994)</ref>. This previous literature has discussed the role of the common agent in implementing collusion among competitors and maximizing their joint profits. To obtain the maximization of industry profits, the common agent in this previous literature determines the terms of its agreement with the firms contingent upon product market variables such as sales volumes or prices. In contrast, in our setting the media distributor can condition its relationship with the advertisers only on the levels of advertising they choose to deliver to different groups of consumers. In spite of the more restricted class of variables that can be utilized in the contracts, the distributor can still sometimes implement monopoly pricing. However, given that such pricing is obtained by withholding information from some consumers, there is increased likelihood that consumers remain ignorant of the existence of the products and refrain from consumption altogether. Hence, in spite of monopoly pricing, industry profits are not necessarily maximized anymore.</p><p>We are familiar with only one other paper in the marketing literature that relates to targeted advertising. Similar to our investigation, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Iyer et al. (2005)</ref> also consider the implications of targeted advertising on the extent of competition in product markets. However, whereas in our setting the media distributor acts as a common agent in delivering targeted ads to consumers, in Iyer et al. the advertisers themselves have the ability to target advertising messages to consumers. Their finding that advertisers choose to advertise more to consumers who have a strong preference for their products is similar to the one we obtain.</p><p>While the concept of targeted advertising received only scant attention in the marketing literature, the general idea of targeting individual consumers with tailored offers has already been widely discussed (see, for instance, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Blattberg and Deighton 1991</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">, Chen et al. 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">, Lederer and Hurter 1986</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, Montgomery 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">, Zhang and Krishnamurthi 2004</ref>. The main emphasis of this literature, however, has been on evaluating how targeted marketing can facilitate the practice of price discrimination by firms. In contrast, in our model, firms have to quote a single price to all consumers, even when customizing the type of commercials delivered to them <ref type="bibr">(Iyer et al. consider</ref> targeted advertising with and without price discrimination).</p><p>The literature on targeted marketing uses purchase histories, panel data, or other types of consumer behavior as a basis for targeting (see, for instance, Blattberg and Deighton 1991, Bult and Wansbeek 1995, <ref type="bibr">Allenby 1993, Rossi et al. 1996)</ref>. Recent research has also begun to focus on internet advertising, which presents other types of customer behavior that can be analyzed and modeled <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Chickering and Heckerman 2003)</ref>. Our theoretical model places no restrictions on the type of marketing related behavior that can be utilized as a basis for targeting ads. In particular, in the case of the PVR example mentioned above, it is television viewing data that are used in targeting commercials to different demographic groups.</p><p>In our model, advertising plays only an informative role of educating consumers of the attributes of the advertised products. Our assumptions are similar to those considered in <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Dukes and Gal-Or (2003)</ref> or <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Grossman and Shapiro (1984)</ref>. Alternative models, where advertising plays a persuasive role, aimed at enhancing the willingness to pay of customers or the cross-price elasticity between products, have also been considered in the literature (see, for instance, <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Banerjee and Bandyopadhyay 2003</ref><ref type="bibr">, Fruchter 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">, Fruchter and Kalish 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">, Shaffer and Zettelmeyer 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">, von der Fehr and Stevik 1998</ref>. The idea of tailoring the type and volume of ads to the preferences of viewers was not considered in those earlier papers.</p><p>The rest of this paper is organized as follows. In the next section, we describe the main assumptions of the model. In §3 we derive the equilibria, and in §4 we conclude. The appendixes include proofs and several extensions of the basic model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Model</head><p>Consider a media content distributor who has the capability to deliver targeted advertising to consumers. Two advertisers contemplate their advertising strategies with the distributor. The strategy selected by each determines both the overall level and the extent of targeting of its advertising messages to different groups of consumers.</p><p>The two advertisers offer competing brands of a given product class. We model the competition between them by using a Hotelling model. Specifically, the population of consumers is uniformly distributed on a line of unit length, with the two competing brands located at the edges of this line. Each consumer is willing to pay a maximum price of p * for an "ideal" type of product, the characteristics of which exactly match her location on the line. This willingness to pay declines linearly, at the rate of $t per unit of distance, when the consumer buys a brand located at a point different than her location on the line. Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> illustrates the willingness to pay of a representative consumer. In the sequel, we derive a condition to guarantee that at the symmetric equilibrium advertisers find it optimal to serve the entire population of consumers. This condition is stated as</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">p * &gt; 2t (A1)</formula><p>Our model focuses only on the informative role of advertising. Specifically, commercials inform consumers of the attributes and the price of the advertised product. Equipped with this information, consumers choose whether and which of the two brands to purchase. The larger the number of commercials sent to the consumer pertaining to this brand, the more likely the consumer is to be familiar with the brand. Consider, for instance, the PVR example discussed earlier. Because PVRs are programmable, they can record and transmit household viewing patterns. Data mining techniques can be used, in turn, to predict a household's characteristics from its viewing choices. Those techniques can enable the distributor to predict, in particular, the relative preference of the consumer between the two competing brands, as reflected by her location x on the line. For instance, if Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> depicts competition between two brands of cereal, one having higher sugar content than the other, then the distributor can differentially send a larger number of commercials pertaining to the more sweetened brand to households whose viewing patterns indicate an interest in children's programming. Similarly, if the figure depicts competition between two types of automobiles, the distributor can differentially send a larger number of commercials pertaining to sports-like cars (e.g., convertibles) to young couples without children or to unmarried individuals. In contrast, mature adults without children are more likely to receive commercials pertaining to large sedans.</p><p>If a consumer is familiar with only one of the brands, she purchases it as long as its price p i falls short of the consumer's willingness to pay for this brand, namely if p * − tx − p i &gt; 0. If the consumer is familiar with both brands, she purchases brand i if it offers her a positive net payoff that exceeds the payoff she could derive from the competing brand j. Specifically, if p * − tx − p i ≥ p * − t 1 − x − p j and p * − tx − p i &gt; 0. We also assume that brand producers cannot price discriminate, implying that they post a single price common to all consumers. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> In the absence of any advertising with the distributor there is probability that a consumer is familiar with a given brand. This probability is the same for both products. We refer to as the base awareness level of consumers. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> This base awareness level is implied by the existence of alternative sources of information that are available to consumers, including "word of mouth," and commercials on other media outlets such as newspapers, radio, and TV. Advertising with the distributor increases the probability that consumers are familiar with the advertised brand. The increased probability for a given consumer depends on the number of commercials that are transmitted to her by the distributor. Specifically, we assume that a larger number of transmitted commercials results in a more significant rise in the probability that the consumer becomes familiar with the advertised product.</p><p>We formulate the advertising strategy of i in terms of two parameters, a i and b i , which determine the extent to which different consumers are exposed to commercials of brand i. Specifically, the differential transmission of commercials to consumers results in a differential increase of the probability that a consumer becomes familiar with i. This increase for a consumer who is located at distance x from i amounts to a i − b i x . Hence, a higher value of a i implies an overall increase in the number of commercials that are transmitted to all consumers. In contrast, a higher value of b i indicates that the distributor differentiates more significantly between different types of consumers. Those who are judged by the profiling technology to have a stronger preference for i are exposed to many more commercials about this product than are the consumers who are identified as having a stronger preference for the competing brand j. Therefore, the parameter b i measures the extent of targeting that is selected by advertiser i. The parameters a i and b i cannot violate the requirement that probabilities lie in the interval between zero and one. Moreover, the probability of reaching a consumer cannot fall short of her initial awareness level . The restrictions imposed in A2 guarantee that to be the case:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">0 ≤ a i ≤ 1 − 0 ≤ b i ≤ a i (A2)</formula><p>The costs of the distributor might depend on the advertising strategies selected by the two advertisers. We designate those costs as T C a i b i a j b j and assume that this function is nondecreasing with a k ; k = 1 2. Airing additional commercials on behalf of either one of the two brands could increase the costs Marketing Science 24(2), pp. 241-253, © 2005 INFORMS of the distributor for two reasons. First, if the distributor faces limited capacity of advertising slots, additional commercials allocated to one of the brands forces it to give up advertising revenues, accruing possibly from other product markets. Second, if the distributor's customers consider commercials a nuisance because they interrupt regular programming (such as commercial breaks on TV or radio, or popup ads on the Internet), they perceive the distributor to be less attractive if it raises its level of advertising. Hence, even in the absence of capacity constraints on advertising slots, the distributor could experience a decline of its customer base when increasing the number of commercials it airs. Such a decline, in turn, is likely to lower its rating 6 and, as a result, the price the distributor can command from advertisers. We summarize this opportunity cost facing the distributor by assuming the following:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">T C a k ≥ 0 (A3)</formula><p>An increase of the targeting parameters could have two counteracting effects on the cost facing the distributor. On one hand, an increase in b k implies that advertiser k airs fewer commercials, thus potentially freeing up advertising space and reducing the opportunity cost of the distributor. On the other hand, higher values of b k imply also that the distributor needs to invest additional resources to improve the profiling engine because a more precise identification of market segments is required when the type of advertising varies significantly across segments. We assume that the former favorable effect on the distributor's cost more than outweighs the latter unfavorable effect so that: 7</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">T C b k ≤ 0 (A4)</formula><p>We also assume that when a given advertiser increases both parameters by the same amount, the costs of the distributor can only rise; specifically:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">T C a k + T C b k ≥ 0 (A5)</formula><p>Consider, for instance, the case that the costs of the distributor consist of two components: a component that is independent of the value of the advertising parameters, measuring the fixed costs of developing the profiling engine, and a component measuring the opportunity costs of carrying the commercials of the two advertisers. The latter component is proportional to the average number of commercials that the two advertisers select. If each advertiser chooses to send some commercials to all viewers (i.e., if a i − b i ≥ 0), the average number of advertising slots consumed by the two advertisers is proportional to a 1 − b 1 /2 + a 2 − b 2 /2 , and the costs incurred by the distributor can be expressed as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">T C a 1 b 1 a 2 b 2 = F + a 1 − b 1 /2 + a 2 − b 2 /2 (1)</formula><p>where the parameter can be related to the price the distributor could have charged from advertisers in other industries or to the decline of its rating due to the loss of audience that additional commercials entail. The above linear specification satisfies all our earlier assumptions concerning the cost schedule T C • .</p><p>For simplicity, we assume that, other than their payments to the distributor, advertisers incur no production costs. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> We model the game as consisting of three stages. In the first stage, the distributor makes a take-it-or-leaveit offer to the advertisers, specifying their payment schedule as a function of their selected advertising parameters a i and b i . In the second stage, the two brand producers choose their advertising strategies, and in the third and final stage, the two brands compete as Bertrand competitors, after observing the advertising strategies chosen in the second stage of the game. We assume that the distributor is prohibited from offering a different payment schedule to the two competing advertisers. This constraint can be implied by antitrust regulation or by "most favored nation" type of clauses between the distributor and the advertisers of a given industry. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> We designate the payment schedule chosen by the distributor as R a i b i . We do not impose any restrictions on the shape of this schedule. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> In particular, consistent with empirical findings of <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Koschat and Putsis (2002)</ref>, we allow the schedule to be nonlinear.</p><p>Given that consumers are a priori equally familiar with the two products (i.e., 1 = 2 = and given that the distributor cannot discriminate between the two advertisers, we restrict attention to the derivation of symmetric equilibria. At such equilibria, advertisers choose identical advertising parameters and prices for their products.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Solution</head><p>Because we focus only on the derivation of subgame perfect equilibria, we start by considering the third stage of the game. We characterize the competition in this stage as a function of the advertising strategies chosen by the two brand producers in the second stage of the game.</p><p>A consumer who is familiar with both brands will purchase brand 1 if her location on the line in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> satisfies the inequality</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">x ≤ 1 2 + p 2 − p 1 2t</formula><p>Hence, given the advertising parameters a i , b i i = 1 2 selected in the second stage, the proportion of the population that is fully informed and buys brand 1 is equal to</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">A 1 ≡ 1 2 + p 2 −p 1 /2t 0 + a 1 − b 1 x + a 2 − b 2 1 − x dx</formula><p>The integrand of A 1 is the probability that a type x consumer is familiar with both products, and the upper limit of the integration is determined by the threshold consumer who is just indifferent between the two brands.</p><p>A consumer who is familiar with only brand 1 will buy it, assuming that equilibrium prices are sufficiently low so that p 1 + tx ≤ p * . In the sequel, we show that Assumption A1 guarantees this inequality for all x at the symmetric equilibrium. Hence, the proportion of the consumers that buy brand 1 while being informed only of its existence and not of its competitor amounts to</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">B 1 ≡ 1 0 + a 1 − b 1 x 1 − + a 2 − b 2 1 − x dx = + a 1 − b 1 2 − + a 1 − b 1 2 • + a 2 − b 2 2 − b 1 b 2 12</formula><p>The integrand of B 1 is the probability that consumer x is familiar with brand 1 but not with brand 2, and the integration is over the entire population of consumers. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> The above derivation implies that the payoff function of brand producer 1 gross of his payment to the distributor is equal to: 12</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">1 = A 1 + B 1 p 1 (2)</formula><p>Similarly, the payoff function of brand producer 2 gross of his payment to the distributor can be derived as</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">2 = A 2 + B 2 p 2 (3)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">A 2 ≡ 1 2 + p 1 −p 2 /2t 0 + a 2 − b 2 x + a 1 − b 1 1 − x dx B 2 ≡ 1 0 + a 2 − b 2 x 1 − + a 1 − b 1 1 − x dx = + a 2 − b 2 2 − + a 1 − b 1 2 + a 2 − b 2 2 − b 1 b 2 12 (<label>4</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_12">)</formula><p>Producer i chooses his price to maximize i , yielding the following two first-order conditions:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">A i + B i − p i 2t + a 1 − b 1 x + a 2 − b 2 1 − x = 0 i = 1 2 (5)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">x = 1 2 + p 2 − p 1 2t</formula><p>Because the distributor is restricted from offering different payment schedules to the advertisers and because the advertisers face identical production costs (zero for both) and basic awareness levels on the part of consumers 1 = 2 = , we focus primarily on the characterization of symmetric equilibria, <ref type="bibr">13</ref> where <ref type="bibr">11</ref> In the above derivations we implicitly assume that advertisers choose to send messages to all consumers, including those who are located far from them (i.e., + a i − b i x &gt; for all x i &lt; 1). In the technical appendix at http://mktsci.pubs.informs.org, we derive a restriction to guarantee this outcome.</p><p>Marketing Science 24(2), pp. 241-253, © 2005 INFORMS a 1 = a 2 = a, b 1 = b 2 = b, p 1 = p 2 = p, and x = 1/2. Evaluating (5) at the symmetric equilibrium yields</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">p = 2t + a − b/2 − 1 2 + a − b/2 2 + 1 24 b 2 + a − b/2 2 (6)</formula><p>Note that the equilibrium price in ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>) is higher than the transportation parameter t. This is in contrast to the outcome obtained in an environment with perfectly informed consumers, when equilibrium prices are equal to the transportation parameter t. Because in our model, consumers might sometimes be informed of only one brand, producers take advantage of this possible ignorance to raise prices above t. Also, to guarantee that every consumer participates in the market even when she is informed of only one product, we require that p ≤ p * − t. Because from (6), p ≥ t,</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">the region t ≤ p ≤ p * − t is nonempty only if p * ≥ 2t (Assumption A1).</formula><p>In Lemma 1 we summarize the restrictions on the advertising parameters that guarantee that (i) every consumer who is informed of at least one product participates in the market and (ii) producers choose to send at least some messages to every consumer.</p><p>Lemma 1. To guarantee complete coverage of the market, both in terms of full participation of consumers and delivery of commercials by producers, the following restrictions on the advertising parameters have to be imposed at the symmetric equilibrium:</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">Max b + LB ≤ a + ≤ 1 (<label>7</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_18">)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">LB ≡ b 2 + t p * + t p * 2 + b 2 t 12p *<label>(8)</label></formula><p>In Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>, we describe the feasible region of the advertising parameters. In view of Assumption A1, </p><formula xml:id="formula_20">C ′ B ′ A′ D ′ a = b a = b a = b a b panel A empty feasible set 1-α 1-α 1-α a + α = LB a + α = LB a + α = LB 2 t 1 &gt; p* b max 2 b max 1 2 t 1 ≤ p* 0 &lt; v (α) ≤ 2 1 &lt; 0 &lt; v (α) t p* 0 ≤ &lt; v (α)</formula><p>either panel B or C of the figure can arise, implying that the feasible set is nonempty. Note that the lower boundary of this set corresponds to either monopoly pricing by producers (when a + = LB, p = p * − t) or maximum level of targeting selected by them (when a = b, advertisers choose the highest level of targeting consistent with Assumption A2). In panel B, the lower boundary consists only of parameter values that implement monopoly pricing. In panel C, the lower boundary consists also of values that yield maximum targeting (when b &gt; b 2 max ). The threshold level of the ratio t/p * that distinguishes between panels B and C is designated in the figure by v . This threshold level is a positive fraction less than 1/2, whose value depends upon . In particular, when = 0 v = 3/13. It might be interesting to further investigate how the equilibrium prices chosen in the third stage of the game vary when the advertising parameters change. Total differentiation of system (5) around the symmetric equilibrium allows us to conduct a comparative statics analysis to evaluate the relationship between equilibrium price and the advertising parameters. We report the results of this analysis in Proposition 1.</p><p>Proposition 1. Changes in the advertising parameters a i , b i have the following effect on prices around the symmetric equilibrium:</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">(i) p j a i ≤ p i a i ≤ 0 (ii) p j b i ≥ p i b i ≥ 0</formula><p>According to Proposition 1, when advertisers reduce their overall levels of advertising and intensify the extent of targeting of their ads, they compete less aggressively in prices (a similar result is also derived in <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Iyer et al. 2005)</ref>. When consumers receive fewer commercials, they are less informed about the options available to them in the marketplace. As a result, brand producers can raise their prices without having to worry about losing customers. Intensified targeting has the effect of reducing the number of commercials received by consumers who don't have a strong preference for either one of the two brands. Because loyal customers are inclined to buy their favorite products irrespective of their prices, it is usually the consumers with moderate tastes who determine how aggressively brand producers have to compete in prices. It is interesting to note that a change in the advertising strategy of one producer affects the competitor's price to a greater extent than it affects the producer's own price.</p><p>Having solved the third stage of the game, we can now consider the second stage, when each brand producer chooses his advertising strategy. This choice depends on the anticipated effect of the strategy on price competition in the third stage as well as on the payment schedule offered by the distributor in the first stage of the game.</p><p>Let i a i b i a j b j designate the revenues that accrue to each brand producer at the third stage equilibrium, then using system (5),</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">i a i b i a j b j ≡ + a 1 − b 1 x + a 2 − b 2 1 − x p 2 i 2t<label>(9)</label></formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">x = 1 2 + p 2 − p 1 2t</formula><p>and p 1 and p 2 solve (5). Given the payment schedule R a i b i offered by the distributor, the second-stage payoff function of advertiser i becomes</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">u i a i b i a j b j = i a i b i a j b j − R a i b i i = 1 2 (10)</formula><p>The advertiser chooses his strategy as expressed by a i b i to maximize (10), yielding the following firstorder conditions at an interior equilibrium:</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">u i a i = i a i − R a i = 0 u i b i = i b i − R b i = 0 (11)</formula><p>To guarantee that the equilibrium is interior, the objective defined in (10) should be a concave function of the decision variables a i and b i . It is noteworthy that brand producer i chooses positive levels of advertising only if doing so enhances his profits. In the absence of advertising, the expected payoff of i amounts to i 0 0 a j b j . Hence, producer i will choose to transact with the distributor only if u i ≥ i 0 0 a j b j (12)</p><p>Conditions ( <ref type="formula">11</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula">12</ref>) constrain the maximization problem of the distributor in the first stage of the game. Those conditions have been referred to in the literature as incentive compatibility (IC) and individual rationality (IR) constraints.</p><p>In the first stage, the distributor chooses the payment schedules to maximize its proceeds from the advertisers net of the costs it incurs in carrying their ads. It chooses R a i b i , therefore, to maximize</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">Max W = R a 1 b 1 + R a 2 b 2 − T C a 1 b 1 a 2 b 2 s.t. IC + IR constraints</formula><p>It is clear that the solution to the above maximization entails extracting the most surplus possible from each brand producer, implying that the individual rationality constraint ( <ref type="formula">12</ref>) is binding. We can express, therefore, the above objective of the distributor as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">Max W = 1=1 2 j =i i a i b i a j b j − i 0 0 a j b j − T C a 1 b 1 a 2 b 2 (13) s.t. a 1 b 1 a 2 b 2</formula><p>solve the following conditions:</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">i a i = R a i i b i = R b i i = 1 2 (IC)</formula><p>Note that the slope of the payment schedule R • determines the levels of the advertising parameters a i b i , as selected by advertiser i. Hence, the distributor can implement any desired pair of advertising parameters by selecting appropriate steepness of the schedule R • . Its maximization problem can be interpreted, therefore, as a direct choice of the advertising parameters instead of the indirect choice of those parameters as implied by the schedule 14 of R • .</p><p>It is noteworthy that the distributor's objective function in (13) coincides with total industry profits when i 0 0 a j b j = 0. When producers do not have any viable outside alternative to reaching consumers, other than through the distributor, = 0 and the distributor can extract the entire profits generated in the industry.</p><p>While it is difficult, in general, to derive the expression for the "outside option" of the non advertising producer (the expression i 0 0 a b , there are circumstances in which such a characterization is relatively simple. In Lemma 2 we state a condition that guarantees that when only one producer advertises, the equilibrium is characterized by significant Marketing Science 24(2), pp. 241-253, © 2005 INFORMS undercutting of prices on the part of the nonadvertising producer-so much so that this producer dominates the entire market of consumers who are fully informed of both products (if producer 1 is the only one to advertise, x = 0 in (9), in this case). As a result, the advertising producer chooses to obtain revenues only from those consumers who are uninformed of the competing, nonadvertised brand (by charging them the highest price the market can bear, which is equal to p * − t). The nonadvertising producer obtains revenues from all the consumers who are aware of his product, including those who are also familiar with the competing, advertised product. By significantly undercutting the price of the advertising producer and charging p * − 2t, the producer dominates the entire market of fully informed consumers in this case.</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">Lemma 2. If t/p * &gt; 2 / 2 − 3 , then i 0 0 a b = p * − 2t .</formula><p>Lemma 2 states that for sufficiently small values of and/or large values of the ratio t/p * , the "outside option" i 0 0 a b of the nonadvertising producer is determined independently of the values of the advertising parameters selected by the advertising producer. As explained earlier, under the condition of the lemma, the nonadvertising producer charges the price p * − 2t from a proportion of the population. The condition of the lemma holds definitely when = 0, namely when consumers do not have any other sources of information about the products. However, it may be valid even for positive values of . For instance, when t/p * = 1/6 the condition holds as long as &lt; 2/15, and when t/p * assumes its highest possible value of 1/2, this condition holds as long as &lt; 2/7.</p><p>Given our focus on the derivation of symmetric equilibria, we substitute symmetry into (13), while utilizing the expression derived for equilibrium product prices in (6), to obtain the following objective of the distributor:</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">Max a b w a b = 4t 1− 1 2 +a− b 2 + b 2 24 +a−b/2 2 −2 i 0 0 a b −G a b (<label>14</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_31">)</formula><p>where It is noteworthy that the condition of the Lemma 3 is a sufficient condition that is much stronger than is necessary to guarantee the monotonicity <ref type="bibr">15</ref>  for some positive k and k , the monotonicity of w • holds.</p><p>Given the monotonicity of the objective function w • , the solution to the distributor's maximization problem is a "corner solution." We use the feasible region described in Lemma 1, to characterize this solution in Proposition 2.</p><formula xml:id="formula_32">Proposition 2. (i) If t p * &gt; 2 2 − 3</formula><p>the advertising strategies that are selected at the equilibrium yield the highest possible product price that is consistent with full coverage of the population of consumers, namely p = p * − t. The advertising parameters that implement this outcome lie on the lower boundary of the feasible region described in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>. Because this lower boundary is upward sloping (i.e., a/ b &gt; 0), intensified targeting at the equilibrium results in more commercials being delivered to loyal customers.</p><p>(ii) The expected revenues that accrue to each product at the equilibrium can be expressed as a function of the targeting parameter b and the ratio t/p * as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_33">b = p * 2 1 − t p * 2 1 + 1 + b 2 12 t/p * 2 t p * (15)</formula><p>Hence, equilibrium product revenues increase with the value of the targeting parameter b.</p><p>According to Proposition 2, when acting as a common agent for the two producers, the distributor may be able to implement the collusive monopoly price in the product market when the base awareness level of consumers is sufficiently low. This result is related to the one obtained already in the literature on a common agency in oligopoly. The distributor in our setting acts as a common agent to alleviate the extent of price competition in the product market. However, in contrast to the common agency literature, monopoly pricing in our setting cannot guarantee the highest possible revenues that would accrue if brand producers did not compete on prices. In the absence of price competition, each producer would set the price p * − t/2 , yielding the revenues p * /2 1 − t/ 2p * to each. This level of revenues is higher than that reported in ( <ref type="formula">15</ref>), even for the highest possible value of b. A common agent would be able to implement this outcome only if the terms of its relationship with the producers could be determined contingent upon market variables such as sales volumes or prices (this is the standard assumption made in earlier common agency models such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Whinston 1985 and</ref>, for instance). In our setting, the payment transferred between the producers and the distributor is determined as a function of advertising levels but not as a function of sales volumes or prices. As a result, while the agent can alleviate price competition, it cannot quite implement maximization of industry profits.</p><p>The vehicle used by the agent to alleviate price competition is the extent of information consumers have about competing products. By reducing the information available via advertising, consumers are more likely to be uninformed about competing products, thus encouraging producers to raise prices. Part (ii) of the proposition asserts that intensified targeting implies that additional commercials can be transmitted to viewers about their preferred brands without necessarily leading to more aggressive pricing by brand producers, because consumers having moderate tastes are still poorly informed, given that they are exposed to relatively few commercials. With intensified targeting, the distributor finds it optimal, therefore, to increase the exposure of loyal consumers to commercials about their preferred brands ( a/ b &gt; 0 along the lower boundary of the feasible region). Because commercials are transmitted more efficiently to match the preferences of viewers, higher expected revenues can be achieved at the equilibrium.</p><p>Proposition 2 describes different combinations of the advertising parameters that can arise at the symmetric equilibrium. All of these combinations yield monopoly pricing in product markets. In general, it is unclear which pair of advertising parameters from the different combinations maximizes the distributor's objective in <ref type="bibr">(14)</ref>. Because this objective declines with a and increases with b, whereas the advertising parameters a and b move in the same direction when implementing monopoly pricing, the pair that maximizes the distributor's objective depends on the exact shape of the cost function T C • facing the distributor. For the linear cost function specified in (1), it is easy to show that the distributor will implement the maximum amount of targeting 16 consistent with the monopoly price p * − t. We summarize this result in Corollary 1.</p><p>Corollary 1. When the cost function facing the distributor is expressed by (1), the equilibrium is characterized by maximum targeting. Specifically, there exists a threshold level v ∈ 0 1 so that 17</p><formula xml:id="formula_34">b = b 1 max ≡ 2 1− t/p * − t/ 3p * + 1 3 t/p * 2 1−t/ 3p * v &lt; t p * &lt; 1 2 b = b 2 max ≡ 2 t/p * − + t/p * − 2 + 1−t/ 3p * 2t/p * − 1−t/ 3p * 0 &lt; t p * ≤ v (16)</formula><p>Note that the extent of targeting in ( <ref type="formula">16</ref>) is not a monotone function of the ratio t/p * : It is strictly increasing for small values of this ratio (when t/p * &lt; v and a = b) and strictly decreasing for larger values (when t/p * &gt; v and a &gt; b). Also, the extent of targeting is nonincreasing with (strictly decreasing for t/p * ≤ v and independent of otherwise). It is interesting to note that consumers might also benefit from higher levels of targeting implemented by the distributor. In fact, if the distributor implements monopoly pricing, as reported in Proposition 2, consumer welfare is highest when the maximum level of targeting arises at the equilibrium. Specifically, the expression for the consumer surplus when p = p * − t can be derived as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_35">CS = t a + 1 − a + − b 4 − b 3 − 5 96 b 2 (<label>17</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_36">)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_37">where a + = b/2 + t/p * + t/p * 2 + b 2 t/ 12p * .</formula><p>The above expression is a strictly increasing function of b. Because the distributor can use its role as a common agent to implement monopoly pricing for any level of b, increased targeting has only a beneficial effect on the welfare of consumers. Specifically, it increases the likelihood that they are informed of their preferred brand (because a/ b &gt; 0 along the lower boundary of the feasible region of Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>). Such improved information reduces the expected transportation costs that consumers incur, thus enhancing their welfare. If the condition of Proposition 2 does not hold (when is relatively large, for instance), then the distributor may not be able to implement monopoly pricing. In this case, higher values of b result in higher product prices, to the disadvantage of consumers. As a result, when is sufficiently large the welfare of consumers may decline with intensified targeting.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Concluding Remarks and Possible Extensions</head><p>We have demonstrated that when a single media content distributor (such as a television cable company or an Internet provider) delivers advertising messages on behalf of multiple competing brands, it can sometimes utilize customized advertising to implement monopoly pricing. When consumers have only limited information about the given product class and rely heavily on the commercials delivered by the distributor, implementing monopoly pricing becomes feasible. Even though such monopolistic pricing can be implemented with varying degrees of customization of commercials, product revenues and consumer surplus are highest when the distributor chooses the highest level of customization feasible. Consumers would obviously prefer aggressive price competition in product markets. However, given that collusion on prices is facilitated anyhow, when the distributor acts as a common agent, the welfare of consumers is enhanced when commercials are better aligned with their preferences.</p><p>Setting the requirement b 2 max ≤ 1 − yields the threshold level v for the ratio t/p * that distinguishes between panels B and C. When = 0, v = 3/13. In panel B, LB − &gt; b everywhere, implying that the binding constraint on a is a ≥ LB − . In panel C, there is a region (for b ≥ b 2 max over which b &gt; LB − , implying that over this region the binding constraint on a is a ≥ b.</p><p>Proof of Proposition 1 Total differentiation of system (5) yields the following system of equations:</p><formula xml:id="formula_38">− 1 t + a 1 − b 1 x + a 2 − b 2 1 − x − p 1 2t b 1 2t + a 2 − b 2 1 − x − b 2 2t + a 1 − b 1 x p 1 + 1 2t + a 1 − b 1 x + a 2 − b 2 1 − x − p 1 2t − b 1 2t + a 2 − b 2 1 − x + b 2 2t + a 1 − b 1 x p 2 = − + a 2 − b 2 x − b 2 x 2 2 − 1 + + a 2 − b 2 2 + p 1 2t + a 2 − b 2 1 − x a 1 + + a 2 − b 2 x 2 2 + b 2 x 3 3 + 1 2 − 1 2 + a 2 + b 2 6 − p 1 2t x + a 2 − b 2 1 − x b 1 1 2t + a 2 − b 2 1 − x + a 1 − b 1 x − p 2 2t − b 2 2t + a 1 − b 1 x + b 1 2t + a 2 − b 2 1 − x p 1 + − 1 t + a 2 − b 2 1 − x + a 1 − b 1 x − p 2 2t b 2 t + a 1 − b 1 x − b 1 2t + a 2 − b 2 1 − x p 2 = − + a 2 1 − x + b 2 2 1 − x 2 + + a 2 − b 2 2 + p 2 2t + a 2 − b 2 1 − x a 1 + + a 2 2 1 − x 1 + x − b 2 2 1 − x 2 1 − 2 3 1 − x − 1 2 + a 2 + b 2 6 − p 2 2t x + a 2 − b 2 1 − x b 1 (A.2)</formula><p>Gal-Or and Gal-Or: Customized Advertising via a Common Media Distributor </p><formula xml:id="formula_39">+ a − b/2 2 t −1 1 2 1 2 −1 p 1 p 2 =        + a /2 − b/8 − 1 + p/ 2t + a − b/2 − 3 8 + a + b/12 + 1 2 − p/ 4t + a − b/2 + a /2 − 3/8b + p/ 2t + a − b/2 − + a /8 + b/12 − p/ 4t + a − b/2        × a 1 b 1</formula><p>Substituting for p from ( <ref type="formula">6</ref>) we can solve for p i / a i and p i / b i i = 1 2 as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_40">    p 1 a 1 p 2 a 1     = 4t 3 +a−b/2 2      − 1 2 − b 16 − b 2 +a−b/2 16 −1+ b 16 − b 2 +a−b/2 16      (A.3)     p 1 b 1 p 2 b 1     = 4t 3 +a−b/2 2 ×      +a 16 + 1 4 +b/16+ b 2 32 +a−b/2 − +a 16 + 1 2 +b/16+ b 2 32 +a−b/2      (A.4)</formula><p>Recall that + a − bx is a probability measure. Evaluating it at x = 0 implies that + a ≤ 1, and evaluating it at x = 1 yields that + a − b ≥ , implying that b ≤ a. Substituting those inequalities in (A.3) and (A.4) yields the results reported in the proposition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Proof of Lemma 2</head><p>Suppose that producer 1 is the only one to advertise. Hence, a 1 = a, b 1 = b, a 2 = 0, and b 2 = 0. Substituting into system (5) yields</p><formula xml:id="formula_41">p 1 = A 1 + B 1 2t + a − b x p 2 = A 2 + B 2 2t + a − b x (A.5)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_42">x = 1 2 + p 2 − p 1 2t A 1 = + a x − b x 2 2 B 1 = + a − b 2 1 − A 2 = + a − b 1 − x + b 1 − x 2 2 B 2 = 1 − + a − b 2 (A.6)</formula><p>Substituting (A.5) into (A.6) yields the following quadratic equation in x as unknown:</p><formula xml:id="formula_43">4b x 2 − x 6 + a − b + + a + b + 2 − a 1 − + b 1 − 2 2 = 0 Solving for x yields x = 6 +a −b − 6 +a −b 2 −16b +a+b +2 − a 1− + b 1−2 2 /8b (A.7)</formula><p>The solution for x in (A.7) is negative if the following inequality holds:</p><formula xml:id="formula_44">+ a + b + 2 − a 1 − + b 1 − 2 2 &lt; 0 which is equivalent to a &gt; 3 2 2 − 3 + b 1 − 2 − 3 ≡â (A.8)</formula><p>Hence, if (A.8) holds, there is no interior equilibrium with the advertising producer obtaining a positive market share of those consumers who are informed about both products.</p><p>Recall also from ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_17">7</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_19">8</ref>) that to guarantee full participation of consumers in the market,</p><formula xml:id="formula_45">a &gt; b 2 + t p * + t p * 2 + b 2 t 12p * − ≡ LB − (A.9)</formula><p>If the RHS of inequality (A.9) is bigger than the RHS of inequality (A.8), we are guaranteed that (A.8) holds, thus implying the nonexistence of an equilibrium with x &gt; 0.</p><p>Imposing the condition LB − &gt;â yields the following inequality:</p><formula xml:id="formula_46">b 2 4 t 3p * − 2 2 − 3 2 + b t p * 2 − 3 − 2 2 − 3 2 + 4 t p * 2 − 3 − 2 − 3 2 &gt; 0 (A.10)</formula><p>When the condition of Lemma 2 holds, we are guaranteed that (A.10) is indeed valid. Hence x = 0, and the advertising producer obtains revenues only from those consumers who are uniformed about the competing nonadvertised product. Because he does not face any competition in serving those consumers, he charges them the monopoly price of p * − t . To dominate the entire market of the fully informed consumers, as is implied by x = 0, the nonadvertising producer undercuts the price of the advertising producer by an amount t so that p 2 = p * − 2t. When charging this price, even the consumer who is located the farthest away from producer 2 chooses to buy his product. Given that producer 2 charges the price p * − 2t from a proportion of the population (who are informed of his product), 2 0 0 a b = p * − 2t .</p><p>Finally, we will show that under the condition of the lemma, no firm has an incentive to deviate from the above equilibrium (i.e., p 1 = p * − t, p 2 = p * − 2t). Expressing the expected profits of firm 1 when it charges the price p 1 ≤ p * − t and firm 2 charges the price p * − 2t yields Marketing Science 24(2), pp. <ref type="bibr">241-253, © 2005 INFORMS</ref> where A 1 and B 1 are given in (A.6) and</p><formula xml:id="formula_47">x = p * − p 1 2t − 1 2 because p 2 = p * − 2t</formula><p>The function 1 is a strictly concave function of p 1 , implying a unique maximizing solution for p 1 . Differentiating 1 with respect to p 1 and evaluating the derivative at p 1 = p * − t yields</p><formula xml:id="formula_48">1 p 1 p 1 =p * −t = 1 − + a − b 2 − + a 2t p * − t</formula><p>The above derivative is strictly positive under the condition of the lemma. Because 2 1 / p 2 1 &lt; 0, it follows that 1 / p 1 &gt; 0 for all prices p 1 ≤ p * − t, and p 1 = p * − t is the unique best response to p 2 = p * − 2t. Similarly, expressing the expected profits of firm 2 when it charges the price p 2 ≥ p * − 2t and firm 1 charges p 1 = p * − t, yields that 2 = A 2 + B 2 p 2 , where A 2 and B 2 are as defined in (A.6) and</p><formula xml:id="formula_49">x = 1 − p * − p 2 2t because p 1 = p * − t</formula><p>Once again, 2 is a strictly concave function of p 2 , and under the condition of the lemma 2 / p 2 evaluated at p * − 2t is negative. Hence, 2 / p 2 &lt; 0 for all values of p 2 ≥ p * − 2t, and p 2 = p * − 2t is the unique best response to p 1 = p * − t.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Proof of Lemma 3</head><p>Given the condition of the lemma, i 0 0 a b is a constant function, and the derivatives of w • are determined by the slopes of the first and last terms of (14). Differentiating those terms yields the result, given Assumptions A3 and A4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Proof of Proposition 2</head><p>(i) Because w • is strictly monotone, the optimal solution lies on the lower boundary of the feasible region. For sufficiently high values of the ratio t/p * , this boundary consists of a b combinations that satisfy (6) when p = p * − t (panel B). For low values of t/p * (panel C), the boundary includes also a segment of the 45 line when b ≥ b 2 max . We will show, however, that the profit of the distributor are strictly lower on this segment than they are at b 2 max . Substituting a = b into (14) yields</p><formula xml:id="formula_50">w b b = 4t 1 − 1 2 + b 2 + b 2 24 + b/2 2 − G b b − 2 i 0 0 b b (A.11)</formula><p>By Assumption A5, we are guaranteed that the first two terms of (A.11) are strictly decreasing with b. Also, the condition of the proposition implies that i 0 0 b b = p * − 2t for a = b ≥ b 2 max . To see this, note that to guarantee (A.8) with a = b implies that a &gt; 3 2 / 1 − 2 . It is easy to show that b 2 max in (A.1) is larger than 3 2 / 1 − 2 under the condition of the proposition. As a result, for advertising parameters a = b &gt; b 2 max in panel C we are guaranteed that the outside option of the nonadvertising producer is a flat function that is determined independently of the parameter b. Because w b b in ( <ref type="formula">11</ref>) is a strictly decreasing function of b, the optimal solution will never entail a targeting parameter larger than b 2 max . For b ≤ b 2 max , the lower boundary of the feasible region implements, once again, the monopoly price p * −t. This lower boundary is determined by the equation a = LB − , where LB is given by (8). Differentiating LB with respect to b yields the conclusion that a/ b &gt; 0.</p><p>(ii) When both producers set the price p * − t the expected revenues that accrue to each product are A i + B i p * − t , where A i and B i satisfy Equation (4). Substituting into A i and B i , x = 1/2 and the expression for + a from (8) yields the expected revenues that accrue to each product as a function of the targeting parameter. Differentiating the RHS of ( <ref type="formula">15</ref>) with respect to b yields the result.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Proof of Corollary 1</head><p>Evaluating ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_30">14</ref>) for the value of a that satisfies (8) and the cost function given in (1) yields The latter inequality follows from (A.12), to guarantee that the distributor earns nonnegative profits. Hence, the distributor wishes to implement the highest possible level of targeting to maximize profits. Note that in (A.12) i 0 0 a b = p * − 2t , given our assumptions that t p * &gt; 2 3 − 2</p><formula xml:id="formula_51">w = 4p * 1 − t p * 2 t p * 1 + b 2 24X 2 − F − 2 X − − 2 p * − 2t (A.</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Derivation of the Expression for Consumer Surplus</head><p>Given that the distributor implements monopoly pricing, the expected consumer surplus can be derived as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_52">1/2 0 a + − bx a + − b 1 − x t − tx dx + 1 1/2 a + − bx a + − b 1 − x t − t 1 − x dx + 1 0 a + − bx 1 − a + − b 1 − x t − tx dx + 1 0 1 − a + − bx a + − b 1 − x • t − t 1 − x dx (A.13)</formula><p>The first two terms of (A.13) correspond to the case in which the consumer is informed about both products, and the last two terms correspond to the case in which the consumer is informed about only one product. Conducting the integration yields (17).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Competition in the Product Market x</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2Feasible Range of the Advertising Parameters a</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>G a b ≡ TC a b a b . The condition derived in Lemma 2 guarantees that the objective function of the distributor is a strictly decreasing function of a and a strictly increasing function of b. Lemma 3. If t p * &gt; 2 2 − 3 the function w a b is a strictly decreasing function of a and a strictly increasing function of b.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>of the function w • . As long as the derivatives of the outside option function i 0 0 a b are sufficiently flat, i.e.,</figDesc></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">TiVo announced recently that it will sell to advertisers and broadcasters second-by-second information on the television commercials and shows its users are watching or skipping. (TiVo Plans to Sell Information on Customers' Viewing Habits, New York Times, June 3, 2003.)</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4"><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Iyer et al. (2005)</ref> discuss price discrimination in the context of targeted advertising;<ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Chen et al. (2001)</ref> do it in the context of targeted marketing.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">It is possible to extend the analysis to allow for different base awareness levels on the part of consumers. This can be done by assuming that the initial probabilities of awareness are different across brands, namely, 1 = 2 .</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6"> See Dukes and Gal-Or (2003)  andLiu et al. (2004)  for models that tie the revenues of broadcasters to their overall levels of advertising.7  In<ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Iyer et al. (2005)</ref> advertising costs as incurred by the advertisers are proportional to the size of the market being targeted. Hence, intensified targeting reduces the costs incurred by the advertiser.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8">This assumption can be easily relaxed without changing any of our results.9  This assumption guarantees that one advertiser can always observe the terms of the agreement offered to the competing advertiser, because those terms are identical to those he obtains for himself. In the technical appendix at http://mktsci.pubs.informs.org, we consider the possibility that one advertiser cannot observe the terms of the agreement offered to his competitor or the levels of the advertising parameters that the competitor selects. We show that even in this case, the distributor might be able to implement monopoly pricing in the product market.10 Notice that because the distributor is the entity who delivers the ads to the PVR according to the request of the advertiser, it obviously can verify the committed levels of a i and b i , and charge advertiser i accordingly.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="12">Note that the payment to the distributor depends on the advertising parameters selected by the producer but not on his price. Hence, brand producers ignore their payments to the distributor when choosing prices in Stage 3. In essence, those payments are considered sunk at this stage.13  In the sequel, we show that even when restricting attention to symmetric equilibria, monopoly pricing in the product market can be implemented by the distributor. Our analysis can be extended to allow for asymmetry in the payment schedules offered by the distributor (see the technical appendix at http://mktsci.pubs.informs. org) or asymmetry in the inherent characteristics of the advertisers (by assuming that 1 = 2 , for instance).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="14">An example of a payment schedule that will implement the pair a i b i is a linear schedule specified as R a b = K + a + b, where the slopes and are selected to guarantee that desired pair a i b i solves (9), and the fixed payment K guarantees that the (IR) constraint is binding. More sophisticated payment schedules can also implement the same outcome.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="15">Similarly, the assumptions made concerning the function TC • (A3, A4, A5) are also stronger than necessary to guarantee the monotonicity of w • . In particular, if in violation of A4 T C/ b k &gt; 0, w/ b may still be positive if the first expression of w • in (14) is sufficiently steep.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="16">In the technical appendix at http://mktsci.pubs.informs.org, we consider a targeting technology less precise than the one considered in the main text. Specifically, the distributor can distinguish between only two segments of the population. As well, it cannot make "take it or leave it" offers to the advertisers. Instead, the distributor auctions off the rights to reach each of the two identifiable segments. We demonstrate that utilizing the targeting technology is disadvantageous to the distributor in this case.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">t/p * − + t/p * − 2 + 1−t/ 3p * 2t/p * − 1−t/3p * (A.1)</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors acknowledge the helpful suggestions of two anonymous referees and an area editor of the journal.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix Proof of Lemma 1</head><p>To guarantee that the market is always served p ≤ p * − t, so that even when the consumer is informed of only one product she chooses to buy it, irrespective of her location on the line. Setting the price in (6) equal to p * − t yields a+ = LB, where LB is given in (8). Because p/ a ≤ 0 in (6), it follows that p ≤ p * − t if and only if a + ≥ LB.</p><p>To guarantee that some commercials pertaining to a given product are delivered even to the consumer who is located the farthest away from the product, + a − b ≥ , thus implying that a ≥ b. The set of inequalities in (7) guarantees, therefore, that the entire population of consumers participate both in the product market and in the coverage span of commercials.</p><p>The threshold level v in </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advertising competition under consumer inertia</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Banerjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bandyopadhyay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="144" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Common marketing agency as a device for facilitating collusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bernheim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Whinston</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rand J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="269" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Common agency</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bernheim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Whinston</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="923" to="943" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interactive marketing: Exploiting the age of addressability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Blattberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Deighton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sloan Management Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="14" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal selection for direct mail</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bult</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wansbeek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="378" to="394" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual marketing with imperfect targetability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Narasimhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Targeted advertising on the Web with inventory management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Chickering</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Heckerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Interfaces</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="77" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Negotiations and exclusivity contracts for advertising</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dukes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gal-Or</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="222" to="245" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advertisers divide and conquer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Epstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Futurist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online relationships and the consumer&apos;s right to privacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Franzak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Pitta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fritsche</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="631" to="649" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The many player advertising game</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Fructher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1609" to="1611" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Closed-loop advertising strategies in a duopoly</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Fruchter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kalish</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="54" to="63" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A common agency with incomplete information</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gal-Or</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rand J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="274" to="286" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Informative advertising with differentiated products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Grossman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="81" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">System and method for delivering targeted advertisements to consumers using direct commands. United States Patent No</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hite</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Ciciora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Alison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Beauregard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="www/delphion.com" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999-12-14" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">393</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The targeting of advertising</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Iyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Soberman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci. Forthcoming</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Villas-Boas</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How leading advertisers and agencies use cable television</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lancaster</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Advertising Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="30" to="38" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Audience characteristics and bundling: A hedonic analysis of magazine advertising rates</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koschat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Putsis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="262" to="273" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competition of firms: Discriminatory pricing and location</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lederer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hurter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="623" to="640" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Creating micro-marketing pricing strategies using supermarket scanner data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Montgomery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="315" to="337" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy concerns and customer willingness to provide personal information</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Phelps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Nowak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ferrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Public Policy Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Baysian approach to estimating household parameters</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rossi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="171" to="182" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The value of purchase history data in target marketing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rossi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mcculloch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="340" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advertising in a distribution channel</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Shaffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Zettelmeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="619" to="628" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A personalized television listings service</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Smyth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Cotter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="111" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using data mining to profile television viewers in the digital TV era</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Spangler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gal-Or</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="72" />
			<date type="published" when="2003-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sleeping with the enemy-Should competitors share the same advertising agency</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Villas-Boas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="190" to="202" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Persuasive advertising and product differentiation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N.-H</forename><surname>Von Der Fehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Stevik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Southern J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="126" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is having more channels really better? A model of competition among commercial television broadcasters</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Yong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Putler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Weinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="119" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Customizing promotions in online stores</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Krishnamurthi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="561" to="578" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
