<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Do Returns Policies Intensify Retail Competition?</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Hao</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>hwang@ccer.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Economic Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100871</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country>China, P.R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Do Returns Policies Intensify Retail Competition?</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 04 2304 0611</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1030.0025</idno>
					<note type="submission">This paper was received March 6, 2002, and was with the author 1 month for 2 revisions.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:24+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>returns policies, retail competition</term>
					<term>demand uncertainty</term>
					<term>pricing</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>T he paper "Manufacturer's Returns Policies and Retail Competition" by <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Padmanabhan and Png (1997)</ref> argues that returns policies intensify retail competition and therefore raise the manufacturer's profits. They reach that result through a problematic method to solve the game. Particularly, in the game where the manufacturer accepts returns, they unreasonably assume the retailers would never face stock constraints, thus changing the retail competition from a Cournot-like competition to a Bertrand one. Actually, in a game where retailers first order stocks and then compete by choosing prices, even if a manufacturer offers full return policies, the retailers can still use "insufficient" stocks as quantities precommitment in order to uphold retail prices. Hence, the retailers still face stock constraints at the final stage of the game. The nature of the game is essentially unaffected by returns policies when demand is certain. This note shows that returns policies do not intensify retail competition in the model proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Padmanabhan and Png (1997)</ref>.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">The Paper</head><p>In this note we will discuss the paper "Manufacturer's Returns Policies and Retail Competition" by <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Padmanabhan and Png (1997)</ref>-PP hereafterpublished in Marketing Science. PP consider a market where a monopoly upstream manufacturer sells through one or two downstream retailers. The product has limited shelf life. The retailers face linear demand curves. On pages 83-84, the paper defines a three-stage game:</p><p>1. The manufacturer sets distribution policy, which includes a uniform wholesale price and possibly a returns policy; 2. Given the manufacturer's distribution policy, the retailer(s) decide how much stock to order; 3. With stocks in hand, the retailer(s) set prices to the final consumers.</p><p>The central points of the paper can be summarized as follows. It first considers a benchmark where there is a single retailer. It is shown that a returns policy makes no difference in that case. Then the paper studies the case with two competing retailers. It finds a returns policy that intensifies the downstream competition, therefore leading to higher profits for the manufacturer. Notations include marginal production cost c, wholesale price w, retail price p, and retail stock s. Demand functions: q = − p for the monopoly retailer, and q 1 = − p 1 + p 2 , q 2 = − p 2 + p 1 &gt; for the duopoly retailers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Returns Policies and Retail Competition</head><p>Kreps and Scheinkman (1983) study a two-stage oligopoly game. In that game, competing firms first simultaneously choose production quantities. After the production levels are made public, there is price competition. Under certain conditions, they show that the unique equilibrium outcome is the Cournot outcome. The game proposed by PP actually fits the Kreps and Scheinkman model perfectly, except now we have a three-stage game where two competing retailers order stocks from an upstream manufacturer.</p><p>Retail stocks are chosen at the second stage, and retail prices are chosen at the third stage. The question is whether a returns policy at the third stage affects the nature of the game. PP claim that in the game with returns, the retailers should always order sufficient stocks at the second stage, such that they never face stock constraints at the third stage. This means the game with a returns policy is no longer a Cournot-like game, but a Bertrand game, because the only effective decision of the retailers is choosing prices. This belief is not reasonable, because it deprives the retailers of the right to choose optimal stocks at the second stage. In fact, it is still in the retailers' interest to use stocks as quantities precommitment in order to uphold prices at the third stage. For example, suppose both retailers provide exactly identical services to consumers. According to PP, the downstream price competition should result in competitive outcome, which means zero profits for both retailers. However, if either retailer ordered stock less than the competitive level at the second stage, both retailers would make positive profits. Hence, ordering "insufficient" stock makes the retailers better off.</p><p>In the game with returns, PP find the "equilibrium" wholesale price</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">w * = + − c 2 − retail prices p * 1 = p * 2 = 3 − 2 + − c 2 2 − −</formula><p>and minimal retail stocks</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">s * 1 = s * 2 = − − c 2 2 −</formula><p>Assuming that the retailers do not order excess stocks, PP find the manufacturer makes more profit with returns. This result is incorrect because of the problematic method used. The following two claims represent the finding of this research note. Claim 1 shows that the "equilibrium" found by PP is not an equilibrium. Claim 2 shows that returns policies make no difference in equilibrium.</p><p>Claim 1. Starting from stocks s 1 ≥ s * 1 and s 2 ≥ s * 2 = s * 1 at the second stage, if either retailer instead orders stock s * 1 − , where &gt; 0 is sufficiently small, she would make more profits.</p><p>Proof. First we assume s 1 = s 2 = s * 1 = s * 2 . Now suppose Retailer 1 deviates to s 1 = s * 1 − . While PP's "equilibrium" prices p * 1 , p * 2 now lead to a shortage, the retailers should charge higher retail prices that clear the market. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The retail prices satisfy −</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">p 1 + p 2 = s 1 = s * 1 − and − p 2 + p 1 = s * 2 .</formula><p>From them we can work out the retail price p 1 = p * 1 + / 2 − 2 . Therefore, Retailer 1's profit after the deviation is</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">1 = s 1 p 1 −w * = s * 1 − p * 1 −w * + 2 − 2 = * 1 + s * 1 2 − 2 −p * 1 +w * − 2 2 − 2</formula><p>To show 1 &gt; * 1 , we only need s * 1 / 2 − 2 − p * 1 + w * &gt; 0. Substituting s * 1 , p * 1 , and w * into it, we would see that the inequality holds if and only if − c + c &gt; 0, which is assumed in the model. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Thus the deviation makes Retailer 1 better off. Now we show that if s 1 &gt; s * 1 and s 2 &gt; s * 1 , deviating to s 1 = s * 1 − makes Retailer 1 better off. Assuming is sufficiently small, Retailer 1 would face stock constraint, but Retailer 2 would not. Retailer 2 solves: Max p 2 p 2 − w * − p 2 + p 1 , whose second-order condition is − 2 p 2 + p 1 + w * = 0, together with − p 1 + p 2 = s * 1 − , we get p 1 = p * 1 + 2 / 2 2 − 2 . Therefore, Retailer 1's profit after the deviation is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">1 = s 1 p 1 − w * = s * 1 − p * 1 − w * + 2 2 2 − 2 = * 1 + 2 s * 1 2 2 − 2 − p * 1 + w * − 2 2 2 2 − 2 To show 1 ≥ * 1 , we need 2 s * 1 / 2 2 − 2 − p * 1 + w * &gt; 0. Substituting w * , s *</formula><p>1 , and p * 1 into it, the inequality holds if and only if − c + c &gt; 0, which is assumed. It is easy to see that other situations (s 1 &gt; s * 1 and s 2 = s * 1 , or, s 1 = s * 1 and s 2 &gt; s * 1 are not troubling.</p><p>Claim 2. In the game with returns, the equilibrium is the same as that without returns.</p><p>Proof. Please see the Appendix. Claim 2 shows that the retailers still play a Cournotlike game, but not a Bertrand game. That means the retailers still use stocks as quantities precommitment even if the manufacturer accepts returns. Particularly, they never order excess stocks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Conclusion</head><p>The paper by PP (1997) claims that returns policies intensify retail competition. This result cannot be reached if the model is solved correctly. The paper unreasonably assumes that the retailers never face stock constraints when they are offered returns policies. As <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Kreps and Scheinkman (1983)</ref> demonstrate, firms can use quantity precommitment to achieve a Cournot-like outcome, even if they engage in price competition at the final stage of the game. A returns policy cannot change this story, particularly when demand is certain. Due to the problematic method used to solve the model, PP (1997) incorrectly alters the game with returns from a Cournotlike game to a Bertrand game. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Singh and Vives (1984)</ref> show that in a differentiated duopoly, price competition is more intense than quantity competition, provided the goods are substitutes. If the game with returns were treated as a Bertrand game, we would observe more-intense retail competition, which leads to higher upstream profit. PP (1997) provides empirical evidence that returns policies narrow retail margins, but the implication of this note is that we cannot attribute that to intensified retail competition. The demand uncertainty theories <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Marvel and Peck 1995)</ref> might explain that better.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>612</head><label></label><figDesc>Marketing Science 23(4), pp.611-613, © 2004 INFORMS    </figDesc></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">This is because the retailers' revenue functions are strictly concave over the relevant range of p 1 or p 2 .</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">Actually PP do not explicitly assume − c + c &gt; 0, but this condition is required for the model to make sense. Otherwise, even if both retailers charge prices equal to the marginal production cost c, the total quantity demand is still nonpositive. Thus, the equilibrium would be trivial.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">There is a typo in Table2of<ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Png (1997)</ref>. The equilibrium retail prices in the game without returns should be 3+ + 2 − 2 c / 2 2 + − , not 3 + − 2 − 2 c / 2 2 + − .</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgment</head><p>The author is grateful to the editor, area editor, and three anonymous referees for very helpful suggestions.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix</head><p>Proof of Claim 2. Suppose the equilibrium retail stocks are s 1 , s 2 . If both retailers always order excess stocks at the second stage, the outcome would be that which PP find, which is not an equilibrium as Claim 1 shows. If one retailer orders excess stock but the other does not, which means we would have an asymmetric equilibrium, one can show this is impossible because the retailer who orders excess stock can do better by ordering a little bit less than her actual sale. We omit the detail here. If neither retailer orders excess stock, the retail prices must satisfy − p 1 + p 2 = s 1 and − p 2 + p 1 = s 2 . Solving this equation system, we have</p><p>At the second stage, the retailers choose s 1 s 2 to maximize their profits:</p><p>The first-order conditions are</p><p>From this equation system we obtain</p><p>At the first stage, the manufacturer chooses wholesale price w to maximize its profit = w − c s 1 + s 2 . Substituting (2) into and solving the problem, we get wholesale price</p><p>substituting w into (1), we get</p><p>This retail sale and price configuration is feasible, and hence is the unique equilibrium of the game. Referring to Table <ref type="table">2</ref> on page 86 of Png (1997), we see the equilibrium is the same as that without returns. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantity precommitment and Bertrand competition yield Cournot outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kreps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Jose</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Scheinkman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bell J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="326" to="337" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Demand uncertainty and returns policies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Howard</forename><surname>Marvel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Peck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="691" to="714" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manufacturer&apos;s returns policies and retail competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Padmanabhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">P L</forename><surname>Png</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="94" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal pricing and return policies for perishable commodities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barry</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pasternack</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="166" to="176" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Price and quantity competition in a differentiated duopoly</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nirvikar</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xavier</forename><surname>Vives</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rand J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="546" to="554" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
