<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Reply to &quot;Do Returns Policies Intensify Retail Competition?&quot;</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Padmanabhan</surname></persName>
							<email>paddy.padmanabhan@insead.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">P L</forename><surname>Png</surname></persName>
							<email>ipng@comp.nus.edu.sg</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">INSEAD</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1 Ayer Rajah Avenue</addrLine>
									<postCode>138676</postCode>
									<settlement>Singapore</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Information Systems and Business Policy</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>3 Science Drive 2</addrLine>
									<postCode>117543</postCode>
									<settlement>Singapore</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Reply to &quot;Do Returns Policies Intensify Retail Competition?&quot;</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 04 2304 0614</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1040.0091</idno>
					<note type="submission">received January 28, 2004,</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:24+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Marketing, operations management, and economics researchers have been interested in the conditions under which returns policies coordinate channels and supply chains <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Pasternack 1985</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">, Marvel and Peck 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">, Padmanabhan and Png 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">, Butz 1997</ref><ref type="bibr">, Cachon and Lariviere 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">, Granot and Yin 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">, Rao and Mahi 2003</ref>. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Padmanabhan and Png (1997) showed that with demand uncertainty, a returns policy could improve manufacturer profitability under certain conditions. They further claimed that, even in the absence of demand uncertainty, a returns policy could raise manufacturer profitability by dampening price competition between retailers. However, this claim was disproved by <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wang (2004)</ref>, who showed that returns policies do not change manufacturer profitability when demand is certain and retailing is competitive.</p><p>In this paper, we show that returns policies do increase manufacturer profitability by helping it better manage price competition between retailers but that this effect holds only in the presence of demand uncertainty. Interestingly, the conditions under which a returns policy raises the manufacturer's profit <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Returns policies are one type of vertical control, another being resale price maintenance <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Rey and</ref><ref type="bibr">Tirole 1986, Deneckere et al. 1997)</ref>.</p><p>are weaker when retailing is a duopoly than when retailing is a monopoly. This suggests that returns policies serve both to manage competition and mitigate demand uncertainty. 2</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Model</head><p>Let the information structure and sequence of actions be as follows. Initially, all parties are uncertain about the state of primary demand, which could be low or high ( = l or h, respectively). The probability of demand being low is . In the first stage, the manufacturer sets a distribution policy comprising a wholesale price w and whether to accept returns. In the second stage, the retailers independently order stocks s i . Then, in the third stage, the true primary demand state is revealed to all parties, and the retailers independently set prices, p i , i = 1 2, = l h. 3 Let demand at retailer 1 be</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">q 1 = − p 1 + p 2</formula><p>(1) </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>615</head><p>Demand is more sensitive to the retailer's own price than the competitor's price (i.e., &gt; ). Information is symmetric: specifically, , , , and are known to all.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">No Returns</head><p>In this case, the manufacturer sets a wholesale price w and does not accept returns. Below, we derive a condition sufficient that, in Stage 3, if demand is low, both retailers price to leave some stock unsold. If demand is high, both retailers price to sell their entire stock <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Wang 2004)</ref>.</p><p>By (1), if demand is low, retailer 1's sales are</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">q 1l = l − p 1l + p 2l (2)</formula><p>Since the retailers leave some stock unsold and unsold stock has no salvage value, retailer 1 would set price to maximize revenue</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">R 1l = p 1l l − p 1l + p 2l (3)</formula><p>The first-order condition is l − 2 p 1l + p 2l = 0. Similarly, retailer 2 would set price to maximize revenue, and its first-order condition would be l − 2 p 2l + p 1l = 0. Solving simultaneously, we have the retailers' price if demand is low,</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">p 1l = 2 + 4 2 − 2 l = l 2 − = p 2l (4)</formula><p>Substituting ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>) in (2), q 1l is as shown in Table <ref type="table">1</ref>. Since &gt; , it follows that p 1l &gt; 0 and q 1l &gt; 0.</p><p>If demand is high, both retailers sell their entire stock; hence, their sales are </p><formula xml:id="formula_4">q 1h = h − p 1h + p 2h = s 1 (5) q 2h = h − p 2h + p 1h = s 2 (6)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_5">w 1 − h + − c 2 − &lt; 2 + l + 1 − + 2 − h + − + 2 − c 2 − 2 + + 1 − + 2 − (if c = 0) s 1 = q 1h + 1 − h − − c 2 1 − 2 + &lt; + 2 2 + h + 2 + h − l − − + 2 − c 2 − 2 + + 1 − + 2 − p 1l l 2 − &lt; l 2 − + 2 − 2 + l + 1 − + 2 − h + − + 2 − c 2 − 2 + + 1 − + 2 − q 1l l 2 − &gt; l 2 − − 2 − 2 + l + 1 − + 2 − h + − + 2 − c 2 2 + + 1 − + 2 − p 1h 1 − 3 + h + − + c 2 1 − − 2 + &gt; 3 + 2 2 + h − + 2 − 2 + 2 + h − l − − + 2 − c 2 + + 1 − + 2 −</formula><p>Solving for the prices, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">p 1h = + h − s 1 − s 2 2 − 2 (7) p 2h = + h − s 2 − s 1 2 − 2 (8)</formula><p>In Stage 2, the retailers choose stocks s i to maximize expected profit, given the wholesale price w set by the manufacturer. Retailer 1's expected profit is</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">p 1l q 1l + 1 − p 1h s 1 − ws 1 (9)</formula><p>The first-order condition with respect to s 1 yields</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">2 1 − s 1 = 1 − + h − 1 − s 2 − 2 − 2 w (10)</formula><p>and, likewise for retailer 2. In equilibrium, s 1 = s 2 , hence</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">s 1 = + 1 − 2 + 1 − h − − w = s 2 (11)</formula><p>In Stage 1, the manufacturer sets w to maximize profit</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">N = 2 w − c s 1 (12)</formula><p>Substituting ( <ref type="formula">11</ref>) in ( <ref type="formula">12</ref>), the first-order condition with respect to w is</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">w = 1 − h + − c 2 − (<label>13</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_12">)</formula><p>Substituting for w, retailer 1's price when demand is high, p 1h , and stocking quantity, s 1 , are as shown in Table <ref type="table">1</ref>.</p><p>In equilibrium, we require that, if demand is low, both retailers leave some stock unsold, q 1l &lt; s 1 . </p><formula xml:id="formula_13">+ 2 − h − 2 l − 2 2 l &gt; − + 2 − 1 − c (14)</formula><p>Since q 1l &gt; 0, condition ( <ref type="formula">14</ref>) also ensures that s 1 &gt; 0.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Full Returns</head><p>In this case, the manufacturer sets a wholesale price w and gives each retailer a full refund for unsold stock.</p><p>In the appendix (Claim 1), we show that condition ( <ref type="formula">14</ref>) implies that, in Stage 3, if demand is low, both retailers price to leave some stock unsold. If demand is high, both retailers sell their entire stock <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Wang 2004)</ref>.</p><p>By (1), if demand is low, retailer 1's sales are</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">q 1l = l − p 1l + p 2l (<label>15</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_15">)</formula><p>Since the retailers leave stock unsold and the manufacturer accepts full returns, retailer 1 would set price to maximize profit</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">p 1l − w q 1l = p 1l − w l − p 1l + p 2l (<label>16</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_17">)</formula><p>The first-order condition is l − 2 p 1l + p 2l + w = 0 and, similarly, for retailer 2, l − 2 p 2l + p 1l + w = 0. Solving, we have the retailers' price if demand is low,</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">p 1l = l + w 2 − = p 2l (<label>17</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_19">)</formula><p>Substituting in (15), the retailers' sales are</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">q 1l = l − − l + w 2 − = l − − w 2 − (<label>18</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_21">)</formula><p>If demand is high, both retailers price to sell their entire stock. Then the sales and prices of retailers 1 and 2 are given by ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>)-(8).</p><p>In Stage 2, the retailers choose stocks s i to maximize expected profit, given the wholesale price w set by the manufacturer. Retailer 1's expected profit is</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">p 1l − w q 1l + 1 − p 1h − w s 1 (19)</formula><p>Substituting from ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_18">17</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula">7</ref>) in ( <ref type="formula">19</ref>), the first-order condition with respect to s 1 is</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">2 s 1 = + h − 2 − 2 w − s 2 (20)</formula><p>and likewise for s 2 . In equilibrium, s 1 = s 2 , hence</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">s 1 = + 2 + h − − w = s 2 (21)</formula><p>In Stage 1, the manufacturer sets w to maximize profit R = 2 wq 1l + 2 1 − ws 1 − 2cs 1 ( <ref type="formula">22</ref>)</p><p>Substituting ( <ref type="formula">21</ref>) in ( <ref type="formula">22</ref>), the first-order condition with respect to w is</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">w = 2 + l + 1 − + 2 − h + − + 2 − c / 2 − 2 + + 1 − + 2 − (23)</formula><p>Substituting for w in ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_20">18</ref>) and simplifying, the stock is</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">s 1 = + 2 2 + • h + 2 + h − l − − + 2 − c 2 − 2 + + 1− + 2 − (24)</formula><p>The expressions for p 1l , q 1l , and p 1h are as reported in Table <ref type="table">1</ref>. From Table <ref type="table">1</ref>, a sufficient condition for q 1l &gt; 0 is l &gt; w, or by ( <ref type="formula">23</ref>) and simplifying,</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">+ l − − + 2 − c &gt; 1 − + 2 − h − 2 l (25)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Full Returns Vis-à-Vis No Returns</head><p>The Table <ref type="table">1</ref> compares the profit-maximizing wholesale price, and equilibrium retail prices and quantities under the scenarios of full and no returns. <ref type="bibr">4 5</ref> In general, it is difficult to compare the manufacturer's profit under the two scenarios. For tractability, we focus on the case where the marginal cost of the product, c = 0. Then, by (12), ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_11">13</ref>), and (11), the manufacturer profit with no returns simplifies to</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">N = 1 − + 2 h 2 − 2 + (26)</formula><p>Further, by substituting c = 0 in ( <ref type="formula">22</ref>), (23), and (24) and simplifying, the manufacturer's profit with returns is</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">R = 2 + l + 1 − + 2 − h 2 2 − 2 − 2 + 2 + + 1 − + 2 − (27)</formula><p>Comparing ( <ref type="formula">27</ref>) with ( <ref type="formula">26</ref>), the difference in the manufacturer's profit with and without returns, R − N &gt; 0 if</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">1 − 2 + l + 1 − + 2 − h 2 &gt; + 2 − 1 − h 2 • 2 + + 1 − + 2 − (28)</formula><p>After simplifying, we have the following result.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Proposition 1. If the extent to which the high demand exceeds the low demand satisfies</head><formula xml:id="formula_31">h h − 2 l 2 l &lt; 2 + 1 − + 2 − (<label>29</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_32">)</formula><p>and the marginal cost of the product, c, is sufficiently low, then the manufacturer's profit is higher with a returns policy than with no returns.</p><p>Intuitively, the returns policy has conflicting effects on the manufacturer's profit:</p><p>• With returns, the retailers order larger stocks and, if the marginal cost is sufficiently low, the wholesale price is higher.</p><p>• However, with returns, in the event of low demand, retailers return unsold stock and the manufacturer must bear the cost of these returned items.</p><p>The appendix (Claim 2) shows that if c = 0 and, in addition,</p><formula xml:id="formula_33">1 − &gt; 4 2 + 2 − (<label>30</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_34">)</formula><p>then ( <ref type="formula">14</ref>) implies ( <ref type="formula">25</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_31">29</ref>). Accordingly, the conditions under which a returns policy increases the manufacturer's profit are well defined.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Comparing Retail Market Structures</head><p>In a similar setting of demand uncertainty but with a monopoly retailer, <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Padmanabhan and Png (1997)</ref> showed that the manufacturer's profit would be higher with a returns policy than with no returns if c = 0, and the demand parameters satisfied the condition,</p><formula xml:id="formula_35">≤ 1 − 1/2 − 1 − (<label>31</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_36">)</formula><p>where ≡ h / l . Using the same substitution, (29) becomes</p><formula xml:id="formula_37">− 1 2 ≤ 2 + 1 − + 2 − + 1 (32) or ≤ 2 + + 1− 2 2 + − 2 1− + 2 − 1/2 +1 ≡ X (33)</formula><p>say. Note that, with = 0, <ref type="formula">33</ref>), X is increasing in , and thus, for ≥ 0, <ref type="formula" target="#formula_31">29</ref>) is weaker than (31), which leads to the following result.</p><formula xml:id="formula_38">X = 1 1 − 1/2 + 1 = 1 − 1/2 − 1 − (34) By (</formula><formula xml:id="formula_39">X ≡ 2 − + 1− 2 − + 1/2 +1 &gt; 1− 1/2 − 1− (35) Accordingly, (</formula><p>Proposition 2. The returns policy is more likely to raise the manufacturer's profit when retailing is a duopoly than when retailing is a monopoly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Concluding Remarks</head><p>We have shown that, in a setting of a retail duopoly subject to demand uncertainty, a returns policy will raise the manufacturer's profit if the marginal cost of the product is sufficiently low and the demand parameters satisfy particular conditions. Further, these conditions are weaker than the corresponding conditions for a returns policy to raise manufacturer profit with a retail monopoly. Hence, the returns policy is more likely to raise manufacturer profit when retailing is a duopoly than when retailing is a monopoly. The returns policy serves to manage competition and mitigate demand uncertainty.</p><p>Intuitively, when demand is low, the returns policy sets a floor to the retail price and dampens competition. However, when demand is high, the returns policy induces more intense price competition and, consequently, higher retail sales. By eliminating the cost of excess inventory and through its impact on retail competition, the returns policy encourages retailers to order larger stocks. Further, if the marginal cost is sufficient low, the returns policy leads to a higher wholesale price. From the manufacturer's viewpoint, the disadvantage of the returns policy is the cost of items returned in the event that demand is low. Provided that the cost of the product is sufficiently low and the high demand is not too much larger than the low demand, the advantages of the returns policy outweigh the disadvantage.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Marketing Science 23(4), pp. 614-618, © 2004 INFORMS Substituting for these quantities from Table 1, a sufficient condition is</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2"><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Butz (1997)</ref> considered a similar setting but did not characterize the conditions under which a returns policy would increase manufacturer profit. However, he did allow partial returns policies and showed that these maximize the manufacturer's profit.3 Another approach would be to assume that retailers set prices before the state of demand is revealed(Marvel and Peck 1995, Dana  and  Spier 2001, Marvel and Wang 2003).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">In the case of = 0, these variables simplify to the corresponding terms inPadmanabhan and Png (1997, Table 3).5  Most of the results in Table1are simple algebra. Equation (7) characterizes p 1h without and with returns. Since the stock is higher with returns, (7) implies that the price would be lower.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank the editor in chief, area editor, reviewers, and Hao Wang for helpful comments.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix</head><p>Claim 1. In the case of returns, condition (14) implies that s 1 &gt; q 1l . </p><p>Since w &gt; 0, a sufficient condition is that</p><p>which is implied by ( <ref type="formula">14</ref>). Claim 2. If c = 0 and</p><p>then ( <ref type="formula">14</ref>) implies ( <ref type="formula">25</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula">29</ref>).</p><p>Proof. Suppose that c = 0. Then ( <ref type="formula">14</ref>) simplifies to</p><p>Further, (25) simplifies to</p><p>which is implied by (30). Using = h / l , condition (A.4) may be rewritten as</p><p>Now if c = 0, by ( <ref type="formula">29</ref>) and (32), R &gt; N if</p><p>which simplifies to 4 − 3 1 − ≤ 4 2 + + 2 − (A.10) which in turn simplifies to (30).</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vertical price controls with uncertain demand</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Butz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Law Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="433" to="459" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supply chain coordination with revenue-sharing contracts: Strengths and limitations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gérard</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Cachon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lariviere</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci. Forthcoming</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revenue sharing and vertical control in the video rental industry</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Dana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Jr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kathryn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Spier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Indust. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="245" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Demand uncertainty and price maintenance: Markdowns as destructive competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><surname>Deneckere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Howard</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Marvel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Peck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="619" to="641" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On the effectiveness of returns policies in the price-dependent newsvendor model. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Granot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shuya</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Sauder School, University of British Columbia</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Demand uncertainty and returns policies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Howard</forename><surname>Marvel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Peck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="691" to="714" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Inventories, return policy, and equilibrium price dispersion under demand uncertainty. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Howard</forename><surname>Marvel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hao</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>China Center for Economic Research, Beijing University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Returns policies: Make money by making good</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Padmanabhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">P L</forename><surname>Png</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sloan Management Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="72" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manufacturers returns policies and retail price competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Padmanabhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">P L</forename><surname>Png</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="94" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal pricing and return policies for perishable commodities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barry</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pasternack</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="166" to="176" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The price of launching a new product: Empirical evidence on factors affecting the relative magnitude of slotting allowances</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Akshay</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Humaira</forename><surname>Mahi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="246" to="268" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The logic of vertical restraints</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Rey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jean</forename><surname>Tirole</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="921" to="939" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do return policies intensify retail competition?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hao</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="611" to="613" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
