<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Social Contagion and Income Heterogeneity in New Product Diffusion: A Meta-Analytic Test</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2003-07-30">July 30, 2003</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Christophe</forename><surname>Van Den Bulte</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Stremersch</surname></persName>
							<email>stefan_stremersch@bus.emory.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Gary</forename><surname>Lilien</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">The Wharton School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>3730 Walnut St</addrLine>
									<postCode>19104</postCode>
									<settlement>Philadelphia</settlement>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">School of Economics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Goizueta Business School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Erasmus University of Rotterdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Burg. Oudlaan 50, The Netherlands</addrLine>
									<postCode>3000 DR</postCode>
									<settlement>Rotterdam</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Emory University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1300 Clifton Road</addrLine>
									<postCode>30322-2710</postCode>
									<settlement>Atlanta</settlement>
									<country key="GE">Georgia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Social Contagion and Income Heterogeneity in New Product Diffusion: A Meta-Analytic Test</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 04 2304 0530</idno>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2003-07-30">July 30, 2003</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1040.0054</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:31+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>diffusion of innovations</term>
					<term>social contagion</term>
					<term>income heterogeneity</term>
					<term>national culture</term>
					<term>meta-analysis History: This paper was received</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>How new products gain market acceptance has long been of great interest to marketers. It is commonly accepted that new product diffusion is often driven by social contagion, i.e., that actors' adoptions are a function of their exposure to other actors' knowledge, attitudes, or behaviors concerning the new product. Researchers have offered different theoretical accounts of social contagion, including social learning under uncertainty, social-normative pressures, competitive concerns, and performance network effects (Van den Bulte and <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Lilien 2001)</ref>.</p><p>Although these contagion mechanisms are conceptually distinct, their expressions in diffusion data of a single innovation are often indistinguishable, making it impossible to identify the exact nature of the contagion at work. So, although diffusion models often describe new product diffusion patterns over time quite well, it is unclear what kind of contagion process, if any, is being captured in the equations. This has long frustrated marketing researchers <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Gatignon and Robertson 1986</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">, Golder and Tellis 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">, Parker 1994</ref>.</p><p>Some have noted an even more fundamental theoretical issue in diffusion research: S-shaped diffu-sion curves need not stem from social contagion at all but can result from heterogeneity in the intrinsic tendency to adopt. Many of the popular diffusion models can be derived mathematically from both contagion and heterogeneity assumptions (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Bemmaor 1994, Chatterjee and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Eliashberg 1990)</ref>. Consequently, it is impossible to unambiguously interpret the model parameters of any single diffusion curve as reflecting social contagion or heterogeneity in the propensity to adopt.</p><p>The difficulty in identifying which of the many possible mechanisms is at work in the diffusion of a single innovation has led skeptics such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Stoneman (2002)</ref> to deem diffusion model parameters to be more informative as data summary devices than as evidence of any specific process. Although using model parameters as mere summary devices can lead to substantive insights (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bayus 1992</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">, Griliches 1957</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">, Van den Bulte 2000</ref>, the nature of the process matters for marketing strategy recommendations. For instance, a price penetration strategy might be optimal only when contagion exists: A low price can help to get the endogenous feedback process going and the firm can increase its price once the feedback momentum is <ref type="bibr">Van</ref>   <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Horsky 1990</ref>). When the S-shaped diffusion curve stems only from heterogeneity in reservation prices, in contrast, this rationale for price penetration vanishes and skimming clearly seems the better strategy. Another strategy decision affected by the strength of contagion is whether to enter multiple markets sequentially or simultaneously. The benefits of sequential entry depend in part on the strength of contagion across markets <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Kalish et al. 1995)</ref>. Knowing that contagion is at work is not enough. The nature of the process also matters. Depending on the type of contagion that is at work, advertising and sales calls should convey product information and reduce perceived risk, emphasize social-normative expectations, or play on fear of being outpaced by more innovative competitors. Also, the decision on whom to focus one's early viral marketing efforts will depend on the nature of contagion. For social norms and social learning direct ties are important, and an astute marketer will focus on well-connected actors. This need not be a good choice when contagion is driven by competition for status <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Burt 1987)</ref>. So, it is important to know not only the shape of diffusion paths, but also what contagion process, if any, is at work.</p><p>The key idea underlying the present study is that, although fitting the popular <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bass (1969)</ref> model to any single diffusion data series cannot empirically identify which process is at work, one can draw inferences from patterns of variation across multiple diffusion paths (compare <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Taibleson 1974)</ref>. Specifically, while several contagion processes as well as heterogeneity can result in the Bass model and fit the diffusion path of any single innovation equally well, different mechanisms have different implications about how the q/p ratio will vary across multiple diffusion paths, such as the diffusion of the same product in different countries.</p><p>Our research strategy consists in developing hypotheses about conditions under which different contagion mechanisms and heterogeneity are more pronounced, and testing these hypotheses using a meta-analysis of the q/p ratio in applications of the Bass diffusion model to consumer durables. For heterogeneity, we assume that income is an important dimension, and develop hypotheses about the relationship between income heterogeneity and the shape of the diffusion curve as reflected in the q/p ratio. For social contagion, we develop hypotheses about the relationship between <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Hofstede's (2001)</ref> dimensions of national culture and the q/p ratio. Following work on technologically induced endogenous feedback, we also develop hypotheses about the relationship between the presence of competing standards and the q/p ratio. Through these hypotheses we are able to assess empirically the different types of mechanisms that might result in sigmoid diffusion curves.</p><p>Our contribution consists of six findings. First, the Gini index of income inequality, capturing the shape of the income distribution, is positively related to the q/p ratio capturing the shape of the diffusion curve. This is consistent with income threshold models of diffusion. Second, the q/p ratio varies as predicted by <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bemmaor's (1994)</ref> Gamma-Shifted Gompertz (G/SG) model, assuming that the tendency to postpone adoption is inversely related to income. The evidence, however, vanishes once we control for national culture. Third, several methodological choices affect the estimated q/p ratio, increasing the risk of spurious evidence of contagion. Fourth, even after controlling for income heterogeneity and method artifacts, the q/p ratio varies systematically with the four Hofstede dimensions of national culture-for three of them in a direction consistent with the social contagion interpretation. Because the different dimensions of national culture are related to different contagion processes, our results also shed some light on the nature of contagion. Specifically, we find evidence consistent with contagion being fueled by both status concerns and social-normative pressures, but inconsistent with contagion being driven by social learning under uncertainty. Fifth, products with competing standards have a higher q/p ratio, which is again consistent with the social contagion interpretation. Sixth, the presence of competing standards drastically dampens the effects of culture and income inequality. This indicates that social contagion and the fear to adopt a losing technology do not operate independently from each other <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Choi 1997)</ref>.</p><p>Our study provides evidence on two fundamental issues in diffusion theory: the nature of contagion and the relevance of income heterogeneity. Because we analyze how diffusion trajectories vary as a function of the income distribution and national culture across 28 countries, we also provide new insights into international diffusion patterns.</p><p>We first discuss how diffusion through social contagion implies variations in the q/p ratio across national cultures and between products with and without competing standards, and then discuss how diffusion driven by heterogeneity implies variations in the same ratio as a function of the shape and scale of the income distribution. Next, we describe the data, analysis method, and results. The paper concludes with a discussion of implications and limitations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Social Contagion</head><p>The contagion explanation for S-shaped diffusion curves has long dominated the marketing literature. The <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bass (1969)</ref> model specifies the rate at which actors who have not adopted yet do so at time t (more precisely, in the time interval [t t + dt] where dt → 0)</p><p>Marketing Science 23(4), pp. 530-544, © 2004 INFORMS as r t = p + qF t , where F t is the cumulative proportion of adopters in the population, parameter p captures the intrinsic tendency to adopt, and parameter q captures social contagion, be it coarsely. Because the proportion of the population that adopts at time t can be written as dF t /dt = r t 1 − F t , one obtains</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">dF t /dt = p + qF t 1 − F t (1)</formula><p>Whereas this equation clearly conveys social contagion-F t affects future changes in F t -how F t varies over time is better reflected in the solution of the differential Equation (1). Assuming that one starts with zero adoptions F 0 = 0 , the solution is</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">F t = 1 − e − p+q t / 1 + q/p e − p+q t</formula><p>(2)</p><p>The curve is S-shaped when q &gt; p, and more pronouncedly so as the q/p ratio increases. This ratio summarizes the shape of the curve and can be interpreted as a shape parameter <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Chatterjee and Eliashberg 1990)</ref>.</p><p>The model does not specify the nature of the contagion process, such as social learning under uncertainty, social-normative pressures, competitive concerns, or performance network effects. Additional theoretical detail must be provided for one to obtain refutable hypotheses pertaining to each process separately. One can do so by specifying observable contingency factors for each type of contagion. Our research strategy therefore consists in testing, not the contagion explanation in general, but the narrower claim that culture and competing standards affect diffusion in a particular way if contagion is indeed a driver. Because the heterogeneity models we investigate provide testable implications for q/p but not for p and q separately we limit our hypotheses about social contagion to the same ratio which, according to the contagion interpretation, reflects the relative importance of imitative and innovative tendencies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Social Contagion and National Culture</head><p>Since their introduction in 1980, <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Hofstede's (2001)</ref> four dimensions of national culture have become important elements in studying consumer behavior across countries. Several researchers have recognized the value of these dimensions when seeking to explain adoption behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Jain and Maesincee 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">, Sundqvist et al. 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">, Tellis et al. 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">, Yaveroglu and Donthu 2002</ref>. Building on prior research and introducing some additional arguments from sociology, we hypothesize how the q/p ratio should vary across these four dimensions if social contagion affects diffusion. The hypothesis relating individualism to q/p is based on socialnormative pressure, and that relating uncertainty avoidance to q/p is based on social learning under uncertainty. The hypotheses on power distance and masculinity are based on status considerations.</p><p>2.1.1. Individualism. Individualism is the opposite of collectivism, which is the extent to which "people from birth onwards are integrated into strong, cohesive in-groups" <ref type="bibr">(Hofstede 2001, p. 225)</ref>. Because individualist cultures deemphasize conformity to social norms and group behavior (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Bond and Smith 1996)</ref>, they expectedly have lower q values if contagion is a social-normative process. Also, because individualist cultures value novelty and variety more <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Roth 1995)</ref> and use mass media more extensively than collectivist cultures do <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(de Mooij 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">, Hofstede 2001</ref>), they expectedly have higher p values. Hence we posit: Hypothesis 1. The q/p ratio is negatively associated with individualism.</p><p>Consistent with this prediction, <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Yaveroglu and Donthu (2002)</ref> report that individualism was correlated positively with p and negatively with q. Two studies provide further indirect support for Hypothesis 1. Jain and Maesincee (1998) report a negative association between individualism and q, but it was significant (at 95% confidence) for only three of the six products they studied. In a survey of over 3,000 consumers in 11 European countries, <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Steenkamp et al. (1999)</ref> find a positive association between the country's individualism and its citizens' consumer innovativeness, an individual-level construct similar to the intrinsic tendency to adopt captured by the population-level parameter p.</p><p>2.1.2. Uncertainty Avoidance. This is "the extent to which the members of a culture feel threatened by uncertain or unknown situations" <ref type="bibr">(Hofstede 2001, p. 161)</ref>. To the extent that diffusion is driven by social learning under uncertainty, a possibility often advanced by marketing scientists (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Horsky 1990</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">, Kalish 1985</ref>, one would expect high q values in high uncertainty avoidance countries. Also, one would expect a lower intrinsic tendency to adopt innovations (p because consumers in such countries are more averse to what is different and new <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Hofstede 2001)</ref>. In short, to the extent that diffusion is driven by social contagion and that the latter arises from social learning under uncertainty, the following hypothesis should hold: Hypothesis 2. The q/p ratio is positively associated with uncertainty avoidance. <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Yaveroglu and Donthu (2002)</ref> report that uncertainty avoidance is correlated positively with q and negatively with p. Studies by Jain and Maesincee (1998), <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Steenkamp et al. (1999), and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Tellis et al. (2003)</ref> provide additional indirect support. The first finds a negative relation between p and uncertainty avoidance, but only for three of the six products investigated. The second finds a negative association between the country's uncertainty avoidance and its citizens' consumer innovativeness. The third finds that new products took off faster in countries with low uncertainty avoidance.</p><p>2.1.3. Power Distance. This is "the extent to which the less powerful members of [a culture] expect and accept that power is distributed unequally" <ref type="bibr">(Hofstede 2001, p. 98</ref>). More broadly, power distance captures how sensitive people are to status differences and how much people are motivated by the need to conform with those in their status group or in status groups to which they aspire <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Roth 1995)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> This has direct implications for social contagion, because people buy and use products not only for functional purposes, but also to construct a social identity <ref type="bibr">(Baudrillard 1981, Douglas and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Isherwood 1979)</ref> and to confirm the existence and support the reproduction of social status differences <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Bourdieu 1984)</ref>. The extent to which status differences are expected and accepted, then, affects how important it is to adopt the "right" innovations at the "right" time. On the one hand, one must not adopt too early to avoid appearing presumptuous about one's place in society. This implies a low intrinsic tendency to adopt (p) in high powerdistance cultures. On the other hand, people will seek to emulate the consumption behavior of their superiors <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Tarde 1903</ref>) and aspiration groups <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Simmel 1971)</ref> and will also quickly pick up innovations adopted by others of similar status if they fear that such adoptions might undo the present status ordering <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Burt 1987)</ref>. This implies a high contagion effect (q . Hence, to the extent that diffusion is driven by social contagion and that the latter arises from status considerations, the following hypothesis should hold: Hypothesis 3. The q/p ratio is positively associated with power distance.</p><p>Apart from an early intimation by <ref type="bibr">Tarde (1903, p. 198</ref>) that the "common people have always been inclined to copy kings and courts and upper classes according to the measure in which they have submitted to their rule" and <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Yaveroglu and Donthu's (2002)</ref> 1 Note that power distance and income inequality are very different concepts. First, power distance is the extent to which people expect and accept differences in social status and other inequalities, not the extent to which such differences are large or small <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Hofstede 2001)</ref>. Second, social status is defined not only by income and wealth but also by occupation, education, aesthetic preferences, place of residence, lineage, and race (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Blau 1977</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">, Lamont 1992</ref>. Still, although conceptually distinct, power distance and income inequality covary <ref type="bibr">(Hofstede 2001, pp. 128-130)</ref>, because income inequality is likely to be greater in cultures that accept social differentiation and because income and wealth tend to correlate with social status. Hence, while the cultural trait power distance is conceptually distinct from income heterogeneity, their effects expectedly must be analyzed jointly to avoid omitted variable bias.</p><p>recent study reporting a negative correlation between power distance and p, we are not aware of prior work suggesting a similar hypothesis. Jain and Maesincee (1998) do not investigate power distance, <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Steenkamp et al. (1999)</ref> state that it cannot be related to consumer innovativeness, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Tellis et al. (2003)</ref> report having found neither theoretical arguments nor empirical evidence linking it to the take-off time of new products.</p><p>2.1.4. Masculinity. This is the extent to which "social gender roles are clearly distinct: men are supposed to be assertive, tough, and focused on material success; women are supposed to be more modest, tender, and concerned with the quality of life" <ref type="bibr">(Hofstede 2001, p. 297)</ref>. Importantly for consumer behavior, masculine cultures put more emphasis on wealth, material success, and achievement (de Mooij 1998, <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Steenkamp et al. 1999</ref>). Hence, both display of status in general and display of material possessions in particular are more prevalent in masculine than in feminine cultures. As with power distance, this implies a positive association between masculinity and q. However, as <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Steenkamp et al. (1999)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Tellis et al. (2003)</ref> note, the greater importance that masculine cultures attach to material possessions suggests a higher intrinsic tendency to adopt innovations. This implies a positive association between masculinity and p (unlike power distance). So the net effect of q/p is unclear a priori. That the typical diffusion curve is sigmoid even in wealthy countries such as the United States suggests that the association with q is stronger than that with p. So, to the extent that diffusion is driven by social contagion and that the latter arises from competition for status, we expect the following hypothesis to hold: Hypothesis 4. The q/p ratio is positively associated with masculinity.</p><p>We are not aware of prior research advancing a similar hypothesis. Jain and Maesincee (1998) do not investigate masculinity, nor do <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Yaveroglu and Donthu (2002)</ref>. Whereas <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Gatignon et al. (1989)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Talukdar et al. (2002)</ref> investigate relationships between Bass model parameters and the female labor participation rate (they find none), our hypothesis pertains not to whether women work but to the prevalence of values of wealth, material success, and achievement. <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Steenkamp et al. (1999)</ref> find a positive association with consumer innovativeness, but do not investigate the q/p ratio. <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Tellis et al. (2003)</ref>, finally, do not find a positive relation between masculinity and faster take-off.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Social Contagion and Competing Standards</head><p>When faced with competing standards, even innovative consumers might postpone adoption until the uncertainty about what standard will dominate has Marketing Science 23(4), pp. 530-544, © 2004 INFORMS been resolved <ref type="bibr">(Choi 1997, Katz and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Shapiro 1994)</ref>. Such wait-and-see behavior or "excess inertia" should result in a higher q/p ratio because of both a lower intrinsic tendency to adopt and a higher level of endogenous feedback. The presence of competing standards and the related issue of the provision of complements have an important supply-side element that is absent from the purely demand-side social contagion processes discussed above <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Stoneman 2002)</ref>. To acknowledge and assess this alternative explanation for variation in the q/p ratio, we posit: Hypothesis 5. The q/p ratio is higher for products with competing standards. <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Van den Bulte (2000)</ref> reports evidence that the diffusion path of product categories with competing standards has a more pronounced S-shape, but his analysis uses the logistic model featuring q only. We are not aware of prior evidence pertaining to q/p directly.</p><p>The effect of competing standards on adoption might vary across cultures. Competing standards exacerbate the uncertainty faced by early adopters, and this effect is expectedly more pronounced in uncertainty-avoiding cultures. Multiple standards expectedly are a stronger deterrent to early adoption in individualistic than in collectivist cultures. In the latter, consumers are more likely to coordinate their purchases with their peers, hence reducing the fear of being left with a technological orphan and reducing the benefits of waiting until the overall market has decided which standard wins. Multiple standards are also less likely to deter initial adoption in powerdistant and masculine cultures, because the more the product is adopted for symbolic reasons the less consumers care about the risk of ending up with a technological orphan that provides little functional value. Using the minority technology might even signal that one is indeed different from the majority of consumers (an attribution long exploited in advertisements for Apple computers). Hence, we posit: Hypothesis 6. The effect of competing standards on q/p is larger in (a) individualistic and (b) uncertainty avoidant cultures and is smaller in (c) power-distant and (d) masculine cultures.</p><p>Jain and Maesincee (1998) report a negative association between individualism and q, but only for clothes dryers, dishwashers, and microwave ovens, and not for home computers, color TVs, and VCRs. They also find a negative relation between uncertainty avoidance and p, but only for the latter set of products. Although Jain and Maesincee do not interpret these findings in terms of competing standards, they are consistent with Hypotheses 6(a) and 6(b).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Income Heterogeneity</head><p>We consider two types of heterogeneity-based diffusion models: threshold models and <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bemmaor's (1994)</ref> G/SG model. Threshold models posit that actors adopt as soon as the utility of the innovation exceeds some critical level or threshold. If the utility increases systematically over time and the thresholds follow some bell-shaped distribution, then the cumulative number of adopters, i.e., the diffusion curve, will be S-shaped <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Duesenberry 1949)</ref>. For instance, if utility increases linearly and the thresholds are normally distributed, the diffusion curve is the cumulative normal curve <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Dernburg 1958)</ref>. If the distribution of reservation prices is log normal and prices decrease exponentially, then the normal curve results again <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Bonus 1973)</ref>. Many other combinations of exogenous change and threshold distribution are possible. The main result is that S-shaped diffusion curves, including skewed ones such as the lognormal curve <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Davies 1979</ref>) and the Bass curve (Chatterjee and Eliashberg 1990), can result without any contagion. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Bemmaor's (1994) G/SG model is not based on the idea of thresholds, but it too can result in the Bass model. The model assumes that each actor's time of adoption is randomly distributed according to a shifted Gompertz distribution with cumulative distribution function (c.d.f.):</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">G t b = 1 − e −bt exp − e −bt (<label>3</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_3">)</formula><p>where b is a scale parameter that is constant across all actors and &gt; 0 represents the intrinsic tendency to adopt late (the higher , the higher the expected adoption time). Next, the model assumes that the intrinsic tendency varies according to a Gamma distribution. This distribution has two parameters: a shape parameter and a scale parameter , determining the mean ( ) and the variance ( 2 . Combining the shifted Gompertz model of individual adoption times with the Gamma distribution of heterogeneity across individuals, Bemmaor obtains the following expression for the c.d.f. of adoption times:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">F t = 1 − e −bt / 1 + e −bt (4)</formula><p>This function can generate sigmoid curves. When = 1, it reduces to the Bass model because one can reparametrize Equation (4) into Equation (2) using b = p + q and = q/p.</p><p>The threshold and G/SG models do not specify what the dimension is along which relevant heterogeneity exists. However, economic theory and prior research offer a candidate for the case of consumer durables, namely income (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Bonus 1973</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">, Chatterjee and Eliashberg 1990</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">, Dernburg 1958</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">, Russell 1980</ref>. Consequently, we focus on income heterogeneity.</p><p>The two heterogeneity models have very distinct implications for the effect of income distribution on the q/p ratio. Whereas threshold models imply that the shape of the diffusion curve will be determined mostly by the shape of the threshold distribution, the G/SG model implies that q/p is determined by the scale parameter of the income distribution. We detail each model in turn.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Threshold Models</head><p>Income threshold models imply that the diffusion curve is determined mostly by the shape of the income distribution. Assuming that prices decline over time and that income determines reservation prices, one can make the general claim that diffusion curves "will be flatter in countries in which income is more evenly distributed" <ref type="bibr">(Russell 1980, p. S73)</ref>. The most commonly used measure of income inequality that succinctly captures the shape of the income distribution is the Gini concentration index, or Gini coefficient. Hence, if diffusion operates according to threshold models and the threshold distribution reflects the income distribution, the following should hold:</p><p>Hypothesis 7. The q/p ratio is positively associated with the Gini coefficient of income inequality.</p><p>This prediction is unique to the income heterogeneity interpretation and cannot be derived from the contagion interpretation. Actually, reasoning that contagion requires interaction, that interaction is less prevalent in heterogeneous populations due to homophily ("birds of a feather flock together"), and that income is a social dimension affecting interaction frequency implies a negative rather than positive association between income inequality and q. The positive association between q and the Gini coefficient reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Talukdar et al. (2002)</ref> is not consistent with the social contagion interpretation of diffusion, but provides indirect support for the effect on q/p predicted in Hypothesis 7.</p><p>Since the exact shape of the diffusion curve depends on both the income distribution and the pattern of price change, we provide a synthetic example based on empirical generalizations. Income distributions typically have longer tails to the right than to the left and can be described using the Gamma or the inverse Gamma distribution (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Kloek and</ref><ref type="bibr">van Dijk 1978, McDonald 1984)</ref>. Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> shows two distribution densities of reservation prices i . Both are Gamma and have the same scale parameter = 6. The distributions vary in their shape parameter: One has </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Threshold (θ)</head><p>High Gini Coefficient</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Low Gini Coefficient</head><p>= 2 and the other has = 4. The corresponding Gini coefficients are 0.375 and 0.273, reasonable values for national income distributions. A consumer i adopts as soon as the price falls below her reservation price, i &gt; p t . As a result, the proportion of consumers that have adopted by time t, F t , equals 1−F p t , where F is the c.d.f. of the threshold distribution. Because the price of innovations tends to decrease exponentially (e.g., Agarwal and Bayus 2002), we assume p t = 45 e −0 1t . This results in the two diffusion curves shown in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>. Clearly, the diffusion curve corresponding to the higher Gini value (more inequality) is less skewed to the right and has a higher q/p ratio. Fitting the Bass model to each curve and forcing the ceiling to 1 to avoid right-censoring bias yields estimated q/p ratios of 20 and 6.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">G/SG Model</head><p>The G/SG model implies that the q/p ratio varies with the scale parameter of the heterogeneity distribution of . Because high values of lead to late adoption, it cannot be interpreted as income but can be interpreted as the reciprocal of income. Because the G/SG model assumes to be Gamma( ) distributed with mean and variance 2 , this implies income to be Inverse Gamma distributed with mean [ − 1 −1 and variance [ 2 − 1 2 − 2 −1 . Hence, if diffusion Hypothesis 8. The q/p ratio is positively associated with the scale of the reciprocal of income, assuming income is inverse Gamma distributed.</p><p>As Equation (4) shows, the G/SG model reduces exactly to the Bass model only if = 1. Income distributions, however, typically have &gt; 1. Fortunately, the assumption that = 1 is not critical to test Hypothesis 8: Estimates of q/p obtained from a traditional Bass model tend to approximate even when the true data-generating process is G/SG with &gt; 1 (see appendix).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Income Heterogeneity and</head><p>Competing Standards To the extent that competing standards result in excess inertia and endogenous feedback, they might dampen the extent to which the diffusion curve reflects the shape or scale of the income distribution. Hence we posit:</p><p>Hypothesis 9. The effect of competing standards on q/p dampens the effect of (a) the Gini coefficient and (b) the scale of the reciprocal of income, assuming income is Inverse Gamma distributed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Research Design</head><p>We use a meta-analysis of published q/p ratios of consumer durables. Whereas meta-analysis is often used to synthesize prior research, it can also be used to test hypotheses of theoretical interest <ref type="bibr">(Geyskens et al. 1999, Miller and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Pollock 1994)</ref>. We consider only consumer products, because the income heterogeneity hypotheses are less applicable to businesses and other organizations, and only durables because their nonnegligible price makes them a more relevant domain to test our hypotheses: Income thresholds are more likely to matter, products are more likely to convey status, and adoption is more likely to present financial and social risk.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Literature Search and Inclusion Criteria</head><p>We performed a forward citation search in the Social Science Citation Index (SSCI), retrieving all publications between January 1969 and May 2000 that cite the <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bass (1969)</ref> paper. We also performed subject searches in the ABI Inform and EconLit databases for the same period, and manually checked early volumes of Marketing Letters and the International Journal of Research in Marketing excluded from the SSCI, three edited book volumes <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Mahajan and Wind 1986</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">, Mahajan et al. 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">, Wind et al. 1981</ref>, and our file drawers for additional publications before May 2000.</p><p>To be included, a study had to report estimates for the Bass model, possibly extended with control variables, applied to new consumer durables. Botĥ p andq had to be reported in the original form, or sufficient information had to be provided for one to retrieve the original parameters' estimates via some transformation.</p><p>This procedure resulted in 746 sets of estimates pertaining to 75 consumer durables in 77 countries and reported in 54 publications. For 44 of those countries and 694 observations, Hofstede culture scores are available. The requirements that the publication identify the start and end year of the data series used for estimation and that data be available on the average income and Gini coefficient for that country in that period reduced the sample size to 302. Finally, we deleted observations for whichp orq was smaller than zero or larger than 1. Our final data set contains 293 observations on 52 consumer durables in 28 countries reported in 46 publications.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Variables</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.1.">Dependent Variable.</head><p>To reduce skew, we use ln q/p as our dependent variable. It has only moderate skew (−0.68) and kurtosis (5.38), compared with the normal (0 and 3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2.">National</head><p>Culture. We use Hofstede's national culture scores UAI, IDV, PDI, and MAS based on data collected in the early 1970s. Replication studies have shown differences among countries to be stable over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Hofstede 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">, Søndergaard 1994</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.3.">Competing Standards.</head><p>We use a dummy variable for products with competing standards: COMPSTAND equals 1 for PCs, VCRs, and cellular telephones, and equals 0 for other products. The decision to code cellular telephones as a category with competing standards can be questioned (Van den Bulte 2000). So, to assess robustness, we also created a separate CELLTEL dummy variable. The mean effects of cellular telephones were not different from those of other products with competing standards.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.4.">Income Heterogeneity.</head><p>The most commonly used measure of income inequality is the Gini concentration index, or Gini coefficient, C. Another popular index is the Gini's mean differences (GMD), which is the expected value of the absolute difference between the incomes of two independently drawn people or households. The first index measures relative inequality such that scaling all incomes in a country proportionally does not affect the value of the index, whereas the latter measures absolute inequality and does not change when all incomes in a country are increased by the same amount. For variables that do not assume negative values, multiplying the relative index by twice the mean value leads to the absolute index <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Johnson et al. 1994</ref>): GMD = 2C</p><p>(5)</p><p>This identity allows us to operationalize the scale parameter as a function of available macroeconomic data on the mean and Gini coefficient of national income distributions. Recall that Hypotheses 8 and 9(b) assume that income is Inverse Gamma distributed with mean = − 1 −1 and standard deviation = − 1 • − 2 1/2 −1 , where and are the parameters of the G/SG diffusion model. This implies / = − 2 −1/2 . Because many moderately skewed distributions have ≈ GMD (Hosking and Wallis 1997), Equation ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>) implies 2C ≈ − 2 −1/2 , and hence 2C −2 + 1 ≈ − 1. Combining this expression with the formula for the mean = − 1 −1 results in the expression ≈ 2C −2 + 1 −1 , where is the average income and C is the Gini coefficient of the income distribution.</p><p>To make valid comparisons across countries and over time, we measure average income using the real gross domestic product per capita expressed in 1996 international prices reported in the Penn World Table (Mark 6.1) published by the Center for International Comparisons at the University of Pennsylvania <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">(Summers and Heston 1991)</ref>. Because the Penn World Table covers the period 1950-2000, our data set contains only estimates from data series within that period.</p><p>We use the Gini coefficients calculated by <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Deininger and Squire (1996)</ref> and published by the World Bank. To maintain consistency with our measure of average income, we use Gini values computed using personal rather than household income. When multiple values are available for a country, we linearly interpolate between the years. Outside the interval, we use the value observed in the nearest year.</p><p>Because both mean income and the Gini coefficient can vary over time, we use the average Gini and the average mean income observed over the period used for estimating p and q. Because we use the logarithm ofq/p as our dependent variable, we similarly transform our income heterogeneity scale metric [ 2C −2 + 1 −1 , creating the variable LNSCALE. We also take the log of the Gini coefficient, creating the variable LNGINI. 4.3.5. Control Variables. Before computing the dependent variable ln q/p , we recoded eight zero values ofp and four zero values ofq to 0.01. We therefore add control dummy variables, PNULL and QNULL, which take the value 1 when such recoding occurred and 0 otherwise.</p><p>We also add two dummy variables capturing heterogeneity in the products. The first is BRAND, capturing whether the original data series pertained to the product of a particular manufacturer rather than the whole product category. One would expect the former to have a less-pronounced S-shape. The second is INFRA, which equals 1 for one-to-many broadcasting products requiring large investments in infrastructure (black-and-white TV, cable TV, color TV, and radio). We do not code cellular telephones as requiring large infrastructure investments because in many developing countries cellular telephony is used as a means to avoid the even larger investments in fixed-line equipment.</p><p>STARTC is the year in which the data series starts, centered around the sample mean <ref type="bibr">(1972.8)</ref>. This variable captures both genuine changes in the average q/p ratio over time and the bias stemming from different levels of left-truncation across different analyses of the same product in the same country.</p><p>We also control for variation in theq/p ratio induced by differences in how the estimates were obtained. First, we allow for differences across estimation techniques <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Sultan et al. 1990)</ref>. Using nonlinear least squares as the baseline, we coded three dummy variables: ESTOLS for OLS, ESTMLE for maximum likelihood, and ESTOTH for others such as <ref type="bibr">Dekimpe et al.'s (1998)</ref> staged procedure.</p><p>Second, we coded whether the model was formulated in discrete or continuous time (CONTTIME). This takes into account that the discrete-time specification might result in a bias.</p><p>Third, we use two variables to control for the number of observations used in the estimation. WINDOW10 captures the number of years covered by the data series, expressed in decades. LNFREQ is the natural logarithm of the data frequency (1 for annual, 4 for quarterly, 12 for monthly). Research documenting systematic changes inp andq as one extends the data series suggests a negative relation between q/p and WINDOW10. If this effect stems from illconditioning, as Van den Bulte and <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Lilien (1997)</ref> claim, then one should also observe a negative association betweenq/p and LNFREQ. However, LNFREQ might also capture time-aggregation bias, in which case the recent results by <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Non et al. (2003)</ref> imply a positive association.</p><p>A fourth issue is the use of data on sales rather than actual adoptions or penetration rates, which leads to contamination by replacement and additional purchases, a problem likely to be exacerbated in data series covering many years <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Lilien et al. 2000</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">, Parker and Neelamegham 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">, Putsis 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">, Putsis and Srinivasan 2000</ref>. Hence, we use a NONADOP dummy taking value 1 when either sales <ref type="bibr">(N = 196)</ref> or production (N = 6) data were used and taking value 0 when adoption or penetration data were used (N = 91), as well as an interaction term NONADOP*WINDOW10.   Fifth, we use three dummies indicating whether p, q, or m (the ceiling parameter) were allowed to vary as a function of covariates (P_CONTROL, Q_CONTROL, M_CONTROL).</p><p>Finally, the dummy variable PROPCEILING indicates whether m was allowed to vary over time as a proportion of the total population (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bayus 1992</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">, Horsky 1990</ref>). Because failing to control for growth in the ceiling (and hence the population at risk) underestimates the empirical hazard rate early on and overestimates how much it increases over time, we expect both M_CONTROL and PROPCEILING to be negatively associated withq/p.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.">Descriptive Statistics</head><p>The 293 observations pertain to 52 different consumer durables in 28 countries. Color television accounts for 60 observations (20%), VCRs for 57 (19%), cellular telephone for 43 (15%), and microwave ovens for 16 (5%). The United States accounts for 210 observations (72%), Asia for 36 (12%), Europe for 33 (11%), and Latin America for 14 (5%). Forp, the mean is 0.027, the median is 0.012, and the 10%-90% range is 0.001-0.083. Forq, the mean is 0.419, the median is 0.420, and the 10%-90% range is 0.128-0.690. The means are quite close to those reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Sultan et al. (1990)</ref>. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">1</ref> reports descriptive statistics for the variables of substantive interest.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5.">Statistical Model</head><p>Because we have repeated observations across products and countries, we use a multilevel model allowing for random effects in the intercept and slopes across both countries and products. Using subscript i to denote a product, j to denote a country, k to denote a replication, and s to identify a covariate, the model structure we use to explain variations in the observed ln q/p ijk is ln q/p ijk = 0ij + s sij x sijk + ijk s 1 S where</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">sij = s +U si +U sj s 0 S ijk ∼ N 0 2 U si ∼ N 0 2 s and U sj ∼ N 0 2 s (6)</formula><p>Because the panel is very unbalanced with many product-country combinations having no or very few observations, we impose a variance components structure, Cov(U si U s i = 0 and Cov(U sj U s j = 0. We estimate the model using residual maximum likelihood. We use the Bayesian information criterion (BIC) to identify the simplest yet statistically defensible error structure. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> We use t-tests to assess whether the s parameter estimates are significantly different from zero. Note that the model allows for a random effect when the mean effect s is forced to zero. When performing robustness checks pertaining to treating cellular telephones as a separate category, we find that allowing for a random country effect for cellular telephones better captures the error correlation structure than doing so for all products with competing standards, so we report models allowing for such random effects.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Results</head><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">2</ref> reports the fixed or mean effects ( s ) of three models. All include the control variables and the competing standards dummy, but differ in the set of other covariates of theoretical interest. Model 1 includes only the culture variables. Model 2 includes only the income distribution variables. Model 3 includes all covariates. The pseudo-R 2 values, which are the squared Pearson correlations between the predicted and actual values, indicate that all three models capture the variation in the q/p ratio about equally well.</p><p>Because COMPSTAND is binary 0-1, the linear effects of IDV, UAI, PDI, MAS, LNGINI, and LNSCALE pertain to products without competing standards, and their interaction with COMPSTAND captures whether these effects are different from those for products with competing standards. Because we mean-centered the culture and income variables before estimation, the linear effect of COMPSTAND can be interpreted as a main effect. Model 1 gives only partial support to the cultural hypotheses: UAI and PDI do not show the posited effect, and PDI does not have the expected interaction with COMPSTAND. Model 2 shows the expected effects for both LNGINI and LNSCALE. Model 3, incorporating all posited effects and expectedly free of omitted variable bias, finds support for all hypotheses except two: UAI has a negative rather than a positive effect (although this is moderated by the presence of competing standards) and LNSCALE has no effect at all. The effect of LNGINI, an elasticity of 12.6, is quite large but not excessive, considering the difference in range between the explanatory and the dependent variable. Before discussing the findings in greater detail, we report on some robustness checks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Robustness Checks</head><p>To check the robustness of the results in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">2</ref>, we performed five additional analyses reported here only briefly. First, to check the sensitivity to our coding of cellular telephones, we extended the full model with a CELLTEL dummy and with its interaction terms with each of the cultural dimensions. None of the new coefficients was significant (p &gt; 0 10) and the other coefficients barely changed. Second, using the natural Marketing Science 23(4), pp. 530-544, © 2004 INFORMS log of the culture variables does not make the results more consistent with social contagion. In Model 3, for instance, the effect of UAI remains negative and highly significant and the negative effect of IDV remains significant at 90% confidence only. Third, we extended Model 3 with the number of ethnic groups, religions, and languages in each country <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Parker 1997)</ref> as measures of social heterogeneity that, due to homophily, might negatively affect the amount of interaction in the population and depress the q/p ratio. None of these variables had a significant effect (p &gt; 0 10). More importantly, none of the cultural or income effects changed appreciably, with the exception of the confidence level for the IDV effect, that increased to 95%. Fourth, as a check against collinearity artifacts involving LNSCALE and the culture variables, we reestimated Model 3 without LNSCALE. This reduced the coefficient of IDV from −0.109 to −0.053 but increased the confidence level from 92.5% to 95.2%. It also reduced the coefficient of PDI from 0.100 to 0.061 (both significant at 5%). Other coefficients and confidence levels barely changed. This high level of stability indicates that the null effect of LNSCALE in the full model cannot be dismissed as a collinearity artifact <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Myers 1990)</ref>. Rather, the significant effect of LNSCALE in Model 2 is likely to be an omitted variable bias artifact stemming from ignoring the effects of IDV and PDI with which LNSCALE is correlated rather strongly. Finally, we expanded our data set with 107 observations from data series starting in 1949. Because we average income over the entire length of the data series, imputing the 1950 income values for the 1949 values can create only a very low level of measurement error in the covariates. Adding these 107 observations, all from the United States, brings the total sample size to 400 and increases the number of products from 52 to 62, although most new observations pertain to clothes dryers (N = 46) and room air conditioners (N = 42). Reestimating all models on this expanded data set led to remarkably similar coefficients and identical hypothesis test results, the only difference being that the gain in statistical power nudged some effects from the 90% to the 95% confidence level (e.g., IDV and COMPSTAND*PDI in Model 3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Results of Theoretical Interest</head><p>There are five key substantive results. First, we find support for most of the culture hypotheses and, hence, for the social contagion interpretation of the Bass model-at least for categories without competing standards. Second, our results shed some light on the nature of the social contagion process. More collectivistic cultures tend to have a higher q/p ratio. This is consistent with social-normative cohesion accounts of contagion. Also, cultures with high power-distance and masculine values have a higher q/p ratio. This is consistent with a competition for status account of social contagion. Surprisingly, cultures with high uncertainty avoidance tend to have lower rather than higher q/p ratios. This is inconsistent with the interpretation that q captures social learning under uncertainty. However, we do find evidence that uncertaintyavoiding cultures have higher q/p ratios for products with competing standards. Because such products exhibit arguably high levels of uncertainty, this interaction effect is consistent with social learning under uncertainty. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Third, the q/p ratio varies positively with the Gini coefficient of income inequality. This is consistent with theories explaining S-shaped diffusion curves as stemming from heterogeneity in adoption thresholds related to income, rather than (only) from social contagion. Fourth, we also find evidence, consistent with the G/SG model, that the q/p ratio varies positively with the scale of the heterogeneity if is interpreted as the reciprocal of income. The evidence, however, might be an omitted variable bias artifact, because the effect disappears after controlling for national culture.</p><p>Finally, the presence of competing standards not only has a large main effect on the q/p ratio, but also interacts with both culture and income heterogeneity. Strikingly, the interaction effect between each variable and COMPSTAND is about as large as each variable's linear effect, but with the reverse sign. This indicates that cultural and income heterogeneity effects are not just moderated, but are entirely swamped by technology considerations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.">Results of Methodological Interest</head><p>Using longer time series (WINDOW10) and using data with higher frequency (LNFREQ) is associated with lowerq/p values. The effect of WINDOW10 is quite sizable: Increasing the number of observations from 10 to 20 is associated with an expected decline in theq/p ratio of about 75% (1 − e −1 35 ) in Model 3.</p><p>Using sales rather than adoption or penetration data systematically affects parameter estimates, and this effect varies with the length of the data series, as indicated by the significant effects of NONADOP and its interaction term with WINDOW10.</p><p>We find no statistically significant differences among the three main estimation techniques (NLS, OLS, and MLE) that are consistent among the three models in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">2</ref>. Using other techniques is associated with a higherq/p ratio, which might simply reflect that researchers resort to such alternatives when standard techniques fail to produce reasonable estimates.</p><p>As to extending the Bass model with marketing and other control variables, allowing for changes in p does not affect theq/p ratio. The effects of controlling for changes in q are quite marginal. However, those of controlling for changes in the market ceiling m are robust across models and significant at 90% confidence or better. Expressing the ceiling as a proportion of a time-varying total population affectsq/p even more.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.">Implications for Diffusion Theory</head><p>Our results provide empirical support for the role of income heterogeneity in diffusion of consumer innovations. That heterogeneity without contagion could generate Bass-type diffusion curves has long been known. Our results imply that this can no longer be bracketed as merely an interesting but empirically vacuous analytical result. More generally, our meta-analysis of 293 diffusion processes corroborates findings from in-depth case studies that S-shaped diffusion curves and increasing hazards of adoption need not necessarily indicate the presence of contagion (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Van den Bulte and Lilien 2001)</ref>.</p><p>Although our results indicate that income heterogeneity indeed matters, our results regarding culture and competing standards indicate that social contagion is at work as well. More importantly, we are also able to shed some light on the nature of the contagion process, with the key finding being that the extent of contagion is better explained by socialnormative cohesion and status considerations than by social learning under uncertainty. The ideas of emulation being driven by social norms and status concerns have a very long tradition in sociology <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Burt 1987</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">, Simmel 1971</ref>, but have been ignored in diffusion modeling by marketers. This is of particular relevance to research in international new product growth and consumer innovativeness. Prior studies have mostly used a subset of cultural traits. The dimension of power distance, in particular, has been ignored. Our study provides arguments to also include status considerations and the power-distance dimension associated with it in international diffusion theory and research.</p><p>The presence of competing standards is associated with more strongly S-shaped diffusion patterns. This corroborates earlier analytical <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Choi 1997</ref>) and empirical (Van den Bulte 2000) results. Interestingly, we also find interaction effects between the presence of competing standards and cultural dimensions associated with different contagion mechanisms. Because products with competing standards have strong technological network effects, our findings can also be interpreted as evidence that technological network effects and culturally moderated social contagion effects need not operate independently from each other (compare <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Choi 1997)</ref>. The results support our original hypotheses that culture moderates fears of getting stuck with a losing product technology, but the effect sizes can also be interpreted as indicating that cultural effects are simply swamped by technology considerations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.">Implications for Empirical Diffusion</head><p>Modeling The findings regarding the methodological control variables confirm several concerns about inflatedq/p ratios and spurious evidence of contagion. The results about the length of the data window and the data frequency are consistent with the simulation results on bias and systematic change of <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Van den Bulte and Lilien (1997)</ref>. Whereas <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Bemmaor and Lee (2002)</ref> have shown that using short data series can deflate rather than inflate theq/p ratio when the data exhibit more right skew than the Bass model can account for, our results show that this reverse pattern is the exception rather than the rule for consumer durables. The implication is obvious: Short data series should be avoided.</p><p>The results regarding the use of sales data when estimating models of adoption (i.e., first-time purchase) are equally clear: Sales data lead to different parameter estimates than adoption or penetration data, and the size and direction of the deviation is a function of the length of the data series. The implication is again obvious: Unless the replacement cycle is very long and households buy only a single unit, sales data should be avoided when estimating models of diffusion. Trying to avoid data contamination by using shorter data series is not a proper solution because it exacerbates the bias problem just mentioned.</p><p>As expected, failing to account for growth in the overall population or the number of ultimate adopters also tends to inflate theq/p ratio. Even when no data are available beyond the size of the total population, using this information might help one avoid spurious evidence of contagion.</p><p>Our finding that income heterogeneity and national culture are associated with the q/p ratio has an important implication for multinational diffusion studies of cross-country spill-overs (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Elberse and Eliashberg 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">, Kumar and Krishnan 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">, Putsis et al. 1997</ref>. Because income inequality and culture tend to be spatially autocorrelated (i.e., more similar across nearby countries than across distant countries) and because not controlling for relevant attributes that are spatially autocorrelated can lead to spurious spill-over effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Arbia 1989)</ref>, studies of intercountry contagion should control not only for economic variables, but also for Marketing Science 23(4), pp. 530-544, © 2004 INFORMS national culture. Failure to do so might lead to spurious evidence of contagion and misleading policy recommendations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3.">Limitations and Recommended Research</head><p>We did not assess the role of heterogeneity in general but the narrower-and refutable-claim of income heterogeneity as a driver of diffusion under both the threshold model and G/SG structures. Similarly, we did not test the role of contagion in general but the narrower claim that culture and competing standards affect the q/p ratio under the contagion interpretation of the Bass model. Future research might seek to empirically assess the roles of heterogeneity and contagion using different substantive theories than those we used.</p><p>We used cross-cultural variation in diffusion model parameters to infer different contagion mechanisms. Sharper identification of different mechanisms could be obtained from investigating individuals' adoptions using duration models that incorporate direct measures of their risk aversion, status concerns, and susceptibility to normative influence.</p><p>Our meta-analysis could also be complemented by primary studies explicitly designed to assess income heterogeneity arguments. Specifically, we did not use information on the path of price declines when testing the heterogeneity-in-thresholds argument. An alternative research strategy would be to build a database of diffusion time series and price level time series for multiple products, estimate the shape of the income distribution, formulate the expected diffusion curve for each product as a function of prices and the income distribution, and assess how well this performs compared to standard diffusion models assuming contagion. As to the G/SG model, our operationalization of the scale parameter assumes that the Gini mean difference is a good approximation of the coefficient of variation. This might not be true for countries with very skewed income distributions. Also, the q/p estimates we analyzed were obtained from the Bass model where is forced to equal 1. Both assumptions introduced some error in our operationalization of , very probably rendering our test of the G/SG model conservative. Future research that estimates freely might find more supportive evidence for the G/SG model. Moreover, it will allow one to relate not only the scale parameter , but also the shape parameter to income inequality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4.">Conclusion</head><p>Our study provides three findings that raise questions about the importance and nature of social contagion. First, diffusion curves of consumer durables partly reflect the shape of the income distribution, so contagion need not be as important as commonly held.</p><p>Second, several methodological choices affect the estimated q/p ratio, further increasing the risk of spurious evidence of contagion. Third, the cross-cultural patterns point to contagion based on social-normative and status considerations rather than to social learning under uncertainty. Discriminating among these different mechanisms might allow one to more directly capture contagion in future research, which should help to address the skepticism raised by the first two findings. the cumulative G/SG data led to very good fits with all R 2 s in excess of 0.99. More importantly, whileq was somewhat biased upward, theq/p ratio did not diverge very much-certainly compared with random estimation error and previously documented biases-from the true value of in the data-generating process (Table <ref type="table">A</ref>.1). We also fit a discrete-time Bass model that does not use any information (or assumption) about the launch time to the noncumulative G/SG data. This also resulted in very good model fit, with all R 2 's in excess of 0.89. The estimated q/p ratios were very close to the true values. The better recovery of in the discrete-time operationalization might occur because that operationalization does not require making any assumption about the (unknown) true launch time.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Gamma Threshold Distributions with High and Low Gini Coefficient</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2Corresponding Diffusion Curves, Assuming p t = 45 e −0 1t</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>den Bulte and Stremersch: Social Contagion and Income Heterogeneity in New Product Diffusion</figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science 23(4), pp. 530-544, © 2004 INFORMS</cell><cell>531</cell></row><row><cell>strong enough</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Van den Bulte and Stremersch: Social Contagion and Income Heterogeneity in New Product Diffusion</figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science 23(4), pp. 530-544, © 2004 INFORMS</cell><cell>533</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Descriptive Statistics of Variables of Substantive Interest</figDesc><table><row><cell>Correlations</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Effects of Culture, Heterogeneity, and Competing Standards on ln q/p</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Model 1: National culture a</cell><cell cols="2">Model 2: Income heterogeneity b</cell><cell cols="2">Model 3: Full model c</cell></row><row><cell>Independent variables</cell><cell></cell><cell>t</cell><cell></cell><cell>t</cell><cell></cell><cell>t</cell></row><row><cell>Intercept</cell><cell>4 401  *  *  *</cell><cell>8 11</cell><cell>4 052  *  *  *</cell><cell>5 99</cell><cell>4 665  *  *  *</cell><cell>7 64</cell></row><row><cell>IDV</cell><cell>−0 101  *  *  *</cell><cell>−3 84</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>−0 109  *</cell><cell>−1 79</cell></row><row><cell>UAI</cell><cell>−0 023</cell><cell>−1 47</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>−0 137  *  *  *</cell><cell>−2 88</cell></row><row><cell>PDI</cell><cell>−0 008</cell><cell>−0 28</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0 100  *  *</cell><cell>2 00</cell></row><row><cell>MAS</cell><cell>0 233  *  *  *</cell><cell>4 38</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0 277  *  *  *</cell><cell>5 35</cell></row><row><cell>LNGINI</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>2 707  *  *</cell><cell>2 29</cell><cell>12 593  *  *  *</cell><cell>3 90</cell></row><row><cell>LNSCALE</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1 793  *  *  *</cell><cell>6 97</cell><cell>−1 667</cell><cell>−1 04</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Table A.1 Estimating a Bass Model to Left-Censored G/SG Data with &gt; 1 Does Not Affect the Estimated q/p Ratio Much</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Percentage</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">pqq/p</cell><cell>error</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Cumulative data, continuous-time model</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>2.5</cell><cell>0.0289</cell><cell>0.4323</cell><cell>14.98</cell><cell>+18%</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell>0.0269</cell><cell>0.4669</cell><cell>17.35</cell><cell>+37%</cell></row><row><cell>10</cell><cell>0.0284</cell><cell>0.4809</cell><cell>16.91</cell><cell>+33%</cell></row><row><cell>20</cell><cell>0.0325</cell><cell>0.4806</cell><cell>14.77</cell><cell>+17%</cell></row><row><cell>40</cell><cell>0.0388</cell><cell>0.4718</cell><cell>12.17</cell><cell>−4%</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Noncumulative data, discrete-time model</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>2.5</cell><cell>0.0297</cell><cell>0.4192</cell><cell>14.12</cell><cell>+11%</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell>0.0335</cell><cell>0.4385</cell><cell>13.09</cell><cell>+3%</cell></row><row><cell>10</cell><cell>0.0369</cell><cell>0.4464</cell><cell>12.09</cell><cell>−5%</cell></row><row><cell>20</cell><cell>0.0402</cell><cell>0.4471</cell><cell>11.12</cell><cell>−12%</cell></row><row><cell>40</cell><cell>0.0436</cell><cell>0.4441</cell><cell>10.18</cell><cell>−20%</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">Changes in the utility might be a function of previous adoptions. Hence, while contagion and threshold heterogeneity are alternative explanations, they are not mutually exclusive (e.g.,<ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Chatterjee and Eliashberg 1990</ref>).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">We also used a specification with random effects at the level of the individual product-country combination. BIC comparisons indicated this specification to be inferior to one with crossed random effects for product and country.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">* p ≤ 0 10; * * p ≤ 0 05, * * * p ≤ 0 01. a Coefficients with random effects across countries are ESTOLS (Var U = 1 32), ESTOTH (2.60), and CELLTEL (1.23). Coefficients with random effects across products are MAS (0.01), STARTC (0.01), NONADOP (0.74), WINDOW10 (0.91), and PROPCEILING (0.85).b Coefficients with random effects across countries are ESTOTH (Var U = 2 49) and CELLTEL (1.42). Coefficients with random effects across products are the intercept (6.57), STARTC (0.02), WINDOW10 (1.42), and PROPCEILING (1.07).c Coefficients with random effects across countries are ESTOTH (Var U = 2 56) and CELLTEL (1.44). Coefficients with random effects across products are MAS (0.01), STARTC (0.02), NONADOP (0.79), WINDOW10 (1.01), and PROPCEILING (0.90).d Because the residual likelihood function corrects for the number of fixed effects ( coefficients), one cannot compare the likelihoods of models with different explanatory variables, even if nested.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">The negative effect of UAI on q/p might be an artifact operating via the set of potential adopters. In highly uncertainty-avoidant countries, many consumers might prefer to avoid innovations altogether. As a result, the set of potential adopters consists primarily of very innovative consumers, resulting in a low q/p. This explanation is consistent with the finding that uncertainty-avoidant cultures use fewer insurance products, presumably because consumers prefer to avoid thinking about uncertainty altogether (de Mooij 1998).</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We benefitted from comments by Albert Bemmaor, Peter Danaher, Jehoshua Eliashberg, Peter Fader, Philip Hans Franses, Gary Lilien, Kay Peters, Gerard Tellis, audience members at the 2003 INFORMS Annual Meeting, and three reviewers. We also benefitted from discussions with Albert Bemmaor at an early stage of this study and from the assistance of Ritesh Saini in collecting the data.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix</head><p>When &gt; 1, Bemmaor's G/SG model is not identical to the Bass model, and need not exactly equal q/p. This is likely to happen when the distribution of the adoption propensity reflects the income distribution, because in most countries household and personal income is well described using a Gamma or inverse Gamma distribution with &gt; 1. In our dataset, the Gini coefficients range from 0.314 and 0.615. Assuming for computational convenience a Gamma income distribution, the corresponding values range from 2.97 to 0.56. The mean Gini is 0.34, implying a Gamma income distribution with = 2 5. Only 9 out of 293 observations have a Gini larger than 50%, implying an income distribution with &lt; 1. This raises the following question: Is theq/p ratio a useful estimate of whenq andp are obtained from a standard Bass model but the true data-generating process is G/SG with &gt; 1? Given the prevalence of left censoring in diffusion studies, the answer is yes. Because allowing for values of greater than 1 shifts the G/SG diffusion curve toward the right on the time axis without affecting the curve's shape very much <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Bemmaor and Lee 2002)</ref>, and because most studies using the Bass model do not use the actual launch time but the start of the available data series to set the year at which t = 0 (Parker 1994), assuming = 1 even when &gt; 1 does not affect the estimated q/p ratio much. We illustrate this with a small numerical exercise.</p><p>We simulated six data series of the G/SG model, all with p = 0 03 and q = 0 38 <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Sultan et al. 1990)</ref>, and hence b = 0 41 and = 12 667, but with = 1 2 5 5 10 20, and 40, respectively. Plots confirmed that increasing shifts the G/SG diffusion curve toward the right on the time axis but barely affects the curve's shape. We subsequently estimated a standard Bass model (i.e., with = 1) to the data series with &gt; 1 using nonlinear least squares. To reflect common practice in empirical diffusion studies using the Bass model, we treated the first period where sizable penetration is observed as the launch time. As a cut-off, we used 1.5% penetration. We fit two different operationalizations of the Bass model. Fitting a continuous-time Bass c.d.f. to</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The market evolution and sales takeoff of product innovations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barry</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Rajshree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bayus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1024" to="1041" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Spatial Data Configuration in Statistical Analysis of Regional Economic and Related Problems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Arbia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Dordrecht, The Netherlands</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new product growth model for consumer durables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Frank</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="227" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">For a Critique of the Political Economy of the Sign</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jean</forename><surname>Baudrillard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
			<publisher>Telos Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>St. Louis, MO</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Have diffusion rates been accelerating over time?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barry</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bayus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="226" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling the diffusion of new durable goods: Word-of-mouth effect versus consumer heterogeneity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Albert</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Bemmaor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Research Traditions in Marketing</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gilles</forename><surname>Laurent</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gary</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lilien</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bernard</forename><surname>Pras</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="223" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of heterogeneity and ill-conditioning on diffusion model parameter estimates</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Albert</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Bemmaor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yanghyuk</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="220" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Inequality and Heterogeneity: A Primitive Theory of Social Structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Blau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
			<publisher>Free Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A meta-analysis of studies using Asch&apos;s (1952b, 1956) line judgment task</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rod</forename><surname>Bond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psych. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">119</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="137" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quasi-Engel curves, diffusion, and the ownership of major consumer durables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Holger</forename><surname>Bonus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="655" to="677" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Distinction: A Social Critique of the Judgment of Taste</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Bourdieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social contagion and innovation: Cohesion versus structural equivalence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ronald</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Burt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. J. Sociology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1287" to="1335" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The innovation diffusion process in a heterogeneous population: A micromodeling approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rabikar</forename><surname>Chatterjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jehoshua</forename><surname>Eliashberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1057" to="1079" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Herd behavior, the &quot;penguin effect,&quot; and the suppression of informational diffusion: An analysis of informational externalities and payoff interdependency</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jay</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Pil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rand J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="407" to="425" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Davies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The Diffusion of Process Innovations</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, U.K</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new data set measuring income inequality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Klaus</forename><surname>Deininger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lyn</forename><surname>Squire</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">World Bank Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="565" to="591" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Staged estimation of international diffusion models: An application to global cellular telephone adoption</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marnik</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Dekimpe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Philip</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Miklos</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sarvary</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Tech. Forecasting Soc. Change</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="132" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Global Marketing and Advertising: Understanding Cultural Paradoxes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>De Mooij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Marieke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<pubPlace>Sage, Thousand Oaks, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Consumer response to innovation: Television</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas F ;</forename><surname>Dernburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Dernburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Harold</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Rosett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Watts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1958" />
			<publisher>Yale University Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="49" />
			<pubPlace>New Haven, CT</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Studies in Household Economic Behavior</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The World of Goods</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mary</forename><surname>Douglas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Baron</forename><surname>Isherwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
			<publisher>Basic Books</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Income, Saving and the Theory of Consumer Behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Duesenberry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1949" />
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Demand and supply dynamics to sequentially released products in international markets: The case of motion pictures</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anita</forename><surname>Elberse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jehoshua</forename><surname>Eliashberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="329" to="354" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Integration of consumer diffusion theory and diffusion models: New research directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gatignon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Hubert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Innovation Diffusion Models of New Product Acceptance</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vijay</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yoram</forename><surname>Wind</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Ballinger, Cambridge, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="59" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling multinational diffusion patterns: An efficient methodology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hubert</forename><surname>Gatignon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jehoshua</forename><surname>Eliashberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="247" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A meta-analysis of satisfaction in marketing channel relationships</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Inge</forename><surname>Geyskens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jan</forename><forename type="middle">-</forename><surname>Benedict</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Steenkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nirmalya</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="238" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond diffusion: An affordability model of the growth of new consumer durables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Golder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gerard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Tellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Forecasting</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="280" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hybrid corn: An exploration in the economics of technological change</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zvi</forename><surname>Griliches</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="501" to="522" />
			<date type="published" when="1957" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Culture&apos;s Consequences: Comparing Values, Behaviors, Institutions and Organizations Across Nations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Geert</forename><surname>Hofstede</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page">225</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>Thousand Oaks, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed. Sage</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A diffusion model incorporating product benefits, price, income and information</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Horsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="342" to="365" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Regional Frequency Analysis: An Approach Based on L-Moments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R M</forename><surname>Hosking</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wallis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, U.K</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cultural influences on new product acceptance in global markets. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dipak</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Jain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Suvit Maesincee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<pubPlace>Evanston, IL</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Northwestern University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Norman</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Samuel Kotz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Balakrishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Continuous Univariate Distributions</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="530" to="544" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new product adoption model with price, advertising, and uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shlomo</forename><surname>Kalish</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1569" to="1585" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Waterfall and sprinkler new-product strategies in competitive global markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shlomo</forename><surname>Kalish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vijay</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Res. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="119" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Systems competition and network effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carl</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Perspectives</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="115" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient estimation of income distribution parameters</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kloek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Herman</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Teun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Van Dijk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multinational diffusion models: An alternative framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Trichy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Krishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="318" to="330" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Money, Morals, and Manners: The Culture of the French and the American Upper-Middle Class</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michèle</forename><surname>Lamont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>University of Chicago Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Chicago, IL</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diffusion models: Managerial applications and software</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gary</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lilien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arvind</forename><surname>Rangaswamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">New-Product Diffusion Models</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vijay</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jerry</forename><surname>Wind</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="295" to="336" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Christophe Van den Bulte</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Innovation Diffusion Models of New Product Acceptance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vijay</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yoram</forename><surname>Wind</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<pubPlace>Ballinger, Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">New-Product Diffusion Models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vijay</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jerry</forename><surname>Wind</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Boston, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Some generalized functions for the size distribution of income</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="647" to="663" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Meta-analytic synthesis for theory development</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vicki</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Norman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Pollock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>Harris Cooper, Larry V. Hedges</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<publisher>Russell Sage Foundation</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="457" to="483" />
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Handbook of Research Synthesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Classical and Modern Regression with Applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<pubPlace>Boston, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed. PWS-KENT</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Yet another look at temporal aggregation in diffusion models of first-time purchase</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marielle</forename><surname>Non</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Hans Franses</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Claudia</forename><surname>Laheij</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Tech. Forecasting Soc. Change</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="467" to="471" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Tijs Rokers</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aggregate diffusion forecasting models in marketing: A critical review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Philip</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Forecasting</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="353" to="380" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">National Cultures of the World: A Statistical Reference</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Philip</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>Greenwood Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Westport, CT</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Price elasticity dynamics over the product life cycle: A study of consumer durables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Philip</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ramya</forename><surname>Neelamegham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="205" to="216" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parameter variation and new product diffusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Putsis</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Forecasting</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="257" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimation techniques for macro diffusion models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Putsis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Jr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">New-Product Diffusion Models</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vijay</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jerry</forename><surname>Wind</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="291" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mixing behavior in cross-country diffusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Putsis</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sridhar</forename><surname>Balasubramaniam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Edward</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kaplan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Subrata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="354" to="369" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of culture and socioeconomics on the performance of global brand image strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="175" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comments on &quot;The relationship between diffusion rates, experience curves, and demand elasticities for consumer durable technological innovations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="S69" to="S73" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Georg</forename><surname>Simmel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Georg Simmel on Individuality and Social Forms</title>
		<editor>Fashion. Donald N. Levine</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="294" to="323" />
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
			<publisher>University of Chicago Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hofstede&apos;s consequences: A study of reviews, citations and replications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mikael</forename><surname>Søndergaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organ. Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="447" to="456" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A cross-national investigation into the individual and national cultural antecedents of consumer innovativeness</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jan</forename><forename type="middle">-</forename><surname>Steenkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Benedict</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Frenkel Ter Hofstede</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="69" />
			<date type="published" when="1999-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Economics of Technological Diffusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Stoneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<publisher>Blackwell</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Oxford, U.K</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A metaanalysis of diffusion models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sultan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Fareena</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Donald</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Farley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="70" to="77" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Penn World Table (Mark 5): An expanded set of international comparisons, 1950-1988. Quart</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Summers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Heston</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="327" to="368" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling cross-country diffusion of wireless communications: The effect of country characteristics, cultural similarity and adoption timing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sanna</forename><surname>Sundqvist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lauri</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kaisu</forename><surname>Puumalainen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Res. Forthcoming</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinguishing between contagion, heterogeneity, and randomness in stochastic models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mitchell</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Taibleson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Sociological Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="877" to="880" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Investigating new product diffusion across products and countries. Marketing Sci</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Debabrata</forename><surname>Talukdar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sudhir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Ainslie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="114" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Laws of Imitation. Henry Holt and Company</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gabriel</forename><surname>Tarde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1903" />
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The international takeoff of new products: The role of economics, culture and country innovativeness</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gerard</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Stremersch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eden</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="188" to="208" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New product diffusion acceleration: measurement and analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christophe</forename><surname>Van Den Bulte</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="366" to="380" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bias and systematic change in the parameter estimates of macro-level diffusion models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Van Den Bulte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gary</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Christophe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lilien</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="338" to="353" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Medical Innovation revisited: Social contagion versus marketing effort</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Van Den Bulte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gary</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Christophe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lilien</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. J. Sociology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1409" to="1435" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">New-Product Forecasting: Models and Applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yoram</forename><surname>Wind</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vijay</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Cardozo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
			<pubPlace>Lexington Books, Lexington, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cultural influences on the diffusion of new products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Idil</forename><surname>Yaveroglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Naveen</forename><surname>Sayrac</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Donthu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Internat. Consumer Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="63" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
