<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Costs and Benefits of Inducing Intrabrand Competition: The Role of Limited Liability</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Ramarao</forename><surname>Desiraju</surname></persName>
							<email>rdesiraju@bus.ucf.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Marketing</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">College of Business Administration</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Central Florida</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>P.O. Box 161400</postBox>
									<postCode>32816</postCode>
									<settlement>Orlando</settlement>
									<region>Florida</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Marketing</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">College of Business Administration</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Central Florida</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>P.O. Box 161400</postBox>
									<postCode>32816</postCode>
									<settlement>Orlando</settlement>
									<region>Florida</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Costs and Benefits of Inducing Intrabrand Competition: The Role of Limited Liability</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 04 2303 0429</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1040.0049</idno>
					<note type="submission">This paper was received March 31, 2002, and was with the author 9 months for 3 revisions; processed by Arvind Rangaswamy.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:25+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>channels of distribution</term>
					<term>agency theory</term>
					<term>intrabrand competition</term>
					<term>free-riding</term>
					<term>limited liability</term>
					<term>vertical contractual restrictions</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Whether or not to assign exclusive territories has been a longstanding question in the literature. While extant research (see e.g., <ref type="bibr">Stiglitz 1995, Mathewson and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Winter 1984)</ref> provides useful insights on this choice, other important dimensions of the problem remain unexplored. This analysis examines a tradeoff associated with intrabrand competition and highlights the impact of distributors' limited liability on a manufacturer's decision to use exclusive territories.</p><p>More specifically, this paper develops a mathematical model to examine two scenarios. In the first, the manufacturer uses exclusive territories and protects its distributors from intrabrand competition. In the second, the distributors compete against each other to sell the manufacturer's product. The analysis compares these two scenarios and illustrates how the manufacturer's profit is affected by the limits on the distributors' liability.</p><p>Explicit limits on liability (or limited liability clauses) are a common feature in business contracts. A principal reason these clauses arise is due to equity considerations that mandate the guarantee of an appropriate level of well-being for all parties involved in the contract <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Sappington 1983</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">, Barton 1972</ref>. These limits on liability can take the form of bankruptcy clauses, statements outlining the conditions under which breach of contract is permissible, and other clauses involving product returns or cash compensation <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Miller and Jentz 2000)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> In distribution channels, limited liability issues are likely to arise when demand is uncertain and distributors can experience significant losses under adverse demand conditions. To understand this, consider a typical characterization of the interaction between a manufacturer and its distributor: to eliminate all incentive problems, the manufacturer can sell to the distributor at cost and extract the surplus via a fixed fee. (In expectation, the profit balances out the loss. Another way to eliminate incentive problems would be to design a suitable quantity discount schedule to coordinate the distributor's actions <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Jeuland and Shugan 1983)</ref>.) The fixed fee will extract the expected surplus, and when demand is uncertain, the distributor will have a loss when demand is "low," but a strictly positive profit when demand is "high."</p><p>Limits on the distributor's liability, however, restrict how much loss the distributor can bear, and therefore all of the surplus cannot be extracted via the fixed Desiraju: Costs and Benefits of Inducing Intrabrand Competition 430 Marketing Science 23(3), pp. <ref type="bibr">429-450, © 2004 INFORMS</ref> fee. Consequently, to increase revenues, the manufacturer will tend to raise the wholesale price above cost. The higher wholesale price will distort the distributor's price from the requisite levels (due to the standard double-marginalization problem). Moreover, since effort is costly and demand is uncertain, the distributor has an opportunity to shirk its efforts to sell the manufacturer's product. These considerations are particularly relevant in the context of assigning exclusive territories.</p><p>In assigning exclusive territories, conventional wisdom suggests evaluating the costs of intrabrand competition. Practitioners indicate that exclusive territories often serve as an inducement to the selected distributors to put forth the requisite marketing effort, 2 including investments in demonstration equipment and hiring a technical expert. Admittedly, in the absence of exclusive territories, some of these efforts can help generate buyers who may subsequently purchase from a competing distributor selling the same manufacturer's products in that territory.</p><p>In other words, a distributor's investments can be jeopardized by the presence of intrabrand competition, especially in the early stages of market development, when returns are uncertain. Therefore, a positive linkage between the marketing investments of one distributor and the sales of a competing distributor can encourage free-riding 3 and decrease a distributor's incentive to invest in the manufacturer's products. In the presence of such positive linkages, even some academic research supports the imposition of exclusive territories (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Mathewson and Winter 1984)</ref>.</p><p>In contrast, other research suggests that intrabrand competition can motivate distributors to expend the requisite marketing efforts on the manufacturer's behalf. First, tournament theory (see e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Green and</ref><ref type="bibr">Stokey 1983, Kalra and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Shi 2001)</ref> argues that, in a principal-agent context, competition induces agents to work harder. Similarly, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Nalebuff and Stiglitz (1983)</ref> indicate that in oligopolistic industries, competition can make firms raise their efforts to sell the products. The main tenet in these streams of work is that, in the presence of a "common" uncertainty, linking rewards to relative performance reduces the agents' incentive to shirk. Extending these arguments to the present context suggests that, compared to an exclusive territories setting, when two distributors compete to sell the same product, each may have to work harder to obtain and retain customers.</p><p>Overall, in its choice of distribution method, the manufacturer balances the costs arising from freeriding with the benefits of intrabrand competition. This paper argues that as the potential loss borne by the distributor is reduced (i.e., limits on liability become tighter), there will be greater opportunity for distributors in exclusive territories to shirk (because intrabrand competition is not present to discipline their incentives). Consequently, the manufacturer may prefer to use nonexclusive territories; this preference will hold even when distributors can potentially freeride on each other's efforts.</p><p>This paper refines the above intuition by analyzing a model for each type of territorial (exclusive or nonexclusive) arrangement. The analysis demonstrates that the moderating influence of limited liability becomes increasingly apparent as the magnitude of the distributor's liability is progressively reduced.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relevant Literature</head><p>There is related literature in both marketing and economics that bears on this paper's model development and analysis. In marketing, the research on channel coordination, particularly <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Jeuland and Shugan (1983)</ref>  <ref type="bibr">4</ref> and Iyer (1998) are relevant. Jeuland and Shugan propose quantity discounts as a mechanism to coordinate the channel. In his analysis of channel coordination under different types of consumer heterogeneity, Iyer notes that nonlinear pricing may not be sufficient to coordinate the channel when distributors compete on both price and service. In contrast, this paper considers settings where distributors do and do not compete against each other, and where the distributor's surplus cannot be extracted completely. The manufacturer's inability to extract distributors' surplus is captured via the limited liability constraints. In this manner, the present analysis complements the contributions of the existing research. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Next, in economics, there are two streams of research on exclusive distribution. First is the literature on vertical restraints that deals with settings in which all the relevant information is known to all the channel members (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Blair and</ref><ref type="bibr">Kaserman 1985, Mathewson and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Winter 1984)</ref>. In contrast to that, there is the literature that explicitly acknowledges the difficulties of monitoring and observing distributors' actions <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Stiglitz 1995, Rey and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Tirole 1986)</ref>.</p><p>Similar to the latter stream of research, here the analysis takes into account that distributors' actions cannot be observed. Further, in the nonexclusive distribution model, a distributor's demand is positively affected by the effort of a competing distributor. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>431</head><p>Examining the impact of this linkage serves as the primary distinction between the analysis presented here and those of <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Rey and Stiglitz (1995)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Rey and Tirole (1986)</ref>. More specifically, they examine other tradeoffs (e.g., Rey and Tirole 1986 consider costs and benefits of risk sharing versus the effective use of decentralized information) and do not model distributors' effort explicitly.</p><p>The rest of the paper is organized as follows. Section 2 develops the basic model and analyzes the exclusive and nonexclusive distribution versions of that model. The implications of the analysis are highlighted with the help of a numerical example in §3, and the paper concludes in §4. All proofs are available in the technical appendix posted on this journal's website.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">The Model</head><p>A risk-neutral manufacturer, M, sells its product through two distributors, A and B. The sales Q A Q B ∈ R + of the manufacturer's product are random and the focus is on a simple case in which each of Q A and Q B takes one of two values:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">0 ≤ q i L &lt; q i H , i = A B. g i • , i = A B, is used to represent the prob- ability that q i</formula><p>H is realized, and g A • and g B • are parameterized by the prices p A p B ∈ R + charged to customers by the two distributors and the levels of marketing effort e A e B ∈ R + put forth by the distributors. The following notation is used to denote expected sales:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">q i • = q i L + g i • q i H − q i L ∀i = A B (1)</formula><p>Both the manufacturer and the distributors observe the realized sales of the distributors in the market, but the effort supplied by each distributor is observable only to that one distributor. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> It is assumed that all the parties observe prices charged to final customers, and that the density functions, g A • and g B • , are common knowledge.</p><p>The sequence of events in the model is as follows: (1) Manufacturer announces its wholesale price and fixed fees. (2) Based on the manufacturer's announcement, the distributors decide independently whether to work for the manufacturer. If a distributor does not agree to participate, the manufacturer makes zero profit through that distributor, and that distributor makes its reservation level of profit, 0 , from other sources. (3) If the distributors agree to participate, then each distributor chooses final price and effort levels simultaneously and noncollusively. Sales are then realized (as characterized by the density functions) and profits are made. The manufacturer's expected profit, M , is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">M = w − c q A + q B + F A + F B (<label>2</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_3">)</formula><p>where c is the manufacturer's variable cost of production, w the manufacturer's common wholesale price to the distributors, 7 and F i is a fixed fee paid to the manufacturer by distributor i. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> Both distributors are assumed to be risk neutral, and their individual expected profit, i , i = A B, is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">i = p i − w q i − F i − C i e i (3)</formula><p>where C i • is the cost of effort to the ith distributor, with C i • / e i &gt; 0 and 2 C i • / e i 2 &gt; 0, ∀e i &gt; 0 and p i is distributor i's price in the final market. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref> summarizes all the notation employed in the paper. Under either form of distribution, the manufacturer's objective is to maximize its profit with respect to the wholesale price and fixed fees, subject to the constraints that each of the distributors participates and selects prices and efforts to maximize individual profit and that there is an upper bound on the level Marketing Science 23(3), pp. 429-450, © 2004 INFORMS of fixed fee (due to limited liability). These constraints are stated below: For a given w F i that M sets, distributor i will participate if its expected profit exceeds the reservation profit level. Formally,</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">i ≥ 0 ⇔ p i − w q i − F i − C i e i ≥ 0 (4)</formula><p>Next, using F 0 to denote the upper bound on the fixed fee, limited liability requires</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">F i ≤ F 0 ≡ −F i ≥ −F 0 (5)</formula><p>Finally, when participating in the w F i contract with the manufacturer, distributor i selects price, p i w F i , and effort, e i w F i , to maximize its profit:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">e i w F i p i w F i ∈ Arg max e i p i i e i p i (6)</formula><p>The analysis uses the following first-order conditions to capture distributor i's (above) choices of price and effort: 9</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">i e i = 0 ≡ p i − w q i e i − C i e i = 0<label>(7)</label></formula><p>and</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">i p i = 0 ≡ q i + p i − w q i p i = 0 (8)</formula><p>To facilitate employing the above first-order conditions, i is assumed to be concave in p i and e i , i = A B. Notice that concavity implies the following (e g , see <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Takayama 1985)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">2 i p i 2 &lt; 0 2 i e i 2 &lt; 0 (9)</formula><p>and,</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">2 i p i 2 2 i e i 2 − 2 i e i p i 2 &gt; 0<label>(10)</label></formula><p>Using (3), we note the following:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">2 i p i 2 = 2 q i p i + p i − w 2 q i p i 2 (11) 2 i e i 2 = p i − w 2 q i e i 2 − 2 C i e i 2 (<label>12</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_13">)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_14">and 2 i e i p i = q i e i + p i − w 2 q i e i p i (13)</formula><p>The expressions on the right-hand side of (11), (12), and ( <ref type="formula">13</ref>) are therefore assumed to satisfy the conditions in ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) and (10). To ensure this, under either form of distribution, it is assumed that the following relatively standard conditions hold: ∀i = A B, g i e i &gt; 0 2 g i e i 2 ≤ 0 g i p i &lt; 0 and 2 g i p i 2 ≥ 0 (14) Further, for expositional convenience, the crosspartials of the density functions are all set equal to zero; that is, 10 2 g i e i p i = 2 g i e i p j = 2 g i e i e j = 2 g i p i p j = 2 g i p i e j = 0 Note that (13) now reduces to</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">2 i e i p i = q i e i (<label>15</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_16">)</formula><p>The spotlight here is on either a new product entering a market or a relatively established product entering a new market. In either case, distributors' efforts will have a critical role in category expansion. In such instances, one distributor's efforts are likely to have a positive effect on the expected sales of the competing nonexclusive distributor. It is this feature of the setting that facilitates free-riding. Note that prices continue to play the same role as in standard analyses: If a distributor raises the price of an item, its expected demand goes down while the other nonexclusive distributor's expected demand goes up.</p><p>The above considerations are captured in the following additional assumptions on the density functions, g i • . <ref type="bibr">11</ref> To capture free-riding, in the nonexclusive distribution setting it is assumed that g i / e j &gt; 0; under exclusive distribution, it is assumed that g i / e j = 0, where i = j and i j = A B. Similarly, for nonexclusive distribution it is assumed g i / p j &gt; 0, and g i / p j = 0 for exclusive distribution. 12 10 In a previous version of the manuscript, the analysis explicitly accounted for the role of the derivative 2 g i / e j e i ; while the main insights in this paper are not hinged on it, including that interaction term adds some expositional complexity. Investigating and discussing the impact of the various cross-partials in a comprehensive manner is beyond the scope of the current paper. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> It is worth noting that the density functions satisfy both the monotone likelihood ratio condition (MLRC) and convexity of the distribution function condition (CDFC) specified in <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Rogerson (1985)</ref> (see the appendix for a formal proof). For additional sufficient conditions that ensure (9) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_11">10</ref>) hold, see the example in §3. There, 2 q i / p i 2 = 2 q i / e i 2 = 0, and ( <ref type="formula">9</ref>) is automatically satisfied while (10) reduces to −2</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">q i p i 2 C i e i 2 − q i e i 2 &gt; 0 (16)</formula><p>For the selected parameter values in that example, ( <ref type="formula">16</ref>) is indeed satisfied.</p><p>In the above model setup, there are several factors that can potentially impact any difference in the manufacturer's solutions to the two forms of distribution (e g , is it because distributors are choosing both prices and efforts or is it due to the binding limited liability constraints? etc.). Therefore, to understand what is driving any difference in the results, the analysis considers various combinations of territorial exclusivity and the level of manufacturer's control over distributors' actions.</p><p>More specifically, six separate scenarios are examined for each form of distribution. The first three of these scenarios assume that the manufacturer controls the distributors' final prices and in the latter three scenarios this assumption is relaxed. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> Under either assumption, the three scenarios correspond to (i) distributors' efforts are observable, 14 (ii) efforts are unobservable but limited liability constraints are not binding, and (iii) efforts are unobservable and limited liability constraints are binding.</p><p>Under each form of distribution, the solution to the scenario where M controls final prices and where efforts are observable is referred to as the first-best solution. This solution serves as a benchmark to understand how the manufacturer's profit is affected as the distributors obtain more control over final prices and efforts. The technical appendix systematically analyzes the above 12 scenarios; Table <ref type="table">2</ref> highlights the specific constraints examined along with the primary finding (i e , whether or not the first-best solution can be regained) from each analysis. In the main body of the paper, the focus is on the most complex scenario for each form of distribution.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Exclusive Distribution</head><formula xml:id="formula_18">A formal statement of the manufacturer's problem, denoted M − E , is Maximize w F e p M subject to i e i w F i p i w F i ≥ 0 ∀i = A B IR − i e i w F i p i w F i ∈ Arg max e i p i i e i p i ∀w F i ∈ R + i = A B EP − i and −F i ≥ −F 0 i = A B LL − i</formula><p>where IR − i refers to distributor i's participation constraint-see Equation ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>), EP − i to the manner in which each distributor selects effort and price  <ref type="formula" target="#formula_8">7</ref>) and (8), and LL − i to the limited liability constraints-see Equation (5). In solving this nonlinear programming problem, several Lagrange multipliers are employed: i represents the multiplier for distributor i's participation constraint, ie and ip for i's effort and price selection constraints respectively, and i for the limited liability constraint. See Table <ref type="table">3</ref> for the Lagrangian.</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">− i FB solution regained Effort selection E − i 3 Exclusive Participation IR − i FB solution not regained Effort selection E − i Effort less than Limited Liability LL − i first-best level 4 Exclusive Participation IR − i FB solution regained Price selection P − i 5 Exclusive Participation IR − i FB solution regained Price selection EP − i Effort selection EP − i 6 Exclusive Participation IR − i FB solution not regained Price selection EP − i (see Finding 1 in the text) Effort selection EP − i Limited Liability LL − i 7 Nonexclusive Participation IR − i FB (nonexclusive) solution 8 Nonexclusive Participation IR − i FB solution regained Effort selection E − i 9 Nonexclusive Participation IR − i FB solution not regained Effort selection E − i Effort less than Limited Liability LL − i first-best level 10 Nonexclusive Participation IR − i FB solution regained Price selection P − i 11 Nonexclusive Participation IR − i FB solution not regained Price selection EP − i Effort selection EP − i 12 Nonexclusive Participation IR − i FB solution not regained Price selection EP − i (see Finding 2 in the text) Effort selection EP − i Limited Liability LL − i levels-see Equations (</formula><p>Table <ref type="table">3</ref> The Lagrangian</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">L = w − c q A + q B + F A + F B + A p A − w q A − F A − C A e A + B p B − w q B − F B − C B e B + Ae p A − w q A e A − C A e A + Be p B − w q B e B − C B e B + Ap q A + p A − w q A p A + Bp q B + p B − w q B p B + A −F A + F 0 + B −F B + F 0 Note. (i)</formula><p>The demand structure for exclusive distribution is different from that for nonexclusive distribution, so the above Lagrangian gets suitably modified for the two forms of distribution. (ii) The s, ie , ip s, and s represent the Lagrange multipliers for the IR constraints, the EP (effort and price selection) constraints, and the limited liability constraints, respectively. Before considering the solution to M − E , it is worth noting the following benchmark solutions to M's problem: <ref type="bibr">15</ref> Benchmark 1. For all i = A B (a) When M controls final prices and distributors efforts are observable (i.e., constraints EP − i and LL − i do not hold), the optimal contract, referred to as the first-best solution, has the following properties:</p><p>(i) i = 0 (i.e., distributor profit is restricted to the reservation profit level)</p><p>(ii) p i − c q i / e i = C i / e i (i.e., marginal benefit of distributor effort equals its marginal cost to the channel) (iii) q i = − p i − c q i / p i (i.e., marginal benefit of final price equals its marginal cost to the channel) (b) When M does not control final prices and distributors' efforts are unobservable, but limited liability constraints are not binding (i.e., constraints EP − i hold but not LL − i ), the first-best solution is regained when M sets w = c and extracts all of distributor i's surplus via the fixed fee, F i . Now consider the properties of a solution to M −E that are summarized below.</p><p>Finding 1. For all i = A B, (a) In the presence of binding limited liability constraints, inefficiency exists in the distributors' choices of efforts and final prices. More formally, both ie and ip cannot equal zero, and the first-best solution (where both ie and ip equal zero) cannot be achieved. (b) At optimality, distributor i's choices of effort and price are given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">(i) p i − c q i e i − C i e i = − ie p i − w 2 q i e i 2 − 2 C i e i 2 − ip q i e i and (ii) q i + p i − c q i p i = − ie q i e i − ip 2 q i p i + p i − w 2 q i p i 2</formula><p>Proof. See the appendix. Benchmark 1 reiterates the standard result that when limited liability is not an issue, the manufacturer can eliminate any incentive problems by suitably designing w and F (i e , the double-marginalization problem is eliminated via the two-part tariff). However, when limited liability is relevant (for any of a variety of institutional reasons), M cannot extract as large an F as it would like. Then, Finding 1(a) indicates that there is inefficiency under exclusive territories (even with a two-part tariff). The exact nature of the inefficiency (in the choice of effort 16 ) depends on the endogenously determined expressions,</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">− ie p i − w 2 q i e i 2 − 2 C i e i 2</formula><p>(dubbed the slack effect for expositional convenience), and − ip q i / e i (the price effect), given in Finding 1(b). To provide further insight, §3 discusses an example in which ie &gt; 0 and ip &lt; 0 (i e , too little effort and too high prices), and the appendix shows an approach to develop sufficient conditions for unambiguously signing these multipliers.</p><p>In contrast to the exclusive distribution setup, under nonexclusive distribution, even in the absence of binding limited liability constraints, the first-best solution will not be obtained. For a formal discussion of this see <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Iyer (1998)</ref>. The main implication is that, when limited liability is not an issue, the manufacturer strictly prefers exclusive distribution over nonexclusive distribution. The preference is driven by the fact that there is no loss in efficiency with exclusive distributors. With binding limited liability constraints however, as Finding 1(a) reveals, there is inefficiency under exclusive territories.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Nonexclusive Distribution</head><formula xml:id="formula_23">A formal statement of the manufacturer's problem, M − NE , is Maximize w F e p M subject to i e i • p i • e j • p j • ≥ 0 ∀i = j i j = A B IR − i e i w F i F j p i w F i F j ∈ Arg max e i p i i e i p i e j w F i F j p j w F i F j ∀w F i F j ∈ R + i = j i j = A B EP − i and −F i ≥ −F 0 i = A B LL − i</formula><p>where the constraints (and the notation employed for the Lagrange multipliers) have the same meaning as in the exclusive distribution problem. The distributors here, though, simultaneously select prices and efforts as best responses to each other's actions.</p><p>As in the exclusive setting, it is worth noting the following benchmark solutions to M's problem: Benchmark 2. For all i = A B, (a) When M controls final prices and distributors' efforts are observable, the first-best (nonexclusive distribution) solution has the following properties: For i = j; i = A B, (i) i = 0 (i.e., distributor profit is restricted to the reservation profit level)</p><p>(ii) p i − c q i / e i + p j − c q j / e i − C i / e i = 0 (i.e., the marginal benefit of distributor effort equals its marginal cost to the channel) (iii) q i + p i − c q i / p i + p j − c q j / p i = 0 (i.e., the marginal benefit of final price equals its marginal cost to the channel) (b) When M does not control final prices and distributors' efforts are unobservable, but limited liability constraints are not binding, inefficiency exists in the distributors' choices of efforts and final prices. More formally, both ie and ip cannot equal zero and the first-best nonexclusive distribution solution (where both ie and ip equal zero) cannot be regained. </p><formula xml:id="formula_24">(i) p A − c q A e A + p B − c q B e A − C A e A = B p B − w − Bp q B e A − Ae p A − w 2 q A e A 2 − 2 C A e A 2 − Ap q A e A and (ii) q A + p A − c q A p A + p B − c q B p A = B p B − w − Bp q B p A − Ae q A e A − Ap 2 q A p A + p A − w 2 q A p A 2</formula><p>Proof. See the appendix.</p><p>Consistent with previous research, Benchmark 2(b) shows that under intrabrand competition, there is inefficiency in the channel. Finding 2(a) indicates that <ref type="bibr">17</ref> Analogous expressions arise for distributor B.</p><p>such inefficiency continues to exist even under binding limited liability constraints. Further, Finding 2(b) reveals that the distributor's choice of effort 18 is affected by (as in the solution to M − E ) the slack effect, (− Ae p A − w 2 q A / e A 2 − 2 C A / e A 2 ), and the price effect, − Ap q A / e A ; in addition, the free-rider effect, B p B − w − Bp q B / e A , arises from the positive interlinkage between the distributors' demand functions. Since these effects are determined endogenously, an example in the next section provides a better sense of their relative magnitude.</p><p>The main purpose of that example, though, is as follows. The analysis so far has revealed that either form of distribution has inefficiencies (in terms of the distributors' effort/price choices). Conventional wisdom and previous research, however, suggest that when firms can free-ride on each other's efforts, exclusive territories are the preferred form of distribution. However, such suggestions presume that distributors under exclusive territories automatically have appropriate incentives to work on the manufacturer's behalf. Therefore, the next section develops a simple but plausible example in which the manufacturer prefers nonexclusive (over exclusive) territories even when free-riding among distributors is possible.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">An Example</head><p>For the purposes of this example, the reservation level of profit and the manufacturer's marginal cost of production are each set equal to zero (i e , 0 = 0 and c = 0). Each distributor's cost of effort is given by C i e = e 2 /2, i = A B. It is also assumed that q i L = 0, and q i H = 100 000. Therefore, expected sales are now a product of g i • and q i H . Expected sales of each distributor are assumed to have the following structure:</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">q A = K − p A + e A + p B + e B (<label>17</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_26">)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_27">q B = K − p B + e B + p A + e A (<label>18</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_28">)</formula><p>When the distributors are exclusive, and are set equal to zero. Essentially, ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_25">17</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_27">18</ref>) represent the probabilities g A • and g B • , scaled up by q i H . <ref type="bibr">19</ref> The parameter values ensure that the linear structure in (17) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_27">18</ref>) does not result in probabilities outside the open interval 0 1 . This example assumes that both distributors are identical. The values for the parameters of the above functions have been chosen to imitate a real-world Marketing Science 23(3), pp. 429-450, © 2004 INFORMS setting, namely, the sales of different brands of beer in the United States in the 1980s. <ref type="bibr">20</ref> It is useful to recall that beer manufacturers frequently used exclusive wholesalers and were concerned about free-riding among wholesalers. Wholesale sales of beer in the year 1980 were of the order of hundreds of thousands of dollars, ranging from $35,000 in Alaska to $1,897,750 in California, with Florida at $885,500, and Delaware at $48,500. The wholesale price per case of beer was of the order of ones of dollars-in Indianapolis, the price per case of Pabst was about $6 in November 1982-where a case is either a six pack of 12-oz. cans or a four pack of 24-oz. cans. Given these data, 21 the following parameter values were assigned to obtain reasonable optimal prices and quantities. Note that the parameter values are in the order of 10 3 ; that is, a value of 50 would imply 50,000, and 0.001 represents 1. For expositional convenience, the zeros are suppressed and the reader is cautioned to make a note of the "actual" magnitude. However, prices are to be read at face value.</p><p>(a) For exclusive distribution, the parameter values are K = 50, = 7, and = 2.</p><p>(b) For nonexclusive distribution, the parameter values are: = 7, = 2, = 1, = 0 001, and K = 46 64.</p><p>Notice that the value of K in the nonexclusive case is different from that in the exclusive territories setting. This is due to an attempt to control for any differences in the industry-level (expected) demand across the two forms of distribution. The following normalization procedure was followed. The procedure begins by giving a specific value to the intercept for the exclusive setting (in this example, K = 50) and treating the intercept for the nonexclusive setting as an unknown value. To make the two settings equivalent, the optimal first-best solution is derived for both the exclusive and the nonexclusive cases. This solution involves optimal prices and effort levels. At those respective levels, the demand is computed for the exclusive and nonexclusive settings, and the two demand levels are equated to one another to solve for the unknown intercept term for the nonexclusive setting. This procedure ensures that, in the first-best setting, the two types of distribution have identical expected demands when the first-best optimal prices and efforts are selected. <ref type="bibr">22</ref> The goal of this Note. Parameter values: = 7, = 2, and K = 50.</p><p>normalization is to reduce any inherent bias in the model toward either form of distribution.</p><p>With the first-best solutions in hand, the manufacturer's profits in the second-best scenarios (i e , at the solution to M − E and M − NE ) are determined. Then the loss in efficiency for each form of distribution is compared with the other, rather than a summary comparison of manufacturer profit across the two forms of distribution. 23 Mathematica (Wolfram Research Inc.) helped generate the equilibrium values of the relevant variables in the first-and second-best scenarios. The notation used for the column headings in the simulation tables is given in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref>. All the entries in Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">4 and 5</ref> are at optimality. Observation 1. First, as the maximum liability that the distributor can bear becomes smaller, the Lagrange multiplier increases in value. Next, as increases, the effects that distort distributors' effort and price choices (identified in Findings 1 and 2) increase; the manufacturer's profits decrease and the manufacturer's percentage losses ( from the first-best solution) increase.</p><p>This can be seen by going down the columns in Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">4 and 5</ref>.</p><p>Observation 2. For smaller values of = 0 0 1, 0 2 0 3 , the manufacturer incurs a smaller loss with exclusive territories. For larger values of = 0 4 0 5, 0 6 0 7 , the manufacturer incurs a smaller loss with nonexclusive territories.</p><p>This can be seen from a comparison of the percentage losses in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">4</ref> with those in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">5</ref>. The intuition behind this observation is that under more severe limits on liability, the relatively low fixed fees do not make it profitable for the manufacturer to induce the exclusive distributor to work diligently. Instead, under those conditions, it is more profitable to provide the proper incentives via intrabrand <ref type="bibr">23</ref> Another approach would be to compare directly the manufacturer's profit under each form of distribution. This approach, however, is much more complex-since it must be ensured that the two regimes are truly comparable by controlling for differences in the marketing mix's effect on demand-and does not add to the qualitative insights of the paper. Note. Parameter values: = 7, = 2, = 1, = 0 001, and K = 46 64. competition. Consequently, nonexclusive territories are the preferred form of distribution.</p><p>It is worth pointing out that in many institutional settings, the imposable fixed fees are minimal, if not zero <ref type="bibr">(Iyer and Villas-Boas 2001)</ref>. In such settings, this paper's analysis highlights why manufacturers may prefer nonexclusive distribution even when firms at the distribution level can free-ride on one another.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Conclusion</head><p>Suppliers in many product categories often enter major markets through wholesalers or distributors. For instance, a wine supplier wishing to enter the North Carolina market would consider one or more of several wine distributors, each typically with an ability to reach the entire retail market. Similar deliberations arise when suppliers or manufacturers enter foreign markets. In such contexts, the supplier often considers whether to assign exclusive territories to its distributors. Previous research and conventional wisdom suggest that if intrabrand competition encourages free-riding, then exclusive territories can be employed to fix that problem. This paper argues that, even when distributors can free-ride on the efforts of one another, intrabrand competition can be beneficial, since distributors in exclusive territories may not always work diligently. In other words, tolerating some amount of free-riding among the distributors can be optimal for the manufacturer. This benefit becomes important particularly when the manufacturer cannot extract a significant portion of the distributor's surplus; the analysis captured this feature via the presence of binding limited liability constraints. When such constraints are not sufficiently binding, the analysis is consistent with prior research and conventional wisdom that exclusive territories offer a better solution for dealing with the relevant incentive problems.</p><p>One possible direction for further research is to explore the impact of the various demand elasticities (or demand sensitivity to price and effort) on the preference for intrabrand competition. As argued here, these sensitivities would not have any impact in the absence of binding limited liability constraints. A systematic analysis of these sensitivities, along with the impact of the various cross-partial derivatives on the value of the two forms of distribution, seems warranted. This paper's primary contribution lies in identifying the sources of the inefficiency that drives the choice between exclusive and nonexclusive forms of distribution. Overall, the analysis underscores the importance of assessing the benefits of intrabrand competition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The author wishes to thank the editor, the area editor, and three anonymous referees of this journal for their constructive suggestions to improve this paper. Thanks are also due to David Sappington, Bart Weitz, Murali Mantrala, and Kalyan Raman for their comments on an earlier draft of this manuscript. The author assumes sole responsibility for any remaining errors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix</head><p>This appendix is organized as follows. Section A.1 shows that the density functions, g i • , satisfy MLRC and CDFC (cf. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Rogerson 1985)</ref>. Section A.2 analyzes the exclusive distribution model while §A.3 focuses on the nonexclusive distribution model. Sections A.2 and A.3 each examine six separate scenarios: the first three scenarios assume that the manufacturer controls the distributors' final prices; in the latter three scenarios this assumption is relaxed. <ref type="bibr">24</ref> Under either assumption, the three scenarios correspond to (i) distributors' efforts are observable, (ii) efforts are unobservable and limited liability constraints are not binding, and (iii) efforts are unobservable and limited liability constraints are binding.</p><p>Note that each of the above scenarios is considered in a separate subsection. Each subsection begins with the formal statement of the manufacturer's problem, denoted M x , where x is that subsection's number. This formal statement is followed by a "result" that highlights the principal finding for that subsection. This result is then substantiated with a proof that employs the standard Kuhn-Tucker (KT) analysis. The analysis includes writing the entire Lagrangian along with the appropriate KT necessary conditions and using these conditions to derive the result. Throughout the ensuing analysis, s represent the Lagrange multipliers on the distributors' incentive compatibility constraints (i e , effort and price choice constraints), and s and s represent the multipliers on the individual rationality constraints and the limited liability constraints, respectively. Finally, wherever appropriate, the intuition and implication(s) of the result(s) are discussed briefly. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.1. Showing that MLRC and CDFC Hold</head><p>When a density function satisfies MLRC and CDFC, the first-order approach is valid in the sense that a distributor's choice of action (e g , effort) can be replaced by the corresponding first-order condition (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Rogerson 1985)</ref>. The following parallels between the model setup here and § §2 and 4 in <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Rogerson (1985)</ref> are worth noting.</p><p>Here, the outcome for distributor i is either q i L or q i H (where 0 ≤ q i L &lt; q i H ), and the probability that q i H is realized is denoted by g i . These outcomes q i L q i H and the corresponding probabilities of these outcomes 1 − g i g i correspond to Rogerson's outcomes x 1 x 2 and probabilities p 1 p 2 , respectively. Finally, the cumulative probability distribution here is 1 − g i 1 and corresponds to Rogerson's F 1 F 2 . Now, the definition of MLRC (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Rogerson 1985</ref><ref type="bibr">Rogerson , p. 1361</ref>) can be rewritten as follows:</p><p>Definition 1. The functions 1 − g i g i are said to satisfy the MLRC if two effort levels, e 1 and e 2 , are such that e 1 ≤ e 2 implies that g i e 1 /g i e 2 ≤ 1 − g i e 1 / 1 − g i e 2 .</p><p>The following verifies that the model setup here satisfies MLRC: Since e 2 ≥ e 1 , and g i is increasing in effort by assumption, it follows that</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">g i e 2 ≥ g i e 1 (A.1.1.1a) or −g i e 2 ≤ −g i e 1 (A.1.1.1b)</formula><p>Adding one to both sides of the inequality in (A.1.1.1b) gives</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">1 − g i e 2 ≤ 1 − g i e 1 (A.1.1.2) or 1 ≤ 1 − g i e 1 1 − g i e 2 (A.1.1.3)</formula><p>Further, from (A.1.1.1a), it follows that</p><formula xml:id="formula_31">g i e 1 g i e 2 ≤ 1 (A.1.1.4)</formula><p>Combining the inequalities in (A.1.1.3) and (A.1.1.4) gives</p><formula xml:id="formula_32">g i e 1 g i e 2 ≤ 1 ≤ 1 − g i e 1 1 − g i e 2 (A.1.1.5)</formula><p>Consequently: <ref type="bibr">.1.1.6)</ref> as required by MLRC.</p><formula xml:id="formula_33">g i e 1 g i e 2 ≤ 1 − g i e 1 1 − g i e 2 (A</formula><p>Next, the definition of CDFC (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Rogerson 1985</ref><ref type="bibr">Rogerson , p. 1362</ref>) can be rewritten as follows:</p><p>Definition 2. The functions 1 − g i g i satisfy the CDFC if the second derivative of each of the cumulative probabilities is nonnegative.</p><p>Here, the cumulative probabilities are 1 − g i 1 , and the second derivatives are − g i 0 . Further, by assumption, g i &gt; 0, and g i ≤ 0. Consequently, − g i ≥ 0. Therefore, CDFC is also satisfied.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.2. Analysis of the Exclusive Distribution Model</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.2.1. Manufacturer Controls Final Prices in a</head><p>Full-Information Setting In this setting, the manufacturer observes distributor effort costlessly. A solution to the manufacturer's problem in this setting will serve as a benchmark for the analysis of channel settings in which distributor effort is unobservable.</p><p>A formal statement of the manufacturer's problem, de-</p><formula xml:id="formula_34">noted [M.A.2.1], is Maximize w F e p M subject to i ≥ 0 ∀i = A B IR − i A solution to [M.A.2.1] has the following properties: Result 1. For i = A B, (a) i = 0 (b) p i − c q i / e i = C i / e i (c) q i = − p i − c q i / p i .</formula><p>Proof. The Lagrangian, L, for this problem (also note that without loss of generality, 0 = 0 here and throughout the analysis) is</p><formula xml:id="formula_35">L = w −c q A +q B +F A +F B + A p A −w q A −F A −C A e A + B p B −w q B −F B −C B e B (A.2.1.1)</formula><p>Assuming an interior solution for F i , i = A B, gives the following necessary conditions for optimality:</p><formula xml:id="formula_36">L F i = 1 − i = 0 (A.2.1.2a) or i = 1 (A.2.1.</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2b)</head><p>Using (A.2.1.2b) and assuming interior solutions for p i and e i , i = A B, the necessary conditions for optimality are</p><formula xml:id="formula_37">L p i = q i + p i − c q i p i = 0 (A.2.1.3)</formula><p>and</p><formula xml:id="formula_38">L e i = p i − c q i e i − C i e i = 0 (A.2.1.4)</formula><p>The statement of the result follows.</p><p>Result 1(a) indicates that in a full-information setting, both distributors are restricted to their reservation level of profit. Result 1(b) indicates that the marginal benefit (to the channel) of increasing the final price by $1 equals the marginal cost incurred through a loss in demand due to that $1 increase in price. Result 1(c) indicates that the marginal cost of the optimal effort from a distributor exactly equals the marginal benefit to the channel from that effort. In summary, Results 1(b) and 1(c) indicate that efforts and prices are chosen efficiently. <ref type="bibr">25</ref> For expositional purposes, the paper refers to the above solution as either the first-best solution or as the full-information efficient solution.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.2.2. Manufacturer Controls Final Prices and</head><p>Distributor Effort Is Unobservable The formal statement of the manufacturer's problem,</p><formula xml:id="formula_39">[M.A.2.2], is Maximize w F e p M subject to i e i w p i F i ≥ 0 ∀i = A B IR − i e i w p i F i ∈ Arg max e i i e i ∀w p i F i ∈ R + i = A B E − i A solution to [M.A.</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2.2] has the following properties:</head><p>Result 2. In this setting, the manufacturer recovers the first-best solution by setting w = c.</p><p>Proof. Here the analysis employs the first-order approach (cf. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Rogerson 1985)</ref> to solve the manufacturer's problem. That is, the E − i constraint is represented by the appropriate first-order condition from each distributor's profit maximization (i.e.,</p><p>i / e i = 0). Since the density functions satisfy both MLRC and CDFC, 26 and the distributor is selecting only effort (because the manufacturer controls final prices), this setting is similar to the standard analyses of the principal-agent model.</p><p>The Lagrangian, L, for this problem is</p><formula xml:id="formula_40">L = w −c q A +q B +F A +F B + A p A −w q A −F A −C A e A + B p B −w q B −F B −C B e B + Ae p A −w q A e A − C A e A + Be p B −w q B e B − C B e B (A.2.2.1)</formula><p>Assuming an interior solution for F i , i = A B, gives Recall the E − i constraint:</p><formula xml:id="formula_41">L F i = 1 − i = 0 (A.2.2.2a) or i = 1 (A.2.2.2b) Next, the KT condition on w is L w = − Ae q A e A −</formula><formula xml:id="formula_42">L ie = p i − w q i e i − C i e i = 0 (A.2.2.4a) (A.2.2.4a</formula><p>) can be rewritten as</p><formula xml:id="formula_43">p i − c q i e i + c − w q i e i − C i e i = 0 (A.2.2.4b</formula><p>) <ref type="bibr">26</ref> See §A.1 for details.</p><p>or</p><formula xml:id="formula_44">p i − c q i e i − C i e i = w − c q i e i (A.2.2.4c)</formula><p>Notice that the left-hand side of (A.2.2.4c) represents the sum of the marginal benefit and the marginal cost to the channel. Next, since q i / e i &gt; 0 by assumption, the sign of the right-hand side in (A.2.2.4c) is the same as the sign of w − c . It follows that for any given value of w, the lefthand side in (A.2.2.4c) has the same sign for either distributor. This implies that Ae and Be have the same sign. (For example, when w &gt; c, p i − c q i / e i − C i / e i &gt; 0, and the marginal benefit to the channel is greater than the marginal cost, and ie &gt; 0.) Consequently, Ae and Be cannot have opposite signs and the only solution that satisfies (A.2.2.3b) involves Ae = Be = 0. From (A.2.2.4c), it follows that w = c. When w = c, the KT conditions on the prices and efforts satisfy</p><formula xml:id="formula_45">L p i = q i + p i − c q i p i = 0 (A.2.2.5)</formula><p>and</p><formula xml:id="formula_46">L e i = p i − c q i e i − C i e i = 0 (A.2.2.6)</formula><p>Comparing these with the first-best solution, notice that when w = c, the manufacturer regains its full-information efficient solution. The statement of the result follows.</p><p>Setting the wholesale price equal to the marginal cost of production succeeds in aligning the exclusive distributors' objectives (at the margin) with those of the manufacturer. At the aggregate level, the manufacturer extracts distributors' rents through the fixed fees and restricts distributors' expected profits to their reservation level. However, this scheme forces the distributors to bear all the risk in the market. Therefore, the manufacturer capitalizes on the risk neutrality of the distributors to achieve the first-best profit.  Assuming interior solutions, the necessary conditions for F i , i = A B are</p><formula xml:id="formula_47">L F i = 1 − i − i = 0 (A.2.3.2a) or i = 1 − i (A.2.3.2b)</formula><p>Notice from (A.2.3.2b) that if the limited liability constraints are not binding, the principal can implement the full-information efficient solution, as outlined in Result 2. <ref type="bibr">27</ref> Consequently, here the focus is on the following case:</p><formula xml:id="formula_48">i &gt; 0 for all i = A B (A.2.3.3)</formula><p>Next, assuming an interior solution, the KT condition on w is </p><formula xml:id="formula_49">L w = q A + q B − A q A − B q B −</formula><formula xml:id="formula_50">L ie = p i − w q i e i − C i e i = 0 (A.2.3.6)</formula><p>The KT condition on i's effort is</p><formula xml:id="formula_51">L e i = w − c q i e i + i p i − w q i e i − C i e i + ie p i − w 2 q i e i 2 −</formula><p>2 C i e i 2 = 0 (A.2.3.7a) <ref type="bibr">27</ref> Further, even if the limited liability constraint binds for only one of the two distributors, deviation from first-best will be induced in the behavior of both distributors. This is due to the common wholesale price; the reason the common price induces distortions from efficiency in this case is similar to the one provided below. Given that no new insights may be gained from further detailed analysis of asymmetric binding of limited liability constraints (i.e., one distributor's constraint binds and the other distributor's constraint is not binding), the analysis focuses on those settings where the liability constraints bind for both distributors.</p><p>Recalling (A.2.3.2b), (A.2.3.7) can be rewritten as</p><formula xml:id="formula_52">L e i = w −c q i e i + p i −w q i e i − C i e i − i p i −w q i e i − C i e i + ie p i −w 2 q i e i 2 − 2 C i e i 2 = 0 (A.2.3.7b)</formula><p>Noting that w − c q i / e i + p i − w q i / e i simplifies to p i − c q i / e i , and (A.2.3.6) implies that the coefficient of i in (A.2.3.7b) equals zero, (A.2.3.7b) is rewritten as</p><formula xml:id="formula_53">L e i = p i − c q i e i − C i e i + ie p i − w 2 q i e i 2 − 2 C i e i 2 = 0 (A.2.3.7c) or p i − c q i e i − C i e i = − ie p i − w 2 q i e i 2 − 2 C i e i 2 (A.2.3.7d)</formula><p>The right-hand side on (A.2.3.7d) represents the distortion from the first-best effort choice. Notice that the concavity of the distributor's profit expression ensures that the term in the square brackets on the right-hand side of (A.2.3.7d) is strictly negative. Therefore, the sign of that right-hand side depends on the sign of ie . First, (A.2.3.5b) implies that at least one of the s is strictly positive. Further, for i = A B, (A.2.3.6) can be rewritten as  <ref type="bibr">.2.3.11)</ref> The statement of the result follows.</p><formula xml:id="formula_54">p i − c q i e i + c</formula><formula xml:id="formula_55">p i − c q i e i &gt; C i e i (A</formula><p>Result 3(a) indicates that in the presence of binding limited liability constraints, the manufacturer imposes the maximum possible fixed fees on the distributors. From Result 3(b) it follows that it is optimal for the manufacturer to set the wholesale price above the marginal cost of production. The intuition is that, if the manufacturer sets a wholesale price equal to its marginal cost of production, then the distributors have the proper incentives at the margin; however, due to restrictions on the magnitudes of the fixed fees, the manufacturer cannot fully benefit from those proper incentives. Therefore, the manufacturer no longer wants to align the distributors' incentives with its own. Instead, it supplements the restricted fixed fees with some positive profit through a wholesale price that exceeds the marginal cost of production.</p><p>Finally, Result 3(c) indicates that each distributor selects an effort level such that the marginal benefit to the channel from that effort exceeds its marginal cost. This implies that, in the presence of binding limited liability constraints, exclusive distributors do not work hard enough on the manufacturer's behalf; they slack off because they receive too little incentive to exert the first-best level of effort.</p><p>It is worth noting that in all three scenarios analyzed above (i.e., [M.A.2.1]-[M.A.2.3]), it is legitimate to use the standard first-order approach (cf. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Rogerson 1985)</ref>. The extant literature, however, is silent on the validity of the first-order approach when the manufacturer does not control the final prices. Establishing (i.e., identifying exogenous conditions that ensure) the validity of the first-order approach in this new scenario is technical and is outside the scope of this paper.</p><p>Finally, the above analysis has been conducted in a setting where the manufacturer has complete control over the final prices charged to customers. The qualitative considerations identified in the above results do not vanish when the manufacturer ceases to control the distributors' final prices. The next three sections illustrate this.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.2.4. Manufacturer Does Not Control Final Prices and</head><p>Distributor Effort Is Observable Here, distributors' effort is observable, but their prices are beyond the manufacturer's direct control. The formal statement of the manufacturer's problem, [M.A.2.4], is Maximize w F e p M subject to i e i w p i F i ≥ 0 ∀i = A B IR − i p i w e i F i ∈ Arg max</p><formula xml:id="formula_56">p i i p i ∀w e i F i ∈ R + i = A B P − i</formula><p>The P − i constraints take into account the fact that each distributor controls its own price. A solution to [M.A.2.4] has the following property: Result 4. In this setting, too, the manufacturer recovers the first-best solution by setting w = c.</p><p>Proof. The proof technique is identical to that for Result 5.</p><formula xml:id="formula_57">L = w −c q A +q B +F A +F B + A p A −w q A −F A −C A e A + B p B −w q B −F B −C B e B + Ap q A + p A −w q A p A + Bp q B + p B −w q B p B (A.2.4.1)</formula><p>Assuming an interior solution for F i , i = A B, gives</p><formula xml:id="formula_58">L F i = 1 − i = 0 (A.2.4.2a) or i = 1 (A.2.4.2b)</formula><p>The necessary condition for an interior solution for w is  </p><formula xml:id="formula_59">L w = q A + q B − A q A − B q B −</formula><formula xml:id="formula_60">L ip = q i + p i − w q i p i = 0 (A.2.4.5a) or q i + p i − c q i p i + c − w q i p i = 0 (A.2.4.5b) or q i + p i − c q i p i = w − c q i p i (A.</formula><formula xml:id="formula_61">p i w F i ≥ 0 ∀i = A B IR − i</formula><p>where e i w F i p i w F i ∈ Arg max</p><formula xml:id="formula_62">e i p i i e i p i ∀w F i ∈ R + i = A B EP − i A solution to [M.A.2</formula><p>.5] has the following property: Result 5. By setting w = c, the manufacturer regains the full-information efficient solution.</p><p>Proof. The proof technique is identical to that in the previous result. The Lagrangian, L, for this problem is </p><formula xml:id="formula_63">L = w −c q A +q B +F A +F B + A p A −w q A −F A −C A e A + B p B −w q B −F B −C B e B +</formula><formula xml:id="formula_64">= q i + p i − w q i p i = 0 (A.2.6.7)</formula><p>The necessary condition on the ith distributors' choice of effort and price are, for all i = A B:</p><formula xml:id="formula_65">L e i = w − c q i e i + i p i − w q i e i − C i e i + ie p i − w 2 q i e i 2 − 2 C i e i 2 + ip q i e i + p i − w 2 q i e i p i = 0 (A.2.6.8) L p i = w − c q i p i + i q i + p i − w q i p i + ie q i e i + p i − w 2 q i p i e i + ip 2 q i p i + p i − w 2 q i p i 2 = 0 (A.2.6.9)</formula><p>Substituting i with 1 − i , (A.2.6.8) and (A.2.6.9) are rewritten as</p><formula xml:id="formula_66">L e i = w − c q i e i + p i − w q i e i − C i e i − i p i − w q i e i − C i e i + ie p i − w 2 q i e i 2 − 2 C i e i 2 + ip q i e i + p i − w 2 q i e i p i = 0 (A.2.6.10) L p i = w − c q i p i + q i + p i − w q i p i − i q i + p i − w q i p i + ie q i e i + p i − w 2 q i p i e i + ip 2 q i p i + p i − w 2 q i p i 2 = 0 (A.2.6.11)</formula><p>Note that (a) w − c q i / e i + p i − w q i / e i simplifies to p i − c q i / e i ; (b) w − c q i / p i + p i − w q i / p i simplifies to p i − c q i / p i ; (c) from (A.2.6.6) it follows that the coefficient of i in (A.2.6.10) is zero; and (d) from (A.2.6.7) it follows that the coefficient of i in (A.2.6.11) is zero. Given these, the KT conditions on prices and efforts can be rewritten as</p><formula xml:id="formula_67">L e i = p i − c q i e i − C i e i + ie p i − w 2 q i e i 2 − 2 C i e i 2</formula><p>+ ip q i e i + p i − w 2 q i e i p i = 0 (A.2.6.12) Finally, notice that in the KT condition for the ith distributor's effort (see (A.2.6.14)), the effort distortion is comprised of two components: the one involving ie is analogous to the one in the solution to [M.A.2.3]. Here, however, since the distributor also selects its prices, the effort distortion has another component that involves ip . The statement of the result follows.</p><formula xml:id="formula_68">L p i = q i + p i − c q i p i + ie q i e i + p i − w 2 q i p i e i + ip 2 q i p i + p i − w 2 q i p i 2 =</formula><p>As the results indicate, the manufacturer imposes the maximum possible fixed fees on both its exclusive distributors and sets a wholesale price above its marginal cost of production. The intuition behind this result can be explained as follows: If the manufacturer sets w = c, the distributors have the proper incentives at the margin and will exert first-best efforts and choose first-best prices. However, due to limitations on the fixed fees, the manufacturer cannot fully benefit from such optimal behavior. Next, if manufacturer sets w &lt; c, distributors will choose effort levels higher than the first-best levels and set final prices below the firstbest levels. Both these actions serve to enhance demand; however, once again, the manufacturer cannot benefit from these activities because of limitations on the fixed fees. Further, selling more at a loss only serves to decrease the manufacturer's profit even further.</p><p>On the other hand, if the manufacturer sets w &gt; c, then the distributors do not have the first-best incentives at the margin. But if the maximum possible fixed fees can be imposed while ensuring that the distributors participate, then w &gt; c gives the manufacturer some additional profit. Therefore, the manufacturer will set w above c.</p><p>At optimality, the exclusive distributors in turn set their prices too high and put forth too little effort on behalf of the manufacturer. Next, in contrast to Result 3, Result 6 reveals that the effort distortion has an additional component, − Ap q A / e A , due to distributors controlling their own prices. Assuming an interior solution for F i , i = A B, the necessary KT conditions for optimality are</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.3. Analysis of the Nonexclusive</head><formula xml:id="formula_69">L F i = 1 − i = 0 (A.3.1.2a) or i = 1 (A.3.1.2b)</formula><p>Similarly, assuming interior solutions for p i and e i , ∀i = j and i j = A B, the necessary conditions for optimality are L p i = q i + p i − c q i p i + p j − c q j p i = 0 (A.3.1.3) L e i = p i − c q i e i + p j − c q j e i −</p><p>C i e i = 0 (A.3.1.4)</p><p>The statement of the result follows.</p><p>Result 7(a) indicates that both distributors are held to their reservation level of profit. In this nonexclusive distribution model, note that when a distributor changes its price or effort, there are two effects: First, the distributor's own demand is affected, and second, the other distributor's demand is affected. Results 7(b) and 7(c) indicate that the optimal prices and efforts are selected efficiently, taking into account the manner in which the two distributors' demands are interlinked. For this reason, the optimal prices and efforts here are different from those in the exclusive distribution scenario (see Result 1); the exact difference in magnitude and direction between the two sets of prices and efforts will be contingent on the specified demand structure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.3.2. Manufacturer Controls Final Prices and</head><p>Distributor Effort Is Unobservable The formal statement of the manufacturer's problem, [M.A.3.2], is</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Next, a solution to M − NE has the following properties:Finding 2. For all i = A B (a) In the presence of binding limited liability constraints, inefficiency exists in the distributors' choices of efforts and prices.(b) At optimality, distributor A's choice of effort and price are given by17    </figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>∀w p i F i ∈ R + i = A B E − i and −F i ≥ −F 0 i= A B LL − i A solution to [M.A.2.3] has the following properties: Result 3. For all i = A B, (a) F i = F 0 (b) w &gt; c (c) p i − c q i / e i &gt; C i / e i .Marketing Science 23(3), pp. 429-450, © 2004 INFORMS Proof. Employing the first-order approach, the Lagrangian, L, is L = w −c q A +q B +F A +F B + A p A −w q A −F A −C A e A + B p B −w q B −F B −C B e B + Ae p A −w A −F A +F 0 + B −F B +F 0 (A.2.3.1)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Distribution Model A.3.1. Manufacturer Controls Final Prices and Distributor Effort Is Observable As in the exclusive territories setting, the analysis begins by recording a benchmark solution where the manufacturer observes distributor effort costlessly. The formal statement of the manufacturer's problem, [M.A.3.1[M.A.3.1] has the following properties:Result 7. For i = j; i = A B, (a) i = 0 (b) p i − c q i / e i + p j − c q j / e i = C i / e i (c) q i = − p i − c q i / p i − p j − c q j / p i . Proof.The Lagrangian, L, for this problem is L = w − c q A + q B + F A + F B + A p A − w q A − F A − C A e A + B p B − w q B − F B − C B e B (A.3.1.1)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Desiraju: Costs and Benefits of Inducing Intrabrand Competition</figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science 23(3), pp. 429-450, © 2004 INFORMS</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">List of Symbols</cell></row><row><cell>Symbol</cell><cell></cell><cell>Represents</cell></row><row><cell>e i , p i</cell><cell cols="2">Distributor i's effort and price, respectively</cell></row><row><cell>q i g i •</cell><cell cols="2">i's sales, takes one of two values, q i L and q i H , where 0 ≤ q i L &lt; q i H i's probability of obtaining q i H</cell></row><row><cell>w</cell><cell cols="2">Manufacturer (M)'s wholesale price</cell></row><row><cell>F i</cell><cell cols="2">Fixed fee or liability that can be imposed on i</cell></row><row><cell>M , i</cell><cell cols="2">Manufacturer's and distributor i's profits, respectively</cell></row><row><cell>i , i</cell><cell cols="2">Lagrange multiplier on i's IR and LL constraints, respectively</cell></row><row><cell>ie</cell><cell cols="2">Lagrange multiplier on i's effort selection constraints</cell></row><row><cell>ip</cell><cell cols="2">Lagrange multiplier on i's price selection constraints</cell></row><row><cell>K</cell><cell cols="2">Demand function's intercept in the example in  §3</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Price sensitivity parameter in the example</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Effort sensitivity parameter in the example</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Cross-price sensitivity parameter in the example</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Cross-effort sensitivity parameter in the example</cell></row><row><cell>Free</cell><cell cols="2">Magnitude of the free-rider effect</cell></row><row><cell>Slack</cell><cell cols="2">Magnitude of the slack effect</cell></row><row><cell>Priceff</cell><cell cols="2">Magnitude of the price effect</cell></row><row><cell>Loss</cell><cell cols="2">Difference between M's first-and second-best profit</cell></row><row><cell>% Loss</cell><cell>Loss First-best profit</cell><cell>× 100</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Desiraju: Costs and Benefits of Inducing Intrabrand Competition</figDesc><table><row><cell>434</cell><cell>Marketing Science 23(3), pp. 429-450, © 2004 INFORMS</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Exclusive Distribution</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>A</cell><cell>F A</cell><cell>M</cell><cell>Free</cell><cell>Slack</cell><cell>Priceff</cell><cell>Loss</cell><cell>% Loss</cell></row><row><cell>0 0</cell><cell>125 00</cell><cell>250 00</cell><cell>0 00</cell><cell>0 00</cell><cell>0 00</cell><cell>0 00</cell><cell>0 00</cell></row><row><cell>0 1</cell><cell>103 31</cell><cell>246 93</cell><cell>0 00</cell><cell>0 91</cell><cell>0 39</cell><cell>2 07</cell><cell>0 83</cell></row><row><cell>0 2</cell><cell>86 81</cell><cell>243 06</cell><cell>0 00</cell><cell>1 67</cell><cell>0 71</cell><cell>6 94</cell><cell>2 78</cell></row><row><cell>0 3</cell><cell>73 97</cell><cell>236 69</cell><cell>0 00</cell><cell>2 31</cell><cell>0 99</cell><cell>13 31</cell><cell>5 33</cell></row><row><cell>0 4</cell><cell>63 78</cell><cell>229 59</cell><cell>0 00</cell><cell>2 86</cell><cell>1 23</cell><cell>20 41</cell><cell>8 16</cell></row><row><cell>0 5</cell><cell>55 56</cell><cell>222 22</cell><cell>0 00</cell><cell>3 33</cell><cell>1 43</cell><cell>27 78</cell><cell>11 11</cell></row><row><cell>0 6</cell><cell>48 83</cell><cell>214 84</cell><cell>0 00</cell><cell>3 75</cell><cell>1 61</cell><cell>35 16</cell><cell>14 06</cell></row><row><cell>0 7</cell><cell>43 25</cell><cell>207 61</cell><cell>0 00</cell><cell>4 12</cell><cell>1 77</cell><cell>42 39</cell><cell>16 96</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Nonexclusive Distribution</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>A</cell><cell>F A</cell><cell>M</cell><cell>Free</cell><cell cols="2">Slack Priceff</cell><cell>Loss</cell><cell>% Loss</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">0 00 122 47 269 32 −0 0005</cell><cell cols="2">1 66 −0 95</cell><cell>2 77</cell><cell>1 02</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">0 10 102 90 267 45</cell><cell>0 0002</cell><cell cols="2">2 42 −0 48</cell><cell>4 64</cell><cell>1 71</cell></row><row><cell>0 20</cell><cell cols="2">87 67 262 94</cell><cell>0 0008</cell><cell cols="2">3 08 −0 08</cell><cell>9 15</cell><cell>3 36</cell></row><row><cell>0 30</cell><cell cols="2">75 59 256 94</cell><cell>0 0013</cell><cell>3 63</cell><cell>0 26</cell><cell>15 14</cell><cell>5 57</cell></row><row><cell>0 40</cell><cell cols="2">65 85 250 15</cell><cell>0 0017</cell><cell>4 12</cell><cell>0 55</cell><cell>21 93</cell><cell>8 06</cell></row><row><cell>0 50</cell><cell cols="2">57 87 243 00</cell><cell>0 0021</cell><cell>4 54</cell><cell>0 81</cell><cell>29 08</cell><cell>10 69</cell></row><row><cell>0 60</cell><cell cols="2">51 26 235 75</cell><cell>0 0024</cell><cell>4 91</cell><cell>1 03</cell><cell>36 34</cell><cell>13 35</cell></row><row><cell>0 70</cell><cell cols="2">45 72 228 57</cell><cell>0 0027</cell><cell>5 25</cell><cell>1 24</cell><cell>43 52</cell><cell>15 99</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Ae and Be are each equal to zero or (b) Ae and Be are of opposite signs. The analysis will now show that the two multipliers cannot be of opposite signs.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Be</cell><cell>q B e B = 0</cell><cell>(A.2.2.3a)</cell></row><row><cell>or</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Ae</cell><cell>q A e A + Be</cell><cell>q B e B = 0</cell><cell>(A.2.2.3b)</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">(A.2.2.3b) indicates either that (a)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Ap = Bp = 0, or Ap and Bp have opposite signs. From (A.2.4.5c), however, it is clear that both Ap and Bp will have the same sign. Consequently, at the solution to [M.A.2.4], w = c and the incentive problem is eliminated. The statement of the result follows.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>2.4.5c)</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Note that (A.2.4.4) requires that either A.2.5. Manufacturer Does Not Control Final Prices and</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Distributor Effort Is Unobservable</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">A formal statement of the manufacturer's problem,</cell></row><row><cell>[M.A.2.5], is</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>w F e p Maximize</cell><cell>M</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">subject to i e i w F i</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">For instance, business failure is one setting under which the distributor's liability can be limited. In the wholesale trade, which encompasses a variety of product categories, Dun and Bradstreet reports an overall failure rate of 71 per thousand firms in 1995 and 69 per thousand firms in 1996. These rates can be viewed as lower bounds on the prevalence rate of liability clauses in wholesale distribution channels.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">The cost of these efforts easily ranges from $150,000 to $225,000(Corey et al. 1989, p. 79).3 That is, suppose firm A benefits from the efforts of firm B. Then A may reduce its efforts and free-ride on B's efforts.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">See also<ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Moorthy (1987)</ref> and<ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Jeuland and Shugan (1988)</ref>.5  For an analysis of exclusivity outside the context of channel management, see<ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Dukes and Gal-Or (2003)</ref>.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">"Observable" means costlessly observable. Technically, if a variable were observable, it may be contracted upon; here, the focus is on settings where efforts are not explicitly included in the manufacturer-distributor contract.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">There are at least two problems if the manufacturer charges different wholesale prices to different distributors. First, there is the possibility of arbitrage among distributors, particularly when transaction costs are not too high. Second, unless it offers a menu, the manufacturer can be prosecuted for price discrimination. For these reasons, and for ease of exposition, the analysis assumes a common price.8 While there has not been much legal precedent for this, different fixed fees for different distributors may also be argued as discrimination. The qualitative insights from the analysis continue to hold even when the same F is charged to both distributors.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">In the nonexclusive setting, the distributor selects price and effort levels as best responses to the other distributor's choices.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="12">The manufacturer is assumed to use two distributors in both forms of distribution. This helps to control, at least to some degree, any differences in demand that would otherwise have arisen. See more on this in the example in §3.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="13"> See Liu et al. (2003)  for another context in which agents compete without price.<ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bhardwaj (2001)</ref> examines settings in which a principal does (not) delegate pricing authority to its agent.14  This implies that efforts are contractible-that is, effort level can be specified by the manufacturer in the contract.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="15">These are referred to as benchmark solutions also in the sense that some variation of the findings is currently available in the literature.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="16">The components of the expressions determining the distributors' choices of prices are not discussed here. These are available in the appendix.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="18">The corresponding effects for the distributors' choices of prices are not explicitly identified here. These are available in the appendix.19  It may be worth repeating that while the two states, q i L and q i H , are fixed a priori, the probability with which either state arises is affected by the distributors' prices and efforts, and the expressions in (17) and (18) represent the expected demand levels.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="20">As an aside, note that the choice of exclusive distribution continues to be an issue in such product categories (e g , see An Act to Amend the Wine Franchise Law to Provide For Exclusive Territories, a bill introduced in 1999 in North Carolina).21  See, for instance, Malt Beverage Interbrand Competition Act: Hearings on S. 1215 Before the Committee on the Judiciary, 97th Congress, 2nd Session (1982), p. 211.22  The analysis also determined the value of the nonexclusive intercept by equating the manufacturer's first-best profit from the two forms of distribution. There are no qualitative differences in the results of the analysis in either approach.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="24">The rationale for considering these cases is explained at the end of §A.3.3.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="25">The notion of efficiency referred to here and throughout the ensuing analysis is that, from a channel perspective, marginal benefit equals marginal cost.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="29">We can verify this by solving the first-order conditions with respect to e i simultaneously for the s.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>From (A.2.5.2c) and (A.2.5.3b) it is clear that setting w = c will eliminate any deviation from efficiency. That is, at w = c, the final prices and efforts satisfy conditions (b) and (c) in Result 1. Consequently, the statement of the result follows.</p><p>It is worth noting that the full-information efficient solution is regained in this case even when distributor effort is unobservable to the manufacturer. By selling the product at its marginal cost of production, the manufacturer is making each exclusive distributor a residual claimant. Consequently, the distributor's objectives at the margin are completely in line with those of the manufacturer. Of course, the manufacturer extracts all rents through the fixed fees and restricts the expected profit of each exclusive distributor to its reservation level. This standard result is an essential benchmark in discussing the next subsection's results.</p><p>To this point, the analysis has not found any new distortions in the distributors' behavior due to incomplete manufacturer control over final prices. The next case provides the greatest opportunity for distributors to deviate from the full-information efficient levels.</p><p>A.2.6. Manufacturer Does Not Control Final Prices, Distributor Effort Is Unobservable, and the Limited Liability Constraints Are Binding A formal statement of the manufacturer's problem, M − E , is Maximize w F e p M subject to i e i w F i p i w F i ≥ 0 ∀i = A B IR − i e i w F i p i w F i ∈ Arg max</p><p>A solution to M − E is summarized below (this corresponds to Finding 1 in the main paper):</p><p>Result 6. For all i = A B, (a) In the presence of binding limited liability constraints, inefficiency exists in the distributors' choices of efforts and final prices. More formally, both ie and ip cannot equal zero and the first-best solution (where both ie and ip equal zero) cannot be achieved.</p><p>(b) At optimality, the inefficiency arising from distributor i's choice of effort is comprised of the following two components:</p><p>(i) the slack effect, − ie p i − w 2 q i / e i 2 − 2 C i / e i 2 (ii) the price effect, − ip q i / e i (c) Further, suppose 2 q i / p i e i = 2 q i / p i 2 = 0 and q i / p i 2 i / e i 2 − 2 i / p i e i 2 &gt; 0. When these sufficient conditions hold, 28 then</p><p>The necessary (KT) conditions for</p><p>Notice from (A.2.6.2b) that if the limited liability constraints are not binding, the principal can implement the full-information efficient solution, as outlined in Result 5. Again, for the same reasons as those given for (A.2.3.3), the focus is on the following case:</p><p>Next, assuming an interior solution, the KT condition on w is </p><p>The signs on the Lagrange multipliers ie and ip will depend on the sign of the right-hand side in (A.2.6.24). For instance, if the numerator and the denominator on the righthand side of (A.2.6.24) have different signs, then ie and ip cannot have the same sign. Here, the analysis will focus on the case of a simple demand structure that is employed in the example in §3 of the main paper. There, the following additional assumptions are met:</p><p>(1) First, 2 q i / p i e i = 2 q i / p i 2 = 0. This implies: </p><p>(Recall that concavity requires 2 i / p i 2 2 i / e i 2 − 2 i / p i e i 2 &gt; 0. Since the absolute value of 2 i / p i 2 is larger than the absolute value of q i / p i , additional assumption (2) automatically ensures concavity.) Under these assumptions, (A.2.6.24) reduces to</p><p>The numerator in (A.2.6.27) is positive, while from additional assumption (2), the denominator is negative; consequently, ie and ip have to be of opposite signs.</p><p>Next, for ease of exposition, define MR−MC e ≡ p i − c • q i / e i − C i / e i , and MR − MC p ≡ q i + p i − c q i / p i . Now, (A.2.6.14) and (A.2.6.15) can be rewritten as follows:</p><p>Note that from (A.2.6.16) and (A.2.6.17) it follows that for a given w =c , MR − MC p and MR − MC e are of opposite signs. Next, (A.2.6.27) indicates that ie and ip are of opposite signs. The analysis now shows that ie and ip have the same sign as MR−MC e and MR−MC p , respectively. To show that, first assume ie 's sign is opposite that of MR − MC e and ip 's sign is opposite that of MR − MC p , and then arrive at a contradiction as shown below.</p><p>Since the Lagrange multipliers do not have the same sign as MR − MC , the square bracketed terms on the righthand side of (A.2.6.28) and (A.2.6.29) must each be negative. That is </p><p>However, in (A.2.6.32), the right-hand side is strictly positive (since the s are of opposite sign and 2 i / p i e i &gt; 0), while the left-hand side is negative by assumption. (A similar argument holds for (A.2.6.33).) Consequently, the Lagrange multipliers ie and ip have the same sign as MR − MC e and MR − MC p , respectively. (Also, from (A.2.6.16) it follows that Ae and Be must have the same sign, and from (A.2.6.17) that Ap and Bp must have the same sign.) Given the above, two distinct possibilities need to be considered: either ie &gt; 0 and ip &lt; 0 or ie &lt; 0 and ip &gt; 0. Suppose ie &lt; 0 and ip &gt; 0; then the left-hand side of (A.2.6.5) is negative and that equation cannot be satisfied. Consequently, at the solution to M − E , ip &lt; 0 and ie &gt; 0, ∀i = A B, and this requires w &gt; c.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Maximize</head><p>w F e p M subject to i e i • e j • ≥ 0 ∀i = A B IR − i where e i w p i p j F i F j ∈ Arg max</p><p>In the effort selection constraints, E − i , above (and those that will be encountered later on), each distributor chooses his effort level to maximize his own profit as a best response to the other distributor doing the same. A solution to [M.A.3.2] has the following property: Result 8. The manufacturer recovers the full-information efficient solution when it sells to its distributors at a wholesale price, w * , which is below the marginal cost of production, c. At that wholesale price, the following condition is required to hold: Assuming an interior solution for F i , i = A B, gives the following necessary conditions for optimality:  The condition in Result 8 reveals the flexibility enjoyed by a manufacturer when it has direct control over final prices. Further, the condition indicates the problems that can arise when the manufacturer has only indirect control over final prices.</p><p>Notice that to regain the first-best solution, the manufacturer chooses a wholesale price lower than its marginal production cost. When one distributor chooses its effort level, it ignores the positive effect of that effort on the other distributor. Consequently, left to itself, each distributor chooses effort levels that are lower than the full-information efficient levels. To motivate the distributors to put forth the full-information efficient levels, the manufacturer sets the wholesale price lower than cost. As usual, however, the manufacturer recovers any lost revenues through suitably designed fixed fees, which ensure binding IR − i constraints for the distributors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.3.3. Manufacturer Controls Final Prices, Distributor</head><p>Effort Is Unobservable, and the Limited Liability Constraints Are Binding Here, the formal statement of the manufacturer's problem, [M.A.3.3], is Maximize w F e p M subject to i e i • e j • ≥ 0 ∀i = A B IR − i e i w F i F j p i p j ∈ Arg max e i i e i e i w F i F j p i p j ∀w F i F j p i p j ∈ R</p><p>.3] has the following properties: Result 9. For all i = j and i j = A B, (a) F i = F 0 (b) w &gt; w * , where w * is the first-best wholesale price in Result 8 (c) p A − c q A / e A &gt; C A / e A , and the distortion from efficiency in a distributor's choice of effort is comprised of two components:</p><p>(i) the free-rider effect B p B − w q B / e A (i) the slack effect − Ae p A − w 2 q A / e A 2 − 2 C A / e A 2 . Proof. Employing the first-order approach, the Lagrangian, L, is</p><p>Assuming interior solutions, the necessary conditions for</p><p>Notice from (A.3.3.2b) that if the limited liability constraints are not binding, the principal can implement the full-information efficient solution, as outlined in Result 8. <ref type="bibr">30</ref> Consequently, the focus is on the following case:</p><p>Next, assuming an interior solution, the KT condition on w is </p><p>q j e i (A.3.3.8) Suppose w ≤ w * , where w * is the wholesale price that induces the first-best solution to [M.A.3.2], the manufacturer's problem considered in the previous subsection. For such a w, the right-hand side in (A.3.3.8) is negative and the distributor's effort is (weakly) greater than the first-best level. <ref type="bibr">31</ref> Moreover, the corresponding ie is (weakly) negative for i = A B; these values of the multipliers do not satisfy (A.3.3.6). Consequently, the solution must have</p><p>At such a wholesale price</p><p>Clearly, the presence of binding limited liability constraints induces inefficiency in the channel and the manufacturer cannot achieve the first-best solution.</p><p>It is useful to consider the necessary condition on i's effort, i = j and i j = A B:</p><p>+ je p j − w 2 q j e i e j = 0 (A. e A e B = 0 (A.3.3.12a) <ref type="bibr">31</ref> Because when w = w * , distributors' effort is at the first-best level; when w &lt; w * , a distributor puts forth more effort than the first-best level.</p><p>Notice that w − c q A / e A + p A − w q A / e A simplifies to p A −c q A / e A , and w −c q B / The results indicate that when the manufacturer imposes the maximum possible fixed fees on both his distributors, distortions from first-best are induced in the distributors' behavior. This distortion from efficiency can be better understood when its magnitude is split into two components, as in the statement of Result 9.</p><p>The nature of each component becomes clear from its sign. The first component, B p B − w q B / e A , is positive since B &gt; 0, p B − w &gt; 0, and q B / e A &gt; 0. This component is referred to as the free-rider effect since its magnitude is related to the positive interlinkage between the sales of one distributor and the effort of another.</p><p>The second component, − Ae p A − w 2 q A / e A 2 − 2 C A / e A 2 , is referred to as the slack effect, and it characterizes how diligently a distributor is working on behalf of the manufacturer. Notice that the concavity of the distributor's profit function ensures p A − w 2 q A / e A 2 − 2 C A / e A 2 &lt; 0; since Ae &gt; 0, the slack effect serves to distort the effort choice from efficiency. This effect is analogous to the corresponding effect under exclusive distribution with binding limited liability constraints.</p><p>In equilibrium, the net distortion from efficiency is endogenously determined by the sum of the abovedescribed effects. The sign of each effect, however, provides a clue to the dynamics of the inefficiency. Any "positive" effect tends to push the marginal benefit over the marginal cost of that distributor's effort, implying that too little effort is being exerted. In contrast, a "negative" effect drives the marginal cost above the marginal benefit, suggesting that too much effort is being exerted. Given this, notice that the free-rider effect is always positive and consequently induces distributors to put forth too little effort. Next, the slack effect is positive and indicates that distributors tend to work too little in the presence of binding liability constraints.</p><p>The above three components support the intuition that there are inefficiencies associated with each form of distribution. Under exclusive distribution, a manufacturer has to contend with the slack effect; under nonexclusive distribution, the manufacturer deals with the costs of the free-rider effect and the slack effect (this slack effect may be smaller than the one under exclusive territories). Clearly, the relative magnitude of these effects plays an important role in the manufacturer's choice of distribution method.  </p><p>where p i w e i e j F i F j ∈ Arg max p i i p i p j w e i e j F i F j ∀w e i e j F i F j ∈ R + i = j i j = A B P − i Notice that in the P − i constraints above, each distributor selects its final price to maximize its own profits as a best response to the other distributor doing the same. A solution to <ref type="bibr">[M.A.3.4</ref>] has the following properties: Result 10. The manufacturer achieves the full-information efficient solution that was feasible when it had control over the final prices. To do this, the manufacturer sets w &gt; c, and at that wholesale price, the following condition will hold:</p><p>Assuming an interior solution for F i , i = A B, gives</p><p>The necessary condition for an interior solution for w is</p><p>Rewrite (A.3.4.5) as follows: <ref type="bibr">.3.4.6)</ref> The first-best contract requires-− w − c q i p i = p j − c q j p i (A.3.4.7)</p><p>If (A.3.4.7) is satisfied, ip will equal zero and the first-best prices will be selected. Since q j / p i &gt; 0 and q i / p i &lt; 0 by assumption, (A.3.4.7) will hold only when w &gt; c. Further, (A. subject to i e i • p i • e j • p j • ≥ 0 ∀i = j i j = A B IR − i e i w F i F j p i w F i F j ∈ Argmax e i p i i e i p i e j w F i F j p j w F i F j</p><p>The solution to [M.A.3.5] has the following property: Result 11. In this setting, the manufacturer cannot achieve the full-information efficient solution.</p><p>Proof. Suppose that the manufacturer naïvely attempted to implement the first-best solution of Result 10 (i.e., w is set above the marginal cost, and fixed fees are chosen to ensure that the distributors' individual rationality constraints bind). Consider the rate of change of a distributor's expected profit with respect to its effort level at the first-best solution:</p><p>C i e i (A.3.5.1) (A.3.5.1) can be rewritten as</p><p>Next, recall (from (A.3.1.4)) the first-best solution:</p><p>C i e i = 0 (A.3.5.3) (A.3.5.3) can be rewritten as</p><p>q j e i &lt; 0 (A.3.5.4)</p><p>Substituting from (A.3.5.4) into (A.3.5.2) gives i e i = − p j − c q j e i − w − c q i e i &lt; 0 (A.3.5.5)</p><p>When distributors' efforts are unobservable and the manufacturer attempts to implement the first-best effort levels, (A.3.5.5) reveals that each distributor can increase profit by decreasing the level of effort. Similarly, if the manufacturer sets w &lt; c, to induce efficient effort levels (as in Result 8), analogous analysis shows that the distributors will have an incentive to set final prices inefficiently. Also notice that to induce efficient effort levels, w must be set below c; however, to induce efficient price levels, w must be set above c. Therefore, it is not feasible to induce both efficient effort levels as well as price levels via one wholesale price. It follows that the manufacturer cannot obtain the first-best solution in this setting. </p><p>IR − i e i w F i F j p i w F i F j ∈ Argmax e i p i i e i p i e j w F i F j p j w F i F j</p><p>The properties of a solution to M − NE are summarized below (this corresponds to Finding 2 in the main text):</p><p>Result 12. For all i = A B, (a) In the presence of binding limited liability constraints, inefficiency exists in the selection of efforts and final prices by distributors.</p><p>(b) At optimality, the inefficiency arising from a distributor's choice of effort is comprised of the following three components:</p><p>(i) the free-rider effect, B p B − w − Bp q B / e A (ii) the slack effect, − Ae p A − w 2 q A / e A 2 − 2 C A / e A 2 (iii) the price effect, − Ap q A / e A . (c) At optimality, the inefficiency arising from a distributor's choice of price is comprised of the following three components:</p><p>(</p><p>According to KT analysis, the necessary conditions for</p><p>Since the aim is to study settings where the limited liability constraints are binding, the analysis focuses on the following case (see also the earlier discussion in § §A.  <ref type="bibr">.3.6.5</ref>) that not all the s equal zero; consequently, there are inefficiencies in this setting, as indicated in the statement of the result.</p><p>The necessary condition on A's effort is (since the term multiplying A is zero, that term is not shown here) Note that the second-cross-partial derivatives of q i with respect to price and effort are zero in this model. The terms on the right-hand side of (A.3.6.9) are the components listed in the statement of the result.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The economic basis of damages for breach of contract</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Barton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Legal Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="277" to="304" />
			<date type="published" when="1972-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Delegating pricing decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pradeep</forename><surname>Bhardwaj</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="169" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Blair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Roger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kaserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Antitrust Economics. Richard D. Irwin, Inc</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Going to Market: Distribution Systems for Industrial Products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Corey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Frank</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Raymond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Cespedes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kasturi Rangan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>Harvard Business School Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Boston, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Negotiations and exclusivity contracts for advertising</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><surname>Dukes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Esther</forename><surname>Gal-Or</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="222" to="245" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A comparison of tournaments and contracts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Stokey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="349" to="364" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coordinating channels under price and nonprice competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ganesh</forename><surname>Iyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="338" to="355" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A bargaining theory of distribution channels</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ganesh</forename><surname>Iyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="100" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Miguel Villas-Boas</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing channel profits</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abel</forename><surname>Jeuland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="272" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abel</forename><surname>Jeuland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Shugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Reply to: Managing channel profits: Comment. Marketing Sci</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="106" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing optimal sales contests: A theoretical perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ajay</forename><surname>Kalra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mengze</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="170" to="193" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is having more channels really better? A model of competition among commercial television broadcasters</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yong</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Putler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Weinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="120" to="133" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An economic theory of vertical restraints</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Mathewson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Winter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">RAND J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="38" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Business Law Today: Comprehensive Edition: Text &amp; Cases-Legal, Ethical, Regulatory, and International Environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roger</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gaylord</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Leroy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Jentz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">West Legal Studies in Business</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">369</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="442" to="446" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing channel profits: Comment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Moorthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sridhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="375" to="379" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information, competition, and markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barry</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Nalebuff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Joseph</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Stiglitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">732</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="278" to="283" />
			<date type="published" when="1983-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of exclusive territories in producers&apos; competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Rey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Stiglitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="431" to="451" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The logic of vertical restraints</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Rey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jean</forename><surname>Tirole</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. Econom. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="921" to="939" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The first-order approach to principalagent problems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Rogerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1357" to="1367" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Limited liability contracts between principal and agent</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">E M</forename><surname>Sappington</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econom. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="1983-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mathematical Economics. Cambridge University Press</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Akira</forename><surname>Takayama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
			<pubPlace>Boston, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
