<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Evolutionary Estimation of Macro-Level Diffusion Models Using Genetic Algorithms: An Alternative to Nonlinear Least Squares</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Rajkumar</forename><surname>Venkatesan</surname></persName>
							<email>rvenkatesan@sba.uconn.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Trichy</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Krishnan</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Connecticut</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>06269-1041</postCode>
									<settlement>Storrs</settlement>
									<region>Connecticut</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Marketing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Connecticut</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>06269-1041</postCode>
									<settlement>Storrs</settlement>
									<region>Connecticut</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Evolutionary Estimation of Macro-Level Diffusion Models Using Genetic Algorithms: An Alternative to Nonlinear Least Squares</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">0732-2399 e 1526-548X 04 2303 0451</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.1040.0056</idno>
					<note type="submission">This paper was received August 30, 2002, and was with the authors 4 months for 5 revisions; processed by Roland Rust.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:29+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Bass model</term>
					<term>starting values</term>
					<term>systematic change and bias</term>
					<term>closed-form solution</term>
					<term>nonlinear least squares</term>
					<term>genetic algorithms</term>
					<term>pre-peak sales forecasting</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Data available for estimation of the Bass model or its extensions are usually restricted to a set of 12 to 15 observations. There are two reasons for this. First, sales data are typically collected annually to avoid fluctuations in sales within a year and seasonality issues. Second, sales of most of the new products tend to stop growing, and in fact start decreasing, after 7 to 10 years. Because a manager's interest is very likely to diminish after the growth stage of a new product, researchers have to work with a smaller dataset in many cases. A natural outcome of this problem is researchers' interest in exploring more and more sophisticated estimation techniques that can extract as much information as possible from smaller datasets with maximum efficiency. Alternatively, researchers have also investigated using information such as advance purchase orders <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Moe and Fader 2002)</ref> and spatial dimensions of product adoption <ref type="bibr">(Garber et al. 2003)</ref> for early prediction of new product sales.</p><p>The chronology of the various estimation techniques and the benefits and drawbacks of each method are outlined in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. Of the three timeinvariant estimation techniques employed in the diffusion literature, namely, Ordinary Least Squares (OLS), Maximum Likelihood (ML), and Nonlinear Least Squares (NLS), it is generally accepted that NLS is the best option among the current alternatives <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Putsis and Srinivasan 2000)</ref>. For the <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bass (1969)</ref> model, NLS is applied to the equation</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">s t = m * F t − F t − 1 + t (1)</formula><p>where s t is the sales function, m is the market potential parameter, t is the normal additive error, F t is the cumulative density function of time of adoption given by F t = 1 − e − p+q t 1 + q/p e − p+q t</p><p>(2) t = time period, p = coefficient of innovation, and q = coefficient of imitation.   <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bass (1969)</ref> Ordinary least squares (OLS) Easy and straightforward implementation. Discrete form for a continuous process. No Good fit.</p><p>standard errors for the parameter estimates. Parameters may sometimes be outside the allowable range.</p><p>Schmittlien and Maximum likelihood (ML) Continuous form operationalization. Not efficient in reducing errors from sources other <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Mahajan (1982)</ref> Minimizes sampling error. than sampling.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Srinivasan and</head><p>Nonlinear least squares Continuous form operationalization. Problems with convergence when data does not <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Mason (1986)</ref>, (SSB-NLS) Provides better fit than other methods, contain peak time period. Bias and systematic <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Jain and Rao (1990)</ref> especially maximum likelihood. change in parameter estimates. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Lenk and Rao (1990)</ref> Hierarchical Bayes (HB) Provides good predictions of future sales Distribution assumptions about parameters. Lower including before peak time period when accuracy when diffusion curves are skewed. Not compared with ML. Utilizes variation in easy for practitioners to use. previous diffusion histories to avoid convergence in local minima. <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Xie et al. (1997)</ref> Augmented Kalman Provides better predictions of future sales Does not provide as good a forecast as the GA filter (continuous including before peak time period when estimates. (Shown in the present study.) Not observation-discrete compared with adaptive filter, SSB-NLS, easy for practitioners to use. measurement)</p><p>OLS, and ML.</p><p>Present study Genetic algorithm (GA) Addresses all three problems associated Need specific software. with SSB-NLS. Consistently performs better than other estimation methods.</p><p>NLS used in popular computer packages employs a sequential search technique to obtain parameter estimates. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The widely used sequential search-based (SSB) NLS places three major restrictions on the estimation that span every stage of the product lifecycle. SSB-NLS estimation seems to have problems with data that covers three stages of a diffusion curve: pre-peak sales, peak sales, and post-peak sales (see Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>). With the pre-peak sales data, SSB-NLS has been repeatedly found to not achieve convergence <ref type="bibr">Mason 1986, Lenk and</ref>. With the peak-sales data, it has been found that SSB-NLS's convergence largely depends on the initial values one provides for the parameters. With the postpeak sales data, it has been found that the SSB-NLS estimates of the Bass model are biased and change systematically as we add datapoints from later years (Van den Bulte and Lilien 1997, <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bemmaor and</ref><ref type="bibr">Lee 2002, Venkatesan et al. 2000)</ref>.</p><p>In §2, we provide theoretical arguments and intuition for how GA is, under certain circumstances, able to arrive at global optimal parameter estimates more efficiently even when the response surface is multimodal and noisy. We also show how a SSB-NLS has a probability of converging at a local optimal solution in these cases. In §3, using simulated data we show that the estimates from GA are similar to estimates from SSB-NLS under commonly encountered error variances and parameter estimate values, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Recently researchers have also found issues with statistical procedures implemented in Microsoft Excel <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(McCullough and Wilson 1999)</ref>.</p><p>provided full datasets are used for estimation. Then, using empirical datasets we compare the performance of GA with SSB-NLS and other techniques proposed in the literature when the data does not contain peak sales, when there is data until peak sales, and when datapoints are added sequentially to post-peak sales data. Based on the results of our analyses in §4 and Appendix 2 we conclude that GA is able to produce better parameter estimates than SSB-NLS as evident in lower Mean Squared Errors (MSE) and Mean Absolute Deviation (MAD) under the three data related scenarios mentioned above. In this section, we provide intuitive reasons for why we expect GA to perform better than SSB-NLS and other search algorithms (e.g., a grid search) even though the estimation techniques use the identical objective function. Details on the estimation of the Bass model using GA are provided in Appendix A.</p><p>Comparison with SSB-NLS. The SSB-NLS and GA have several important and substantive differences due to which SSB-NLS and GA need not always provide the same solutions. A vast body of research outside of marketing has investigated the properties of parameter estimates from GA <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Del Moral and</ref><ref type="bibr">Miclo 2001, Dorsey and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Mayer 1995)</ref> and has also compared the performance of estimates from GA with traditional gradient search algorithms used in SSB-NLS <ref type="bibr">(Salomon 1998, Dorsey and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Mayer 1995)</ref>. We summarize the major findings from these studies below:</p><p>• SSB-NLS techniques use single-point gradient search algorithms to locate the parameters that optimize the objective function (minimum sum of squared errors).</p><p>• GA uses parallel, evolutionary search algorithms to locate parameters that optimize the objective function (minimum sum of squared errors in this case).</p><p>• Theoretical expectations are that GA has a higher probability of convergence to global optimum solutions when datapoints are less, number of parameters is large, the parameter space is multimodal, and the model is inherently nonlinear <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Del Moral and Miclo 2001)</ref>. However, SSB-NLS is dependent on smooth, and mostly quadratic surfaces to ensure convergence to local optimal-with the expectation that if appropriate starting values are chosen the local optimum will represent the global optimal solution <ref type="bibr">(Seber and Wild 1988)</ref>.</p><p>• The estimates from GA provide better fit and forecasting performance as compared to SSB-NLS for highly nonlinear functions <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Dorsey and Mayer 1995)</ref> and they represent inherently two different classes of optimization techniques that have different properties <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Salomon 1989)</ref>.</p><p>We further expand on these key features using an illustrative example shown in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>.</p><p>Suppose that the solution space is not smooth and that it has a surface as shown in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>. The optimal points A and C are local but are very dominant because a vast majority of starting values will move towards these two local optima. The global optimal point B is reachable only from a few starting values. In the SSB-NLS, unless you happen to be in those few spots, you would never reach the global optimum, however hard you try. This is because in current NLS packages there is SEQUENTIAL SEARCHING in that the next point in the search has to have a lower Sum of Squared Errors (SSE), i.e., there has to be a systematic continuity. For example, if we start at x1 (see Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>), SSB-NLS will definitely take us only to x2 and never to x3 or x4. But in GA, if we start at x1, it will not only consider x2 in the next step (as NLS does) but also consider x3 or/and x4! In other words, in GA, in each iteration, the program not only maintains the systematic search as the sequential search-based NLS does, but also searches for nonsequential points. So, it keeps trying random values as well simultaneously. This is the strength of GA. It combines the unique advantage of sequential search-based NLS and that of the random search to the maximum advantage. So, it has a much better chance to reach the global optima.</p><p>Also, one can argue that by trying NLS with different starting values, one should theoretically reach the global optimal. However, the issue is that we currently do not have any algorithm to help us carry out such "searching for initial values." Take the Bass model, where we typically have m in the order of thousands, p in the order of thousandths and hundredths, and q in the order of hundredths and tenths. This means that with just three parameters, there are literally millions of starting value combinations that are possible. As mentioned above, we do not have a systematic way to check all these values. This problem becomes multifold:</p><p>(1) if we have a model such as the Generalized Bass Model <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bass et al. 1994)</ref> or cross-national diffusion models as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Kumar and Krishnan (2002)</ref> that have more than six parameters, and/or</p><p>(2) if we have only few datapoints, in which case the solution space becomes very rough, and/or</p><p>(3) if we have those few points not in any "smooth" manner but in a very noisy manner as evidenced by the data used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Van den Bulte and Lilien (1997)</ref>. of points to cover the region where the parameter estimates are known to exist, evaluating the objective function (least squares in this case) at each of the points, and taking the smallest value of the objective function as the optimal value. This can give precision of one "cell." Clearly, the grid must be fine enough so that the objective function is constant within each cell. Halving the cell edge length leads to 2 3 times as many function evaluations. The grid search method is extremely costly because it makes a large number of unnecessary function evaluations and there is not a scope for learning from past values. Also, the efficiency of grid search degrades as the number of parameter estimates required for estimation increases (e.g., the Nonuniform Influence models and the Generalized Bass Model). Hence, we do not expect the grid search to obtain parameter estimates that are closer to the truth when we restrict the time required for estimation to reasonable limits.</p><p>The GA has, however, two limitations. First, the search can entail many evaluations of the objective function and, consequently, a longer execution time when compared to SSB-NLS. However, with present day computational power this is not a major issue. The second limitation of the GA is that, one has to carefully select the convergence criteria to obtain an optimal solution (further details are in Appendix 1). Although the complexity of coding involved in implementing GA is a major impediment to its widespread applicability, many software packages (GA toolboxes for use with MatLab, S-Plus, C++, and Excel) are being released with wide-ranging functions and applications built into them, and these software packages can be run even on commonly available spreadsheets. A short technical description of how the GA works is given in Appendix 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">GA as an Alternative Estimation</head><p>Tool for the Bass Diffusion Model</p><p>In this section, we have two objectives. First, using simulated data we show that the estimates from GA are similar to estimates from SSB-NLS under commonly encountered error variances and parameter estimate values, provided full datasets are used for estimation. Then, using empirical datasets we compare the performance of GA with SSB-NLS and other techniques proposed in the literature when the data does not contain peak sales, when there is data until peak sales, and when datapoints are added sequentially to post-peak sales data. All the estimates reported in our analyses are median values based on 1,000 repeats of the GA estimation and the standard errors are computed from the standard deviation of the 1,000 estimates obtained from the repeats. The starting values (solution set in the initial iteration) for an estimation run is generated using uniform random values with the appropriate boundary conditions. The stopping rule for an estimation run is as follows: Terminate if the optimal solution string has changed by more than 0.1% in the last 10,000 iterations. The probability of crossover is set at 0.8, and the probability of mutation is set at 0.25. For each iteration, 200 sample solution vectors are generated (in other words, the population size for the estimation is equal to 200).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Properties of the Estimates from GA</head><p>Given that a GA is a simulation-based estimation technique, the finite sample properties of GA estimates 2 need to be established by conducting a Monte Carlo simulation study. The desirable properties of the estimates from NLS routines include (1) approximate normal distribution, and (2) variance of</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">≈ 2 2 d 2 f x t d 2 −1</formula><p>(3) <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Griffiths et al. 1993</ref>). The estimates from GA are reliable if they exhibit these properties of estimates from SSB-NLS. The investigation of the asymptotic properties of the estimates from GA is important for deriving inferences based on the estimates from GA.</p><p>We conducted a simulation experiment to compare the properties of estimates from SSB-NLS, grid search, and GA. In the simulation experiment, we generated a total of 15 cells, where a dataset in each cell has a sample size of T = 17, by manipulating the q/p ratio over three levels <ref type="bibr">(2,</ref><ref type="bibr">5,</ref><ref type="bibr">50)</ref> and the error variance 2 of a mean zero normal random variable over five levels (0.06, 0.24, 0.40, 0.58, 0.78). We manipulated the values of q, p, and error variance to test the robustness of estimates from GA across the range of parameter values and error variances observed in the diffusion literature (Van den Bulte and Lilien 1997). We used the Srinivasan-Mason operationalization for generating the data and add a multiplicative proportional normal random error. Specifically, the data was generated as</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">s t = m * F t − F t − 1 * e (<label>4</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_3">)</formula><p>where e = 1 + norm 0 2 and norm(0 2 ) is a random value from the normal distribution with mean = 0 and variance = 2 . For each of the 15 datasets we estimated the values of p, q, and m using SSB-NLS, grid search, and GA. The values are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">2</ref>. We also plot a histogram of the 1,000 estimates for two datasets in our simulation  experiment: (1) q/p = 2 and 2 = 0 06, and (2) q/p = 50 and 2 = 0 78 as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">3</ref>. These two datasets represent the two extreme ends in our simulation experiment and we use these to illustrate the distribution of estimates from GA.</p><p>Results. The estimates obtained from GA closely resemble the estimates from SSB-NLS and the grid search. The GA estimates also have acceptable standard errors that are proportional to the asymptotic standard errors obtained from the SSB-NLS method. The average deviations (from the true values) of the estimates from GA are 36%, 49%, and 33% for p, q, and m, respectively. Similarly, the average deviations from SSB-NLS are 45%, 58%, and 63% for p, q, and m, respectively, and 33%, 49%, and 45% for p, q, and m, respectively, for grid search. We also observe that the values of the standard errors from GA are consistently lower than the standard errors from SSB-NLS. This implies that GA is able to produce estimates that are more stable (consistent or robust) than SSB-NLS. However, we also need to acknowledge that the lower standard errors from GA as compared to SSB-NLS are an indication of the superiority of the estimation technique only when there is symmetric error in the data. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The estimates from SSB-NLS do not converge for two out of the 15 datasets. GA and the grid search produces estimates that are reliable for all the datasets even when SSB-NLS fails to converge.</p><p>To evaluate if there is any statistical difference between the estimates, the confidence intervals of the estimates from GA and the estimates from SSB-NLS are calculated. If the confidence intervals do not intersect, then the estimates from GA and SSB-NLS estimates are statistically different. The estimates from GA are significantly different from SSB-NLS in only two cases (for dataset 6, q/p = 5 and 2 = 0 06, p GA is significantly different from p SSB-NLS at &lt; 0 05, and for dataset 10, q/p = 5 and 2 = 0 78, m GA is significantly different from m SSB-NLS at &lt; 0 05). The histogram of estimates from dataset 1 (p = 0 03, q = 0 06, m = 100, and 2 = 06) and the estimates from dataset 15 (p = 0 15, q = 0 75, m = 100, and   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>m_15</head><p>Frequency * Dataset 1 has q/p = 2 and error variance = 0 06 and Dataset 15 has q/p = 50 and error variance = 0 78. All the standard errors are computed over 1,000 repeats of the GA estimation.</p><p>2 = 0 78) are provided in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">3</ref>. This figure shows that the estimates obtained from GA are normally distributed even when the error variance is very high (for p_15, q_15, and m_15) and very low (for p_1, q_1, and m_1). Thus, it can be inferred that the parameter estimates obtained from GA are consistent and have the desirable properties of standard statistical techniques 4 and are comparable to SSB-NLS under most commonly encountered.</p><p>Having shown that GA estimation is an appropriate alternative estimation technique for the diffusion models, we now compare the estimates obtained from GA with those from SSB-NLS with respect to the three issues discussed previously.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Estimation with Pre-Peak Sales Data</head><p>Although GA may perform better than SSB-NLS, we need another benchmark to evaluate the performance of GA. Hierarchical Bayesian methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Lenk and Rao 1990)</ref> and Augmented Kalman Filter estimation techniques <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Xie et al. 1997)</ref> have been proposed in the extant literature to overcome the nonconvergence issue of SSB-NLS (with pre-peak sales period data). <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Xie et al. (1997)</ref> show the superiority of the Augmented Kalman Filter (AKF(C-D)) technique over the Hierarchical Bayes method. Hence, we use the <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Xie et al. (1997)</ref> study as our benchmark for evaluating the performance of GA. We also compare the performance of GA with a simple grid search. For comparability purposes, we use the same diffusion datasets-room air conditioners, color television, clothes dryer, ultrasound, mammography, foreign language, and accelerated program-that were used by <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Xie et al. (1997)</ref>. We assess the effectiveness of one step ahead forecasts from each method using the MAD measure. To ensure comparability in the MAD measures we use the priors 5 published in <ref type="bibr">Xie et al. (1997, Appendix A)</ref>. Managers in general are interested in forecasting capability when using diffusion models during the growth phase. Hence, we compare the various techniques on only forecasting performance.</p><p>Sales at Each Time Period. We use the prior values as estimates of the diffusion curve before the product is launched (i.e., for time t = 0). The prior estimates predict sales/adoption at t = 1. We then repeat the above process by advancing one time period in each step until the peak is reached. By taking the mean of all the absolute deviations thus obtained we get the MAD for that dataset. The MAD measures for the AKF(C-D) and AF are obtained from <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Xie et al. (1997)</ref>. The results of our analyses are shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">3a</ref>. The reduction in prediction error as compared with AKF(C-D) ranges from 28% (clothes dryer) to 55% (mammography). In addition to reporting the MAD, we also test if the MAD from the GA estimates is significantly different from the other techniques for each product category using a pairwise test of the absolute deviations in each time period. We use a nonparametric bootstrap methodology for the pairwise tests because it accommodates for the time series nature of the data and does not make any assumptions regarding the distribution of the error terms <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Davison and Hinkley 1997)</ref>. The details of the statistical tests are provided in Appendix 2. We see from Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">3a</ref> that the MAD from GA is significantly lower from AF, and grid search across all product categories and the MAD from GA is significantly lower from AKF(C-D) for all product categories expect foreign language.</p><p>We also assess the prediction errors from GA for the post-peak sales for a diffusion curve. In this case, we compare the prediction errors from GA with AKF(C-D), AF, SSB-NLS, OLS, and grid search. For the post-peak one step forecasts we compute the absolute deviations from time periods t * +1 until the entire data available for estimation is used (note that t * is the peak sales time period). The reduction in prediction error as compared with AKF(C-D) ranges from 56% (clothes dryer) to 71% (mammography). We also performed statistical tests similar to the pre-peak data on the post-peak sales data. We see from Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">3a</ref> that the MAD from GA is significantly lower from AF, grid search, AKF(C-D), and OLS across all product categories and is significantly lower than the MAD for SSB-NLS for all product categories except foreign language for post-peak data as well. Hence, we can infer that the GA provides a viable alternative to current estimation techniques with respect to forecasting of both pre-peak sales and post-peak sales. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Time to Peak Sales and Sales at Peak Time Period. Using the estimates obtained for predicting each period sales we also compare the forecasting capability of GA with grid search and AKF(C-D) for predicting time until peak sales and the sales at peak time period. The results of our analyses are provided in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">3b</ref>. With respect to time until peak sales, the reduction in prediction error as compared with AKF(C-D) ranges from 20% (ultrasound) to 60% (mammography). With respect to sales at peak time period, the reduction in prediction error as compared with AKF(C-D) ranges from 8% (clothes dryer) to 28% (foreign language). The MAD for time to peak sales and sales at peak time period are significantly lower from grid search for all the product categories. Again, the MAD of the GA estimates are significantly lower than the MAD from AKF(C-D) for all product categories except clothes dryer and ultrasound with respect to time to peak sales and is significantly lower than the MAD from AKF(C-D) for all product categories except mammography with respect to sales at peak time period. Next, we will explore the utility of GA in overcoming the initial (starting) values issues faced by SSB-NLS in estimating with data up to peak sales period.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Peak Sales Period Data and Initial Values</head><p>As stated earlier, GA starts by sampling n number of possible solutions from the search space as the population in the first iteration. Hence, by definition GA estimation is not affected by the starting point issues that SSB-NLS faces. To explain this phenomenon in more detail, we provide examples of situations where the SSB-NLS fails to converge (even if the peak sales exists in the data). We used three representative datasets: corn 1943 (Van den Bulte and Lilien 1997), air conditioner, and clothes dryer <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bass et al. 1994</ref>  </p><formula xml:id="formula_4">1 2 * MAD = 1/k K k=1 x k −x k ,</formula><p>where k = number of forecasts for each product category, x k is the observed number of incremental adopters in the kth time interval t k−1 t k , andx k is the predicted value of x k . * * The values for the AF and AKF(C-D) are sourced from <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Xie et al. (1997)</ref>. n.a. = not applicable; reliable estimates were not obtained from OLS. The signs of the coefficients were negative.</p><p>a Significant at &lt; 0 01; b Significant at &lt; 0 05; c Significant at &lt; 0 10. Grid search 2 1 a 3 8 a 1 8 1 2 2 1 a 14 3 a 4 1 a AKF(C-D) 1 9 b 2 6 b 1 2 1 0 1 7 b 11 1 a 2 9 a GA 1 4 1 8 0 9 0 8 0 68 6 7 1 3</p><p>Sales at peak time period MAD * * Grid search 43 2 a 130 8 a 69 4 a 9 7 a 11 2 a 5 9 1 1 9 a AKF(C-D) 38 6 c 104 1 b 55 7 6 4 a 9 1 4 5 7 8 b GA 30 5 8 5 7 5 0 9 4 8 8 5 3 2 5 7 * MAD = 1/k K k=1 actpt − predpt k , where k = number of forecasts for each product category, actpt = actual peak sales time period, and predpt = predicted peak sales time period based on estimates using data up to time period t. * * MAD = 1/k K k=1 actps− predps k , where k = number of forecasts for each product category, actps = actual peak time period sales, and predps = predicted peak time period sales based on estimates using data up to time period t.</p><p>a Significant at &lt; 0 01; b Significant at &lt; 0 05; c Significant at &lt; 0 10.</p><p>We censored these datasets so that they only contain datapoints until the peak sales time period. The peak sales for the various datasets were t = 11, t = 8, and t = 8 for corn 1943, air conditioner, and clothes dryer, respectively. In SSB-NLS, when we first used the starting points recommended by <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Sultan et al. (1990)</ref>, i.e., p = 0 03, q = 0 38, and m = 1,000, the SSB-NLS algorithm failed to converge as shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">4</ref>. Subsequently, we tried different combinations of starting values in a systematic manner. Specifically, the values of p were changed by 0.01 in the interval of p = 0 001 to p = 0 09. Similarly, the values of q were changed from 0.1 to 0.9 in the interval of 0.1 and the values of m were changed from 500 to 1,100 in intervals of 50 for air conditioner and clothes dryer. In a total of 1,053 combinations were used for (9 for p, 9 for q, and 13 for m) for air conditioner and clothes dryer. However, for corn 1943, we varied p from 0.0001 to 0.01 in increments of 0.0001, q from 0.1 to 0.9 in increments of 0.1, and m from 100 to 500 in increments of 100. Hence, we used a total of 4,500 combinations (100 for p, 9 for q, and 5 for m) for corn 1943. 7 SSB-NLS failed to converge in 25% of the cases for corn 1943, in 38% for air conditioner, and in 41% for clothes dryer. 8  We then estimated these datasets using GA and used the estimates from GA as starting values for SSB-NLS. We see that in all these cases, the SSB-NLS algorithm attained convergence and the estimates from SSB-NLS are similar to the starting values provided by GA. We compared the estimates from NLS and the starting values provided by GA using a t-test. The starting value provided to SSB-NLS is the mean value of 100 estimations based on GA (the standard error of the starting values can hence be calculated based on these 100 starting values). The SSB-NLS procedure provides the mean and standard error of the estimates. Hence, the confidence intervals of the starting values from GA and the estimates from SSB-NLS can be calculated. If the confidence intervals do not intersect, then the starting values and the SSB-NLS estimates are statistically different.</p><p>From these tests we found that the estimates from SSB-NLS and the starting values provided by GA are not significantly different from each other. Thus, we find that GA estimation allows us to overcome the starting value problem faced by the SSB-NLS in data until peak sales. Our analyses also highlight the severity of the starting value issues when using SSB-NLS to estimate the Bass model. Now, we will show how the GA estimation fares better in the post-peak sales data-based estimation as well.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.">Bias and Systematic Change in Parameter</head><p>Estimates To evaluate the performance of GA with respect to the bias and systematic change in parameter estimates, we performed two tests. We first employed the same datasets used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Van den Bulte and Lilien (1997)</ref> and replicated their analysis to ensure that we were able to obtain the same results. Second, we used the GA technique in place of SSB-NLS and repeated the exercise. While repeating what Van den Bulte and Lilien (1997) did, we made a minor, although materially insignificant, change to their original analysis. They used the following equation to check whether the dataset length affects the estimates systematically:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">log Y irt = ir + 1r log X t + it + 2r log t + it + e irt</formula><p>(5) where r = p, q, or m.</p><p>In Equation ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>), the subscript i indicates the innovation (i.e., the product), Y irt is the estimate of parameter r (i.e., p, q, or m) corresponding to t + on the right-hand side of the equation, and ir is the innovation-specific constant. After estimating the Bass model on the datasets of 11 products 9 (each with multiple truncations in the end), we used the following regression (in place of Equation ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>)) to explore the impact of truncation of a dataset on the estimates of the three parameters, namely, p, q, and m:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">Y irt − Y ir Y ir = 1r X t + it + 2r t + it + e irt (<label>6</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_7">)</formula><p>Our dependent variable Y irt − Y ir /Y ir directly measures for each dataset the extent of bias at the innovation level and, hence, we do not need the innovation specific constant used by Van den Bulte and Lilien (1997) on the right-hand side of their Equation (5).</p><p>We use Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_6">6</ref>) for our analyses because Equation (5) suffers from being confounded by level effects when estimates from various datasets are pooled. It is quite possible that the market potential, m, is high when the cumulative sales for a product is high, thus resulting in significant coefficients for x t + and t + irrespective of the amount of systematic change in the estimates. Similar arguments can be forwarded   </p><formula xml:id="formula_8">q ir t − q ir /q ir r = 2 −0 0000968 0 026 −0 004 0 078 0 000015 −0 00414 0 090 p ir t − p ir /p ir r = 3 −0 0000277 0 001 −0 000245 0 022 0 0000584</formula><p>−0 0032 0 026 * We have a sample size of 44 because we removed tetracycline from our analysis because it was monthly data for 1.5 years without any indication of when the product was introduced relative to the time period available. We do not expect a new product to have a significant change in diffusion pattern over 1.5 years. Based on the findings of <ref type="bibr">Putsis (1996)</ref>, that the estimates of the Bass model are sensitive to the level of aggregation (monthly, quarterly, semiannual, and annual) in the diffusion data, we also aggregated the semiannual data for the CT-scanner to annual values, given that the rest of the data were at the annual values.</p><p>a Significant at &lt; 0 01; b Significant at &lt; 0 05; c Significant at &lt; 0 10.</p><p>for the coefficient of imitation and the time period t + .</p><p>The coefficient of imitation q is normally high for highly left-skewed data that require more datapoints for estimation with SSB-NLS (the peak sales occurs much later in the left-skewed data as compared to others). A more conservative test would be to normalize the estimates with respect to systematic change and then evaluate the influence of x t + and t + . We hence believe that Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_6">6</ref>) captures the concept we are trying to address better. The regression results are shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">5</ref>. We obtain the same effects that Van den Bulte and Lilien (1997) report: (1) either 1m or 2m was significant and positive, (2) either 1q or m estimate, the lower the q estimate, and the higher the p estimate. In other words, if one adds datapoints from later years in the estimation, the estimates of m and p increase while that of q decreases systematically. The R 2 values for our operationalization range from 5% to 34% while the R 2 values from Van den Bulte and Lilien (1997) range from 10% to 42%.</p><p>In the next step, we performed a similar analysis on the 11 datasets with estimates obtained from GA estimates. The results are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">5</ref>. Overall, as can be seen from the table we do not observe the effects found from SSB-NLS. Note from Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">5</ref> that although there are some changes in estimates as we change the length of the dataset, those variations are not related in any systematic fashion to the number of datapoints used for estimation or cumulative sales. In other words, the coefficients in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">5</ref> indicate that neither of the independent variables ( 1r = cumulative sales and 2r = time period is significantly related to the variation in the parameters occurring as datapoints from later years are added to the dataset. This clearly demonstrates that the findings of Van den Bulte and Lilien (1997) and later of <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bemmaor and Lee (2002)</ref> regarding the systematic change do not show up when GA estimation is used in place of SSB-NLS estimation.</p><p>We also compared the SSE from SSB-NLS and GA for each product category and censoring level. We found that GA consistently outperformed or was at least equal to SSB-NLS in terms of in-sample fit. GA provided an improvement of at least 1% in the SSE when compared with the SSE from SSB-NLS. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> When we subjected the GA estimates of the GBM model to the same experiments we conducted on the Bass model earlier, we still found no evidence of the systematic change and bias.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Conclusions and Future Research</head><p>In this paper, we have discussed in detail key problems that have been raised regarding SSB-NLS. These are: nonconvergence with pre-peak sales period dataset, need for appropriate starting values with data until peak sales, and systematic change and bias that are a function of the dataset length with postpeak sales data. We showed that GA is able to efficiently produce better parameter estimates as evident in the MSE and MAD when compared with SSB-NLS under the scenarios mentioned above. We find that the estimates from GA perform better than current alternatives such as AKF(C-D) and HB in providing forecasts of new product sales before peak. Also, by definition, GA does not suffer from starting value issues. We also find that estimates from GA do not suffer from bias and systematic changes observed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Van den Bulte and Lilien (1997)</ref>. Overall, the above benefits make GA an excellent candidate for timeinvariant estimation of parameters of the highly nonlinear Bass model. In fact, reliable estimation of the diffusion curve before peak sales would allow managers to efficiently allocate marketing resources.</p><p>Researchers can further investigate the utility of GA as a tool for estimating marketing models that do not have the luxury of large datasets. Previous studies in marketing have used GA as an algorithm to either provide optimal advertising schedules <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Naik et al. 1997)</ref>, optimal product design <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Balakrishnan and Jacob 1996)</ref>, optimal competitive strategies <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Midgley et al. 1997)</ref>, or optimal customer contact and resource allocation rules <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Venkatesan and Kumar 2004)</ref>. The applicability of GA in estimation of continuous time mixture models is also an interesting venue for research.</p><p>GA can prove to be an excellent estimation technique for complex nonlinear models with less datapoints. Also, given the flexibility of GA, researchers can develop complex diffusion models (which may or may not have a closed-form solution) that address issues such as the influence of marketing-mix variables on multiple generations of technology and the diffusion of innovations across multiple countries <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Parker 1994</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">, Talukdar et al. 2002</ref>, take-off of new products <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Tellis et al. 2003)</ref>, indirect network externality effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Basu et al. 2003)</ref>, competitive marketingmix reactions to new product introductions <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Shankar et al. 1998)</ref>, dynamics of brand level diffusion <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Krishnan et al. 2000)</ref>, and nonuniform diffusion of products <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Easingwood et al. 1983)</ref>. We fitted the NUI model using GA and a two-step iterative SSB-NLS technique and compared the parameter estimates from the above two methods. However, we did not find any significant difference in the performance of the estimates (measured in terms of MAD) between the two methods. Given that GA is able to produce better parameter estimates of the Bass model when there is less data and when the data are noisy, it would be worthwhile to investigate if the performance of GA improves when more complex models are estimated with less number of datapoints.</p><p>Also, the availability of GA even in commonly available spreadsheets makes GA very useful for managers who are interested in performing sensitivity analyses on the various parameters under their control, especially during the pre-peak sales time phase. Future researchers can use extensions of the Bass model that incorporate competitive effects and GA to assess the equilibrium state of various marketing strategies for new products in competitive markets. Future researchers can also investigate the extent to which the performance of GA depends on the fitness function that is used in the analyses. For example, in the case of the Bass diffusion models, do the parameter estimates obtained from GA differ if the fitness function is minimizing the first difference of each period sales function with respect to the parameter than if the SSE is minimized directly?</p><p>Marketing Science 23(3), pp. 451-464, © 2004 INFORMS Appendix 1. Iteration Mechanism for a GA A simple GA is composed of three operators: reproduction, crossover, and mutation. Using these three operations, the GA iterates through the following three steps.</p><p>Step 1. Reproduction is a process in which individual strings of a generation (parent generation) are copied to the next generation (child) according to their objective function values, f . We can think of the objective function f in our case to be the SSE between the predicted values of sales and the actual value of sales. Selecting strings according to their fitness values means that strings with a higher fitness value have a higher probability of contributing one or more offspring in the next generation. The probabilities could depend on the proportion of solutions present in a parent generation, based on linear ranking system of the solutions or based on a tournament selection. This operator is an artificial version of natural selection, a Darwinian survival of the fittest among string creatures.</p><p>Step 2. After reproduction, simple crossover may proceed in two steps. First, members of the newly reproduced strings (or new generation) are paired at random. Second, each pair of strings undergoes crossing over as follows: an integer position K along the string is selected uniformly at random between one and the string length less one 1 l − 1 . Two new strings are created by swapping all characters between positions K + 1 and l. The mechanics of reproduction and crossover are simple, involving random number generation, string copies, and some partial string exchanges. Nonetheless, the combined emphasis of reproduction and the structured, though randomized, information exchange of crossover give GA much of their power.</p><p>Step 3. Mutation is the process of randomly changing a cell in the string or the solution vector. Mutation is the process by which the algorithm attempts to ensure a globally optimal solution. If the algorithm is trapped in a local minimum, the mutation operator randomly shifts the solution to another point in the search space, thus removing itself out of the trap.</p><p>The above steps are repeated until the algorithm is halted. The decision to halt the program can depend either on a pre-fixed number of generations, the time elapsed in the evolutionary process, or the change in the optimal solution in the previous n generations. The composition of the final generation of strings-the best strings-is the GA's solution to the problem. It should be noted that when new strings are created, the old ones (those belonging to the previous generation) are discarded. Because the reproduction process tends to choose the "fittest" members of a generation, the generations tend to evolve. Thus, an initial population of relatively undistinguished solutions evolves to yield a set of solutions that cover the optimal region in the final generation. To obtain the optimal solution, one can either use a gradient search algorithm such as hill climbing from the mean value in the final generation or use the solution with the best fitness in the last generation as the optimal solution. The decision on which method to choose to find the optimal solution vector depends on the criterion used to terminate the iterations. For example, if the iterations are stopped because the best solution string does not change by more than 0.1% in the last n iterations, then using the best solution in the last iteration is a good option. On the other hand, if we stop the iterations after a pre-fixed number n, then searching for the optimal solution using a hill-climbing algorithm would be a better option.</p><p>The operations crossover and mutation are not performed for every reproduction. The probability of a string being selected for crossover is proportional to the string's fitness. Each operation is assigned a particular probability of occurrence or application. For example, if the probability of crossover is 0.6, 60 out of every 100 strings undergo crossover. Likewise, if the probability of mutation is 0.03, 3 out of every 100 strings undergo mutation. The probability of mutation is traditionally lower than the probability of crossover, because the primary function of a mutation operator is to remove the solution from a local minimum. The probabilities are assigned based on the characteristics of the problem. For example, if the problem is characterized by a turbulent environment (i.e., if the solution space is not uniform all over), the probability of crossover and mutation are chosen to be high.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix 2. Statistical Tests for Comparing Forecasting Accuracy Across Product Categories</head><p>Pre-Peak Sales Data In Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">3a</ref>, we report the MAD of the one step ahead forecasts starting from the first datapoint until the peak sales datapoint for the pre-peak sales data. Specifically, we use prior values as estimates of the diffusion curve before the product is launched (i.e., for time t = 0). The prior estimates predict sales/adoption at t = 1. We then repeat the above process by advancing one time period each step until the peak is reached. By taking the mean of all the absolute deviations thus obtained we get the MAD for that dataset. We report the MAD for all estimation techniques across product categories in Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">3a and 3b</ref>. While performing statistical tests comparing the one step ahead forecast absolute deviations across different estimation techniques, we need to consider the following features:</p><p>(1) The scale of the absolute deviations may be related to the number of time periods used for estimation. For example, the absolute deviation obtained from forecasting the third time period based on two time periods for estimation may be higher than the absolute deviation obtained from forecasting the fourth time period based on three time periods for estimation.</p><p>(2) The estimated values of sales are correlated across time periods.</p><p>(3) The error distribution need not necessarily be normal.</p><p>To accommodate for the above features we perform a pairwise comparison of absolute deviations using a nonparametric test-bootstrap resampling for time series data <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Davison and Hinkley 1997)</ref>. The test is performed as follows.</p><p>Let us consider the case of comparing the absolute deviations of one step ahead forecasts from AF with those from GA for data with room air conditioners for pre-peak data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Estimating Errors</head><p>Step 1. Estimate the sales data ŝ GA t using GA with the room air conditioner pre-peak sales data s t .</p><p>Step 2. Compute the errors GA t for each time period (10 time periods in this case) from the estimated sales data and the true sales data GA t =ŝ GA t − s t .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Generate Simulated Sales Datasets</head><p>Step 3. Assuming that the errors are exchangeable, sample with replacement, for example, 10 error values sampGA i from the errors computed in Step 2. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">16</ref> The values of the subscript i range from 1 to 10 in this case, corresponding to the 10 time periods of pre-peak sales data for room air conditioners.</p><p>Step 4. Generate simulated sales data as S simul =ŝ GA t + sampGA i . For example, for the first time period, the simulated sales data is generated by adding the error value that was sampled first i = 1 in Step 3 with the estimated value of sales from GA for the first time period.</p><p>Step 5. Repeat Steps 3 and 4 one thousand times to generate one thousand simulated datasets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computing the Distribution of MAD</head><p>For each of the simulated datasets compute the pairwise absolute deviations as follows:</p><p>Step 6. Compute the one step ahead forecast absolute deviations from AF by estimating the Bass model using AF and censoring the simulated datasets from time period = 0 until time period = 9. The absolute deviation (AD) for time period 3 for simulated data 1 is given as ADAF 3 1 = ŝ AFsimul 3 1 − S simul 3 1 .ŝ AFsimul 3 1 is the predicted value of sales for time period 3 based on the estimates from AF using the first two time periods of data from simulated dataset 1.</p><p>Step 7. Compute the one step ahead forecast absolute deviation from GA similar to the procedure followed for AF. The absolute deviation for time period 3 for simulated data 1 is given as ADGA 3 1 = ŝ GAsimul 3 1 − S simul 3 1 .</p><p>Step 8. Compute the pairwise deviation by computing the difference between the absolute deviations from AF and GA. For example, the pairwise deviation (PD) for time period 3 using simulated data 1 is given as PD AFGA 3 1 = ADAF 3 1 − ADGA 3 1 .</p><p>Using the above process we can compute 10,000 pairwise deviations (10 pairwise deviations for each of the 1,000 simulated datasets). The confidence interval of the pairwise deviations will enable us to infer if the forecast errors from GA are similar (confidence interval contains zero), better (confidence interval is less than zero), or worse (confidence interval is greater than zero) as compared to the forecast errors from AF. The above process can be repeated for absolute deviations of post-peak sales data, predictions of time to peak sales, and predictions of sales at peak time period.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Sample Diffusion Path of a New Product Innovation</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure2NLS vs. GA</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>a</head><label></label><figDesc>Values in parentheses represent standard errors. n.a. = not applicable, the algorithm did not converge. * * Significant at &lt; 0 05.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3Distributions of Parameter Estimates from GA for the Simulated Datasets 1 and 15 *</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>015 * We did not find any significant difference between the SSB-NLS estimates and the starting values provided from GA. n.a. = not applicable; the estimates do not converge. Values in parentheses are the standard errors of the estimates.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Estimation technique = GA N = 44 m ir t − m ir /m ir r = 1</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Evolution of Econometric Estimation Techniques for the Bass Model</figDesc><table><row><cell>Author</cell><cell>Estimation method</cell><cell>Advantages</cell><cell>Drawbacks</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results from the Simulation Study a</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Error</cell><cell></cell><cell>True values</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Estimates from SSB-NLS</cell><cell cols="3">Estimates from grid search</cell><cell></cell><cell>Estimates from GA</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>q/p</cell><cell>variance</cell><cell>p  *</cell><cell>q  *</cell><cell>m  *</cell><cell>p SSB-NLS</cell><cell>q SSB-NLS</cell><cell>m SSB-NLS</cell><cell>p GS</cell><cell>q GS</cell><cell>m GS</cell><cell>p GA</cell><cell>q GA</cell><cell>m GA</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>).</figDesc><table><row><cell>Marketing Science 23(3), pp. 451-464, © 2004 INFORMS</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 3a Prediction</head><label>3a</label><figDesc>Errors of OneStep Ahead Forecasts from GA * *</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Room air</cell><cell>Color</cell><cell>Clothes</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Foreign</cell><cell>Accelerated</cell></row><row><cell>Criterion</cell><cell>Method</cell><cell>conditioners</cell><cell>television</cell><cell>dryer</cell><cell>Ultrasound</cell><cell>Mammography</cell><cell>language</cell><cell>program</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Pre-peak sales</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>MAD  *</cell><cell>AF</cell><cell>524 3 a</cell><cell>2 714 4 a</cell><cell>368 2 a</cell><cell>5 9 a</cell><cell>5 1 a</cell><cell>1 5 b</cell><cell>3 6 a</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Grid search</cell><cell>503 7 a</cell><cell>1 786 4 a</cell><cell>305 9 a</cell><cell>5 5 a</cell><cell>4 8 a</cell><cell>2 4 b</cell><cell>3 4 a</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>AKF(C-D)</cell><cell>261 0 a</cell><cell>971 0 b</cell><cell>211 0 c</cell><cell>4 8 a</cell><cell>2 7 a</cell><cell>1 0</cell><cell>2 8 a</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>GA</cell><cell>148 5</cell><cell>620 0</cell><cell>150 2</cell><cell>3 1</cell><cell>1 2</cell><cell>0 5</cell><cell>1 4</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Post-peak sales</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>MAD  *</cell><cell>OLS</cell><cell>791 3 a</cell><cell>2 523 0 a</cell><cell>401 7 a</cell><cell>n.a.</cell><cell>n.a.</cell><cell>n.a.</cell><cell>n.a.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>SSB-NLS</cell><cell>334 3 a</cell><cell>1 083 8 a</cell><cell>296 0 a</cell><cell>4 8 a</cell><cell>4 2 a</cell><cell>1 0</cell><cell>2 5 c</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>AF</cell><cell>558 3 a</cell><cell>3 835 4 a</cell><cell>103 6 a</cell><cell>17 0 a</cell><cell>2 9 a</cell><cell>2 4 b</cell><cell>5 0 a</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Grid search</cell><cell>61 8 a</cell><cell>267 1 a</cell><cell>94 6 a</cell><cell>4 2 a</cell><cell>3 5 a</cell><cell>2 2 b</cell><cell>3 4 a</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>AKF(C-D)</cell><cell>55 0 b</cell><cell>241 0 a</cell><cell>77 0 b</cell><cell>4 6 a</cell><cell>3 1 a</cell><cell>2 1 b</cell><cell>2 2 a</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>GA</cell><cell>34 2</cell><cell>150 8</cell><cell>5 6 4</cell><cell>2 8</cell><cell>0 9</cell><cell>0 8</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 3b Prediction</head><label>3b</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Room air</cell><cell>Color</cell><cell>Clothes</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Foreign</cell><cell>Accelerated</cell></row><row><cell>Criterion</cell><cell>Method</cell><cell>conditioners</cell><cell>television</cell><cell>dryer</cell><cell>Ultrasound</cell><cell>Mammography</cell><cell>language</cell><cell>program</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Time to peak sales</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>MAD  *</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>Errors for Time to Peak Sales and Sales at Peak Time Period</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Influence of Starting Values on SSB-NLS Convergence</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Starting value</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>SSB-NLS estimates</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Product</cell><cell>p  *</cell><cell>q  *</cell><cell>m  *</cell><cell>p</cell><cell>q</cell><cell>M</cell></row><row><cell>Corn 1943</cell><cell>0 03</cell><cell>0 38</cell><cell>500</cell><cell>n.a.</cell><cell>n.a.</cell><cell>n.a.</cell></row><row><cell>Air conditioner</cell><cell>0 03</cell><cell>0 38</cell><cell>500</cell><cell>n.a.</cell><cell>n.a.</cell><cell>n.a.</cell></row><row><cell>Clothes dryer</cell><cell>0 03</cell><cell>0 38</cell><cell>500</cell><cell>n.a.</cell><cell>n.a.</cell><cell>n.a.</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">After using starting values from GA  *</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Bias and Systematic Change</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Independent variables</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Dependent variables</cell><cell>Cumulative sales: x t +</cell><cell>Time period: t +</cell><cell>R 2  *</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Estimation technique = SSB-NLS N = 44</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">The package "Evolver" is used for estimation using GA. Evolver is an Excel-based add-on package distributed by Palisade, Inc. for conducting analysis using GA.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Marketing Science 23(3), pp.451-464, © 2004 INFORMS   </note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">The bias in the parameter estimates can also be checked from the contour plots of the residuals obtained from the parameter estimates.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">In the case of GA, the prior is used to provide a prediction of sales/adoption at time period t = 1 before the product is launched.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">We also compared the performance of GA and SSB-NLS with multiple step ahead forecasts and other datasets such as cellular phone diffusion in Western Europe. GA performs better than SSB-NLS even here. The results can be obtained from the authors.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">We use different ranges for corn 1943 because it was based on adoption data and the cumulative adoption was in the range of 100 before peak sales. Also, the data for corn 1943 was highly left skewed indicating a low p estimate. SSB-NLS converged only 10% of the time when the 1,053 combinations used for air conditioner and clothes dryer were used for corn 1943, due to large starting values for m.8  We need to qualify that SSB-NLS would fail to converge less frequently if the starting values were based on experience (or management judgment). We use the above procedure for illustrative purposes only.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">We have a sample size of 44 because we removed tetracycline from our analysis. Tetracycline had monthly data for 1.5 years without any indication of when the product was introduced relative to the time period available. We do not expect a new product to have a significant change in diffusion pattern over 1.5 years. Based on the findings ofPutsis (1996), that the estimates of the Bass model are sensitive to the level of aggregation (monthly, quarterly, semiannual, and annual) in the diffusion data, we also aggregated the semiannual data for the CT-scanner to annual values, given that the rest of the data were at the annual values.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">2q was significant and negative, or (3) either 1p or 2p was significant and positive. 10 This led them to conclude that the longer the dataset or the larger the cumulative sales at the last datapoint, the higher the 10 Our choice for Equation (6) is questionable if we do not observe the same phenomenon as Van den Bulte and Lilien (1997) on the estimates from SSB-NLS. However, we do observe the same phenomenon as Van den Bulte and Lilien (1997).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="11">We need to compare the SSE of the estimates from GA with those from SSB-NLS in this case because the bias and systematic change in estimates from GA may not occur even if the estimates are suboptimal as compared to SSB-NLS (in other words, if the GA estimates have lower SSE as compared to the SSB-NLS estimates). However, we find that the estimates from GA have lower SSE as compared to the estimates from SSB-NLS, hence, ruling out the alternate explanation.Venkatesan, Krishnan, and Kumar: Alternative to Nonlinear Least Squares Marketing Science 23(3), pp. 451-464, © 2004 INFORMS</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="12">The random numbers need to be generated accounting for restrictions on the range of each individual coefficient.13  We use uniform random numbers for this case for lack of any distributional assumptions on the parameters.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="15">This refers to the solution string that produces the minimal sum of squared errors (or fitness) in that particular generation.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank the editor, area editor, and the four reviewers for their comments on this manuscript. They also thank the participants of the Texas Faculty Consortium-2000, Dallas, Texas, and the INFORMS Marketing Science Conference 2000, UCLA, Los Angeles, California, Frank M. Bass, Rajesh Chandy, Ed Blair, Scott Baggett, and Kumar Mehta for their comments on an earlier draft of this paper.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix A. Estimation of Diffusion Models</head><p>Using GA</p><p>GA <ref type="bibr">(Goldberg 1989, Dorsey and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Mayer 1995)</ref> is a parallel search algorithm that is based upon Darwin's theory of evolution. For our case, we use the <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Srinivasan and Mason (1986)</ref> operationalization of the Bass model (Equation (1)) for estimation using GA. The estimation proceeds as follows:</p><p>Solution String: 12 p q m . Fitness Function:</p><p>where x t = actual sales andx t = m F t − F t − 1 .</p><p>Step 1. Generate 1,000 random 13 candidate solution strings to create generation i = 1.</p><p>Step 2. Select candidate solution vectors for iteration i + 1 from solution strings in iteration i. Solution vectors with a lower SSE have a higher probability of being selected for iteration i + 1.</p><p>Step 3. Perform crossover and mutation 14 on the candidate solution vectors to generate a solution set for iteration i + 1.</p><p>Step 4. Compute fitness value for solution vectors and the optimal solution string 15 in iteration i + 1.</p><p>Step 5. Proceed to Step 2 if the optimal solution string has changed by more than 0.1% in the last 10,000 iterations; else terminate. Appendix 1.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Genetic algorithms of product design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Balakrishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Varghese</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Jacob</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1105" to="1118" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new product growth model for consumer durables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Frank</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="227" />
			<date type="published" when="1969-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why the Bass model fits without decision variables</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Frank</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Trichy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Krishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dipak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Jain</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Indirect network externality effects on product attributes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amiya</forename><surname>Basu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tridib</forename><surname>Mazumdar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Raj</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="221" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">We give equal probability for sampling each error value</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>In other words, we assume that the errors have a uniform distribution</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of heterogeneity and ill-conditioning on diffusion model parameter estimates</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Albert</forename><surname>Bemmaor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Janghyuk</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="220" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Davison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Hinkley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Bootstrap Methods and Their Applications. Cambridge Series in Statistical and Probabilistic Mathematics</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, U.K</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Asymptotic results for genetic algorithms with applications to nonlinear estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Del Moral</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Miclo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Theoretical Aspects of Evolutionary Computation</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kallel</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Naudts</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="439" to="494" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Genetic algorithms for estimation problems with multiple optima, nondifferentiability, and other irregular features</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Dorsey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Walter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Mayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. Econom. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="53" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A non-uniform influence innovation diffusion model of new product acceptance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Easingwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Vijay Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="272" to="296" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From density to destiny: Using spatial dimension of sales data for early prediction of new product success</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tal</forename><surname>Garber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Goldenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barak</forename><surname>Libai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="419" to="428" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Genetic Algorithms in Search, Optimization and Machine Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Reading, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Learning and Practicing Econometrics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Judge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<publisher>John Wiley and Sons</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effect of price on the demand for durables: Modeling, estimation, and findings</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Jain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ram</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Dipak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bus. and Econom. Statist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="170" />
			<date type="published" when="1990-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impact of a late entrant on the diffusion of a new product or service</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Trichy</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Krishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="269" to="278" />
			<date type="published" when="2000-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multinational diffusion models: An alternative framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Trichy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Krishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="318" to="330" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New model from old: Forecasting product adoption by hierarchical Bayes procedures</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lenk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Amber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="42" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the accuracy of statistical procedures in Microsoft Excel 97</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Mccullough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Berry</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Statist. and Data Anal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="37" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Breeding competitive strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Midgley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lee</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Marks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="257" to="275" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using advance purchase orders to forecast new product sales</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Moe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="347" to="364" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Planning media schedules in the presence of dynamic advertising quality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Prasad</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Naik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Murali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alan</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Mantrala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sawyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="214" to="234" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aggregate diffusion forecasting models in marketing: A critical review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Philip</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internat. J. Forecasting</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="353" to="380" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parameter variation and new product diffusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Willam</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Putsis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Jr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Forecasting</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="257" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimation techniques for macro diffusion models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Willam</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Putsis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Jr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">New-Product Diffusion Models</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vijay</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eitan</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yoram</forename><surname>Wind</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="293" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evolutionary algorithms and gradient search: Similarities and differences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ralf</forename><surname>Salomon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. on Evolutionary Comput</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Nonlinear Regression</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A F</forename><surname>Seber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wild</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>John Wiley and Sons</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">92</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximum likelihood estimation for an innovation diffusion model of new product acceptance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Schmittlein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Late mover advantage: How innovative late entrants outsell pioneers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Shankar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Venkatesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="54" to="70" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Lakshman Krishnamurthi</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Krishnan</forename><surname>Venkatesan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Alternative to Nonlinear Least Squares</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">464</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="464" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonlinear least squares estimation of new product diffusion models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Charlotte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Mason</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="178" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A metaanalysis of diffusion models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sultan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Fareena</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Donald</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Farley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="70" to="77" />
			<date type="published" when="1990-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating new product diffusion across products and countries</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Debabrata</forename><surname>Talukdar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sudhir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Ainslie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="114" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The international takeoff of new products: The role of economics, culture, and country innovativeness</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gerard</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Stremersch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eden</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="188" to="208" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bias and systematic change in the parameter estimates of macro-level diffusion models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Van Den Bulte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gary</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Christophe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lilien</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="338" to="353" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A customer lifetime value framework for customer selection and resource allocation strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rajkumar</forename><surname>Venkatesan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing. Forthcoming</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Systematic changes in parameters of macro-level diffusion models: A further inquiry</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rajkumar</forename><surname>Venkatesan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Trichy</forename><surname>Krishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Marketing Science Conference</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Los Angeles, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of California at Los Angeles</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Kalman filter estimation of new product diffusion models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jinhong</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><forename type="middle">Michael</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marvin</forename><surname>Sirbu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qiong</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="378" to="393" />
			<date type="published" when="1997-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
