<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Advertising Competition Under Consumer Inertia</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Bibek</forename><surname>Banerjee</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Subir</forename><surname>Bandyopadhyay</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><roleName>Dr</roleName><surname>Banerjee</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Marketing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Indian Institute of Management</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>380015</postCode>
									<settlement>Vastrapur</settlement>
									<region>Ahmedabad</region>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Walker College of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Appalachian State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>28608</postCode>
									<settlement>Boone</settlement>
									<region>North Carolina</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">School of Business and Economics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Indiana University Northwest</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>3400, 46408-1197</postCode>
									<settlement>Broadway, Gary</settlement>
									<region>Indiana</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Appala-chian State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Publication details, including instructions for authors and subscription information: http://pubsonline.informs.org Advertising Competition Under Consumer Inertia</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.22.1.131.12843</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-07-06T11:27+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Inertia</term>
					<term>Duopoly</term>
					<term>Advertising Competition</term>
					<term>Game Theory</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Please scroll down for article-it is on subsequent pages</head><p>With 12,500 members from nearly 90 countries, INFORMS is the largest international association of operations research (O.R.) and analytics professionals and students. INFORMS provides unique networking and learning opportunities for individual professionals, and organizations of all types and sizes, to better understand and use O.R. and analytics tools and methods to transform strategic visions and achieve better outcomes. For more information on INFORMS, its publications, membership, or meetings visit http://www.informs.org</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Models of advertising competition and its effects on consumer behavior and market performance have two broad schools. One looks at advertising as a channel that provides valuable information to consumers, enabling them to make rational choices by reducing informational product differentiation. The other school views advertising as a device that persuades consumers by means of intangible and/or psychic differentiators. It creates differentiation among products <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Comanor and Wilson 1974)</ref>, which at times may not be real <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Tirole 1990)</ref>. This is especially true for most "feel" products, such as beer, cigarettes, soft drinks, perfumes, etc.</p><p>However, advertising in the extant literature plays a predominantly unidimensional role. For instance, the large body of literature on informative advertising looks at it as a tool for information dissemination, announcing a brand's existence, available locations, important attributes, price, quality, etc. <ref type="bibr">(namely, Nelson 1970</ref><ref type="bibr">(namely, Nelson , 1974</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Butters 1977;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Grossman and Shapiro 1984)</ref>. On the other hand, the literature on persuasive advertising, which is relatively scarce, uses advertis-ADVERTISING COMPETITION UNDER CONSUMER INERTIA ing as a device to persuade people to buy a particular product or brand <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Koh and Leung 1992)</ref>.</p><p>Although there are situations in which either of the advertising roles (awareness and persuasion) is used separately by marketers (e.g., solely informational features in localized retail advertising, vis-à-vis TV advertising), firms often use advertising as a mix element that informs and persuades simultaneously. For example, a typical beer commercial will contain product/brand-related information (e.g., draft, lager, light), but concurrently the creative strategy contains elements that have nothing to do with the product per se, but helps build the so-called brand effect. In most mature categories in the consumer goods industry, the role of affective persuasion through mass media advertising is an important aspect of the entire marketing strategy. The competition between Coke and Pepsi is a case in point. Hence, it is our goal in this paper to examine competition when advertising simultaneously informs as well as persuades consumers.</p><p>We examine the cross-effects of advertising on prices, about which the marketing literature has been somewhat equivocal. Some experimental <ref type="bibr">(Moriarty 1983, Bemmaor and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Mouchoux 1991)</ref> and econometric studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bolton 1989 and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Popkowski-Leszczyc and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Rao 1989)</ref> indicate that advertising tends to increase price sensitivity. However, there are some <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Staelin and Winer 1976</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">, Ghosh et al. 1983</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">, Krishnamurthi and Raj 1985</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">, Boulding et al. 1994</ref>) that indicate the contrary. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kaul and Wittink (1995)</ref> suggest that the conflicting evidence depends on the type of the advertisement: price or nonprice. In this paper, we demonstrate that the direction of advertising effect on prices depends on the extent of latent inertia in consumers' purchase behavior. In particular, if a large proportion of consumers is locked into a certain brand, such that they exhibit strong tendencies of inertial (repeat) buying, then the impact of low levels of advertising on prices is negative. However, this impact is positive for high levels of advertising (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr">Kanetkar et al. 1992, Mitra and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Lynch 1995)</ref>. The effect of advertising on prices is governed by the relative magnitudes of the advertising elasticity of consumer consideration and that of persuasive goodwill. This endogenously generates sales, as well as profit functions, that are S-shaped, giving rise to the so-called "threshold effect" in advertising spending. We find that this effect is most pronounced when the cohort of inertial consumers is large.</p><p>In our duopoly model, advertising has no defensive role to play. No amount of advertising can prevent consumers of a brand from considering the other brand, if the other brand chooses to go after them by advertising. We show that, even in a symmetric game, there exist asymmetric (advertising) equilibria, wherein only one firm advertises, sets a higher price, and also captures a greater share of the market. An implication of the existence of asymmetric advertising equilibria in our static model seems to suggest that continuous advertising schedules may dominate pulsing policies in markets where consumers exhibit strong tendencies of inertial buying.</p><p>The remainder of the paper is organized as follows: §2 describes the model, §3 characterizes the equilibrium in the price-setting subgame, and §4 analyzes the different classes of the advertising equilibria for symmetric firms and discusses some of the comparative static issues. Section 5 provides a discussion on the model with asymmetric firms, and §6 concludes with directions for future research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">The Model</head><p>We consider a duopolistic market in which two firms, i = 1 and i = 2, produce a differentiated product with identical constant marginal cost of production equal to zero. The firms are risk neutral and engage in a two-stage noncooperative game. In Stage 1, the firms simultaneously choose their advertising levels; and in Stage 2, given the first-stage choices of advertising levels, the firms set prices simultaneously.</p><p>The firms compete over a market of fixed size, N , of whom 1 bought from Firm 1 before, and 2 = N − 1 bought from Firm 2 before. We could also interpret l /N and 2 /N as market shares of the respective firms. All consumers have unit demands; they buy one unit of the product as long as the price does not exceed their reservation price. Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hauser and Wernerfelt (1990)</ref>, brand choice is described as a twostage process: First, a consumer forms his/her consideration set (which may be influenced by the firms' BANERJEE AND BANDYOPADHYAY Advertising Competition Under Consumer Inertia advertising efforts) and decides whether to include one or both brands in the set. Then the actual purchase is made, depending on the brands in the consideration set and their respective prices.</p><p>Consistent with empirical regularity, our purpose is to analyze the scenario in which some consumers exhibit some amounts of inertia in forming their choice sets. We assume that all consumers who bought from Firm 1 (Firm 2) before will automatically include Brand 1 (Brand 2) in their choice sets. This amounts to saying that consumption of a brand results in some amount of locking in of customers for the following period. Now, whether the inertial consumers will include the brand they did not buy before in their choice sets will depend on the advertising levels of that brand. The choice set response to advertising is described herein.</p><p>Firms advertise in Stage 1 for two purposes. First, advertising allows consumers who did not buy the firm's product before to consider its brand as relevant. This endogenously partitions the market into a loyal segment (those who consider only one brand: a monopoly market for the brand) and a competitive segment (those who consider both brands: a duopoly market). If Firm 1 spends a 1 dollars on advertising, then a fraction K a l of the ( 2 ) Brand 2 consumers will include Brand 1 in their consideration set. We will call K a i the consideration function. Therefore, (1 − K a l 2 will be the number of consumers who will continue to have only Brand 2 in their consideration set. 1 Firm 2's advertising levels will have a similar effect. Note that this part of our model is similar in spirit to <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hauser and Wernerfelt (1989)</ref>. Therefore, we define the various segments in the market in the following way: M i = 1 − K a j i = the number of consumers with only Brand i in their consideration set (i.e., a monopoly segment for Firm i) and similarly for Brand j; and D = K a 2 1 + K a 1 2 = the number of consumers with both brands in their choice set (i.e., a duopoly segment). <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Second, advertising plays a persuasive role by way of scaling up the "perceived utility" attached to the consumption of one unit of the product. We model the persuasive role of advertising on the duopoly segment using the standard linear spatial model. For the consumers with both products in their choice set, the two firms are located at the extremes of a linear segment of unit distance. The consumers are distributed uniformly along the segment between the two firms, with density D. The perceived utility (gross of price paid) that a particular consumer attaches to consuming one unit of product i is given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Perceived utility of Brand i = r − tx i f a i i = 1 2 (1)</formula><p>where r &gt; 0 is a constant taken as a proxy for product quality, 0 &lt; x i &lt; 1 is the distance of the consumer from Firm i, and t is the transport cost per unit distance. Throughout the remainder of the paper, we assume r &gt; t = 1, so that perceived utility in ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>) is positive for all x. Note that the persuasiveness of advertising is relevant only for the duopoly segment, because the consumers with only one brand in their choice set will buy the product anyway (as long as the price does not exceed their reservation price).</p><p>Because we derive our results using numerical simulation, we will use specific forms to characterize the two advertising functions, K a i and f a i . Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Koh and Leung (1992)</ref>, we characterize the "persuasion" function of advertising, as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">f a i = 1+ a i w where w ∈ 0 1 (2)</formula><p>Note that f a i &gt;0; f a i &lt;0 ∀a i &gt; 0; and f 0 = 1, i = 1 2. On the other hand, the consideration function is described as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">K a i = 1− 1 d + a i s</formula><p>where d &gt;1 and s ∈ 0 1 . (3) Note that K a i &gt;0; K a i &lt;0 ∀a i &gt; 0; 0 &lt;K 0 &lt;1; and lim a i → K a i = 1, i = 1 2. In other words, K • is strictly concave (i.e., exhibits diminishing returns to advertising) and is asymptotic at 1 (i.e., it costs a firm infinite amount of advertising dollars to get the entire market to consider its brand). Furthermore, K • has an intercept, d −1 /d, which is a positive fraction. We shall call d the "inertia" parameter, such that K 0 → 0 or d → 1 implies extreme inertia in that the consumers do not consider the nonpurchased brand in the absence of advertising by the latter. Similarly, K 0 → 1 or d → reduces the model into a standard spatial model without any locked-in consumers. Because d &gt;1 in our model, there is always a cohort of consumers who will consider both brands, even in the absence of advertising by either firm.</p><p>Although our results will continue to hold with no further restrictions on f • other than strict concavity as in (2), it is intuitive that f • needs to be sufficiently concave relative to K • to prevent the perceived value of a brand for a large segment of the market from being driven to infinity by large advertising spending. For this purpose, in what follows, we state our results by pegging w = 0 5 and by assuming s ≤ w.</p><p>In summary, when a firm advertises in Stage 1, two effects are simultaneously in action. First, the density of the duopoly segment (i.e., consumers with both brands in their consideration sets) is determined. At the same time, the perceived values of the brands for the consumers therein are influenced. In Stage 2, the firms simultaneously set prices to maximize profits without being able to engage in any price discrimination.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">The Price-Setting Subgame</head><p>In what follows, we characterize the set of perfect equilibria in the multistage game for symmetric firms described, using the standard technique of backward induction. Hence, we examine the pricing subgame first.</p><p>Let us define L i &gt;r as the maximum price that any consumer is willing to pay for Brand i, i = 1 2. It may be argued that L i should realistically be a function of a i . However, in the context of our model, this would only complicate the algebra without having an effect on our main results. First, note that Firm i can sell to its entire monopoly segment (of size M i as long as p i ≤ L i . Now let us consider the duopoly segment. Using the standard solution concept for horizontal production differentiation (à la Hotelling) models, the sales for Firm 1 is obtained by the location (x D ) of the consumer who is indifferent to purchasing either of the two brands. For the indifferent customer: (r −x 1 f a 1 − p 1 = r − 1−x 1 f a 2 −p 2 , which when solved for x 1 yields Firm 1's share of sales to the duopoly segment as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">x D = p 2 −p 1 +r f a 1 −f a 2 +f a 2 f a 1 +f a 2 (4)</formula><p>Note that x D is a fraction, provided p 1 ≤ p 2 +r f a l − f a 2 +f a 2 , that becomes larger (smaller) as a 1 a 2 increases, or p 1 p 2 decreases (holding all other variables constant). If p 1 ≥ p 2 +r f a l −f a 2 +f a 2 , then Firm 1 has no sales in the duopoly segment. Also, if p 1 ≤ p 2 +r f a 1 −f a 2 −f a 1 , then Firm 1 is undercutting Firm 2's price enough to serve the entire duopoly market in addition to its M 1 locked-in customers.</p><p>Given that the marginal cost of production is assumed to be zero and that advertising expenditure is sunk in Stage 2, we can write Firm 1's profit function as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">1 = p 1 M 1 if L 1 ≥ p 1 ≥ p 2 +r f a l −f a 2 +f a 2 (5a) = p 1 M 1 +x D •D if L 1 ≥ p 2 +r f a l −f a 2 +f a 2 ≥ p 1 ≥ p 2 +r f a l −f a 2 −f a l (5b) = p 1 M 1 +D if L 1 ≥ p 2 +r f a l −f a 2 −f a l ≥ p 1 (5c)</formula><p>It is important to note here that the three distinct zones in Equations (5a), (5b), and (5c) make the profit function non-quasi-concave in prices. It can be shown that, in the pricing subgame, the best response function of Firm 1 (and similarly, Firm 2) is of the BANERJEE AND BANDYOPADHYAY Advertising Competition Under Consumer Inertia following form:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">1 p 2 =                      L 1 if p 2 ≤p 2 R 1 p 2 ifp 2 ≤ p 2 ≤ p 1 +r f a 2 −f a 1 +f a 1 p 2 +r f a 1 −f a 2 −f a 1 if L 2 ≥ p 2 ≥ p 1 +r f a 2 −f a 1 +f a 1 6a 6b 6c</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">R 1 p 2 = 1 2 p 2 + 1 2 f a 2 +r f a 1 −f a 2 + f a 1 +f a 2 M 1 D (7) andp 2 = maxp 2 M 1 L 1 = M 1 +Dx D R 1 p 2 p 2 R 1 p 2 (see Appendix for proof).</formula><p>Assuming that L i is never large enough to deter firms from competing for the duopoly segment and sell only to their respective monopoly segments, the pricing subgame has a unique equilibrium in pure strategies (p * 1 p * 2 ), which is obtained by solving R 1 p 2 = R 2 p 1 and is characterized by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">p * i = 1 3 1+r f a i + 2−r f a j + f a i +f a j D M j +2M i (8) i = 1 2; j = 3−i.</formula><p>Now we can show by differentiating Equation (8) with respect to a i and rearranging terms that:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">p * i a i = 1 3 f a i +f a j • r + 3−K a j K a i +K a j i v − 3−K a j K a i +K a j i c (<label>9</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_9">)</formula><p>where i v = f a i / a i / f a i +f a j is the "persuasion elasticity," whereas i c = K a i / a i / K a i + K a j is the "consideration elasticity" of advertising for Firm i. Note that the first term involving i v in parentheses in ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_8">9</ref>) is positive, whereas the last term involving i c is negative. Hence, the sign of the crosseffect of advertising on prices may not be unidirectional and will be determined by the interplay of the elasticities of the two advertising functions, i v and i c .</p><p>Proposition 1. Given any arbitrary a j , p * i / a i &gt; 0, 2 p * i / a 2 i &lt; 0, when d is large. However, p * i / a i &lt; 0 in the neighborhood of a i = 0 + , when d is small. Generally, equilibrium prices of firms increase (at a decreasing rate) with its own advertising spending, except when d is small, wherein prices initially decline with low levels of advertising.</p><p>Given that K • has an asymptote at 1, i c → 0 for large a i , whereas i v is positive. Therefore, when a i is large, p * i is increasing in a i in ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_8">9</ref>). Furthermore, concavity of f • by (3) ensures that 2 p * i / a 2 i &lt; 0 for large a i . However, an examination of ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_8">9</ref>) in the neighborhood of a i = 0 + yields an inflection in the price elasticity such that p * i / a i &lt; 0. Using the candidate functions in (2) and ( <ref type="formula">3</ref>), it can be shown that</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">p * i a i &lt; 0 if i c i v = sa s i 2+a w i +a w j wa w i d +a s i 2 2− 1 d +a s i − 1 d +a s j &gt; 1+ r K a i +K a j 3−K a j = 1+ r 2− 1 d +a s i − 1 d +a s j 2+ 1 d +a s j (10)</formula><p>This inequality holds when d → 1 and a i → 0 + . Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> illustrates the claim in the proposition for representative values of rival advertising levels. Note that the critical (small) value of d that generates the inflection in the neighborhood of a i = 0 + is increasing in the rival firm's advertising.</p><p>Proposition 2. Given any arbitrary a i , p * i / a j &gt; 0, 2 p * i / a 2 j &lt; 0, when d is large. However, p * i / a j &lt; 0 in the neighborhood of a j = 0, when d is small. Differentiating (8) with respect to a j and rearranging terms, we get</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">p * i a j = 1 3 f a i +f a j • 3+K a i K a i +K a j −r j v − 3+K a i K a i +K a j j c (11)</formula><p>The claim is established by proceeding similarly as in Proposition 1 by examining ( <ref type="formula">11</ref> (a) advertising _ j = 0 (b) advertising _ j = 1000 a j → 0 + . Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> illustrates the effects of the rival firm's advertising on the prices of firm i for representative values of its own advertising levels.</p><p>Compared with models with no consumer inertia, our model yields higher prices. However, the individual impacts of the two advertising functions on prices are somewhat different. The persuasive elements of advertising per se exert upward pressures on prices by communicating the brand differentiators more effectively. However, the "consideration" element of advertising increases the density of the duopoly segment at the expense of the monopoly segments, thereby leading to more aggressive pricing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">The Advertising Competition</head><p>With the pure strategy equilibrium prices characterized as functions of advertising levels in Equation ( <ref type="formula">8</ref>), we now fold the game backward to solve for the perfect Nash equilibrium in advertising under conditions of symmetry ( i = j . In Stage 1, Firm i faces the BANERJEE AND BANDYOPADHYAY Advertising Competition Under Consumer Inertia problem:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">Max a i i a i a j = p *</formula><p>i a i a j ×q i p * i a i a j p * j a i a j a i a j −a i where i • is the profit and q i • is sales at the end of Stage 2. Using p * i and p * j in (8), and the expression for sales from (5b), it can be shown that q i p * i p * j a i a j = Ap * i , where A = D/ f a i +f a j . This reduces the firm's problem to:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">Max a i i a i a j = Ap * i 2 −a i (<label>12</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_14">)</formula><p>Since the nonlinear advertising functions, (2) and ( <ref type="formula">3</ref>), enter the profit equation in ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_13">12</ref>) in a complex way, it is cumbersome to solve for the advertising equilibrium explicitly. Hence, in what follows, we implicitly derive the equilibria in the advertising game. (c) Except for an inflection in the neighborhood of a i = 0 + , the profit function is concave, such that interior maximizer in advertising exists. However, when d is small, the profit function has an S-shape, wherein profits initially decline (i.e., in the neighborhood of a i → 0 + and reach a minimum, and then begin to increase.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Proposition 3. The profit function in advertising levels (Equation (12)) has the following properties. (a) The intercept of the profit function is positive (i.e., firms make</head><p>The claims in (a) and (b) follow from the construction of the model and the fact that d &gt;1. To establish the claim in (c), note that differentiating (12) with respect to a i yields:</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">i a i = 2Ap * i p * i a i +p * i 2 A a i −1 (13)</formula><p>First, it can be shown that A/ a i = A i c − i v . Now, consider (13) when d is large. From Proposition 1, p * i / a i &gt; 0 implies that A/ a i &lt; 0. Also note that 2 p * i / a 2 i &lt; 0 ensures that (13) will have a unique maximizer in a i . However, by Proposition 1, p * i / a i &lt; 0 in the neighborhood of a i = 0 + , when d is small. It is seen that, although A/ a i &gt; 0 in this range of parameter values, 2Ap</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">* i p * i / a i −1 &gt; p * i 2</formula><p>A/ a i , such that the profit function has the claimed inflection in the neighborhood of a i = 0 + , when d → 1, that gives it the S-shape. Therefore, the shape of the profit function is also determined by the interplay of the two advertising elasticities, i c and i v , as in the price function in (8), with a dampened effect from the cost of advertising. Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref> illustrates the profit function for representative values of all the relevant parameters.</p><p>Given the properties of the profit functions as in Proposition 3, the first-order conditions for the profit maximization problem in (12) yield a pair of bestresponse functions in advertising, for i = 1 2. The Nash equilibrium in pure strategies in advertising levels a * i , a * j can be obtained from the solution(s) to the best response functions, i.e., by solving:</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">2Ap * i p * i a i +p * i 2 A a i = 2Ap * j p * j a j +p * j 2 A a j (<label>14</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_18">)</formula><p>Letã i denote firm i's advertising level, which solves Equation ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_17">14</ref>) for the range of a j , such that i ã i &gt; i 0 . We know (refer to Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>) that such anã i exists because i a i , a j is locally concave by Proposition 3, and max a i i a i a j &gt; i 0 a j for a range of a j ≥ 0. Therefore,ã i a j partially defines Firm i's bestresponse function in advertising.</p><p>Lemma 1. The best-response function in advertising is downward sloping, with a discontinuous segment, given as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">T i a j = ã i a j if a j ≤â j 0 otherwise, (<label>15</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_20">)</formula><p>whereâ j is the level of Firm j's advertising, such that i ã i â j â j = i 0 â j (see Appendix for proof ). Proposition 4. In the advertising game, equilibrium in pure strategy always exists. Given the advertising functions in (2) and (3), there exists a d * such that, (a) when d ≤ d * , the advertising game has three pure strategy equilibria, namely, a symmetric equilibrium (a * i = a * j &gt; 0), and two asymmetric equilibria (a i = 0 a j = a j 0 &gt;0 i j = 1 2 i = j); and</p><p>(b) when d &gt;d * , the symmetric equilibrium (a * i = a * j &gt; 0) is the only equilibrium of the game in pure strategies.</p><p>The proposition is best explained using Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref>, which illustrates Scenario (a). 3 Numerical computations show thatã i 0 is decreasing in d (i.e., Firm i's optimal advertising level in the absence of the rival brand advertising falls as inertia in consumer-buying behavior reduces). On the other hand,â i is seen to be increasing in d (i.e., Firm i's advertising level for which Firm j's best-response function will jump down to zero level of advertising increases as consumers become less inertial (see Table <ref type="table">1</ref>)). Now a small d generates a regime, whereã i 0 &gt;â j ≥ã i â j , that yields Case (a) in the proposition (see Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref>). However, a large d generates a regime, whereâ j &gt; a i 0 ≥ã i â j , which supports Case (b) in the proposition. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Table 1 exhibits howã i 0 â i and i ã i 0 change for different values of the inertia parameter, d, and traces d * given various configurations of the advertising parameters, s and w.</p><p>Although the intuition for the symmetric equilibrium is obvious, the existence of the asymmetric equilibria (in which only one firm advertises) is caused by the S-shaped nature of the profit function when d is small. Note that there is a locked-in (monopoly) segment always available to the firm to milk. Also, there will always be a finite group of consumers who are preferentially close to a brand (given the heterogeneity in the duopoly segment). Therefore, the optimal response to heavy rival advertising will be not to advertise.</p><p>Proposition 5. The firm that spends more in advertising charges a higher price and also sells more in equilibrium. A p * i −p * j ); i.e., the higher-priced firm sells more in equilibrium.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Using (8), we can show that p</head><formula xml:id="formula_21">* i −p * j = 1 3 2r −1 • f a i −f a j +D −1 f a i +f a j M i −M j . Clearly, p * i &gt;p * j if a i &gt;a j . Also, given sales, q * i = Ap * i , q * i −q * j =</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>BANERJEE AND BANDYOPADHYAY Advertising Competition Under Consumer Inertia</head><p>In summary, when a large percentage of consumers exhibit strong tendencies of inertial buying (d close to 1), our advertising game has two asymmetric equilibria in addition to a symmetric equilibrium (we ignore possibilities of mixed strategies). It is difficult to predict which of the above class of equilibria will actually emerge. It appears that, instead of simultaneous choice of advertising, if firms were to move sequentially (à la Stackelberg), then the asymmetric equilibrium will be the likely outcome. The firm moving first will advertise enough to position its product vis-à-vis the other's to make it unprofitable for the rival firm to choose advertising as a competitive tool. However, even in the asymmetric equilibria, the firm that does the advertising does not spend in a manner to drive the other firm out of the market.</p><p>On the other hand, when d is reasonably large (i.e., a sizeable portion of the consumers does not have any latent inertia in favor of repeat purchase), the advertising equilibrium will be uniquely determined. In such a case, both firms will choose the same level of advertising, charge the same price, and split the market in half.</p><p>The two different classes of the market outcome in the advertising game are driven by the nature of the profit function. In particular, local nonconcavities in the profit functions that are brought about by the so-called threshold effects of advertising response will generate the different kinds of equilibria. We claim that such threshold effects in revenue or profit response to advertising are caused by the interaction of the multidimensional effects of advertising, namely, getting consumers to include a brand in the consideration sets and subsequently influencing the brand valuation through persuasive communication.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Discussion: Asymmetric Firms</head><p>We showed in the preceding section that multiple equilibria in advertising competition exist even under the assumption of symmetry of market shares (i.e.,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>BANERJEE AND BANDYOPADHYAY Advertising Competition Under Consumer Inertia</head><p>Table <ref type="table">1</ref> Effect of Change in d on the Nature of Advertising Equilibria, for Various Values of s and w s = 0 1; w = 0 5; i = j = 50; r = 2     </p><formula xml:id="formula_22">d 1 1 1 125 1 15 * 1 2 1 3 1 4 ã i (</formula><formula xml:id="formula_23">s = 0 2; w = 0 5; i = j = 50; r = 2 d 1 1 1 15 1 2 * 1 3 1 4 1 5 ã i (</formula><formula xml:id="formula_24">s = 0 3; w = 0 5; i = j = 50; r = 2 d 1 1 1 2 1 25 1 3 * 1 4 1 5 ã i (</formula><formula xml:id="formula_25">s = 0 4; w = 0 5; i = j = 50; r = 2 d 1 1 1 2 1 3 1 35 * 1 4 1 5 ã i (</formula><formula xml:id="formula_26">s = 0 5; w = 0 5; i = j = 50; r = 2 d 1 1 1 2 1 3 1 35 1 4 * 1 5 ã i (</formula><formula xml:id="formula_27">1 = 2 ).</formula><p>It is worthwhile at this stage to reexamine the model under conditions of asymmetry ( 1 = 2 . We report our findings in Table <ref type="table">2</ref> for a representative set of parameter values and to provide a discussion.</p><p>It is evident that asymmetry in the shares of firms may change the nature of equilibria in our model. In particular, we find that there exist two scenarios that are in contrast to the symmetric firms case. First, for i sufficiently larger than j , we may have two advertising equilibria in pure strategies: one in which both firms spend positive (but different) amounts in advertising and another in which only the large firm advertises (Table <ref type="table">2</ref>, Regime a). When the difference in i and j is significantly more pronounced, the game has an unique equilibrium in which only the large firm advertises and the small one does not (Table <ref type="table">2</ref>, Regime b). Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref> illustrates Regime a.</p><p>To explain the result that a small share brand does not advertise in equilibrium, we revisit the price elasticity expressions ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_8">9</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_13">12</ref>) under asymmetry (i.e., when 1 = 2 ). Defining = 1 / 2 , it can be shown that:</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">p * i a i = 1 3 f a i +f a j r + 2−K a j +1 K a i + K a j i v − 2−K a j +1 K a i + K a j • K a i K a i + K a j (<label>16</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_29">)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_30">p * i a j = 1 3 f a i +f a j 1+K a i +2 K a i + K a j −r j v − 1+K a i +2 K a i + K a j • K a j K a i + K a j (<label>17</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_31">)</formula><p>We find that lim → p * i / a i &gt; 0 and also that lim →0 p * i / a j &gt; 0, indicating that the large brand's advertising spending unambiguously tends to increase not only its own price, but also that of the rival (small) firm. On the other hand, we find that lim →0 p * i / a i &lt; 0 and also lim → p * i / a j &lt; 0 in the neighborhood of a i = 0 and a j = 0, respectively, for d → 1 (similar to the inflection effects in the symmetric case in §3). This indicates that the initial advertising of the small firm immediately triggers a heightened price competition wherein both firms cut prices. Thus, when firms' shares of the market are sufficiently different (Regime b in Table <ref type="table">2</ref>), we find that advertising is never a viable competitive tool for the small firm. Although the small brand's advertising is proportionately more effective in the consideration stage, the prices are driven down to levels in which the incremental revenue from advertising does not cover the incremental costs of advertising for the small firm.</p><p>This finding supports the claim that a competitive tool like advertising does not serve the same purpose even for firms in the same industry <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Sutton 1991)</ref>. In oligopolistic industries comprised of large national brands, as well as small private labels, larger firms use advertising to reinforce their brand proposition among the value-conscious customer franchise. In contrast, the smaller players tend to compete on the basis of prices. This finding is consistent with</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>BANERJEE AND BANDYOPADHYAY Advertising Competition Under Consumer Inertia</head><p>Table <ref type="table">2</ref> Illustrations of Asymmetric Firms Equilibria (for s = 0 2, w = 0 5, d = 1 3, r = 2) ã 1 (0) â 1 ã 2 (0) â 2 ã 2 ã 1 â 2 1 0 ã 2 0 2 0 ã 2 0  A comparison of the small firm's profits in the equilibrium, where only the large firm is advertising, deserves emphasis. Note that, in Table <ref type="table">2</ref>, 1 0 ã 2 is increasing as 1 becomes smaller and smaller (i.e., the smaller the small firm, the better the profitability). The implication of this finding is that when large national brands advertise extensively in mature markets, the primary focus is on persuasive brand communication that also creates a halo around the "perceived value" of the category. This in turn increases the reference price umbrella, which is more efficient for the purpose of profit maximization, not only for themselves but also for the small firms. This assertion is further supported by the fact that the total spending on advertising by the large firm at the corner equilibrium exceeds the combined spending of both firms at the interior equilibrium, whenever it exists (see Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>). Our result explains why private label brands that never advertise in categories, such as beer continue to thrive in markets in which large entrenched national brands command a high share of the consumers' mind (Wall Street Journal 1994).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusion</head><p>Several studies in the marketing literature have postulated that advertising competition has to contend with the so-called threshold effect (wherein small advertising spending is are unprofitable) caused by the S-shaped response function. In this paper, we construct a model of advertising competition that endogenously generates such an S-shaped advertising response function. We show that such a shape of the profit-and-sales response function arises when advertising influences consumers in multidimensional ways that alter the proportion of consumer segments in a manner that creates opposing crosseffects on prices. We show that prices will increase or decrease from advertising, depending on the relative magnitudes of the consideration elasticity (encroaching into competitors' customer franchise) and the persuasion elasticity (enhancing value perception of a brand) of advertising. In the face of substantial media weight of the rival, the potential profitability from increased consumer consideration and goodwill through insubstantial advertising outlays is dissipated away through more intense price competition for the duopoly or competitive segment. It may be hypothesized that small spending on advertising has a competitive "commodification effect" ("just another beer"), which exerts downward pressures on prices. Consumers register the brand differentiators only when the advertising spending is substantial, and this in turn allows brands to earn a higher price premium. Our paper, therefore, provides a theoretical reconciliation of the longstanding debate in the marketing literature regarding the impact of advertising on prices (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kaul and Wittink 1995)</ref>.</p><p>Consumer inertia or lock-in is a critical parameter that drives the market outcome in our model of advertising price competition. When a large proportion of consumers exhibit latent inertia against brand switching, then a multiplicity of market outcomes may be supported as equilibria in our simultaneous move game. Although it is difficult to predict which of the equilibrium outcomes would actually occur, we can conclude that, given the equilibrium payoffs, there exists a strong first-mover advantage for competing (symmetric) firms. In particular, if the firms' advertising decisions were sequential, then the firm moving first may advertise in such a way as to force an equilibrium, where advertising as a competitive tool is not viable for the follower firm.</p><p>The extension of our analysis for asymmetric firms (in terms of their market shares) suggests that advertising is generally a nonviable competitive tool for smaller firms. In particular, we establish that, when the market shares of the firm are significantly different, then the unique equilibrium has only the large firm advertising. More significantly, our numerical calculations show that when firm sizes are sufficiently asymmetric, the smaller the size of the small firm, the better is its profitability in equilibrium in which only the large firm advertises. In the absence of the small brand advertising, larger brand shares encourage firms to allocate higher expenditures on advertising to enhance the perceived brand value of their brand, which in turn shore up the average prices in the industry from which both the firms benefit.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>BANERJEE AND BANDYOPADHYAY Advertising Competition Under Consumer Inertia</head><p>Our results suggest that the existence of consumer heterogeneity, which slices the market into discontinuous segments, introduces local convexities in the firms' objective functions. These often lead to outcomes and marketing implications, which cannot really be inferred from marketing models that rely on conceptualizing consumer heterogeneity on a continuum.</p><p>Ours is a simple static model that examines advertising price cross-effects. It may be worthwhile to examine advertising scheduling decisions in a dynamic version of our model of advertising competition in oligopolistic markets with high levels of latent consumer inertia. We hypothesize that a continuous advertising schedule may outperform pulsing policies in such a model. Another useful extension of our model would be to allow firms to choose awareness and persuasive advertising separately, and then engage in price competition.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1Impact of d on Price Sensitivity from Own Advertising</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2Impact of d on Price-Sensitivity from Rival Advertising</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3Profit Functions in Own Advertising Levels</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 4Advertising Equilibria</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 5Advertising Equilibria</figDesc></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">If N is large, we could convert this model into a one consumer model, where K a i will be the probability that a consumer who previously purchased Brand j now considers Brand i.2 If we interpret K • purely as an information transmission process, then M i is the number of people who are only informed</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">about Brand i, i = 1 2; and D is the number of people who are informed about both brands.Marketing Science/Vol. 22, No. 1, Winter 2003</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Marketing Science/Vol. 22, No. 1, Winter 2003</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">The existence of equilibrium for symmetric firms is guaranteed because the best-response functions in (15) are downward sloping for a j ≤â j and the fact thatã i = 0 for a j ≥â j .4  Note that there exists another theoretical possibility, namelỹ a i 0 &gt;ã i â j &gt;â j , under which the two asymmetric equilibria (a i = 0, a j =ã j 0 &gt;0; i j = 1 2 i = j) will be the only two pure strategy equilibria in advertising. However, computations using (2) and (3) and our parameter restriction s ≤ w = 0 5 show that this scenario does not occur.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">This paper was received January 24, 2000, and was with the authors 21 months for 3 revisions; processed by K. Sridhar Moorthy.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank Dan Kovenock, Manohar Kalwani, Stylianos Perrakis, Murgie Krishnan, and three anonymous referees for their useful comments on earlier drafts of this paper. We also thank Dheeraj Awasthy for his research assistance. The second author gratefully acknowledges the financial support of the School of Business and Economics, Indiana University Northwest; Research and the University Graduate School, Indiana University; and the Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council of Canada (Grant 410-95-0732).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix</head><p>The best-response function of Firm 1 (and similarly, Firm 2) is of the following form:</p><p>Proof. For an arbitrary p 2 , the shape of the profit function of Firm 1 (given in Equations (6a), (6b), and (6c)) is not quasi-concave in p 1 . Given any p 2 , Firm 1's profit function is not differentiable at p 1 = p 2 +r f a l −f a 2 −f a 2 and at p 1 = p 2 +r f a 1 −f a 2 − f a l . Therefore, we need to analyze three different cases to specify completely the firms' best-response functions in prices.</p><p>First, since Firm 1 (Firm 2) has a segment of locked-in consumers whose choice sets contain only Brand 1, it is assured of the monopoly profit it can make from them. Hence, if L 1 &gt; 0 is the maximum price the captive consumers are willing to pay for Brand 1, then for very low prices of Firm 2 (such as in the range of prices given in (6a)), Firm 1's best response may be to charge L 1 and make the maximum possible profit from its locked-in customers. This implies that there will be a discontinuity in the two firms' best-response functions in the p 1 −p 2 space.</p><p>At the other extreme, in the range of prices given in (6c), Firm 1 is selling to the entire competitive segment in addition to its lockedin customers; hence, assuming all consumers buy, its best response is to set</p><p>Finally, in the range of prices given in (6b), Firm 1's profit function is strictly concave in its price. This is the range of prices in which some consumers from the duopoly segment buy from Firm 1, whereas others buy from Firm 2. Therefore, in this case, we can get Firm 1's best-response to Firm 2's prices by looking at the first-order condition for profit maximization. Thus, for prices as in (6c),</p><p>1 / p 1 = 0 yields:</p><p>The second-order condition for a global maximum holds, since</p><p>Similar analysis for Firm 2 yields the following first-order condition:</p><p>As noted previously, Equations (A1) and (A2) only partially describe a pair of reaction functions in the p 1 −p 2 space. We now need to look at the point of discontinuity in the firms' price reaction functions. For that purpose, let us define:</p><p>In other words,p 2 is that price of Firm 2 for which Firm 1 is indifferent to selling only to its captive customers at price L 1 and going after part of the duopoly segment (along with its captive customers) by its best alternative (i.e., R 1 p 2 . Therefore, only when p 2 &gt;p 2 will Firm 1 attempt to sell to a portion of the duopoly segment. Now we can specify Firm 1's reaction function in prices as follows (ignoring the case when p 2 &gt;L 2 , because such a price is strictly dominated):</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>BANERJEE AND BANDYOPADHYAY Advertising Competition Under Consumer Inertia</head><p>Similar analysis for Firm 2 will yield its corresponding reaction function 2 p 1 with the point of discontinuity beingp 1 , defined similar to (A3).</p><p>Lemma. The best-response function in advertising is downward sloping, with a discontinuous segment, given as:</p><p>whereâ j is defined as the level of Firm j's advertising such that i ã i â j â j = i 0 â j .</p><p>Proof. We know that Firm i's profits are decreasing in Firm j's advertising levels by Proposition 3a. Now by Proposition 3c in the previous text, and the fact that 1 0 &gt;0, there exists anâ j such that i ã i â j â j = i 0 â j . Given that profits of firms decrease in rival's advertising by Proposition 3b, for all a j &gt; â j , we have i 0 &gt; i ã i a j . Hence, whenever Firm j's advertising level exceedsâ j , Firm i's best response is to choose a i = 0 and earn profit i 0 a j . This establishes the claim in the lemma.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring the shortterm effect of in-store promotion and retail advertising on brand sales: A factorial experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Bemmaor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mouchoux</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="202" to="214" />
			<date type="published" when="1991-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The relationship between market characteristics and promotional price elasticities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Bolton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="169" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mastering the mix: Do advertising, promotion, and sales-force activities lead to differentiation?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Boulding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="172" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Equilibrium distribution of sales and advertising prices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Butters</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">138</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="465" to="491" />
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Advertising and Market Power</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Comanor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Are there associations between price elasticity and brand characteristics?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ghosh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Neslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Shoemaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Educators&apos; Conf. Proc</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gene</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Laczniak</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ferrell</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>AMA, Chicago, IL</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="226" to="230" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Informative advertising with differentiated products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Grossman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econom. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="81" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The competitive implications of relevant-set/response analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Wernerfelt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="391" to="405" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>An evaluation cost model of consideration sets</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="393" to="409" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Price sensitivity and television advertising exposures: Some empirical findings</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kanetkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Weinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Weiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="359" to="371" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empirical generalizations about the impact of advertising on price sensitivity and price</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kaul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wittink</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Part 2 of 2) G151-G160</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Persuasive Advertising. Department of Business Policy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T H</forename><surname>Koh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Leung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>National University of Singapore</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of advertising on consumer price sensitivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Krishnamurthi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Raj</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Marketing Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="129" />
			<date type="published" when="1985-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a reconciliation of market power and information theories of advertising effects on price elasticity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lynch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Consumer Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="644" to="659" />
			<date type="published" when="1995-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feature advertising-price interaction effects in the retail environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Moriarty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Retailing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="98" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information and consumer behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Political Economy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="729" to="742" />
			<date type="published" when="1970" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>J. Political Economy</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical analysis of national and local brands advertising effects on price elasticity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Popkowski-Leszczyc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="160" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An unobservable variable model for determining the effect of advertising on consumer purchases</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Staelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Russell</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Winer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Marketing 1776-1976 and Beyond: 1976 Educators&apos; Proc. AMA</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kenneth</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bernhardt</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Chicago, IL</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sunk Costs and Market Structures-Price Competition, Advertising, and the Evolution of Concentration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Boston, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Theory of Industrial Organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tirole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Boston, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>4th ed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Private label beers try to brew interest</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wall Street Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994-01-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
